<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<TEI.2>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div0 type="ordinarysAccount" id="OA16891023">
            <interp inst="OA16891023" type="uri" value="ordinarysAccounts/OA16891023"/>
            <interp inst="OA16891023" type="date" value="16891023"/>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA168910230001"/>
            <p>A True ACCOUNT of the BEHAVIOR, CONFESSION, AND Last Dying SPEECHES Of the Prisoners that were Executed at TYBURN, On the 23d of OCTOBER.1689.</p>
            <p>THE Ordinary visited the condemned Prisoners every day, from that on which the Sentence of Death was past on them, till and at the day of their Execution.</p>
            <p>On the first day, being Thursday was Seven night, he found, them little sensible of their sinful and deplorable condition. The next day they were more awakened from their Security. On Saturday, after three days counsel, and often praying with them, they much lamented the sinful course of their Lives, and gave the Ordinary good Encouragement and hopes of the success of his Care for their Souls. After he had excited them to examine their Hearts, and to bring their Sins to remembrance, and was apprehensive of some dispositions tending to Repentance. He desired them to beg of God, that the Convictions on their Conscience might proceed to a thorow Conversion, and that they might not deceive themselves with any false hopes of Heaven, staring the Nature of True Faith and Repentance, as indispensible Qualifications for Eternal Happiness. Every day some Hours were spent in Discourse and Prayers relating thereunto.</p>
            <p>On the Saturday the Ordinary exhorted them to prepare for the Duties of the Sabbath, which they denied not that they had prophan'd.</p>
            <p>In the Forenoon and Afternoon of the Lord's Day, he preacht on the 12th Chapter of the 2d Book of the Chronicles, and the 14th Verse Rehoboam did much Evil, because he prepared net his heart to seek the Lord, &amp;c.</p>
            <p>First, That the Omission of any Duty, if it be Indulged, doth not only marr or deprive of the Benefit of every other Duty, but exposes us to the commission of many Sins.</p>
            <p>Secondly, That we may sin to the doing of our Duty, if we do not discharge it dutifully and faithfully; God's Command being the Motive, and his Glory our Aim in which we centre with delight. Rehoboam did seek the Lord, but yet he prepared not his heart to seek him with the full strength of his Souls Faculties and Delight. The Lord accounts formal flight Addresses to him as a disservice, and dishonour. He would cast back such Sacrifices, as Dung in our Faces, Mal. 23. They call not on God's Name acceptably, who do not stir up themselves to take hold on him, and rejoice to work Righteonsness. sa 4, 7, 8. If we think by saint hearted Services to palliate our Iniquities, we multiply them without suspicion, and so Satan takes a deeper and firmer possession of our hearts. Let not therefore our hearts gather Vanity to themselves, in seeking the Face of God Remisly. God the Father seeks out such, who Worship him in Spirit and Truth, according to the Rule of Truth in his Sacred Word, and in the Truth or Uprightness of their hearts, St. John 4-23. He seeks them, such arc very few, and it denotes also, that they are of a rare and most excellent Spirit, according to Psalm 24. 6. Such are Blessed indeed, who seek their whole heart, Psal. 119, 2. But the Wicked through the Pride of his Countenance will not seek after God, they say we are Lords, can Stand alone by ourselves, we will came no more at Thee, Jer. 2.3. He would set his Face and Heart against such, when they come to Inquire after him in Distress, Ezek 34. 7, 8. Prov. 1. 26, 27, 28: Psal. 8 1. 11, 12.</p>
            <p>
               <persName id="OA16891023n9-2">
                  <interp inst="OA16891023n9-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16891023n9-2" type="surname" value="Brooks"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16891023n9-2" type="given" value="Charles"/>Charles Brooks</persName> Condemned for breaking open the House of Mr. <persName id="OA16891023n9-1">
                  <interp inst="OA16891023n9-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16891023n9-1" type="surname" value="BARRINGER"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16891023n9-1" type="given" value="WILLIAM"/>William Barringer</persName>, and bearing thence several things, as also Money, in all to the Value of about 100 l. He was more knowing than the other, therefore I told him, his Sin was the greater, That he who knew his Masters Will, and prepared not himself to do it, shall be beaten with many stripes. He was from the beginning very traable to me, Attentive to Counsel, Reverent in Praying. Some doubts he had, which I resolved. He was very Penitent, and desired me to sit him for the Holy Communion before his Condemnation, not like some who desire it in an hurry of distracted Thoughts only on the Morning of the Execution, when they are not well prepared for it. I shall say the less of him, because he hath promised to give me the Narrative of his Life at the publick place of Suffering.</p>
            <p>
               <persName id="OA16891023n10-1">
                  <interp inst="OA16891023n10-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16891023n10-1" type="surname" value="DELACORE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16891023n10-1" type="given" value="WILLIAM"/>William Delacore</persName> did the like, and was in as good a frame as the former. He was <rs id="OA16891023-occupation-1" type="occupation">Apprentice</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA16891023n10-1 OA16891023-occupation-1"/> to Mr. <persName id="OA16891023n10-2">
                  <interp inst="OA16891023n10-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16891023n10-2" type="surname" value="COOK"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16891023n10-2" type="given" value="THOMAS"/>Thomas Cook</persName>, a <rs id="OA16891023-occupation-2" type="occupation">Merchant</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA16891023n10-2 OA16891023-occupation-2"/>. But served not fully out his time. He had 30 l. per Annum left him by his Father in Ireland, of which being deprived, as other Protestants lately. He said, this brought him into streights, then he joined with bad Company, in hope of Advantage by wronging of others, he says this was the first Fact, for which he is heartily sorry. But he promised me to give large, satisfaction in a Narrative of his former Life, and present fitness to Die.</p>
            <p>Delacore farther said, That if he may be spared, he hopes and intends to lead a New Life. Being Ask'd what Saving Faith is, he said, Its an humble Relyance on Gods Mercies and Christ for Eternal Life. His Faith working by Love, which he hopes it doth, because he is more Grieved for offending God, than for Shame and Punishment, tho some are more troubled for offending a Friend than God. I think he was Penirent.</p>
            <p>
               <persName id="OA16891023n12-2">
                  <interp inst="OA16891023n12-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16891023n12-2" type="surname" value="Kelsay"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16891023n12-2" type="given" value="Thomas"/>Thomas Kelsay</persName> Condemnd for Felony and Burglary. He is Aged Twenty Years, was Born in <placeName id="OA16891023-geo-1">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA16891023n12-2 OA16891023-geo-1"/>St. Andrews Holborn</placeName> Parish, was bred up at Mr. Lanes <placeName id="OA16891023-geo-2">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA16891023n12-2 OA16891023-geo-2"/>School at St. Lawrence Church</placeName>. Was <rs id="OA16891023-occupation-3" type="occupation">Prentice to a Weaver</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA16891023n12-2 OA16891023-occupation-3"/> Three Years and an Half. He is sorry that he joined with ill Company, that since he left his Trade he hath been given to follow Bad Women, with whom he was Unclean, but hates the thoughts of them now, and of breaking the Sabbath. He Prays for Divide Assistance, that his heart may be changed. If he may Live, he intends to mind and serve God better. And said if his Peace be made with him, he shall not much fear Death.</p>
            <p>
               <persName id="OA16891023n13-1">
                  <interp inst="OA16891023n13-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16891023n13-1" type="surname" value="Bond"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16891023n13-1" type="given" value="William"/>William Bond</persName> Condemned for Felony and Burglary, Aged 21, Born in <placeName id="OA16891023-geo-3">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA16891023n13-1 OA16891023-geo-3"/>Wiltshire</placeName>, a <rs id="OA16891023-occupation-4" type="occupation">Baker</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA16891023n13-1 OA16891023-occupation-4"/> by Trade: He was once a <rs id="OA16891023-occupation-5" type="occupation">Soldier</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA16891023n13-1 OA16891023-occupation-5"/> in the West. He Lifted himself, because after Two Years Service he had spent his Masters Money upon Women. And that on the Sabbath, tho' he went to Church with his Master, yet he would slip out thence to the Alehouse, that he Seldom Prayd. But now he hopes he Repents, and is sorry, that he is no more knowing in Matters of Religion: That his sorrow for Sin makes God no Amends, he hopes to be saved only by Christs Merits, vet begs that he may not be deceived as to his preparations for ternal Life.</p>
            <p>
               <persName id="OA16891023n14-1">
                  <interp inst="OA16891023n14-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16891023n14-1" type="surname" value="Hoane"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16891023n14-1" type="given" value="John"/>John Hoane</persName>, Aged 20 Years, Born in <placeName id="OA16891023-geo-4">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA16891023n14-1 OA16891023-geo-4"/>Southward</placeName>, he was not Obedient to his tender Mother, he rose formerly on the Sabbath to go to an Early Lecture, But afterward neglected Religious Duties, and joind himself to Bad Company. He is sorry that he followed not the Advice of good Ministers, whose Preaching be once attended upon, but of late hath been given to Swearing, and said, he grieved that he is fallen away from that Knowledg which once he did live up to, but hopes that God will not take his Spirit tterly from him. He Prays that he would take away his Stony. Heart, and that it may not deceive him in his preparation for Death, but may be upright in what he doth.</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA168910230002"/>
            <p>The paper delivered by <persName id="OA16891023n15-2">
                  <interp inst="OA16891023n15-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16891023n15-2" type="surname" value="Delacore"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16891023n15-2" type="given" value="William"/>William</persName>, alias <persName id="OA16891023n15-1">
                  <interp inst="OA16891023n15-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16891023n15-1" type="surname" value="DELACORE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16891023n15-1" type="given" value="GEORGE"/>George Delacore</persName>, at the place of Execution.</p>
            <p>I Was born a <rs id="OA16891023-occupation-6" type="occupation">Gentleman</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA16891023n15-1 n15-2 OA16891023-occupation-6"/>, my Father was a Quartermaster of a Troop of Horse, and a Man of a pretty good Estate. As for my Education, I was brought up to <rs id="OA16891023-occupation-7" type="occupation">Merchandize, Apprentice</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA16891023n15-1 n15-2 OA16891023-occupation-7"/> to <persName id="OA16891023n16-1">
                  <interp inst="OA16891023n16-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16891023n16-1" type="surname" value="COOK"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16891023n16-1" type="given" value="THOMAS"/>Thomas Cook</persName> of <placeName id="OA16891023-geo-5">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA16891023n15-1 n15-2 n16-1 OA16891023-geo-5"/>Cork</placeName> in <placeName id="OA16891023-geo-6">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA16891023n15-1 n15-2 n16-1 OA16891023-geo-6"/>Ireland</placeName>, but was led away by lewd Woman, first as to the breaking the Sabbath, and then to a habit of Drunkenness, and other Debanche ies, insomach that I denied my self nothing of sensual Pleasure: But, upon better consideration, thinking to shake off this Course of Life, I went with a small Venture to <placeName id="OA16891023-geo-7">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA16891023n15-1 n15-2 OA16891023-geo-7"/>Flanders</placeName>, but not being successful therein, I returned, and entered my self in a Troop belonging to the Lord of Shannon, Governor of Cork, and when King Charles II. dyed, I quitted the Troop, and came for London, doubting the Alteration the Protestants would find by the scourge of Popery. And here I married, setling in a <rs id="OA16891023-occupation-8" type="occupation">Victualling-House</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA16891023n15-1 n15-2 OA16891023-occupation-8"/>, living in Credit, by the support of what Yearly my Father left me: But that being cut off, by the Troubles that have since airsen in Ireland, and Debts growing fast upon me, I, in those Circumstances, unfortunately hapned with one <persName id="OA16891023n16-2">
                  <interp inst="OA16891023n16-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16891023n16-2" type="surname" value="WOOD"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16891023n16-2" type="given" value="GEORGE"/>George Wood</persName>, who gain'd so much influence over me, as to bring me to the Commitment of the Crime I am now to Die for. Having given this satisfaction to the World, I humbly beg pardon of all those I have wronged, as I hope I shall receive the same from Almighty God for my Sins upon my departing this Life, which I trust is for a better in Heaven: But if it had pleased Almighty God to have prolonged my Days, I should, with an afflicted Heart, have repented me of my mispent Time, and redeem it, in my Duty to God and Man, to my Lives end, to the Honour and Glory of my Master, and the Comfort of my own Soul. So departing this Life in Amity, begging the Prayers of all good Christians, I recommend my self to God, concluding these my imperfect Prayers, in the words of my Redeemer, VIZ. Our Father, &amp;c.</p>
            <p>A Paper delivered by <persName id="OA16891023n17-1">
                  <interp inst="OA16891023n17-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16891023n17-1" type="surname" value="BROOKS"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16891023n17-1" type="given" value="CHARLES"/>Charles Brooks</persName> at the place of Execution.</p>
            <p>I Came of honest Parents, who, whilst they lived, brought me up in the Fear of God, and in the Communion of the Church of England, in which I now die, and do hope, through the Merits of my Lord and Saviour Jesus Christ; That although I am dispossessed of this Life, I shall not be so of that which is to come. I must own I have been a great Sinner, for several Years, for which I humbly beg pardon of God. The breaking of the Sabbath lies heavy upon me, for which notwithstanding, through the Merits of Jesus Christ, I hope for Pardon: But as for Murder, I thank God I never had that in my Thoughts, but cannot excuse my self upon the account of most other Sins, for my Sins were many and grievous, though my Years have been few and evil. I beg that my sad Example may be a Warning to all that see or hear of my untimely End; therefore, for God's sake, keep the Sabbath, and serve the Lord your God, and pray that you may not come to this shame. However, I abundantly thank my Maker, That he has let me know the number of my days, even to the hour of my Departure: Fore Death, many times, comes like a Thief, when Man least expects it: I beg all good Peoples Prayers, and recommend my Soul to God that gave it, and the Lord have Mercy upon me; The Lord gave, and the Lord taketh away, Blessed be the Name of the Lord. Signed C.B.</p>
            <p>The prisoners above mentioned were put in Two Carts between Ten and Eleven in the Morning. in order to be carried to the place of Execution, but by the way, in hopes of his Amendment of Life, <persName id="OA16891023n19-1">
                  <interp inst="OA16891023n19-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16891023n19-1" type="surname" value="KELSEY"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16891023n19-1" type="given" value="THOMAS"/>Thomas Kelsey</persName> received a Reprieve, and the rest were carried to Tyburn, where Horn and Delacourt, in a more especial manner, bewailed their unhappy Ends, begging Pardon of God for their manifold Offences, and of all they had Injured, confessing themselves to be great Sinners, and desiring the Prayers of the Spectators, and that they would take Warning by their untimely Ends, not to break the Sabbath, follow Drunkenness, or Evil Company, or hearken to Temptations than might draw them into Ruin. Delacourt's Wife, a young Woman, that had been married to him about 9 Months, all in Tears, came up into the Carr, and he there Exhorted to be Contented, and serve God, thas so she might Live to see happy Days; and indeed they were all of them very Penitent. The Ordinary Prayed with them, gave them the Absolution of the Church of England, seriously Exhorted them, that in this their great Extremity, they would not give way to Temptation, but lay hold on Christ by way of Faith, repeated the Articles of the Christian Faith, which they owned to be the true ground of Salvation, and Sung a psalm, in which they joined, and after they had Prayed to themselves, and Delacourt had Answered some Questions asked him by the Party he had Robbed, the Cart drew a way, and they were Committed to the Mercy of their Creator.</p>
            <p>This is all the Account that I can give of this Session.</p>
            <p>Dated this 23d if October, 1689. <persName id="OA16891023n21-1">
                  <interp inst="OA16891023n21-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16891023n21-1" type="surname" value="SMITH"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16891023n21-1" type="given" value="SAMUEL"/>Samuel Smith</persName>, <rs id="OA16891023-occupation-9" type="occupation">Ordinary</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA16891023n21-1 OA16891023-occupation-9"/>.</p>
            <p>Licens'd, October 23. 1689.</p>
            <p>Advertisements.</p>
            <p>These are to give Notice to all Persons, for the Benefit of the Publick, That mr. Elmy, Professor of Physick, and Operator, of known Integrity, and above 25 Years practice, Liveth at the Blue Ball in WhaleBone Court, at the Lower End of Bartholomew-lane by the royal Exchange, who most safely and expeditiously Cures Deafness and Noise in the Ears in any of what Age soever, (if Curable) and at first Sight, by Inspection, Resolves the Patient if so or not, as most Eminent Persons of Quality in this City can TeslifieHe hath likewise a most excellent Gargarism or MouthWater, which will make black or yellow Teeth as white as Ivory, in a few times using; and it will certainly cure the Scurvy, and all other Diseases incident to the Mouth, Teeth and Gums, which in many persons eauseth a stinking breath, which (by the Blessing of God, and the use of this Water) I dare affirm you will be freed from those maladies before mentioned, with Directions. His Pills only prepared for the French Disease, and the Running of the Reins, may be had in Boxes of several prices, with other Venereal Arcana's, as occasion requires, with Directions.</p>
            <p>In Plow-Yard in Grays-Inn-Lane, lives Dr. <persName id="OA16891023n25-1">
                  <interp inst="OA16891023n25-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16891023n25-1" type="surname" value="KIRLEUS"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16891023n25-1" type="given" value="THOMAS"/>Thomas Kirleus</persName> a <rs id="OA16891023-occupation-10" type="occupation">Collegiate physician</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA16891023n25-1 OA16891023-occupation-10"/>, and Sworn Physician to Charles II. until his Death: Who with a Drink and Pill, hindering no Business, Cures all Ulcers, Scabs, Scurfs in the Face, or elsewhere; Kings-Evil, Leprosie, and Venereal Disease, expecting nothing if he Cures notOf the last, he hath Cured above 500 persons in this City, many after Fluxing. It quickly and safely Cures it in the beginning, which cannot be done with Mercury, without danger of Life. The Drink in 3 s. the Quare, the Pill 1 s. the Box, which is two Purges. They excel all Purges, in cleansing all Crudities and Impurities, and So prevent and Cure many Diseases, and especially the Gout and Stone. In all Diseases he gives his Opinion for nothing, and his Medicines for little.</p>
            <p>
               <placeName id="OA16891023-geo-8">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA16891023n26-1 OA16891023-geo-8"/>LONDON</placeName>, Printed for <persName id="OA16891023n26-1">
                  <interp inst="OA16891023n26-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16891023n26-1" type="surname" value="CURTISS"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16891023n26-1" type="given" value="LANGLEY"/>Langley Curtiss</persName> at <placeName id="OA16891023-geo-9">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA16891023n26-1 OA16891023-geo-9"/>Sir Edmondbury Godfrey's Head</placeName> near <placeName id="OA16891023-geo-10">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA16891023n26-1 OA16891023-geo-10"/>Fleet-bridge</placeName>. 1689.</p>
         </div0>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>