<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<TEI.2>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div0 type="ordinarysAccount" id="OA16840917">
            <interp inst="OA16840917" type="uri" value="ordinarysAccounts/OA16840917"/>
            <interp inst="OA16840917" type="date" value="16840917"/>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA168409170001"/>
            <p>THE BEHAVIOUR OF THE Condemned Criminals IN NEWGATE,VIZ; <persName id="OA16840917n2-1">
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n2-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n2-1" type="surname" value="CASKEY"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n2-1" type="given" value="GEORGE"/>George Caskey</persName>, <persName id="OA16840917n2-2">
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n2-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n2-2" type="surname" value="PEVANSON"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n2-2" type="given" value="FRANCIS"/>Francis Pevanson</persName>, <persName id="OA16840917n2-3">
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n2-3" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n2-3" type="surname" value="BALLANTINE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n2-3" type="given" value="DANIEL"/>Daniel Ballantine</persName>, <persName id="OA16840917n2-4">
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n2-4" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n2-4" type="surname" value="PIERCE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n2-4" type="given" value="WILLIAM"/>William Pierce</persName>, <persName id="OA16840917n2-5">
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n2-5" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n2-5" type="surname" value="VICKERS"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n2-5" type="given" value="THOMAS"/>Thomas Vickers</persName>. and <persName id="OA16840917n2-6">
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n2-6" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n2-6" type="surname" value="BROOMFIELD"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n2-6" type="given" value="CHRISTIAN"/>Christian Broomfield</persName>, <persName id="OA16840917n2-7">
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n2-7" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n2-7" type="surname" value="RATCLIFF"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n2-7" type="given" value="ELIZABETH"/>Elizabeth Ratcliff</persName>, <persName id="OA16840917n2-8">
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n2-8" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n2-8" type="surname" value="VOSSE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n2-8" type="given" value="MARY"/>Mary Vosse</persName>, <persName id="OA16840917n2-9">
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n2-9" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n2-9" type="surname" value="BOURNE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n2-9" type="given" value="JANE"/>Jane Bourne</persName>, <persName id="OA16840917n2-10">
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n2-10" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n2-10" type="surname" value="SMITH"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n2-10" type="given" value="ANN"/>Ann Smith</persName>. From their Sentence, to his Majesties Gracious Repreive. As Also Of <persName id="OA16840917n2-12">
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n2-12" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n2-12" type="surname" value="Richardson"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n2-12" type="given" value="John"/>John Richardson</persName>, a <rs id="OA16840917-occupation-1" type="occupation">Tinker</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA16840917n2-12 OA16840917-occupation-1"/> (for Murdering, his Wife) and <persName id="OA16840917n2-11">
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n2-11" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n2-11" type="surname" value="TUE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n2-11" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Tue</persName>, for Murdering the Bayliffs Follower, To Their Execution at Tyburn, On Wendesday the 17th. of September, 1684.</p>
            <p>TOGETHER With his last FAREWELL to his Dear Wife, and little INFANT.</p>
            <p>WHereas at the late Sessions of Gaol-Delivery, held in the Old-Bayly, on Wendesday, Thursday and Friday, the 3d, 4th, and 5th Days of September Instant. Twelve Persons received Sentence of Death, viz. <persName id="OA16840917n4-1">
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n4-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n4-1" type="surname" value="CASKEY"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n4-1" type="given" value="GEORGE"/>George Caskey</persName>, <persName id="OA16840917n4-2">
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n4-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n4-2" type="surname" value="PEVANSON"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n4-2" type="given" value="FRANCIS"/>Francis Pevanson</persName>, <persName id="OA16840917n4-3">
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n4-3" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n4-3" type="surname" value="BALLANTINE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n4-3" type="given" value="DANIEL"/>Daniel Ballantine</persName>, <persName id="OA16840917n4-4">
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n4-4" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n4-4" type="surname" value="BROOMFIELD"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n4-4" type="given" value="CHRISTIAN"/>Christian Broomfield</persName>, <persName id="OA16840917n4-5">
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n4-5" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n4-5" type="surname" value="RATCLIFF"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n4-5" type="given" value="ELIZABETH"/>Elizabeth Ratcliff</persName>, <persName id="OA16840917n4-6">
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n4-6" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n4-6" type="surname" value="VOSSE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n4-6" type="given" value="MARY"/>Mary Vosse</persName>, <persName id="OA16840917n4-7">
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n4-7" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n4-7" type="surname" value="PIERCE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n4-7" type="given" value="WILLIAM"/>William Pierce</persName>, <persName id="OA16840917n4-8">
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n4-8" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n4-8" type="surname" value="VICKERS"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n4-8" type="given" value="THOMAS"/>Thomas Vickers</persName>, <persName id="OA16840917n4-9">
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n4-9" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n4-9" type="surname" value="BOURNE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n4-9" type="given" value="JANE"/>Jane Bourne</persName>, <persName id="OA16840917n4-10">
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n4-10" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n4-10" type="surname" value="SMITH"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n4-10" type="given" value="ANN"/>Ann Smith</persName>, <persName id="OA16840917n4-11">
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n4-11" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n4-11" type="surname" value="RICHARDSON"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n4-11" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Richardson</persName> and <persName id="OA16840917n4-12">
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n4-12" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n4-12" type="surname" value="TUE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n4-12" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Tue</persName>. Of which the Ten first, had on Thursday the 11th. of this Instant, notice of their Reprieve: and the two latter of the Warrant for their Execution, on Wednesday the 17th. of September.</p>
            <p>The Ordinary thinks fit to Publish, with the content of the Condemned Prisoners, and for the Warning of all others, what the said Persons of their own accord communicated to him of their former manner and course of Life, and how they now stand affected under the sentence of Death, and Prospect of that Eternity, into which they are Launching: when in all Moral credibility they speak the truth, and have another view of a future Estate than what in the careires of Sin and Vanity, and the Excesses of Youth and a Debauched Life they were wont to have; and also in reference to the Grounds they have to hope for a future, happy Estate.</p>
            <p>As to  the Ten former, of which (they being Reprieved;) he hath thought fit to</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA168409170002"/>
            <p>give the World a Satisfaction of their Contrition, before such time they had notice thereof, in their own Words as followeth: As also subjoyned a full Account of the continuance of the Behaviour of <persName id="OA16840917n7-1">
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n7-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n7-1" type="surname" value="RICHARDSON"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n7-1" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Richardson</persName>, and <persName id="OA16840917n7-2">
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n7-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n7-2" type="surname" value="TUE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n7-2" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Tue</persName>; who sufferred the due Demerits of their Crimes at <placeName id="OA16840917-geo-1">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA16840917n7-1 n7-2 OA16840917-geo-1"/>Tybourn</placeName>, on Wednesday the 17th. this Instant September.</p>
            <p>I. <persName id="OA16840917n8-1">
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n8-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n8-1" type="surname" value="CASKEY"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n8-1" type="given" value="GEORGE"/>George Caskey</persName>, a Scotch-man; <persName id="OA16840917n8-2">
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n8-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n8-2" type="surname" value="PEVANSON"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n8-2" type="given" value="FRANCIS"/>Francis Pevanson</persName>, an Italian: and <persName id="OA16840917n8-3">
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n8-3" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n8-3" type="surname" value="BALLANTINE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n8-3" type="given" value="DANIEL"/>Daniel Ballantine</persName>, a French-man; who were all three found Guilty, and accordingly Sentenced for the Murder of one <persName id="OA16840917n8-4">
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n8-4" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n8-4" type="surname" value="TEAGLE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n8-4" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Teagle</persName>, a <rs id="OA16840917-occupation-2" type="occupation">Watchman</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA16840917n8-4 OA16840917-occupation-2"/>, at <placeName id="OA16840917-geo-2">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA16840917n8-1 n8-2 n8-3 n8-4 OA16840917-geo-2"/>Rosemary-Lane</placeName>; Behaved themselves with great Remorse and Contrition for their past Crimes, and particulary the Italian, who was Born of <rs id="OA16840917-occupation-3" type="occupation">Popish</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA16840917n8-2 OA16840917-occupation-3"/> Parent; in whose Religion, it being the same wherein he was Education ated, he said he should do well to Dye. The Ordinary replied, that it was no Rational Ground of Choosing or Adhering to any Religion, to make our Parents Profession or Opinion, the Standard thereof: because the Just shall live by his own Faith, grounded on the Scriptures: that the sentiments of Progentitors as such, ought not to Model and Confine our Belief, in matters of Salvation; for that is a Humane, rather than a Divine Faith, which the Opinion of others influences upon us: and not the Authority of God, Revealed in the Scriptures of Truth. That the Prisoners Resolution to Dye in his Parents Belief, because it was theirs, and Instilled into him in his Minority, was no Rational Ground for him to be Circumscribed for adhering thereunto; for he was Conceived and Born in Sin: yet this is no Argument why he should Live and Dye in a Sinful State. Besides which, the Ordinary had a long Conference with him, inquiring of his former Life, and present preparations for his last End. As to the first, he acquainted him, that he had for 14 Years been a <rs id="OA16840917-occupation-4" type="occupation">Souldier</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA16840917n8-2 OA16840917-occupation-4"/> to the French King, in the Lord Dunbartons Regiment; that he did not willfully Kill the Watch-man, nor joyn in it; but was afraid of Loosing his own Life. That he had many ways Provoked God, for which he Desired heartily to Repent; and thereupon gave the Ordinary a very distinct and true account of the nature of Repentance: affirming that a true and lively Faith in Jesus Christ, was his encouragement to Repent: and he expected Gods Pardon, because his Heart was freely enclined to forgive all his Enemies. he said he hoped Christ Died for him. The Ordinary desiring from him a reason of that Hope, because he said he was not fondly in Love with his Natural Life, nor in any slavish fear of Death; that seeing it the Lords Pleasure he must Dye for this Fact, he doth not Repine thereat. (At which Words he Wept Bitterly:) And being asked why he Wept if he did not Repine the Sentence must take place: he replied, I weep not that I must Dye, but for all my Sins whereby I have Offended God, and count it better for me to Dye, than Live to Multiplie my Sins.</p>
            <p>II. <persName id="OA16840917n9-1">
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n9-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n9-1" type="surname" value="PIERCE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n9-1" type="given" value="WILLIAM"/>William Pierce</persName>, who was found Guilty of Stealing a Horse, was Born in <placeName id="OA16840917-geo-3">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA16840917n9-1 OA16840917-geo-3"/>London</placeName>, and was by Calling a <rs id="OA16840917-occupation-5" type="occupation">Chirurgeon</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA16840917n9-1 OA16840917-occupation-5"/>, and had served in his Majesties Ships. He denied the Fact, but said that he Hired the Horse, for which he now Suffers, and knew not that the same was Stolen. The Ordinary replyed, it appeared otherwise upon his Trial; .and that it was not his work to receive any Extenuation of Mens Crimes, but to inquire into as the Truth of their Repentance; and labour as much as in him lay, to fit and prepare them for another World: they having forfeited all Claim and Benefit to this: whereupon he said he Blessed God, for the Merrits of Jesus Christ, through which he hoped he should be Saved, tho he had been a Sinner many ways; that in particular, he had been a Companion of ill Women; that he used to Drink to Excess: Prophance the Lords Name, in Oaths and Execration: neglect the Sabbath Day, and the observation of those Duties which he ought to have Guarded him from many Temptations, in which he had been Ensnared; that not withstanding he hoped God would Pardon him, because of the Riches of his Grace, and free Mercy in Jesus Christ, his Redeemer and Intercessor at the Right Hand of God the Father.</p>
            <p>That he had every Hour almost since his Condemnation, Recollected himself, in the search of his Heart and ways, how evil they have been; that he might now seriously and unfeignedly Repent and return to God his Creator and Preserver.</p>
            <p>III. <persName id="OA16840917n11-1">
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n11-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n11-1" type="surname" value="VICKARS"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n11-1" type="given" value="THOMAS"/>Thomas Vickars</persName>, who was found Guilty in 2 Indictments for Stealing of several yards of Cloath from the Tenters in <placeName id="OA16840917-geo-4">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA16840917n11-1 OA16840917-geo-4"/>Goodmans Feilds</placeName>, and other goods in the Fields by <placeName id="OA16840917-geo-5">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA16840917n11-1 OA16840917-geo-5"/>Anna St. Clare</placeName>. He was Born in <placeName id="OA16840917-geo-6">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA16840917n11-1 OA16840917-geo-6"/>Bishopgsate-Street</placeName>, and is now about the Age of 28 Years, and a <rs id="OA16840917-occupation-6" type="occupation">Silk-stocking-Maker</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA16840917n11-1 OA16840917-occupation-6"/>, by Trade. He faith that meeting with several disappointments in the World, his Servants running away from, him and losses ensuing, he became unable to provide for his Family or carry on his Employment, so that being under great distress and necessity he was thereby Tempted to do the Crime, for which he now suffers: It being the First of this nature that ever he was guilty of, the as to other Sins he could not excuse himself, and that Gods Judgments were just upon him for the same: And particularly he confessed with much remorse that he did not repaire to the publick Service and Worship of God as he ought to have done, making light</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA168409170003"/>
            <p>of the Sabbath Day and neglecting his duty thereupon; seldome comeing above once a Month to Church; that he had lost the sence of all goodness and was given over to a hard Heart and a seared Conscience; till such time as he had been 5 weeks a Prisoner in <placeName id="OA16840917-geo-7">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA16840917n11-1 OA16840917-geo-7"/>Newgate</placeName>: tho he could not but confess, that the Spirit of God had often warned him of his condition, and by secret and Heartsearching convictons put him in mind of his Sin and Iniquity. He confessed his Crime; and said that he took the goods over Night for which he is to suffer: and that he layd them in a Ditch, and next morning Comeing over the Feilds to take them away; a Stranger Surprised him and upon Suspition caused him to be Apprehended: But heartily lamented that he denyed the Fact at his Tryal, being Conscious that he therein told a gross untruth: which he desires now to Acknowledge unto Man: and beggs forgiveness therefore of God Allmighty, to whom he Prayes: that his said fact may become a warning to all others to beware of those Crimes which deservedly brought the same upon him. And withall advises all Men that tho they sinck in the success of their affairs, yet that they would waite on Divine Providence for a Maintenance: and not put forth their hands to Worke any Iniquity to break his Laws and Wound the Peace of their own Consciences. He said that he prayed as God enabled him and that he had rather Dye then live to Sin.</p>
            <p>IV. <persName id="OA16840917n13-3">
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n13-3" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n13-3" type="surname" value="Broomfield"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n13-3" type="given" value="Christian"/>Christian Broomfield</persName>, alias <persName id="OA16840917n13-4">
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n13-4" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n13-4" type="surname" value="Jorden"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n13-4" type="given" value="Christian"/>Jorden</persName>, was Born at <placeName id="OA16840917-geo-8">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA16840917n13-3 n13-4 OA16840917-geo-8"/>Durham</placeName>, and is of the Age of 26 Years, she said that one <persName id="OA16840917n13-1">
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n13-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n13-1" type="surname" value="WILLIAMS"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n13-1" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Williams</persName>, promised to Marry her, and thereupon enticed her from her Uncle, to go with him to <placeName id="OA16840917-geo-9">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA16840917n13-1 n13-3 n13-4 OA16840917-geo-9"/>London</placeName>; and that when she had spent all her Money, she was forced to go to the Service of Mr. <persName id="OA16840917n13-5">
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n13-5" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n13-5" type="surname" value="Broomffeld"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n13-5" type="given" value="George"/>George Broomffeld</persName>, in <placeName id="OA16840917-geo-10">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA16840917n13-3 n13-4 n13-5 OA16840917-geo-10"/>Mugwell-street</placeName>, where <persName id="OA16840917n13-2">
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n13-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n13-2" type="surname" value="WILLIAMS"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n13-2" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Williams</persName> perswaded her to Rob her Master; and that he came to her that very Day, to accompany her to <placeName id="OA16840917-geo-11">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA16840917n13-1 n13-3 n13-4 OA16840917-geo-11"/>New-Castle</placeName> with the Goods she Stole. She acknowledged her self to be truly Sorrowful for the Fact and said she never followed such bad Practices before: the prayed God, that those Truths and Counsels which the Ordinary gave her, might be grounded in her Heart; she but seldom frequented the Assemblies of Gods Worship, and when she went to Church, little minded the Word Preached: for which she now desired to be truly Penitent.</p>
            <p>V. <persName id="OA16840917n14-1">
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n14-1" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n14-1" type="surname" value="RATCLIFF"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n14-1" type="given" value="ELIZABETH"/>Elizabeth Ratcliff</persName>, was Born in <placeName id="OA16840917-geo-12">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA16840917n14-1 OA16840917-geo-12"/>Staffordshire</placeName>, near <placeName id="OA16840917-geo-13">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA16840917n14-1 OA16840917-geo-13"/>Farly</placeName>; she is now 30 Years of Age, she lived in several Places in <placeName id="OA16840917-geo-14">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA16840917n14-1 OA16840917-geo-14"/>London</placeName> as a <rs id="OA16840917-occupation-7" type="occupation">Servant</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA16840917n14-1 OA16840917-occupation-7"/>: the Ordinary asked her why she shifted from one Place to another, it might raise a suspition she was not Honest: she replied, she never did any Wrong till the came to, dwell with Mr. Scot, of <placeName id="OA16840917-geo-15">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA16840917n14-1 OA16840917-geo-15"/>Kent</placeName>, where she Robbed him. She had before been guilty of Prophaning the Sabbath Day; and believes for that very Sin, God left her to be Tempted by the Devil to Rob her Master. She was very Ignorant in matters of Religion, and therefore expressed less than others.</p>
            <p>VI. <persName id="OA16840917n15-1">
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n15-1" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n15-1" type="surname" value="VOSSE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n15-1" type="given" value="MARY"/>Mary Vosse</persName>, was Born in <placeName id="OA16840917-geo-16">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA16840917n15-1 OA16840917-geo-16"/>Hereford-shire</placeName>, Aged 27 Years: she hath lived in <placeName id="OA16840917-geo-17">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA16840917n15-1 OA16840917-geo-17"/>London</placeName> two Years; first with Mr. Gumbleton, in <placeName id="OA16840917-geo-18">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA16840917n15-1 OA16840917-geo-18"/>Augustin-Fryers</placeName>, and afterwards with Mr. Turner, a Victualler, in <placeName id="OA16840917-geo-19">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA16840917n15-1 OA16840917-geo-19"/>Thames-street</placeName>. She complained she had been guilty of Prophaning the Lords Day, and little regarded the Duties thereof; that she seldom Prayed to God, and confessed her self guilty of the Fact for which she Received Sentence; that before she came to London, she was left to her self to commit a very foolish Act, and therefore warns all of her Sex not to believe fair Promises.</p>
            <p>VII. <persName id="OA16840917n16-1">
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n16-1" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n16-1" type="surname" value="BOURN"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n16-1" type="given" value="JANE"/>Jane Bourn</persName>, was Born in <placeName id="OA16840917-geo-20">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA16840917n16-1 OA16840917-geo-20"/>Lancashire</placeName>: her Father is. a Farmer there: the lived at last, at the <placeName id="OA16840917-geo-21">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA16840917n16-1 OA16840917-geo-21"/>White-Horse-Tavern</placeName> in the <placeName id="OA16840917-geo-22">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA16840917n16-1 OA16840917-geo-22"/>Strand</placeName>, over against <placeName id="OA16840917-geo-23">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA16840917n16-1 OA16840917-geo-23"/>St. Clements Church</placeName>, where she Rob'd her Mistriss of a considerable Value. She said that she was very negligent of her Duty to God, and thereupon left to commit this Crime.</p>
            <p>VIII <persName id="OA16840917n17-1">
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n17-1" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n17-1" type="surname" value="SMITH"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n17-1" type="given" value="ANN"/>Ann Smith</persName>, was Born likewise in <placeName id="OA16840917-geo-24">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA16840917n17-1 OA16840917-geo-24"/>Lancashire</placeName>, and aged about 26 Years: she Married one <persName id="OA16840917n17-2">
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n17-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n17-2" type="surname" value="BAGNALL"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n17-2" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Bagnall</persName> a <rs id="OA16840917-occupation-8" type="occupation">Taylor</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA16840917n17-2 OA16840917-occupation-8"/>, that she had for many Years been Acquainted with. <persName id="OA16840917n17-3">
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n17-3" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n17-3" type="surname" value="BOURN"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n17-3" type="given" value="JANE"/>Jane Bourn</persName>, her Country-Woman, she said <persName id="OA16840917n17-4">
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n17-4" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n17-4" type="surname" value="BOURN"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n17-4" type="given" value="JANE"/>Jane Bourn</persName>, Stole the Goods of Mrs. Clutton but delivered the same to this <persName id="OA16840917n17-5">
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n17-5" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n17-5" type="surname" value="SMITH"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n17-5" type="given" value="ANN"/>Ann Smith</persName> to Sell: she says that the knew not that <persName id="OA16840917n17-6">
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n17-6" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n17-6" type="surname" value="BOURN"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n17-6" type="given" value="JANE"/>Jane Bourn</persName> had Stolen them, till afterwards. She confessed she had been a great Sinner, and had on the Sabbath Day joyned with merry Company, of which she now Repents: she said that her Heart was not so Relenting as she desired; that she could not Pray as she would, but hoped that God would make her more sensible of her Offences against him.</p>
            <p>IX. <persName id="OA16840917n18-1">
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n18-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n18-1" type="surname" value="RICHARDSON"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n18-1" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Richardson</persName>, who was by Trade a <rs id="OA16840917-occupation-9" type="occupation">Tinker</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA16840917n18-1 OA16840917-occupation-9"/>, and may well deserve the name of a Bloudy and ill man, was Indicted for Murthering his Wife on the 22th. day of July last. The Evidence against him was very clear that he threw her Violently down on the ground, kicked and beat her on the Head Neck, Shoulders and Belly: of which Blows and bruises the Languishing from the said 22d. of July, and Languishing dyed the 6th. of August following, and that the Woman to the hour of her Death laid the same at his door. After Sentence the Ordinary took a large time to awaken and convince him of that heinous and unnatural Crime; and enquiring into what might move him to do it, He said that he had left off his Trade for some time, and followed the Employment of a <rs id="OA16840917-occupation-10" type="occupation">Hunts-Man</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA16840917n18-1 OA16840917-occupation-10"/>, in the Service of a Person</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA168409170004"/>
            <p>of Quality: but leaving the said Service, he went out to <rs id="OA16840917-occupation-11" type="occupation">day Labour</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA16840917n18-1 OA16840917-occupation-11"/>; that when he came home at Night his Wife was Absent, who should have taken care for his Refreshment: He went to find her out, and she was so Drunk that she could not stand; that she bid him let her stand as well as she could, which he permitting, she Violently fell and Bruised her self; that after this he had her Home, and took her in his Arms, and carried her to her Bed, wherein for a quarter of an Hour she Slept well. The Ordinary replied, that at his Trial it appeared sufficiently that he was guilty of her Death, and therefore he did not give Credit to this Story, but advised him to a Trueand sincere Repentance; telling him withall, that it was supposed his former Wife came to a like End, by his Cruelty and Wickedness: All which he utterly denied, and seemed to justify himself; that he used constantly to repair to his Parish Church, Morning and After noon, and used to Read good Books, and Pray by himself, but indeed of late had grown Careless, but hoped that God would Pardon him of all his Sins, and that his Heart was near Broken for his Miscarriages. If he gave Violence to his Conscience in not speaking Truth, I must leave him to God.</p>
            <p>X. <persName id="OA16840917n20-1">
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n20-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n20-1" type="surname" value="TUE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n20-1" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Tue</persName>, of the Parish of <placeName id="OA16840917-geo-25">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA16840917n20-1 OA16840917-geo-25"/>St. Martins in the Fields</placeName> 
               <rs id="OA16840917-occupation-12" type="occupation">Victualler</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA16840917n20-1 OA16840917-occupation-12"/>, who was Indicted, and found Guilty of the Murder of <persName id="OA16840917n20-2">
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n20-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n20-2" type="surname" value="GRAVES"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n20-2" type="given" value="WILLIAM"/>William Graves</persName>, a <rs id="OA16840917-occupation-13" type="occupation">Bayliffs-Follower</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA16840917n20-2 OA16840917-occupation-13"/>, who came with others to Arrest him, as in his Trial may be seen at Large. After his Sentence, he shewed very great signs of a true and unfeigned Remorse for the Crime of Bloodshed, and all other Sins he stood Guilty of. He was Born at <placeName id="OA16840917-geo-26">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA16840917n20-1 OA16840917-geo-26"/>Napton,-Hill</placeName> in <placeName id="OA16840917-geo-27">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA16840917n20-1 OA16840917-geo-27"/>Warwick sheir</placeName>, that he now dwell&#8217;d in <placeName id="OA16840917-geo-28">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA16840917n20-1 OA16840917-geo-28"/>Newport Street</placeName>, at the upper end of <placeName id="OA16840917-geo-29">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA16840917n20-1 OA16840917-geo-29"/>St. Martins-Lane</placeName>; and had been Married about a Year and a Quarter since; living very Comfortably, till such time as this unfortunate occasion removed him to the place he then was; which he looked upon as Gods just judgment against him for his former Impieties in that he had been Disobedient to his Parents; and no sooner out worn his Minority; but neglected his Duty to God, never Praying unto him for the Continuance of his Blessings, or returned Praise and Thanks givings, for those he had received from him; but gave himself up to the Excesses of a Debauch'd and Disordered Life, in Gaming, Drinking, and other Lewdness which is generally the product of the former: as Swearing, Whoring, and the like. Upon which Accounts, he acknowledged that it was his Belief, that God had most justly left him to the Violence of his Passion; and the rather, in that he had never repented him of his Sins as he now stands Convinced, the ought and should have done. Upon the whole, he gave the Ordinary a very probable account of his Remorse; and several times wish'd that God would more and more soften his Heart. Which may be hoped, was in some measure effected; as appears by his last Farewell to his Wife.</p>
            <p>My Dear Wife,</p>
            <p>IT is now but a few Hours, and I must shake-Hands with thee for Ever; a short time will make thee a Widdow, and thy little Infant Fatherless: Such is the good Pleasure of Almighty Providence: which as I ought not to Repine at (the same, being but the just Demerit of my part Offences:) So neither would I have thee lay the same too near thy Heart, but trust in God the Father of Mercies, who is able to do for thee above what thou art able to ask or think. It is God that can supply the Want of all Relations, he'le be a Husband to Provide for, and sustain thee: He&#8217;le be a Father to that little Pledge I have left at thy Breast: And in stead of one who too often neglected his Duty and Matrimonial Vows, (which I now heartily acknowledge, and beg Pardon for.) He&#8217;le be ever by to Comfort and relieve thee. Oh my dearest! Rest, assured, that till thou leavest him he&#8217;le never forsake thee: He is a good God, I have found him so in my utmost Extremities, when the sight of Death hath Terrified my Soul, the Beams of his Countenance have shon in upon, and supported me. I am now going to his Tribunal, to Answer for my past Miscarriages: and had I not Faith in Jesus Christ my dear Redeemer, all the World could never support me: for who is it that can stand against the Wrath of the Almighty? Who is it that can outbravethe fear of Death, but in hopes of his Favour? or pass quietly through the Valley of Dissolution, without a Prospect of the Hills of Salvation. Like a Foolish Pilate I have Shipwrackt the Vessel of this Life, and am now Sinking into the Ocean of Eternity. Pray with me therefore to my God, to bear me up through the Billows of Death, Shame, and the Graze, till he brings me to that Haven of Happiness where I shall behold him Face to Face, where I shall see my Blessed Saviour Christ Jesus: And where tho I never behold thy Face more on Earth, I trust to meet thee, who am</p>
            <p>Thy Disconsolate, tho not Despairing Husband John Tue</p>
            <p>This being upon the whole, what the said several Prisoners consess'd to Mr.Ordinary. All that I have to perfect this sheet, is to acquaint the Reader that <persName id="OA16840917n24-1">
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n24-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n24-1" type="surname" value="RICHARDSON"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n24-1" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Richardson</persName>, and <persName id="OA16840917n24-2">
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n24-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n24-2" type="surname" value="TUE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n24-2" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Tue</persName>, being this present 17th. Day of September, at the usual Hours put into the Cart at <placeName id="OA16840917-geo-30">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA16840917n24-1 n24-2 OA16840917-geo-30"/>Newgate</placeName>, were carried to <placeName id="OA16840917-geo-31">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA16840917n24-1 n24-2 OA16840917-geo-31"/>Tyburn</placeName>; Where between a 11 and 12 of the Clock, the Ordinary having Prayed and Sung a Psalm, with them after some few words spoken by the said <persName id="OA16840917n24-3">
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n24-3" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n24-3" type="surname" value="TUE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n24-3" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Tue</persName>, in advice to the Spectators and in pursuance of his Confession aforesaid, They both suffer'd Death according to the Law, expressing great signs of Remorse and Penitence for their past Crimes.</p>
            <p>Dated the 17th.day of September, 1684. <persName id="OA16840917n25-1">
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n25-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n25-1" type="surname" value="SMITH"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n25-1" type="given" value="SAMUEL"/>Samuel Smith</persName>, <rs id="OA16840917-occupation-14" type="occupation">Ordinary</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA16840917n25-1 OA16840917-occupation-14"/>.</p>
            <p>
               <placeName id="OA16840917-geo-32">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA16840917n26-1 OA16840917-geo-32"/>LONDON</placeName>,Printed by <persName id="OA16840917n26-1">
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n26-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n26-1" type="surname" value="CROOM"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16840917n26-1" type="given" value="GEORGE"/>George Croom</persName>, over-against <placeName id="OA16840917-geo-33">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA16840917n26-1 OA16840917-geo-33"/>Baynard's Castle</placeName> in <placeName id="OA16840917-geo-34">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA16840917n26-1 OA16840917-geo-34"/>Thames-Street</placeName>.1684.</p>
         </div0>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>