<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<TEI.2>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div0 type="ordinarysAccount" id="OA16950712">
            <interp inst="OA16950712" type="uri" value="ordinarysAccounts/OA16950712"/>
            <interp inst="OA16950712" type="date" value="16950712"/>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA169507120001"/>
            <p>A True Account of the Behaviour, Confession, and Last Dying SPEECHES, of the Criminals that were Executed at Tyburn, on Friday the 12th of July, 1695.</p>
            <p>THe Ordinary on the Lord's Day preacht to the Condemned Criminals from the 21st. and 22d. Verses of the 11th Chapter of St. Luke's Gospel, on these words, When the strong man armed keeps or defends his Palace, the things which he possesses are in Peace. But when a stronger than he comes upon him, and overcomes him, he takes from him all his Armour in which he trusted, and devides the Spoils.</p>
            <p>I shall Treat on these words, under several General Heads; First, How Sinners contribute, in strengthning Satan's Tyranny over them.</p>
            <p>1. He makes them Confident that Abstinence from some particular Sin disgusted, as procuring the smart of Punishment, or the blasting of their Credit, is the real Mortification of that Lust at the very Root of it.</p>
            <p>2. He forms in them an impatient Rage at the proper means of dispossessing him; because these cross the Pride of their Carnal Wisdom, cut short their fleshly Liberty, superstitious Zeal, and addictedness to Formality in Religion.</p>
            <p>3. He strengthens in them groundless Prejudices against the way of Holiness and Self-denial. It is a Pardon which the Hypocrite aims at, not a clean Heart, nor a strict Life.</p>
            <p>4. They gratify Satan, and strengthen their Bondage, as concerning the Pride of their Hearts, in seeking Justification by a Self-righteousness. To cure this refin'd Mystery of Iniquity, the Sovereignty of God's free Grace, and the All-sufficiency of Christ's Righteousness, must be submitted unto, and rely'd upon, by the sincere Resignation of the Heart to the Discretion of Christ, to deal with the Self-abased Sinner, on Christ's own terms of Salvation.</p>
            <p>5. Sinners draw up Pleadings for the Extenuation of their Lusts. They plead for delay in the Execution of them, yet this Repreive tends to a greater familiarity with Sin, and a seared Obduration of their Conscience.</p>
            <p>6. Sinners plead that it is Folly and Pride, not to accommodate themselves to the Corrupt Customs of other Men, when Sin grows Epidemical and in Fashion. Thus, they have neither Will, Strength, nor Courage to cast off Satan's Yoke. He binds this upon them, as his contented Slaves, so that he fears not any mutiny to free themselves from his Tyranny. This is the Language of Satan's Sophistry, Will ye give a stab to all Mirth, by entertaining any Effeminate purpose of Repentance? Will ye break away from the Worlds soft Embraces, and prove Changlings in the profest Mysteries of Iniquity, to take up the Severities of a mortified Conversation? If there be any day of Account for all your Excesses in sinning; yet, you have time enough before you, wherein to be pensive, thereby to expiate the Guilt and Defilement of all your Sins. Satan will permit himself to be defied by Sinners, protesting against his gross works of Darkness, so he may be Deified as the Head of the Carnal State, to rule more unsuspected in the Heart. He will not oppose a Reverent Opinion of Christ, so that it never ripen into a resolute closing with him, upon the terms of Self-denial and universal Obedience to the Scepter of his Righteousness. He will for a time relax the severity of his imposed Tasks, but they must give some pledge not to quit his Service totally.</p>
            <p>How deplorable is the misery of Sinners, who go securely to Hell, under the delusions of a false Peace? This is a pleasing Phrensy, and hardly to be cured. When Sinners make a sport of the Devil's Druggery, it is the surest pledge of their Eternal Ruin. Then only is Satan dispossest, when the Pride of Carnal Wisdom, the stubbornness of the depraved Will, and the Exorbitancy of wild Affections in sinning are mortified by the Power of Chist's Death, and the lovely Beauty of a Crucified Jesus.</p>
            <p>How doth Christ bind Satan and unbind the Sinner, he takes off all Prejudices against Himself and the ways of Righteousness. He Convinces the Sinner of the Equity and Excellency of his Government. The Eternal Word of the Father, being made Flesh, overcame the Devil by a word in the Flesh. No sooner, said Christ, to the unclean Spirit, Come forth, but he presently resign'd up his Possession. Satan was more surely and shamefully conquer'd, while he less suspected, but despised the Omnipotency of his Antagonist, vail'd under the Infirmity of Humane Nature. Christ came upon Satan to bind and overcome Him, when he presum'd that he had obtain'd an Empire over the greatest part of Mankind, who were his Tame Slaves, yet Projectors of prodigious Wickedness. By the sufferings of Christ's Flesh on the Cross, He adjudg'd Satan to be smitten to death, when the Malice of this inveterate Serpent, most shot out it self at length. It is therefore great Ingratitude, Rebellion and Self-cruelty, not to surrender the Heart at Christ's summons.</p>
            <p>Here were described the Properties of such out of whose Hearts Satan is ejected, and in whom Christ reigns by the Spirit of Santification. They will justify Christ's ways of Righteousness, and promote the Exercise of those Virtues which adorn the Profession of Christianity. They will not be discontented, that their design in any unlawful way is blasted, by falling under the restraint of the severest Affliction. They cancil and make void their Indentures of Service to Satan and set their Seal of Approbation, to fulfil the Laws of Holiness. The sincerity of your Repentance and hatred of Sin, is declared by seeking the utter Extirpation of every Lust, tho' the power and love of it be subdued. They so destroy the works of the Devil, that they grow up to a considerable strength of Consistency and Activity in a Course of Holiness.</p>
            <p>The Conclusion was thus directed to the Condemned.</p>
            <p>How unable are you, from a confirm'd Custom in sinning, to break out of the snare of Impenitency, and a stupid Lethargy in Conscience? It is impossible, by a slight crazy Repentance, to abandon all the deliberate Artifices and presumptuous Accomplishments of Sinning. Do not stout it out any longer against all the offers of Peace by Christ, least He storm you into utter Ruin by his severest Indignation. Throw down rather the Weapons of your Unrighteousness, your Pride and Carnal Confidence, that tho' you stand out against Christ's Summons till death, yet you may make easie Terms to obtain your Pardon and Reconciliation with God. Such trifling with the offers of Peace and Salvation by Christ, may gradually so harden your Hearts, that you may resolve to dye fighting against God, as under the despair of Mercy; prosecute your Warfare against Sin and Satan with a deadly Enmity, not to be appeased. Continue in a right posture of Soul, to conquer Satan. Set God before you, as your Invincible Guardian. Keep the World under your feet in a resolute Contempt of it. Let Grace be active within you, and the prospect of Glory be alway in your Eye; Then you shall break thorough all Temptations to Sinning, with an undaunted Faith. Be thankful for the least degree of conquest and persue it, as a pledge of future Triumph, in a total abolishing the Works of Sin and Satan. For your Encouragement herein, Christ will force Satan to leave behind him the Remarks of shameful Triumph over him. He shall not recover his Usurpation, but with the utmost Consternation shall despair of Re-possessing the Hearts of Christ's Converted Loyal Subjects.</p>
            <p>They shall grow Impregnable by the Power of Christ, who will strengthen their Graces by constant Conflicts with the Prince of Darkness, and the remainers of a depraved Nature, till they lodge the Ensigns of their compleat Victory, in the Celestial Sanctuary of the God of Glory.</p>
            <p>I proceed to give an Account of the Behavior, and Confessions of the Condemned Criminals.</p>
            <p>1. <persName id="OA16950712n18-1">
                  <interp inst="OA16950712n18-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16950712n18-1" type="surname" value="MOORE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16950712n18-1" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Moore</persName>, condemned for High Treason, in forging and stamping one Piece of false Gold, in the likeness of a Guinea, and one other piece of Counterfeit Silver, in the likeness of a Shilling. He is 45 years of Age; he said that he was born of Honest Parents: That his Father at the time of his Death left 500 l. to bring him up; But the whole Sum was lost by placing it in the hands of such who fail'd and run-out their own Estate. Then he was forc'd to serve a Farrier eight Years, whose Wife dealt in a Tripe-Trade, which he more regarded to get an insight into than in the Employment which his Master follow'd. After eight Years <rs id="OA16950712-occupation-1" type="occupation">Service</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA16950712n18-1 OA16950712-occupation-1"/> he assisted his Mistress in the <rs id="OA16950712-occupation-2" type="occupation">Tripe-Trade</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA16950712n18-1 OA16950712-occupation-2"/>, but some Person undermining him in the Employment, expos'd him to shift for himself, in some other way. He said that he was put to streights for a Livelihood, being Married, so that to support himself and his Wife, he <rs id="OA16950712-occupation-3" type="occupation">cry'd Faggots</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA16950712n18-1 OA16950712-occupation-3"/> Five for Six-pence, by which he got Twelve Shillings every Week. By his Industry, with his Wife's help, he laid up Mony; for he lived frugally, having been accustomed so to do from his Youth; for he never spent Two-pence till Eighteen years of Age, in any Ale-house. After some Mony gotten by his Industry, he purchased an Horse and Cart, and sold Faggots very plentifully; Then he purchased an House, in which he dwelt, part of which, he rented out to one whose name was Chapman, who, he said, accused him of the Crime of Clipping and Coining. Being about making an appeal to</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA169507120002"/>
            <p>God of his Innocency, I stopt him, telling him the danger he would bring upon his Soul, as to Future Happiness, if he appeal'd to God concerning his Innocency, and yet knew the contrary in his Conscience; yet he persisted, tho' I told him, that the Crime was fully prov'd against him; he averr'd notwithstanding that he did not at any time Clip nor Coin Mony in his own Person, but conceal'd others that were guilty; and now repents that he did not discover them, yet, said he, God is Just in my Condemnation, for I have led an Evil Life. I was not Constant nor Faithful to my first Wife, but affected other Women. I sometimes in Trading did drink in excess, and was not so Circumspect in my Conversation as I ought to have been. He said, that he did not serve God, but minded worldly Matters, more than how to take care of his Soul for a better Life. He added, that this doth wound his Conscience, that when he was sick unto death, (as himself and others thought) he made several Vows to God, that if he would spare his Life he would walk more strictly; but he soon forgot his good Resolutions, and became vain in his Conversation, not minding the Dutys of God's Worship, upon the recovery of his Health. He was submissive to good Advice, and seem'd Penitent.</p>
            <p>II. <persName id="OA16950712n20-1">
                  <interp inst="OA16950712n20-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16950712n20-1" type="surname" value="ALLEN"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16950712n20-1" type="given" value="EDMUND"/>Edmund Allen</persName>, condemned for Poysoning his Wife; He said that he had married two Women formerly at the same time, for which he was burnt in the Hand, about fifteen Years since. That he had liv'd with this Wife lately deceased, about fifteen Years; but had not three thousand Pounds Estate with her, only some Land, not amounting to that value. He said, that they did not disagree in their Conversation, till some Persons rais'd discord betwixt them. He was the Son of a considerable Person, well-known in London, deceased; had good Education from him, but he did not follow his Father's religious Counsel. He said, that he had sinned many ways against Knowledge, and the frequent checks of his Conscience, which makes the burden of his Sins the heavier; yet he hopes that God upon his sincere Repentance will be reconcil'd to him. He used many good Expressions, yet, I told him, that these did not demonstrate the truth of his Repentance, unless he confest the Crime, and that it was in vain to conceal it, for it was sufficiently prov'd against him. He stood out in denying it, with great Asseverations of his Innocency; I reply'd, that David was not pardon'd till he confest the Murther of Uriah, and the Defilement of Bathsheba to the Prophet Nathan; for in such crying Sins, where no Restitution could be made, the Criminal ought freely and fully to acknowledge it, to give God the Glory of his Justice, who brings to light secret Sins, committed out of Atheism, and conceal'd with the hazard of the Souls Salvation, to maintain a false Reputation among Men; He said, that he must stand or fall to God's Judgment, I told him of a Person who was Executed for the Murthering of his Wife, who at the place of Suffering, wish't he might be damned thrice successively, if he knew any thing how she came by her death: Yet when I went out of the Cart, telling him it would be too late to speak the Truth, when he should be turn'd off, he desir'd me to come back, and told me, That he shot his Wife in the Head with a Pistol-Bullet; I caus'd him to declare it to the People, which he did, weeping, and saying, Blessed be God for the Ordinary's Plain-dealing and Patience with me; for had I dy'd denying it, I had been damn'd; desiring me to pray that God would forgive his Presumption and Imprecation upon himself, who, to preserve his Credit, had like to have ruin'd his Soul. This did not affect Mr. Allen, who persisted in his Resolution, saying, Urge me no more; do not put me into a Fret tempt me not to tell a Lye, but leave me to my self, I will neither confess it, nor deny it. So that we must leave him to the Justice of the Omniscient, pitying him in his obstinate Humour and Impenitency.</p>
            <p>III. <persName id="OA16950712n21-1">
                  <interp inst="OA16950712n21-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16950712n21-1" type="surname" value="ANDERSON"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16950712n21-1" type="given" value="DAVID"/>David Anderson</persName> a Scotchman, condemned for the Barbarous Murther of one <persName id="OA16950712n21-2">
                  <interp inst="OA16950712n21-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16950712n21-2" type="surname" value="JEFFERSON"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16950712n21-2" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Jefferson</persName>, the manner of it is set down in the Book of Tryals. He is aged 26 Years, had been a <rs id="OA16950712-occupation-4" type="occupation">Soldier</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA16950712n21-1 OA16950712-occupation-4"/> 8 Years in <placeName id="OA16950712-geo-1">
                  <interp inst="OA16950712-geo-1" type="type" value="region"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA16950712n21-1 OA16950712-geo-1"/>Flanders</placeName>, but came over into <placeName id="OA16950712-geo-2">
                  <interp inst="OA16950712-geo-2" type="type" value="region"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA16950712n21-1 OA16950712-geo-2"/>England</placeName> with his Captain, who cashier'd him for his irregular Courses. That he led since a more idle and vicious Life, for he said, that he had temper'd too much with Lewd Women, had broke the Sabbath, been Drunk, and guilty of much Swearing.</p>
            <p>IV. <persName id="OA16950712n22-1">
                  <interp inst="OA16950712n22-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16950712n22-1" type="surname" value="NORMAN"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16950712n22-1" type="given" value="LEO"/>Leo Norman</persName>, condemn'd for High-Treason, in forging Counterfeit Half-Crowns and other pieces of mixt Metal; Aged 22 Years, born at <placeName id="OA16950712-geo-3">
                  <interp inst="OA16950712-geo-3" type="type" value="county"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA16950712n22-1 OA16950712-geo-3"/>
                  <placeName id="OA16950712-geo-4">
                     <interp inst="OA16950712-geo-4" type="type" value="urban_centre"/>
                     <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA16950712n22-1 OA16950712-geo-4"/>Evesham</placeName> in Worcester-shire</placeName>. He was <rs id="OA16950712-occupation-5" type="occupation">Prentice to a Goldsmith</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA16950712n22-1 OA16950712-occupation-5"/>, and after five Years run away from his Master, who refused to take him again. Afterward he fell to the Trade of Clipping, and follow'd it for two Years, counting it to be no sin: It troubled him he made a Vow of Secrecy to two Partners, and join'd with them in making a Mill to Coin false Mony. He wept, and I hope was Penitent.</p>
            <p>V. <persName id="OA16950712n23-1">
                  <interp inst="OA16950712n23-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16950712n23-1" type="surname" value="BILLET"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16950712n23-1" type="given" value="CHARLES"/>Charles Billet</persName>, condemned for Clipping the Current Coin of England, aged 29 Years. He was a Farrier, and did not deny the Crime. He said he had committed a great many Sins, and was guilty of frequent Lying; he cry'd out, Lord, how can I expect Mercy from thee, who have committed millions of Sins.</p>
            <p>There were several Women Condemned for Clipping, but are reprieved, as being reported to be Quick with Children; Hereupon they grow very secure and Impudent, the worst in the Prison, by abusing the Clemency of the Law, which intends the compleating of their Repentance and Amendment; yet they all refused to give any account of their evil Lives, only <persName id="OA16950712n24-1">
                  <interp inst="OA16950712n24-1" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16950712n24-1" type="surname" value="BOOKER"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16950712n24-1" type="given" value="MARY"/>Mary Booker</persName>, I hope, was Penitent.</p>
            <p>The Ordinary visited the Condemned Criminals every Day, and acknowledges the great Kindness of the Right Honourable and Reverend Father in God the Lord Bishop of London, in sending to his Assistance Mr. Waple the Minister of St. Sepulchres, who preacht in the Afternoon of the Lord's Day; Also Dr. Mandevel and Mr. Whytefield, Minister of Ludgate Parish, came by appointment, and exhorted and pray'd with the Condemned on the Week days.</p>
            <p>On Friday the 12th Instant, <persName id="OA16950712n26-1">
                  <interp inst="OA16950712n26-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16950712n26-1" type="surname" value="ANDERSON"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16950712n26-1" type="given" value="DAVID"/>David Anderson</persName>, <persName id="OA16950712n26-2">
                  <interp inst="OA16950712n26-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16950712n26-2" type="surname" value="BILLET"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16950712n26-2" type="given" value="CHARLES"/>Charles Billet</persName>, <persName id="OA16950712n26-3">
                  <interp inst="OA16950712n26-3" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16950712n26-3" type="surname" value="MOORE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16950712n26-3" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Moore</persName>, and <persName id="OA16950712n26-4">
                  <interp inst="OA16950712n26-4" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16950712n26-4" type="surname" value="NORMAN"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16950712n26-4" type="given" value="LEO"/>Leo Norman</persName>, were convey'd to <placeName id="OA16950712-geo-5">
                  <interp inst="OA16950712-geo-5" type="type" value="site"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA16950712n26-1 n26-2 n26-3 n26-4 OA16950712-geo-5"/>Tyburn</placeName>, the first in a Cart, and the other three on a Sledge, who all seem'd to be very Penitent, (the other two being Reprieved till the 19th of this Instant July) and being come to the Tree, were all tyed up: Anderson declar'd that he was sorry for the Fact he had committed, but hop'd that God would have Mercy upon his Soul. Mr. Moore spoke to this Effect, and said, That he had endeavour'd very honestly for to get his Livelihood, and that as he was a Dying Man he was not actually guilty of the Fact, for which he was Condemned, nor would not acknowledge how any of the Things came there, and that he did never in all his Life-time Clip or Coin himself; and that he dyed in Peace and forgave all Persons that had Witnessed against him. Billet said that he did justly deserve to Dye for his Offence. <persName id="OA16950712n26-5">
                  <interp inst="OA16950712n26-5" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16950712n26-5" type="surname" value="NORMAN"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16950712n26-5" type="given" value="LEO"/>Leo Norman</persName> spake to the People, and said, Good People pray for me, I am a wicked Sinner, and have wronged you all in Clipping of the Current Mony of this Kingdom, for which I now do Justly suffer: Then the Ordinary pray'd with them and Sung a Penitential Psalm; so they were all turn'd off.</p>
            <p>This is all the Account I can give of this Sessions. Dated July 12. <persName id="OA16950712n27-1">
                  <interp inst="OA16950712n27-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16950712n27-1" type="surname" value="Smith"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16950712n27-1" type="given" value="Sam"/>Sam. Smith</persName>, <rs id="OA16950712-occupation-6" type="occupation">Ordinary</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA16950712n27-1 OA16950712-occupation-6"/>.</p>
            <p>ADVERTISEMENT.</p>
            <p>THE Person that lately lived on Ludgate-hill next door to the Kings-Arms-Tavern near Fleetbridge, is now removed into Essex Court in White Fryers, the first door on the Left hand, where any one may be furnished with the Water for taking away Freckles, Pimples, Worms, and Morphew in the Face; and excellent Water and Oyntment for the Eyes, Ointments for the Rickets, Burns, Scalds, Wounds, Aches, Sprains, &amp;c. Powders, Dentrifices, Elixirs, Essences, Oyls, Spirits, &amp;c. for the easing and curing of most Distempers incident to Humane Bodies, prepared and Sold by B. L. The Water for taking away the Freckels, Pimples, &amp;c. is likewise sold at these places following, viz. at Mr. Milners in Popes-Head-Alley, and Mrs. Suttons at the Corner of Exchange-Alley over-against the Royal-Exchange in Cornhil, Cane-shops. Mrs. Hamptons, next door to the Golden-ball in the Old-Bayy. Mrs. Miners Semstress in the Inner Temple Lane. Mrs. Labrahams at the Sign of the Crown in Blew Ancher Alley, over against the Artellery-Ground, on Bunhil. And at Mr. Palmer's Tart-House on Clay-hill at Epsom. To prevent mistakes and counterfeits, my Bottles will be Sealed with my Coat of Arms, viz. the Three Water Bugets and Half-Moon.</p>
            <p>At the Blew Ball in Whale-Bone Court, at the lower end of Bartholomew Lane, by the Royal-Exchange, liveth a Physitian.</p>
            <p>WHo infallibly Cures the French Disease and Claps, and and all others its Numerous Attendant, which oftentimes are the products of other grievous and lasting Diseases, to the utter ruine of many, besides frequently untimely Death procured by them through grand Abuses, Committed by the irregular and base Methods and Medicines of foolish and unskilful Pretenders.</p>
            <p>These are therefore to Advertise all Persons who are Afflicted with the Disease abovesaid to repair to him, for he performeth the true and perfect Cure thereof, without hinderance of business, and with all imaginable speed and secresy.</p>
            <p>His Pills only prepared for the French Desease and the Running of the Reins, may be had in Boxes of several prices, with other Venerial Arcanoes, as occasion requires. Price, from 1s. 6d. to 3s. and from 3s. to 6s the Box with Directions.</p>
            <p>London, Printed for E. Mallet, at Sir Edmunbury Godfrey's Head, near Fleet-Bridge, 1695.</p>
         </div0>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>