<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<TEI.2>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div0 type="ordinarysAccount" id="OA16930517">
            <interp inst="OA16930517" type="uri" value="ordinarysAccounts/OA16930517"/>
            <interp inst="OA16930517" type="date" value="16930517"/>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA169305170001"/>
            <p>AN ACCOUNT OF THE Condemnation, Behaviour, Execution, and Last dying Words OF <rs id="OA16930517-occupation-1" type="occupation">Captain</rs> 
               <persName id="OA16930517n1-1">
                  <interp inst="OA16930517n1-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16930517n1-1" type="surname" value="Winter"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16930517n1-1" type="given" value="Francis"/>Francis Winter</persName>,</p>
            <p>Who was Condemned at the Sessions-House in the <placeName id="OA16930517-geo-1">Old-Baily</placeName>, on Saturday the 29April, For the Murther of one <persName id="OA16930517n2-1">
                  <interp inst="OA16930517n2-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16930517n2-1" type="surname" value="CHANDLER"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16930517n2-1" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Chandler</persName>, in <placeName id="OA16930517-geo-2">White Fryers</placeName> in London, Etc. and Executed for the same at <placeName id="OA16930517-geo-3">White-Fryars-Gate</placeName> in <placeName id="OA16930517-geo-4">Fleet street</placeName>, on Wednesday the 17 May1693.</p>
            <p>19May1693.</p>
            <p>SEveral Reports, of this Nature, have been oftentimes Manifested in Print; many, of which, have seemed to look somewhat obscure, till it hath been more particularly diffected, and laid open, in all its Agravating Circumstances. And indeed; till that be done, there area sort of Men in the World, who are apt to asperse the Superior Powers, as if they were too Severe in the Execution of Justice; but, when their Eyes are enlightned by the due Weight of Reason, then perhaps they will be of another mind, unless they are Prejudiced beyond the bounds of Natural Reason, and Common Sence, therefore, it will not be inconvenient to give the Reader a Brief Account (by the way) of the Matter of Fact, in Relation to this Unfortunate Gentleman, Etc.</p>
            <p>Some Persons (it is very likely) have not forgotten, that about the 4July last, was Twelve Month, there was a Mutinous, or Riotous Assembly Raised, and got together in <placeName id="OA16930517-geo-5">White Fryars</placeName>, in London, in opposition to the Gentlemen of the <placeName id="OA16930517-geo-6">Inner Temple</placeName>, who stopt up a Passage that led out of the said Fryars into the <placeName id="OA16930517-geo-7">Temple walks</placeName>, the Gentlemen finding the said Passage to be very incommodious to them, upon the hot Resistance of the White Fryars men, there was likely to be great Mischief done, to prevent, appease, and qualifie which, the then present Sheriffs of London, (being sent for) came with their Officers and Attendants, entered in at the <placeName id="OA16930517-geo-8">Fryars Gate</placeName>, endeavouring to make open Proclamation, that all Persons should Cease, and go Home in Peace to their Respective Abodes: But this was not Regarded by the Mutineers, for they were the more Incensed, and came with great Fury against the High Sheriffs, this Gentleman being at the Head of about Fourscore of them, as their Captain and Leader, with a Blunderbuss in his hand, which he was seen to Fire of several times, bidding defiance to the Sheriffs; and all those who were their Assistance, crying One and all, they would kill them, rather than any Man should be taken out from them, by way of an Arrest, but that was lookt upon to be but a false Suggestion, and a Cunning Plea of their own Forging they having no Regard to Authority, for they had placed several Casks on both sides of the Street, on purpose to Impede the Passage of the Sheriffs, and some of them lay secretly behind them, as it were on purpose, to lye in Wait to take an Advantage, Etc. Firing several times against the Sheriffs and their Men, the Captain being at the Head of them, as aforesaid. And Chandler, the poor Man, who was killed, being on the Sheriffs side, had the misfortune to be shot in the Calf of his Leg, with a Leaden Bullet, which wound killed him in two or three Days, he solemnly protesting upon his Death-Bed, that he knew Captain Winter very well, and that he was the Man that shot him for which Fact the Captain, for some considerable time, Absconded, but was lately Apprehended, and</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA169305170002"/>
            <p>Committed to <placeName id="OA16930517-geo-9">Newgate</placeName> for the same, and was this last Sessions tryed for it, and sound Guilty of Murther, and on the 29April he was Condemned, in Order to be Executed with the other Criminals, who suffer'd at <placeName id="OA16930517-geo-10">Tyburn</placeName>, the 8th. Instant. But, by Vertue of Her Majestys Gracious Reprieve, he was Respited until this day, Etc. As for his Birth, he was Born at <placeName id="OA16930517-geo-11">Truro</placeName> in <placeName id="OA16930517-geo-12">Cornwall</placeName>, then sent <rs id="OA16930517-occupation-2" type="occupation">Apprentice to a Captain of Ship</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA16930517n1-1 OA16930517-occupation-2"/>, after this he was made a <rs id="OA16930517-occupation-3" type="occupation">Captain of a Merchant Man</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA16930517n1-1 OA16930517-occupation-3"/> to the <placeName id="OA16930517-geo-13">West Indias</placeName> himself, after that he <rs id="OA16930517-occupation-4" type="occupation">Commanded a Ship in the last Dutch Wars</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA16930517n1-1 OA16930517-occupation-4"/>, where (to say the Truth) he behaved himself with a great deal of Candor and Courage, afterwards he fell into decay, and had Contracted some Debts in the World, which occasioned him to fly for Refuge into <placeName id="OA16930517-geo-14">White Fryers</placeName>, where he had the Unhappiness to be Engaged in such an unworthy Design, and Violent Attempt, as aforesaid.</p>
            <p>He had not much to offer in his Defence at his Tryal, only in the General, that altho' he was there amongst the Multitude, yet there were others that Shot, and therefore the Man might fall by another hand as well as his, or to that Effect, Etc. After Condemnation he Behav'd himself in a Christian like manner, being much Concerned for his Souls Everlasting Welfare, desiring the Advice, Good Counsel, and Prayers, of all those Worthy Divines that came dear him, acknowledging the Justice of God, in bringing him to Undergo so Severe a Punishment, for that he had been guilty of several Irregularities in the Course of his Life, and had not walked up to the strict Rules of the Christian Religion as he ought to have done, which he now Lamented, and was exceedingly troubled for, therefore he hoped that God would forgive him, being willing to submit to the Righteous Judgement of God Almighty. He gave himself to Reading, Prayer, Hearing God's Word, and to all other Exercises of Religion, being willing to adhear to all Seasonable Advice, that might any ways advance his mind, and set his thoughts on Heavenly Things, Relying only upon the Merits of Christ, for his future Happiness; he carryed himself humbly, during his Imprisonment, both before and after Conviction, though Naturally of a stout, hardy and undaunted spirit, was no ways affrighted at the near approaches of Death, giving God the Praise for such a Respite of Time, in Order to prepare his soul for another World.</p>
            <p>On Wednesday morning, the 17th. Instant as abovesaid, (by Vertue of a Fresh Warrant from her Majesty) he was put into a Coach at <placeName id="OA16930517-geo-15">Newgate Stairs</placeName>, and from thence Conveyed down <placeName id="OA16930517-geo-16">Old Baily</placeName>, and over <placeName id="OA16930517-geo-17">Fleet-Bridge</placeName>, to the <placeName id="OA16930517-geo-18">Fryars Gate</placeName>, in the way to which place, there were several Thousands of Spectators, who thronged to see him, when the Cart was settled under the Gibbet, and he put into it, (which was Erected there on purpose) he stood up, and spake as follows: I have no Publick Declaration to make here, my Thoughts being wholly taken up in the Concerns of my Eternal Welfare, for that is the Work that I am come here to do: Therefore I desire that I may not be interrupted. Then the Minister Prayed with him, and for him, and Recommended him to the Mercy of God, Etc.</p>
            <p>After this, he Pray'd in these Words.</p>
            <p>O Most Great and Glorious Lord God, do thou look down in Mercy upon me, a Poor Miserable Sinner, and shew thy blessed Face to me, now in this Hour of my Extremity, for what am I without thee, therefore O Lord! I beseech thee to Pardon my Sins, and Wash my Soul clean in the Blood of CHRIST JESUS. and deliver me O Lord from the guilt and defilement of Sin; Holy Father do thou Receive me into Mercy, for into thy Hands I Commend my Sprit: O Lord let it be Precious in thy Sight, and let it live with thee in Everlasting Glory: Now I come, sweet JESUS now I am coming to thee; Dear JESUS do thou plead my Cause with the Great GOD of Heaven and Earth, and send down thy Blessed Spirit to Assist and Help me in this Great Work I am now about; I am a Poor Worthless Creature, full of Sin and Misery; yet do thou Lord JESUS take pitty upon my Precious Soul: O Lord JESUS come quickly, for I am now coming to thee, therefore I Humbly beg thee O GOD to Receive my poor Soul into the Arms of thy Everlasting loving Kindness, Lord! Into thy Hands I Commend my Sprit, for thou hast Redeemed it O LORD GOD of Truth Amen.</p>
            <p>Then the Cartaway, and afterwards he was Carryed into <placeName id="OA16930517-geo-19">White-Fryars</placeName>, to be Inter's in <placeName id="OA16930517-geo-20">the Sepulchre</placeName> with his Ben, Etc.</p>
         </div0>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>