<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<TEI.2>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div0 type="ordinarysAccount" id="OA16780906">
            <interp inst="OA16780906" type="uri" value="ordinarysAccounts/OA16780906"/>
            <interp inst="OA16780906" type="date" value="16780906"/>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA167809060001"/>
            <p>THE CONFESSION AND EXECUTION Of the Five PRISONERS That suffered on the New Gallows at <placeName id="OA16780906-geo-1">TYBURN</placeName> On Friday the6th of September 1678.</p>
            <p>At which time were Executed</p>
            <p>
               <persName id="OA16780906n3-1">
                  <interp inst="OA16780906n3-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16780906n3-1" type="surname" value="MASSEY"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16780906n3-1" type="given" value="DANIEL"/>Daniel Massey</persName>, <persName id="OA16780906n3-2">
                  <interp inst="OA16780906n3-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16780906n3-2" type="surname" value="JOHNSON"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16780906n3-2" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Johnson</persName>. <persName id="OA16780906n3-5">
                  <interp inst="OA16780906n3-5" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16780906n3-5" type="surname" value="Brampfield"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16780906n3-5" type="given" value="Sarah"/>Sarah Brampfield</persName>. {<persName id="OA16780906n3-3">
                  <interp inst="OA16780906n3-3" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16780906n3-3" type="surname" value="SMITH"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16780906n3-3" type="given" value="HANNAH"/>Hannah Smith</persName>, otherwise call'd <persName id="OA16780906n3-6">
                  <interp inst="OA16780906n3-6" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16780906n3-6" type="surname" value="Cobb"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16780906n3-6" type="given" value="Hebshebeth"/>Hebshebeth Cobb</persName>. <persName id="OA16780906n3-4">
                  <interp inst="OA16780906n3-4" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16780906n3-4" type="surname" value="DAVIS"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16780906n3-4" type="given" value="ANNE"/>Anne Davis</persName>, alias <persName id="OA16780906n3-7">
                  <interp inst="OA16780906n3-7" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16780906n3-7" type="surname" value="Smalman"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16780906n3-7" type="given" value="Anne"/>Smalman</persName>.</p>
            <p>WITH Brief Notes of Two SERMONS Preached before them after Condemnation, their Carriage in Prison, and last Speeches at the place of Execution.</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA167809060002"/>
            <p>The Confession &amp; Executionof the several Prisoners that sufferedon the New Gallows at <placeName id="OA16780906-geo-2">Tyburn</placeName>, on Friday the6th of September 1678.</p>
            <p>AT the last Sessions there were in all Tenpersons Condemned to die; Four menfor Robberies on the Highway, and Sixwomen for Felonies here in Town, either Lifting(as they call it) of Goods out of Shops, or elseRobbing those whom they pretended to serve:both which wicked Practises are become so common, and more than once followed by these incorrigible Prisoners, that it was highly necessaryto make them Exemplary. Two of the before-mentioned men, viz. those concerned in that barbarous Assault and Robbery, whereof a particularNarrative hath been made publick by the unexpected Mediation of some generous Friends;and the women whose Crimes had not been sogreat and obstinately continued in as the others,obtained his Majesties gracious Reprieve: andanother woman, immediately after she stood attainted, was reprieved by the Court, in reguard</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA167809060003"/>
            <p>she was found by a Female Jury to be quick with Childe.</p>
            <p>The Rest came this day to suffer, being charitably indulged in pity to their Souls, so long time to fit and prepare themselves for their great and terrible Change. In order to which, on the Lords-day before, there were two Sermons on most suitable Texts preached before them in the Chappel of Newgate. That in the Forenoon on the fifth verse of the 38 PsalmMy wounds stink and are corrupt, because of my foolishness: Wherein the Minister very pathetically laid open the deplorable Condition such sinners are in by Nature, wallowing not onely in their original Depravity and Corruption, but in continued actual Transgressions against the holy Laws of God; whereby they become abominable, and as a loathsome stench in the Nostrils of that pure Majesty and all good men; and all this occasioned by their own foolishness, that is, their wilful rebellion and obstinacy against all the dictates of Reason, offers of Grace, and impulses of the Holy Spirit upon their Consciences. Which having, like a true Bonaerges, hereby endeavoured to awaken, and put them into a serious sense and apprehension of their lost, undone, and perishing Estate, without speedy and sincere Repentance.</p>
            <p>In the Afternoon, as a Son of Consolation, from the 147 Psalm, verf. 3. He healeth the broken in heart, and bindeth up their wounds, he came to shew them the infinite Mercies of God, and Love of Jesus Christ, if they would come in and accept of Pardon and Salvation upon Gospel-terms. That although they had made their wounds to fester and rankle by their foolishness, and had Souls all over bespread with a filthy Le-prosie, yet there was Balm in Gilead, an Almighty Physician, both able and willing to heal them, if they would submit to his Prescriptions. In order to which, he gave them divers most necessary and excellent Directions; Not to deceive themselves with a false and palliated Cure, but to close with Christ on his own Terms, and in all his Offices, as their King to Rule them, and their Prophet to Guide them, as well as their Priest to Intercede and make Atonement for them. To hate Sin more, because it was displeasing to God, than because it brought upon them temporal or eternal Punishments. To be as desirous to be Holy as to be Happy; because none can be justified until they are sanctified, Etc.</p>
            <p>During the whole time of Religious Worship, and the Sermons, they behaved themselves very Reverently and Atten-</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA167809060004"/>
            <p>tively; nor was the Minister wanting afterwards, daily to visit them, with pressing Exhortations, and necessary directions to sit them for their last end; especially charging them to disburthen their Consciences, and give glory to God by a free and hearty Confession of their Sins; which had so good an effect, as to bring them to an Acknowledgment; not only in general term, but particularly bewailing the Ill Courses of their past Lives; in neglect of the publick Divine Worship Violation of the Lords day, Drunkenness, Swearing, and continual practises of Lascivious Debauchery; Two of them above the rest abounding in expressions of Penitence, and endeavouring to improve those few moments of their Lives, to work out their Salvation, and make their peace with God; begging heartily forgiveness from his most holy Majesty, for their Rebellion against his Precepts, and of all those whom they had wronged, by violent taking away their Temporal Goods.</p>
            <p>Some of the Women had been Condemned before, and would often bewail the wickedness of their Hearts, that would take no warning thereby: the Men alleadged, they were ignorantly drawn in to that ill Fact, for which they suffer'd. being their first of that kind, and rather by the unhappy operation of too much Drink, than any premeditated design; yet confessed, they had more than once deserved to Dye, and freely acknowledged the justice of the punishment they were to suffer.</p>
            <p>At the place of Execution they said little, besides those common, but too much neglected Exhortations, desiring all present to take Warning by them, and remember their Creator in the days of their youth; Not to suffer themselves to be seduced by Ill Company, or sensual pleasures, which had been the means of their destruction, and would be so of all, that did not continually keep a reverent fear of God, and his Worship and Laws in their Hearts.</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA167809060005"/>
            <p>This heartily praying to God for Forgiveness, and to receive their Souls for the alone Merits of his blessed Son; and desiring all good people to joyn with them and for them in those Supplications, they submitted to the Sentence, and taking their leave of all things in this world, were wasted into the unfathomable Regions of Eternity.</p>
         </div0>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>