<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<TEI.2>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div0 type="ordinarysAccount" id="OA16771017">
            <interp inst="OA16771017" type="uri" value="ordinarysAccounts/OA16771017"/>
            <interp inst="OA16771017" type="date" value="16771017"/>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA167710170001"/>
            <p>THE CONFESSION AND EXECUTION Of the Three Prisoners suffering at <placeName id="OA16771017-geo-1">TYBURN</placeName> On Wednesday the 17th of October 1677. At which time suffered <persName id="OA16771017n1-1">
                  <interp inst="OA16771017n1-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16771017n1-1" type="surname" value="FLETCHER"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16771017n1-1" type="given" value="JOHN WILLIAM"/>John S. William Fletcher</persName>, and <persName id="OA16771017n1-2">
                  <interp inst="OA16771017n1-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16771017n1-2" type="surname" value="Perkins"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16771017n1-2" type="given" value="Rob"/>Rob, Perkins</persName>. TOGETHER</p>
            <p>With their Behaviour, and several remarkable Discourses had with one of the Highway-men in <placeName id="OA16771017-geo-2">Newgate</placeName> After his Condemnation.</p>
            <p>Published for a Warning-piece to all others to avoid the lewd Courses which brought these Poor men to this Ignominious End.</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA167710170002"/>
            <p>The Confession and Execution of the Prisoners dying at Tyburn.</p>
            <p>AT the Sessions of Oyer and Terminer for London, and Gaole-delivery of Newgate begun at Justice-Hall in the <placeName id="OA16771017-geo-3">Old Bayly</placeName>, 10Octob. and ending on the 12 of the same Month, there were in all (as by a Printed Narrative you may already have heard) Five persons, who being Convicted on fair Tryals (per Patriam) of several capital Crimes, received Sentence of Death: But Two of them, whose Crime was stealing of two horses, appearing to be objects of mercy, as having never been concern'd in any such offences before, and seeming now extremely penitent for the same, obtained a Gracious Reprieve. The other Three were this present Wednesday 17Octob. carryed</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA167710170003"/>
            <p>The Confession and Execution of the Prisoners dying at Tyburn.</p>
            <p>AT the Sessions of Oyer and Terminer for London, and Gaole-delivery of Newgate begun at Justice-Hall in the <placeName id="OA16771017-geo-4">Old Bayly</placeName>, 10Octob. and ending on the 12 of the same Month, there were in all (as by a Printed Narrative you may already have heard) Five persons, who being Convicted on fair Tryals (per Patriam) of several capital Crimes, received Sentence of Death: But Two of them, whose Crime was stealing of two horses, appearing to be objects of mercy, as having never been concern'd in any such offences before, and seeming now extremely penitent for the same, obtained a Gracious Reprieve. The other Three were this present Wednesday 17Octob. carryed</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA167710170004"/>
            <p>in the very acts of their impiety Etc. These and many other pressing exhortations, together with severe threatnings to affright them and sweet promises to allure them, taken from the Word of God, were made use of, to bring them to a due sense of their sins, and to cry mightily to God for salvation. But the deaf adder refuses the voice of the charmer, charm he never so wisely All this good seed could take no root, or produce very little visible fruit on the stony ground of two of these Prisoners obdurate hearts; they not seeming (to outward appearance at least) to take that due and sensible notice of this most important counsel, as might be expected from persons in their condition. But the Spirit bloweth where it listeth. The third seemed much affected with this pious advice, and was very earnest and frequent in bewailing his sins, and condemning himself bitterly for having so wickedly mis-spent his precious time heretoforr. He acknowledged to some, that he had several years been a Thief, but not till of late upon the High-way: that at fust his Conscience would after every fact severely check him; but since custom of sinning taking away the sense, he had run on from one degree of wickedness to a greater without controul. He was very frequent in Prayer, wherein he has been heard to express himself to this effect.</p>
            <p>Most dreadful and glorious God, though then hatest all the workers of iniquity, yet through the Mediation of they blessed son, with pity behold me a miserable sinner. Had I lived according to thy Commandments, or submitted to the Gospel of thy son, I might approach thee with the confidence of a childe: but I have been a Rebel against thee from my youth up, forgetting the God that made me, and the saviour that redeemed me, quenching and grieving the holy spirit, and slighting the endless Glory which thou hast prepared for me. Oh the precious time which I have lost, which all the world cannot call back; the wonderful love which I unthankfully rejected! How have I lived in continual acts of all kinde of Profaneness, all kind of Debanchery, whoring, swearing, Drunkenness, and especially Theft, which now has brought me to this woful, forlorn, condemned case wherein I am a shame to my friends, and burden to my self; and thou, O God, art my Terrour, who shouldot be my onely Hope and Comfort. Lord, thou knowest my secret sins, which yet are unknown to men, and all their Aggravations. Mine iniquities, Lord, have found me out; my fears and sorrows overwhelm me: a shameful</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA167710170005"/>
            <p>death expects me in this world, and endless torments are ready to receive me in the other. But, Lord! thy Goodness is equal to they Greatness, thy Mercy over all thy works. Good God, be merciful therefore unto me, the vilest of sinners: save me for thy abundant mercy, for the merit of thy Son, and for the promise of forgiveness which thou hast made through him; for in these alone is all my trust. Thou who didst patiently endure me when I despised thee, Oh do not refuse me now I seek unto thee, and in the dust implore thy mercy. Lord, I ask not for longer life in this world, but for life eternal; not for liberty to sin again, but for deliverance from this sinning nature, and that body of death which overwhelms me. To this purpose Lord give me thy grace to improve these few minutes, and prepare me for death and Judgement; that when I leave this world with Shame, I may be received into glory, and yeeld my departing soul with joy into the faithful hands of my Redeemer. Amen.</p>
            <p>He behaved himself very penitently in the Cart, Prayed a considerable time by himself privately at the place of Execution; desired all people to take warning by him to avoid Idleness and Ill Company, which brought him to this Ignominious End. The other joyned in the publick Prayers, but said very little that could be heard. But all of them together suffered very patiently, and with submissive acknowledgements of the Justice of the Sentence.</p>
         </div0>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>