<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<TEI.2>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div0 type="ordinarysAccount" id="OA16950417">
            <interp inst="OA16950417" type="uri" value="ordinarysAccounts/OA16950417"/>
            <interp inst="OA16950417" type="date" value="16950417"/>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA169504170001"/>
            <p>A True ACCOUNT of the BEHAVIOUR, CONFESSION AND Last Dying SPEECHES, Of the Criminals that were Executed at TYBURN, On Wednesday the 17th of this Instant April 1695.</p>
            <p>AT the Sessions House in the Old-Bayly, on Fryday the 5th of April 1695, Six Persons had their Sentence of Death pronounced upon them, viz. five Men and one Woman; on Saturday the Ordinary visited them, and endeavoured to make them sensible of their Crimes, <persName id="OA16950417n3-1">
                  <interp inst="OA16950417n3-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16950417n3-1" type="surname" value="NEWLAND"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16950417n3-1" type="given" value="FRANCIS"/>Francis Newland</persName>, Condemned for the Barbarous Murther of Mr. Thomas, the manner of it is described in the Book of Tryals. I went to him in his Chamber, hoping to make him thereby, the more sensible of his Crime, exhorting him to consider how deeply he had defiled his Soul, with shedding the Blood of an innocent Gentleman; I told him that very great Repentance was requisite for such an heinous Crime, added to the sins of his whole life. And that because he did not Reform in time, God was justly provoked to withdraw his preventing Grace, which would have restrained him from this bloody fact. He was willing to receive the good advice which I gave him, and I prayed with him sutably to his sinful distressed Condition. Afterwards I went to the other Condemned persons, and exhorted them to call to remembrance, the sinful course of their whole Lives. I mentioned many Sins usually committed by young persons, which they little consider, so as to repent of them unfeignedly: Therefore publick shame and punishment convinces them of their Atheistical hopes of secrecy and impurity in sinning. I desired them to mourn chiefly for offending a gracious God, who had so long extended his sparing mercy, yet they had perversly abused it to the abounding in Iniquity. Much more I said, instructing them in the Duties of Faith and Repentance.</p>
            <p>On the Lords Day in the Afternoon, the Ordinary preacht from the 133d verse of the 119th Psalm, in these words, Order my steps in thy word, so shall not any Iniquity have dominion over me. Hence six general Heads were treated on, with several particulars branching from each Head.</p>
            <p>1. What is meant by a mans stps in my Text. Not only the outward conversation, but also the motions and tendencies of the Will, and the affections of the Heart. The object of our desires must be chosen for its intrinsical worth and excellency, and also for its beneficial usefulness unto our selves. Our Actions must be lawful, expedient, and commendable, such, which must Adorn the professions of the Christian Religion. Our affections as the Souls Pulse, must not saulter in too violent a motion after lawful things, nor may they beat slow and faintly in the duties of Gods Worship. The spring of the Heart must be raised to an high pitch of heavenly mindedness, but it must be let down in a moderate pursuit of what the will desires, as to the gratifications of worldly Interest and concernments.</p>
            <p>2. Why must we order our conversations according to the institutions of God in his Sacred Word. First, because the highest Rules in moral Philosophy, cannot effect any sanctifying change in the Heart, nor truely subdue any corrupt Affection. These only work a palliating Cure upon the customariness of a sinful course. Secondly, Satan lays many subtle Temptations, to bewilder you in your progressive advancing a state of Holiness. These sares cannot be discerned, much less avoided, unless the word of God be consulted with, and obeyed. Thirdly, Popish guide of mens Consciences, by their casuistical Doctrine of probability, which makes most things lawful, pervert the words of Gods Holiness, thereby ruining mens precious Souls, only the testimonies of the Lord are safe and sure guides, in all doubtful and difficult cases.</p>
            <p>3. What are those false Rules, whereby the conversation is more perverted. First, the entering into any order of a superstitious Society, which pretends to greater strictness in Religion, yet cannot produce any advances in sincere Piety. Secondly, the consulting carnal wisdom and worldly Interest in stating mens duties, and not the institutions of Christ. Thirdly, the singling out any one command of God, to be exercised in a conformity to this, yet presuming that a dispensation will be granted, for the neglect of any other command, equally as necessary, yea, more tending to promote the power of Godliness.</p>
            <p>4. The signs of sins having Deminion over a person. First, when it is committed, not by the sudden surprisal of Temptation, but by wicked deliberation and contrivance. Secondly, when men justify their Abominations, abusing the promptness of wit, to plead in the defence of sinning, Thirdly, when the Lords tenderest mercies cannot invite men to Repentance nor the severity of punishments cure the malignity of their Hearts. Fourthly, when persons mock at the fear of the Lord, making a sport of sinning, yea, count this to be their Glory to have no Competitor equal with themselves in sinning.</p>
            <p>The Character of such who sincerely order their steps in Gods word.</p>
            <p>1. They abominate the very thoughts of sinning, even the first stirrings of any vitious Inclination.</p>
            <p>2. They strengthen their Faith, when Gods word of promise seems to fail, yea fight against them in the extremities of Adversity. They persevere in following the conduct of the Lord in the known beaten way of their Duty, when they cannot trace him out, in the mysterious Paths of dark and dismal providences.</p>
            <p>3. They count this to be the Spirit and Beauty of Religion when they are formed to such a pitch of selfdenyal, as to rejoyce, in the Government of sanctifyed reason over all inordinate passions of Love, Grief, or Anger. They count the indulgence of any sin, to be the severest Condemnation to a self tormenting Licentiousness.</p>
            <p>Motives to perswade to the right ordering of the Heart, and Conversation in the paths of Gods Commandments.</p>
            <p>First, Hereby you will be prepared for the ready, most solemn entrance of Christ into your Hearts, to rule you by the Scepter of his Righteousness. This will make your progress in Religion, more easy, safe, stedfast, and delightful. Secondly, consider that meer sensitive Creatures, which are only guided by the law of natural Instinct, may instruct men in many weighty duties of Religion, several instances were given hereof. Thirdly, you cannot rationally expect that the Almighty should defend you from Terrors in the night, if he doth not guide your Paths in the Day. Fourthly, thus great Peace will flow into your Hearts, and nothing shall offend you, neither the laws strictest purity, nor any extremest distresses in the World. Fifthly, the following the conduct of God in his word, will prevent giving any credit to wild Enthusiastick dreams, as if these were a divine Revelation, but if any thing manifestly be your duty, embrace and pursue it, tho you meet with difficulties dangers, and Reproaches. These will be dispised and overcome, if you truely trust in God for safety and success.</p>
            <p>The conclusion was thus directed to the Condemned</p>
            <p>How contrary have you acted to David Parer, and Examples, you have been Zealous agents in promoting Satans Kingdom, propagating sin by your wicked Counsel; you have arriv</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA169504170002"/>
            <p>ed to such an height of Atheism, that you are grown audaciously eless in sinning, as not regarding the Inspection of Omnisciency. You have joyned in a confederacy to break through the restraints of all pedal Law: Yet the association of sinners will inevitably augment the common Treasury of divine wrath. Take heed that you deceive not your selves, with faint false wishes to Reform. Some seeming Penitents, when the present anguish of their Consciences is worn off, return to the excesses of sinning with greater grediness. Beg of God therefore, that you may Improve right, the season granted for making Peace with your Eternal judge, then you will disdain any mean common Actings, in the working out your Salvation, that you may not mistake in so weighty a concernment. Let the least  of Gods will be imprest in your Hearts, as a prevailing Law. Let your Souls follow hard after the Lord, to tread in the very steps of your Saviour, by imitating of him, who under the Agonies of Death, prayed the more fervently to overcme them. Conform compleatly to Gods statutes, so shall you not be shamed by Hypocrisy, nor shall any sin get Dominion over you. Keep a stict watchful guard over your Hearts, that you may not be surprized by security to all into Satans snares by tempting you to presumption or despair. Commit your selves to the custody of the spirit of Holiness, pray that he would make your Resolutions of Reformation to be sincere, that he would preserve you to a perfect state of Holiness in Heavenly Felicity.</p>
            <p>I Proceed to give an Account of the Behaviour, and Confession of the Condemned Criminals.</p>
            <p>I. <persName id="OA16950417n19-1">
                  <interp inst="OA16950417n19-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16950417n19-1" type="surname" value="Sterne"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16950417n19-1" type="given" value="Robert"/>Robert Sterne</persName> Condemned for Felony and Burglary. He said that he was born at <placeName id="OA16950417-geo-1">
                  <interp inst="OA16950417-geo-1" type="type" value="county"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA16950417n19-1 OA16950417-geo-1"/>
                  <placeName id="OA16950417-geo-2">
                     <interp inst="OA16950417-geo-2" type="type" value="urban_centre"/>
                     <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA16950417n19-1 OA16950417-geo-2"/>Hadleigh</placeName> in Essex</placeName>, that he had been in <rs id="OA16950417-occupation-1" type="occupation">Sea service</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA16950417n19-1 OA16950417-occupation-1"/>, that he since employed himself in <rs id="OA16950417-occupation-2" type="occupation">Husbandry</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA16950417n19-1 OA16950417-occupation-2"/>, but he neglected it, so being addicted to Idleness, he joyned with bad Company; he confest the Crime with Tears, saying, that his sins had been many and great, tho he knew Gods Commandments, yet he broke them against the many checks and convictions of his Conscience. This was increased by his not praying that God would keep him from the evil Inclinations of his own Heart. But he hopes that he doth truely Repent of all his sins, and that those in which he most delighted, are now most hated by him.</p>
            <p>II. W - R - Condemned for Clipping the currant Coyn of this Nation. He is Thirty Years of Age, he said that he was well educated at a Grammer School, and so was fitted for the Trade of a Bookseller, and might have lived comfortably in that employment. But he grew Idle, and thereupon was forced through Poverty, to list himself into military service by Land. He repents that he contracted acquaintance with bad Persons, and was given to vain expences, to supply which, he did some unlawful acts, yet he declined the confession of his Crime tho he did not utterly deny it. He was attentive to Instructions and Prayers, he seemed penitent, saying that altho his chain did fre his skin, yet this was light in comparison of his sin, which had laid a load of guilt upon his Conscience, but he hoped that Christ would take it off, by Repentance and change of his heart.</p>
            <p>III. <persName id="OA16950417n21-1">
                  <interp inst="OA16950417n21-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16950417n21-1" type="surname" value="HANCOCK"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16950417n21-1" type="given" value="WILLIAM"/>William Hancock</persName>, Condemned for Robbing on the Kings High-way. He was born in <placeName id="OA16950417-geo-3">
                  <interp inst="OA16950417-geo-3" type="type" value="urban_centre"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA16950417n21-1 OA16950417-geo-3"/>Southwark</placeName>, Aged 19 Years. He said that he was a <rs id="OA16950417-occupation-3" type="occupation">Butcher</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA16950417n21-1 OA16950417-occupation-3"/>, but being excessive in his expences and having brought himself to extream poverty, he was forced to enter himself into the <rs id="OA16950417-occupation-4" type="occupation">Kings service</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA16950417n21-1 OA16950417-occupation-4"/> above a twelve Month since. He confest that he did walk in the Fields on the Lords-Day, and joyned with bad company. He acknowledged that he had, been guilty of swearing and drunkenness, but said that now he desires to sepent of all his sins, which he can call to mind, I askt him what is true saving Faith and Repentance? he could not describe them to my satisfaction, therefore I instructed him more clearly and fully in the nature of them.</p>
            <p>IV. <persName id="OA16950417n22-1">
                  <interp inst="OA16950417n22-1" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16950417n22-1" type="surname" value="BATES"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16950417n22-1" type="given" value="JOAN"/>Joan Bates</persName>, alias <persName id="OA16950417n22-2">
                  <interp inst="OA16950417n22-2" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16950417n22-2" type="surname" value="CLARK"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16950417n22-2" type="given" value="JOAN"/>Clark</persName>, Condemned for Felony, in Robbing one Mrs. Courtney of Plate to a great value. She denyed not the Fact; she at first lived with her Father, but being put out to service, she Robbed another mistriss before; for which she was burnt in the Hand. After this she said that her father took her home to him, thinking to reform her; but she was weary of his good Councel. So leaving her Father she joyned with bad company, and so being poor, her own wicked Heart inticed her to commit this second Felony. She said that now she call'd to mind er former iniquities, which she did not repent of sincerely, and therefore was justly left to fill up the measure of her sins, which had brought untimely Death upon her; yet that the publick shame of this doth not so much afflict her, as that she did not take warning by a lesser punishment.</p>
            <p>V. <persName id="OA16950417n23-2">
                  <interp inst="OA16950417n23-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16950417n23-2" type="surname" value="Newland"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16950417n23-2" type="given" value="Francis"/>Francis Newland</persName>' Condemned for the murther of <persName id="OA16950417n23-1">
                  <interp inst="OA16950417n23-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16950417n23-1" type="surname" value="THOMAS"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16950417n23-1" type="given" value="FRANCIS"/>Francis Thomas</persName> 
               <rs id="OA16950417-occupation-5" type="occupation">Esq</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA16950417n23-1 OA16950417-occupation-5"/>; Aged 21 years; he said that he had good education at a Grammer School, that he was in <rs id="OA16950417-occupation-6" type="occupation">Sea service</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA16950417n23-2 OA16950417-occupation-6"/>, that he had nor addicted himself to a vicious course of life, yet denied not that he neglected Religious duties, and that for this God permitted him to fall into bad acquaintance of late. He denyed not that he was in the company of those Persons, who offred affronts at the dancing School in <placeName id="OA16950417-geo-4">
                  <interp inst="OA16950417-geo-4" type="type" value="street"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA16950417n23-2 OA16950417-geo-4"/>Drury lane</placeName>, that they prevaild upon him to go farther with them that he was present when they aused Mr. Thomas in the Fruit womans Sellar, that the persons mentioned  the Book of Tryals did persue Mr. Thomas, himself knowing no reason for it. I askt him if they were in drink, he said no, but an hectoing fit was upon them. He said that be knew not when nor how he lost his Sword. He protested as a dying person, that he did not give any wound to Mr. Thomas, only he saw one of the Philboys (since fled) to fight with Mr. Thomas, and believes, that he gave him his mortal Wound. He said it much greives him, that he did sall into such mad Company, and he desires all young Persons to beware of the Idle and sinful wasting of their time; lest they expose themselves to such Company, as may prevail on them to be present at Bloody Quarrels, and so be involved in a sentence of Death.</p>
            <p>He is very much cast down, and grieves for his foolish rashness, as being in such dissolute Company. He takes well the severest admonitions given to him, hoping that God will sanctify his distressed condition, that it may tend, by Gods mercyful Goodness, to be an occasion to work toward his Repentance and the salvation of his Soul.</p>
            <p>On Wednesday the 17 instant, <persName id="OA16950417n25-1">
                  <interp inst="OA16950417n25-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16950417n25-1" type="surname" value="HANCOCK"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16950417n25-1" type="given" value="WILLIAM"/>William Hancock</persName>, <persName id="OA16950417n25-2">
                  <interp inst="OA16950417n25-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16950417n25-2" type="surname" value="STERN"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16950417n25-2" type="given" value="ROBERT"/>Robert Stern</persName>, ad W - R - were all Conveyed to <placeName id="OA16950417-geo-5">
                  <interp inst="OA16950417-geo-5" type="type" value="site"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA16950417n25-1 n25-2 OA16950417-geo-5"/>Tyburn</placeName>; the two former in a Cart, the latter in a Sledge, the rest being Reprieved by Vertue of his Majesties Most Gracious Clemency, but Mr. Newland is only respted till Friday next. All the way to <placeName id="OA16950417-geo-6">
                  <interp inst="OA16950417-geo-6" type="type" value="site"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA16950417n25-1 n25-2 OA16950417-geo-6"/>Tyburn</placeName> they lamented, and bewailed themselves, being brought to undergo such a reproach and publick shame; and when they came to the Tree, and were tyed up all in one Cart, <persName id="OA16950417n25-3">
                  <interp inst="OA16950417n25-3" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16950417n25-3" type="surname" value="STERN"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16950417n25-3" type="given" value="ROBERT"/>Robert Stern</persName> pake to this effect. Good People, let my shameful end excite you to have a care how you live in the World that ou be not overtaken by the Temptations of the Devil and the World, and be sure to keep good Company, and be tender of the Sabbath Day; and Remember to keep it Holy; I was Tempted by wicked men, to joyn with them in commiting of several Robberys, and particularty in this for which I come here to Dye, this most shameful Death, I am willing to dye,  me beg your prayers. He was more penitent than the other two, as to outward appearance. W - R - desired all the spectators to pray for him, and behaved himself very soberly and seriously to the last, confessing that he had been a great sinner, for which he now heartily repented, and hopes for Salvation thro Christ Jesus. <persName id="OA16950417n25-4">
                  <interp inst="OA16950417n25-4" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16950417n25-4" type="surname" value="HANCOCK"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16950417n25-4" type="given" value="WILLIAM"/>William Hancock</persName> seemed not so much concerned as the other, but at the last says he, if there be any one here that knows me, let me desire them to pull me by the Legs when I am turn'd off, to dispatch me out of my pain. Pray God bless you all I hope you'll pray for me. Then the Ordinary Prayed with them, and sung a Penitential Psalm, so they were all turn'd off.</p>
            <p>This is all the Account I can give of this Sessions, <persName id="OA16950417n26-1">
                  <interp inst="OA16950417n26-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16950417n26-1" type="surname" value="Smith"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16950417n26-1" type="given" value="Sam"/>Sam. Smith</persName> 
               <rs id="OA16950417-occupation-7" type="occupation">Ordinary</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA16950417n26-1 OA16950417-occupation-7"/>.</p>
            <p>Licensed April 17th, 1695.</p>
            <p>ADVERTISEMENT.</p>
            <p>THis is to give notice, that Mrs. Norridge is removed from the Blue Ball in Exeter Street, to a Turners, next door to Semmerset House in the Strand. Who hath an infallible Powder for the Stone and Cravel in the Kidneys, Stone and Stranguary, and Stone Cholick, which great secret with many more, her Father Dr. Duncan, left her at his decease, who practiced Physick for the space of Sixty Years, and lived till the Age of Eighty Eight. This powder hath wrought many eminent Cures upon Persons of both sexes, as is attested by several Persons of note, whose Names and places of Abode, is incerted in her printed paper of Directions. This Powder is sealed up with her Coat of Arms, in Five and Ten Shilling papers, and in half Crown papers, to take in a morning fasting, to carry off the Gravel, and prevent the Stone from contracting to a Body.</p>
            <p>She hath likewise an excellent purging Pill and Elixer, which purisies and sweetens the Blood, and destroys Ws in Men, Women, and Children. The Pills are fealed up in 18 d. Boxes, and the Elixer in 2 and 3 s. Bottles, with Directions.</p>
            <p>She is very expert in cleansing Teeth, and taketh out ny perisht part betwixt the Teeth, and setteth in Artificial ones.</p>
            <p>She hath a most Excellent Water for sore Eyes, that strengthens the weak sight, and cures the Evil in the Eyes, or any Rheumatick Eye, that is got by Cold or Weeping.</p>
            <p>She is to be spoken with every Morning till Ten, and Tuesdays, and Thursdays all day.</p>
            <p>IN <placeName id="OA16950417-geo-7">
                  <interp inst="OA16950417-geo-7" type="type" value="street"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA16950417n34-1 OA16950417-geo-7"/>
                  <placeName id="OA16950417-geo-8">
                     <interp inst="OA16950417-geo-8" type="type" value="street"/>
                     <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA16950417n34-1 OA16950417-geo-8"/>Grays-Inn lane</placeName> in Plow-yard</placeName>, the third door, lives Dr. <persName id="OA16950417n34-1">
                  <interp inst="OA16950417n34-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16950417n34-1" type="surname" value="KIRLEUS"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16950417n34-1" type="given" value="THOMAS"/>Thomas Kirleus</persName>, a Collegiate <rs id="OA16950417-occupation-8" type="occupation">Physician</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA16950417n34-1 OA16950417-occupation-8"/>, and Sworn Physician in Ordinary to King Charles the Second, until his death; who with a Drink and Pill (hinring no Business) undertakes to Cure any Ulcers, Sores, Swellings in the Nose, Face, or other parts; Scabs, In, Scurfs, Leprosies, and Venereal Disease expecting nothing untill the Cure be finished. Of the last he hath cured many hundreds in this City, many of them after fluxing, which carries the evil from the lower parts to the Head, and so destroys many. The Drink is 3 s. the Quart, the Pill 1 s. a box with Directions, a better purger than which was never given, for they cleanse the body of all Impurities, which are the causes of Dropsies, Gouts, Scurvies, Stone or Gravel, Pains in the Head, and other parts. Take heed whom you trust in Physick, for it's become a common Cheat to profess it. He gives his opinion to all that write or come, for nothing.</p>
            <p>LONDON, Printed for E. Mallet, at Sir Edmundbury Godfry's Head, near Fleet-bridge, 1695.</p>
         </div0>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>