<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<TEI.2>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div0 type="ordinarysAccount" id="OA16850304">
            <interp inst="OA16850304" type="uri" value="ordinarysAccounts/OA16850304"/>
            <interp inst="OA16850304" type="date" value="16850304"/>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA168503040001"/>
            <p>THE BEHAVIOUR OF THE Condemned Criminals IN NEWGATE, VIZ. <persName id="OA16850304n2-1">
                  <interp inst="OA16850304n2-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16850304n2-1" type="surname" value="RAWSON"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16850304n2-1" type="given" value="WILLIAM"/>William Rawson</persName>, <persName id="OA16850304n2-2">
                  <interp inst="OA16850304n2-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16850304n2-2" type="surname" value="BUCKLER"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16850304n2-2" type="given" value="CHARLES"/>Charles Buckler</persName>, <persName id="OA16850304n2-3">
                  <interp inst="OA16850304n2-3" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16850304n2-3" type="surname" value="HARRISON"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16850304n2-3" type="given" value="RALPH"/>Ralph Harrison</persName>, and <persName id="OA16850304n2-4">
                  <interp inst="OA16850304n2-4" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16850304n2-4" type="surname" value="LIST"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16850304n2-4" type="given" value="HENRY"/>Henry List</persName>, As Also The Last Dying Words OF <persName id="OA16850304n2-10">
                  <interp inst="OA16850304n2-10" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16850304n2-10" type="surname" value="Fallowfield"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16850304n2-10" type="given" value="Thomas"/>Thomas Fallowfield</persName> for Murdering of <persName id="OA16850304n2-5">
                  <interp inst="OA16850304n2-5" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16850304n2-5" type="surname" value="SMITH"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16850304n2-5" type="given" value="MARY"/>Mary Smith</persName> alias <persName id="OA16850304n2-11">
                  <interp inst="OA16850304n2-11" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16850304n2-11" type="surname" value="Hunt"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16850304n2-11" type="given" value="Mary"/>Hunt</persName>, who was Executed at <placeName id="OA16850304-geo-1">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA16850304n2-10 OA16850304-geo-1"/>LEICESTER-FEILD</placeName>, <persName id="OA16850304n2-6">
                  <interp inst="OA16850304n2-6" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16850304n2-6" type="surname" value="COATES"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16850304n2-6" type="given" value="JOSEPH"/>Joseph Coates</persName> for Felony, <rs id="OA16850304-occupation-1" type="occupation">Cap</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA16850304n2-7 OA16850304-occupation-1"/>. <persName id="OA16850304n2-7">
                  <interp inst="OA16850304n2-7" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16850304n2-7" type="surname" value="BAKER"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16850304n2-7" type="given" value="GEORGE"/>George Baker</persName>, <persName id="OA16850304n2-8">
                  <interp inst="OA16850304n2-8" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16850304n2-8" type="surname" value="SAUNDERS"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16850304n2-8" type="given" value="GEORGE"/>George Saunders</persName>, and <persName id="OA16850304n2-9">
                  <interp inst="OA16850304n2-9" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16850304n2-9" type="surname" value="MULLINS"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16850304n2-9" type="given" value="WILLIAM"/>William Mullins</persName>, for Robbing on the High-way, was Executed at TYBURN. On Wednesday the 4th. day of March, 1684.</p>
            <p>IT is sad to Consider, (that notwithstanding the frequent Examples of publick Justice on Capital Offenders, for the warning of all others, to Avoid the same Crimes, yet) that in the short Intervale of time from the former sessions, there should be such a Confluence of persons now Condemned. It is probable, that they did presumptuously hope for a General pardon at this sessions, tho they did Gracelesly antidate an Act of Royal Grace and Mercy to Incourage themselves in their Impieties.</p>
            <p>This may convince obdurate Sinners of that Secret Atheism which Reigns in their Hearts, by Crying up false peace and safety to themselves, whereby they are frequently made Exemplary in a publick and shameful Death. 34. of Job 26. 27. Ver. He strickes them, as wicked men in the open sight of others, because they turned back from him and would not consider any of his ways.</p>
            <p>Thus ye Hypocrite in Heart, such who are heartily in their Hypocrites, and thereby Confirm&#8217;d in Athism heap up wrath, so that they Dye in youth, and their Life is among the Unclean  36. of Feb 13, 14th</p>
            <p>After the Sentence of Death past on the aforesaid Criminals on Friday the 27th. Instant February, they were Visited on Saturday, to bring them to a Conviction; of their Sinful and Deplorable Convictions; and in order to their more serious preparation, for those Prayers and Exhortations, which were to Follow on the next Lords Day.</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA168503040002"/>
            <p>In the Forenoon a Sermon was Preached on the 17. of Genesis, and the first Verse: Walk before me, and be Perfect or Upright.</p>
            <p>In the Afternoon of the same Day, a Sermon was Preached on the 11. Chap. of the first Epistle to the Cor. and the 31. Verse: For if we would Judge our Selves, we Should not be Judged of the Lord.</p>
            <p>From which Text, the Ordinary offered to their Consideration, that self Judgment and self Condemnation, in the Impartial Acknowledgement of the Equity of the Divine Law-giver in his process of Judgment, tho most Severe, as the Righteous Demerit and result of the least. Sin, is the only ready and sure way to escape that Divine Wrath, which is Impendent over the Heads of Sinners.</p>
            <p>In the Progress of that discourse, especially at the practical Improvement of it, to the present Condemned, they seemed to be much awaked from their Security in a Sinful state, to preserve Increase any signs of Contrition, the Ordinary Visited them again on Munday, and after Payer, for them, Exhorted them to search their own Hearts, that they might discover for what special secret Sins, God had been provoked to withdraw his preventing Grace, so as to leave them to commit those Hinous Crimes, in which, they have wilfully insnared themselves.</p>
            <p>On Monday and Tuesday, the ordinary after Prayers, Inquired into their former manner and course of Life, and how they now stand affected under the Sentence of Death, and prospect of that Eternity into which they are Launching: whither they Repent of their Sine and the Excesses of their Youth and a Debauched Life, be as bitter and Loathsome as at any time before they were Delightful.</p>
            <p>Of which Conferences with them apart, which are most affective of them, the Ordinary now proceeds to give a True and Impartial Account, taken from their own Mouths in Wrighting.</p>
            <p>
               <persName id="OA16850304n13-1">
                  <interp inst="OA16850304n13-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16850304n13-1" type="surname" value="RAWSON"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16850304n13-1" type="given" value="WILLIAM"/>William Rawson</persName>, he was Born in <placeName id="OA16850304-geo-2">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA16850304n13-1 OA16850304-geo-2"/>Cumberland</placeName>, is 27 Years of Age; he was Educated at School by his Parents, in order to have been sent to the University, as being of Good Natural Parts, and was hopeful in the Improvement of them: But his Parents not being afterward of Estate Sufficient, to perfect their Intention of forming him for an University, himself also growing Remiss in his Learning, he came to <placeName id="OA16850304-geo-3">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA16850304n13-1 OA16850304-geo-3"/>London</placeName>, where he stayed for some time with a Gentleman of Good Repute: but not answering his Expectation, he went back into his own Country: where continuing for some good space of time; he lived in Idleness; yet presumed at last to Marry, tho he knew not how to provide for the necessary support of that Condition: so becoming very Poor, he faith he sought for Imployment in London; but about a Month past, he was so unhappy as to grow acquainted with Bad Company, who Tempted him to many Miscarriages; particularly to associate himself with them in Robbing on the Highway. He confess&#8217;d himself guilty of the Crime he stands Condemned for, yet being g&#8217;d to make Acknowledgement how long he had used Highway Robbing, and who Tempted him first into such a Dissolute course of Life, he made no other reply, but that they were fled beyond Reach and would not name any particular Person, tho he ought to have broke the Combination by a Discovery.</p>
            <p>He said he had been many ways Sinful, but he hoped by Repentence through christ&#8217;s Merits, the Lord would Pardon him, and receive him to his Mercy.</p>
            <p>
               <persName id="OA16850304n15-1">
                  <interp inst="OA16850304n15-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16850304n15-1" type="surname" value="Saunders"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16850304n15-1" type="given" value="George"/>George Saunders</persName>, he was Born in <placeName id="OA16850304-geo-4">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA16850304n15-1 OA16850304-geo-4"/>Ireland</placeName>, of Protestant Parents, in <placeName id="OA16850304-geo-5">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA16850304n15-1 OA16850304-geo-5"/>Limbrick</placeName>; by them he was sent to School, to sit him for future Imployment; but there he behaved himself like a very Unlucky Lad; afterward he was put an <rs id="OA16850304-occupation-2" type="occupation">Apprentice to a Weaver</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA16850304n15-1 OA16850304-occupation-2"/>, in whose Service he remained for some time, but leaving it off, he <rs id="OA16850304-occupation-3" type="occupation">Waited on a Gentleman</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA16850304n15-1 OA16850304-occupation-3"/>: whom deserting he eutred himself into the Kings Service, and was a <rs id="OA16850304-occupation-4" type="occupation">Soldier</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA16850304n15-1 OA16850304-occupation-4"/> in <placeName id="OA16850304-geo-6">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA16850304n15-1 OA16850304-geo-6"/>Tangier</placeName> for the Space of four Year: after that, he Lifted himself in the Queens Regiment, but meeting with ill Company, he was enticed out of that Imployment; and said it is not past three weeks or a</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA168503040003"/>
            <p>Month since he left that Service. He Acknowledged that he had been given to Intemporance, and had often taken God&#8217;s Name in Vain, yet he Prayed to God sometimes to keep him from Evil Courses. It repented him that he left the former Imployment of a Soldier, saying that was the occasion though Idleness of exposing him to be Tempted to Rob on the Highway. He also particularly confess&#8217;d the Crime he stands Condemned for. He much Lamented his illspent Life, and gave the ordinary very Hopeful signs of the Truth of his Contrition, earnestly desiring him to pray for him, and promised to be very Compliant with his Directions, in order to Eternal Life.</p>
            <p>
               <persName id="OA16850304n17-1">
                  <interp inst="OA16850304n17-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16850304n17-1" type="surname" value="MULLINS"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16850304n17-1" type="given" value="WILLIAM"/>William Mullins</persName>, was Born in <placeName id="OA16850304-geo-7">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA16850304n17-1 OA16850304-geo-7"/>London</placeName>, of Godly and Religious Parents; he was well instructed and Educated by them and thereupon Acknowledged his Sins to have been the Greater and more Aggravated because be had Sinned against much Light and Knowledge: for he said Where much is Given, there also is much Required. He Confess'd furthermore that he had been a great Neglecter of God&#8217;s Worship and Service on the Lord s Day; a frequenter of and associate of ill Company; and for that he had omitted a due Attendance on those two great means of Grace and Salvation, Prayer and Preaching, he judg'd it was for that God had left him to himself, and suffered him to become Guilty of so great a Sin as that he was Condemned for. And being urg&#8217;d to a more Particular Confession of his Crimes, he said they had been so sundry and so many, that he could not enumerate them: but as for the particular sinful Fact for which he was now to Dye, he owned he was guilty of it; yet withal added that 'twas the first Felony he was ever engaged in. He Reproved one of his fellow Condemned Criminals for the lightness of his Spirit, in smiling when press'd to a free Ingenuous confession of his Offences, and said, I am afraid he has little sense of his Sins; 'tis hope of a Reprieve which makes him less Serious, but persons do ill who give him those Hopes, for it may make him backward in the works of his Conversation: and were he fit to Dye, he were the siter to Live, He said he acknowledged the Justice of a Righteous God, in bring in him to this his deserved Capital Punishment, and that he little mattered Temporal Death, so that he had Comfortable Expectations, that would prove, unto him an entrance into Eternal Life: and added moreover that he was now equally desirous of Inward Sanctification and Holiness, as of endless Glory and Happiness.</p>
            <p>In short, he shewed great outward signs of a True and Internal change of Heart, and Godly sincere Sorrow for his manifold Transgressions; hoping for the forgivenes and remission of the guilt of is them, in and through the alone Merits and satisfaction of his Crucified Saviour.</p>
            <p>
               <persName id="OA16850304n19-1">
                  <interp inst="OA16850304n19-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16850304n19-1" type="surname" value="COATES"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16850304n19-1" type="given" value="JOSEPH"/>Joseph Coates</persName>, was Born in <placeName id="OA16850304-geo-8">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA16850304n19-1 OA16850304-geo-8"/>York-shire</placeName>, he is now 31 Years of Age; he was educated at <placeName id="OA16850304-geo-9">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA16850304n19-1 OA16850304-geo-9"/>York</placeName>, and <placeName id="OA16850304-geo-10">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA16850304n19-1 OA16850304-geo-10"/>Tadcastle</placeName>, as himself called it, where he went to School:afterward he lived in the Service of Squire Thyn for the space of six years; after that, he went with the Lord Orory into <placeName id="OA16850304-geo-11">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA16850304n19-1 OA16850304-geo-11"/>Ireland</placeName>, and stayed with him only half a Year: after that he served the late Earl of Essex, as his <rs id="OA16850304-occupation-5" type="occupation">Footman</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA16850304n19-1 OA16850304-occupation-5"/>, in Ireland: afterward he came into England and Served, Col. Fitz, Patrick, but left his Imployment Under him. Two Years last past he Was an <rs id="OA16850304-occupation-6" type="occupation">Horse-Course</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA16850304n19-1 OA16850304-occupation-6"/>; after he laid down that way of Livelyhoods he intended to go into Staffordshire for Imployment, but altering his purpose, he fell into bad Company, upon neglecting the Service of God, soon after he grew very Wicked, was given to Excessive Drinking and Swearing; at last he was acquainted with three Men, who Tempted him into the Burglary, for which he stands Condemned, but expressed not their Names to the Ordinary. Being asked what hopes he had of a future Happy State, he replied that he had been a great Sinner, but now his Heart was through God's Mercy made to Relent, more for his Wicked Practices than for the fear of Death, and he hoped</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA168503040004"/>
            <p>if he might be spared, that he should become a new Man: of which he gave at present very probable Signs.</p>
            <p>
               <persName id="OA16850304n21-1">
                  <interp inst="OA16850304n21-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16850304n21-1" type="surname" value="HARRISON"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16850304n21-1" type="given" value="RALPH"/>Ralph Harrison</persName>, he was Born in <placeName id="OA16850304-geo-12">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA16850304n21-1 OA16850304-geo-12"/>Shoreditch Parish</placeName>, being now about 20 Years of Age. He was placed an <rs id="OA16850304-occupation-7" type="occupation">Apprentice to a Broad-Weaver</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA16850304n21-1 OA16850304-occupation-7"/>, with whom he tarried two Years, and then Run away from his Master: he said that for two Years past he had been enticed into Bad Company, who brought him into the acquaintance of Lewd Woman, which was the cause of his breaking the Sabbath; and by that means gave himself over to all manner of Exceess; as Drunkenness, Swearing, &amp;c. But if he might escape for this time, he would go to Sea to avoid such evil Courses.</p>
            <p>
               <persName id="OA16850304n22-1">
                  <interp inst="OA16850304n22-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16850304n22-1" type="surname" value="LIST"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16850304n22-1" type="given" value="HENRY"/>Henry List</persName>, was Born in <placeName id="OA16850304-geo-13">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA16850304n22-1 OA16850304-geo-13"/>Stepney Parish</placeName>, being now 19 or 20 Years of Age, he said that he was not educated upto Knowledge, and therefore could not so fully express himself in Religious Matters, he served a <rs id="OA16850304-occupation-8" type="occupation">Weaver</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA16850304n22-1 OA16850304-occupation-8"/> for some time, who gave him the residue of it, in which he was Bound to him: that his own Father being Dead, his Mother and Father in Law, gave him all the good Counsel they could, but he would not be ruled by them; for which, he said, God had justly brought upon him this Punnishment; which if he should Escape, he would amend those Evil course of Life: he farther said that he was not acquainted with Harrison till after the Burglary committed by him.</p>
            <p>The next Person whom the Ordinary Visited as well in his Chamber, as exhorted and Prayed with him among the other Criminals, was <rs id="OA16850304-occupation-9" type="occupation">Cap.</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA16850304n23-1 OA16850304-occupation-9"/> 
               <persName id="OA16850304n23-1">
                  <interp inst="OA16850304n23-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16850304n23-1" type="surname" value="BAKER"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16850304n23-1" type="given" value="GEORGE"/>George Baker</persName>, who did not make so large a Confession as the forementioned Criminals: yet this he acknowledged that he was Born of creditable Parents, who were of a plentiful Estate, and brought him up not to any Employment, only he lived a Life of Ease as a <rs id="OA16850304-occupation-10" type="occupation">Gentleman</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA16850304n23-1 OA16850304-occupation-10"/>, which was his Misery, especially his Parents declining afterward in their Estate: so being reduced to Straits for a Livelyhood he served formerly as a <rs id="OA16850304-occupation-11" type="occupation">Voluntier</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA16850304n23-1 OA16850304-occupation-11"/> beyond Sea, and so signalized his Valour, that meeting with six French, who Confronted him riding toward Nancy, he Killed one of them, and put the rest to Flight. The Ordinary asked him how long he had beset Travelors in England; he did not state the set time, but said, he had used that course of Livelyhood for some time, yet he never Murthered any Person: the Ordinary replied that he was more oblieged to thank God for his preventing him in such an horrid Act, than to impute it to any thing else. There was some Discourse used with him to convince him of the Heinous Crime of Robbery; tho it were occasioned out pf Poverty even therein; a Person Assaulting another must first offer Violence to his own Conscience, and the Laws of humane Society: but it is an Aggravation to Rob out of Wantonness of Spirit, to furnish with Materials to indulge themselves in Luxury, and to follow the chase of Robbing as a Trade or accustomary Delight. He said he repented of his evil Life, but he had confess&#8217;d his particular Sins to God, and, hoped, had made his Peace with him, through the satisfaction of Chirst&#8217;s Death: yet he said that he feared not Death, for he was assured of Eternal Life. The Ordinary replied the Hearts of Men are apt to Deceive themselves, and therefore the surest way would be to mistrust his own Heart in such Assurances, in as much as he could never enough repent him of his Sins.</p>
            <p>The next Person that confess&#8217;d to the Ordinary, was <persName id="OA16850304n24-1">
                  <interp inst="OA16850304n24-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16850304n24-1" type="surname" value="Fallowfield"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16850304n24-1" type="given" value="Tho"/>Tho. Fallowfield</persName>, who Murthered a Young Maid: fee the ground of his Malice in his Trial. The Ordinary would have taken him apart to have made him sensible, but the Crime is very Soul hardning; and so it proved with him; for the refused to give any account of his former course of Life; and tho Exhorted to Repent, shewed little or no signs thereof; so he must be left to the Tribunal of God, to pass his deteminate Judgment upon him.</p>
            <p>About 9 or 10 of the Clock in the Morning Thomas Fallowfeild, was put into the Cart at <placeName id="OA16850304-geo-14">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA16850304n24-1 OA16850304-geo-14"/>Newgate</placeName>, he seemed very Penitent all the way he went to <placeName id="OA16850304-geo-15">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA16850304n24-1 OA16850304-geo-15"/>Leicesterfeilds</placeName>, where the Ordianry Prayed with him and Sung a Psalm, after which he was Executed, the rest of the Prisoners where put into the Cart about 10 or 11 of the Clock, they all seemed very Penitent all the way they went; when they came to Tybuen Mr. Ordinary Prayed with them and Sung a Psalm, after which, they Exhorted the standers by to take warning by their Disman Ends of the Effects of Sin; which had brought them to that Place. And they all Prayed earnestly to God that he would forgive them their Sins, and desired the People to Pray for them, after which they were all Executed.</p>
            <p>Dated the 4th. day of March, 1685. <persName id="OA16850304n26-1">
                  <interp inst="OA16850304n26-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16850304n26-1" type="surname" value="SMITH"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16850304n26-1" type="given" value="SAMUEL"/>Samuel Smith</persName>, <rs id="OA16850304-occupation-12" type="occupation">Ordinary</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA16850304n26-1 OA16850304-occupation-12"/>.</p>
            <p>
               <placeName id="OA16850304-geo-16">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA16850304n27-1 OA16850304-geo-16"/>LONDON</placeName>,Printed by <persName id="OA16850304n27-1">
                  <interp inst="OA16850304n27-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16850304n27-1" type="surname" value="CROOM"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16850304n27-1" type="given" value="GEORGE"/>George Croom</persName>, at the <placeName id="OA16850304-geo-17">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA16850304n27-1 OA16850304-geo-17"/>Sign of the Blue-Ball</placeName> in <placeName id="OA16850304-geo-18">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA16850304n27-1 OA16850304-geo-18"/>Thames-Street</placeName>, over against <placeName id="OA16850304-geo-19">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA16850304n27-1 OA16850304-geo-19"/>Baynard's-Castle</placeName>. 1684.</p>
         </div0>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>