<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<TEI.2>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div0 type="ordinarysAccount" id="OA16930308">
            <interp inst="OA16930308" type="uri" value="ordinarysAccounts/OA16930308"/>
            <interp inst="OA16930308" type="date" value="16930308"/>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA169303080001"/>
            <p>A True ACCOUNT of the BEHAVIOUR, CONFESSION, AND Last Dying SPEECHES Of the Criminals that were Executed at TYBURN, On Wednesday the 8th, of March, 1693.</p>
            <p>ON the Lord's-Day, in the Forenoon the Ordinary preacht on the 16th. Verse of the 24tb. Chapter of the Acts of the Apostles, viz. And herein, I exercise my self, to keep always a Conscience void of offence toward God and Men. From which Words, The Doctrinal Observation was, that it is the Duty and Priviledge of every True Christian, to get aud retain the Integrity of Conscience. For the Explicating of this Four General Heads were inquired into, and Stated.</p>
            <p>First, What is Conscience? It is a Mans Judgment of his Souls Estate and Actions, as these are subjected to the Judgment of God in his Revealed Will. The Lord hath placed Conscience in all Men to approve of what is Right with Complacency, and to disallow what is Evil with Grief, Shame, and Abhorrence. It is a Spy and Register in the Bosom of Ungodly Men, that they cannot Sin, in quiet. Conscience makes a Judgment and Determination. How we have observed the Rule of God's Sacred Law, or swered from it, accordingly, it Acquits and Comforts; or, Condems and Terrifies.</p>
            <p>Secondly, What is essentially necessary to constitute your Conscience Morally Good and Comfortable. First, It must be cleansed and sanctified by Renewing Grace, that it may be conformable in all Things to the Law of God. Secondly, Because its exactest Obedience is defective, therefore it must be spingled with the Propiatory Merits of Christ's Bloodshed. Thirdly, From the Virtue of Christ's death, there must be exprest, the lively Fruits of an Holy Conversation, with a constant Reliance on Christ's Intercession to preserve the Integrity of Conscience, under the Violence of all Temptation to Sin, and to support its Comfort, under the deepest Tryals of Affliction.</p>
            <p>Thirdly, What Influence doth the Practical believe of the Judgment Day.</p>
            <p>What doth the Exercise which preserves a Good Conscience include? It signifies, to be train'd up, under the Discipline of Christianity, so as to be confirm'd in an Holy Conversation against all Contempt and Opposition. So dare be openly Good and Strict in the Practice of all Christian Virtues, when the present Age is most degenerate. It is to make True Religigion our Recreation, and to promote its Aymiableness, in the Uniformity of our Obedience. Righteousness toward Men, Severe from Piety toward God, is veiled Athism; and Holy Exercises toward Him, with the neglect of Relative Duties toward men is demure and glittering Hypocrisie. Therefore the Charitable Testimony of others, cannot comfort the Conscience, under its presumptive Groundles Hopes, concerning its Renewed State. This is Infallibly known to God, altho' Conscience may make a false Report, by Self-flattery, and the Sinners deep Security. Therefore, let us Summon our Hearts, to a strict Account, what preparative Dispositions are formed in us, which may present us before Christ's Tribunal, with Approbation. Bu such, who carry their unpardoned Guilt and unrenewed Nature, to the Judgment Seat of Christ, shall have Convulsive pangs of desperation in their Conscience, and shall be rejected by Christ, with the Greatest Abhorrency. After several Rules and Directions, how to get and preserve a Good Conscience, The Conclusion was thus directed to the Condemned Criminals. How may St. Paul's Example in the Text, reflect a sad Aspect on your Consciences. These you have defiled, by prostituting them to the Infamous Lusts of your Fleshly Minds. Have you not striven to rase out the Dictates and Sentiments of common Equity? when your Convictions have been troublesome, you have flattered Conscience, with Carnal Reasonings. How have you deafed it to Divine Instructions. By Wordly Diversions, and have drowned the Cries thereof in sensual Pleasures, and thereby, brought the sly Artifices of Sining, unto a destructive Maturity. You have sinned in despight of all Admonitions, and the Examples of Publick Justice. Notwithstanding, when your Consciences shall be arm'd with God's Commission, they will be active to Condemn you, though cast at present, into a Lethargy of Stupidity. You cannot deny, that you have tbeen great Sinners, yet, there is pardoning Mercy to be obained, by that Satisfaction Christ's death hath made to God's offended Justice. This applied by Faith unfeigned, purifies the Heart in Obedience to all Divine Commands. This Renewed Frame, by sprinkling the Merits of Christ's Bloodshed on the Conscience, turns his Tribunal of Strict Justice, into a Throne of Grace and Mercy. So shall we (at last) be presented to God the Father, not only void of Offence, but in a perfect State of Holiness to all Eternity.</p>
            <p>I proceed to give an Account of the Behaviour and Confessions of the Condemned Criminals.</p>
            <p>I. Mr. Best Condemned for High-Treason, in Clipping, Filing, and Diminishing the Current Coyn of England. He is Aged 50 Years. War Educated at School in <placeName id="OA16930308-geo-1">
                  <interp inst="OA16930308-geo-1" type="type" value="county"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA16930308n18-1 OA16930308-geo-1"/>Hertfordshire</placeName>. His Father sent him to in <placeName id="OA16930308-geo-2">
                  <interp inst="OA16930308-geo-2" type="type" value="site"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA16930308n18-1 OA16930308-geo-2"/>Cambridge</placeName>, where, he continued his Studies, till he took the <rs id="OA16930308-occupation-1" type="occupation">Degree of Bachelor in Physick</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA16930308n18-1 OA16930308-occupation-1"/>. Afterwards, he <rs id="OA16930308-occupation-2" type="occupation">practised in that Science</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA16930308n18-1 OA16930308-occupation-2"/>, and might have lived comfortably upon it. But by Degrees, he neglected to follow his Profession; and was drawn into Bad Company, of which he now Repents. He denied not, that he had been a great Sinner. I enquired into the Particulars of his Evil Conversation, it being a necessary Duty, to unburthen the Conscience of a Load of Sin, by a free discovery, of it, that so, Secenity of Mind, may be obtained. Besides, there is great difference betwixt Person lying on a sick Bed whose Sins are more secreet, and who may recover to a longer Space of Repentance. Such, are not so strictly obliged, to confess their particular Enormities. But for those, who by Notorious Crimes have given Publick Scandal to the Christian Religion, and brought themselves under the Sentence of Death; such onght to make Publick Acknowledgment of their Excesses in Sinning, that their Repentance may be as Exemplary, as their Conversation hath been Vicious upon this, Mr. Best, was better convinced of his Duty. And freely confest, that he had been Guilty of most Sins, Murther only excepted. Saying withal, that he doubted not the Truth of his Repentance, and that God was reconciled to him, in Christ. I replied, that the Heart of Man is very deceitful in Judging its Spiritual State Godward, especially when Persons have con</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA169303080002"/>
            <p>tracted a Custom in Sinning, and thereby hardned their Hearts, to persist therein. To this he replied, that Naturally Man's Heart is inclined to Self-flattery, but he hoped, the Spirit of God had so sanctified this distress, that his Heart was thoroughly broken for and from the Love of all Sin, chiefly, as an offence against God, who might have justly cut him off, by an untimely death, for his younger Excesses in Sinning. But, said he, I would not be Reclamed, by a more gentle Rod; therefore God now compells me, by greater Severity, to turn to him, and Blessed is the Man, whom the Reproachful stroke of Death, makes (tho' late) a Partaker of God's Holiness. I replied, that I was glad, he was convinced of his sinful State, and in some Preparation, to apply the Promises of Salvation. But, it is safest, to be poor in Spirit, and thereby, to Magnifie the All-sufficiency of God's Grace. He replied, that he endeavoured to be Self abas'd in as much, as the Omniscient, Heart-searching God, would not be Mockt, and could not be deceived with semblant Flourishes in Soul-Concernments.</p>
            <p>II. <persName id="OA16930308n11-1">
                  <interp inst="OA16930308n11-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16930308n11-1" type="surname" value="STEWARD"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16930308n11-1" type="given" value="JAMES"/>James Steward</persName>. Condemned for Breaking the House of <persName id="OA16930308n11-2">
                  <interp inst="OA16930308n11-2" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16930308n11-2" type="surname" value="THORNE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16930308n11-2" type="given" value="ELIZABETH"/>Elizabeth Thorne</persName>. He is Aged 24 Years, or thereabout. His Father placed him forth, to the Employment of a <rs id="OA16930308-occupation-3" type="occupation">Chyrugeon</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA16930308n11-1 OA16930308-occupation-3"/>. He said, that his Father was of the <rs id="OA16930308-occupation-4" type="occupation">Roman Religion</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA16930308n11-1 OA16930308-occupation-4"/>, and bred him up, in it, so that he knew not well how to quit it. I replied, that we are not obliged to live and de, in the Religion of our Parents, not grounded on the Purity of God's Word. And endeavoured to convince him of the Hazard and Danger, in Adhearing to False Principles in Religion, in as much, as these have Influence on an Immortal Conversation. He replied, that he had so much Knowledge, as not to believe the gross Errors of the Romish Church. He also said, that be could not have wanted this Severe. Yet, Just Dealing of God with him in as much, that now he is thoroughly awakend from his Security, and Hopes, that God will turn this distress, into a means of his Conversion; and then, he shall not be troubled for his Reproachful Death. I Stated to him, the Nature and Effects of True Saving Faith and Godly Sorrow for Sin: To which he was attentive and seemed to comply with my Advice, that he might be prepared for Death. He said, that if he had followed his Wives Good Counsel to have been content with an Honest Employment, he had not fallen into this Shameful and Untimely End.</p>
            <p>III. <persName id="OA16930308n12-1">
                  <interp inst="OA16930308n12-1" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16930308n12-1" type="surname" value="Wann"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16930308n12-1" type="given" value="Elizabeth"/>Elizabeth Wann</persName>, Condemned for Robbing <persName id="OA16930308n12-2">
                  <interp inst="OA16930308n12-2" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16930308n12-2" type="surname" value="Coguer"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16930308n12-2" type="given" value="Frances"/>Frances Coguer</persName> of a Gold-Chain, Value 8 l. being stopt, the Neck-Lace was found in her Mouth. She is Aged 16 Years. Had Good Education, but was Disobedient to her Mother. Whereupon she left her Family, and entered her self a <rs id="OA16930308-occupation-5" type="occupation">Servant</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA16930308n12-1 OA16930308-occupation-5"/> in <placeName id="OA16930308-geo-3">
                  <interp inst="OA16930308-geo-3" type="type" value="urban_centre"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA16930308n12-1 OA16930308-geo-3"/>London</placeName> with a Mistress, who employ'd her, most what in Needle-work; but she soon left that Service. Then she grew idle and kept bad Company. She confest, that not Poverty, but only her wicked Heart, inclined her to commit the Crime she did not observe the Sabboth days of later time, and when she did pray, (which was seldom) she performed that Holy Part of Worship, very carelesly. She denied not that she had been a Great Sinner, but being Reprieved, as with Child she promised, that she would not absent her self from the Publick Worship of God, but would endeavour, to beg of Him, firrm Resolutions of Amendment.</p>
            <p>IV. <persName id="OA16930308n13-1">
                  <interp inst="OA16930308n13-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16930308n13-1" type="surname" value="Shammel"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16930308n13-1" type="given" value="David"/>David Shammel</persName>, Condemn'd for Felony. He is Aged 33 Years. He said, that he was bred up, to <rs id="OA16930308-occupation-6" type="occupation">Husbandry</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA16930308n13-1 OA16930308-occupation-6"/>, and continued that Employment for some length of time, but leaving it, and betaking himself to an Idle Life, he became Poor, and so adventur'd to commit this Felony. He was willing to make an Acknowledgment of his Evil Life. and in particular accused himself of Sabboth-breaking, neglecting to pray that God would keep him, from the wicked incliantions of his own Heart, and the Mischiefs of bad Company. He wept, yet complained of the Hardness of his Heart. Saying, he prayed earnestly, that God would make it thoroughly Contrite, that upon the Change of it, and being made Holy, he might be in a fit Frame to die.</p>
            <p>V. <persName id="OA16930308n14-1">
                  <interp inst="OA16930308n14-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16930308n14-1" type="surname" value="NOBLE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16930308n14-1" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Noble</persName>, Condemn'd for Felony and Burglary in Breaking the House of <persName id="OA16930308n14-2">
                  <interp inst="OA16930308n14-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16930308n14-2" type="surname" value="COOK"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16930308n14-2" type="given" value="WILLIAM"/>William Cook</persName> together with others, not yet taken. He is Aged 53 Years. He said, that he had used the Employment of a <rs id="OA16930308-occupation-7" type="occupation">Seaman</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA16930308n14-1 OA16930308-occupation-7"/> for 38 Years. That he had been <rs id="OA16930308-occupation-8" type="occupation">Master of a Ship</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA16930308n14-1 OA16930308-occupation-8"/>, some time since, but of late, he serves King William in the Fleet. That he had escaped many Perils at Sea. That in great Distresses, he made several Vows to God, that is he would preserve him, his Life should be Reformed. But he forgot the sparing Mercies of the Lord, and return to his former Evil Course of Life, which is now, a greater Trouble to his Mind. He said, that God was Righteous in bringing him to Shame and Punishment: But he prays, that this may work upon his Heart, to make him thorouhgly sensible of all his Sins, that the Lord may Pardon them and in Mercy, save his Soul, when he shall undergo the Pains of Death. I hope he was Penitent.</p>
            <p>VI. <persName id="OA16930308n15-1">
                  <interp inst="OA16930308n15-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16930308n15-1" type="surname" value="Mackqueere"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16930308n15-1" type="given" value="Philip"/>Philip Mackqueere</persName>, Condemned for Robbing <persName id="OA16930308n15-2">
                  <interp inst="OA16930308n15-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16930308n15-2" type="surname" value="Lacey"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16930308n15-2" type="given" value="John"/>John Lacey</persName> 
               <rs id="OA16930308-occupation-9" type="occupation">Esq</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA16930308n15-2 OA16930308-occupation-9"/>; in the High-way. He is Aged 28 Years. Was born in <placeName id="OA16930308-geo-4">
                  <interp inst="OA16930308-geo-4" type="type" value="region"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA16930308n15-1 OA16930308-geo-4"/>Ireland</placeName> of <rs id="OA16930308-occupation-10" type="occupation">Protestant</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA16930308n15-1 OA16930308-occupation-10"/> Parents. They educated him with Religious Instruction, but he now grieves, that it made not that Impression on him, which they expected. For, he was not obedient to them, as he ought. Upon that, he left them to Travel into <placeName id="OA16930308-geo-5">
                  <interp inst="OA16930308-geo-5" type="type" value="region"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA16930308n15-1 OA16930308-geo-5"/>Spain</placeName> and <placeName id="OA16930308-geo-6">
                  <interp inst="OA16930308-geo-6" type="type" value="region"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA16930308n15-1 OA16930308-geo-6"/>Portugal</placeName>, after that, into the <placeName id="OA16930308-geo-7">
                  <interp inst="OA16930308-geo-7" type="type" value="region"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA16930308n15-1 OA16930308-geo-7"/>West-Indies</placeName> when he returned into England.</p>
            <p>He entr'd into <rs id="OA16930308-occupation-11" type="occupation">Sea-service</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA16930308n15-1 OA16930308-occupation-11"/>, under King Charles the II. He said, that he was entertain'd in a large Ship of War last Summer, and was Engaged in a Sea-Fight: But he left that Employment, and thereupon, joyning with bad Company, fell into many Excesses in Sinning. He said, it Repents him, that he did not take Warning by former escaping the Sentence of Death. But since his last Confinement, he hath endeavour'd to get his Heart made sensible of all his sins, which now lie as an heavy Burden on him. He was attantive to the Exhortations given him, to prepare for Death. He promised that he would endeavour to the utmost, by God's Assistance, to improve his Time, for the getting his Heart into a more penitent Frame, that he may make his Peace with God, and be fit for his Appearance at Christ's Judgment Seat</p>
            <p>On Wednesday the 8th. of March these Five Prisoners were convey'd to <placeName id="OA16930308-geo-8">
                  <interp inst="OA16930308-geo-8" type="type" value="site"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA16930308n18-1 n18-2 n18-3 n18-99 n18-4 OA16930308-geo-8"/>Tyburn</placeName>, viz.</p>
            <p>
               <persName id="OA16930308n18-1">
                  <interp inst="OA16930308n18-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16930308n18-1" type="surname" value="BEST"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16930308n18-1" type="given" value="JOSIAS"/>Josias Best</persName> (who was drawne in a Sledge) <persName id="OA16930308n18-2">
                  <interp inst="OA16930308n18-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16930308n18-2" type="surname" value="MACKGUIRE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16930308n18-2" type="given" value="PHILLIP"/>Phillip Mackguire</persName>, <persName id="OA16930308n18-3">
                  <interp inst="OA16930308n18-3" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16930308n18-3" type="surname" value="STEWARD"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16930308n18-3" type="given" value="JAMES"/>James Steward</persName>, <persName id="OA16930308n18-99">
                  <interp inst="OA16930308n18-99" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16930308n18-99" type="surname" value="Shammell"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16930308n18-99" type="given" value="David"/>David Shammell</persName>, and <persName id="OA16930308n18-4">
                  <interp inst="OA16930308n18-4" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16930308n18-4" type="surname" value="NOBLE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16930308n18-4" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Noble</persName>. Mr. Best Confest that he had been Educated at the <placeName id="OA16930308-geo-9">
                  <interp inst="OA16930308-geo-9" type="type" value="site"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA16930308n18-1 OA16930308-geo-9"/>University of Cambridge</placeName>, and there took the <rs id="OA16930308-occupation-12" type="occupation">Degree of Batchelour in Physick</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA16930308n18-1 OA16930308-occupation-12"/>; though now he had unworthily declined his profession; which was a great trouble to him, he desires the Ordinary to come to him in the Sledge, which he did, where he told him that he had great hopes of Salvation through the Merits of Christ, and that he was very willing to Dye, though he had sometimes some doubts and jealousies upon him as to his Eternal welfare: Yet now he was Composed, and so did continue to the last, in an humble Frame, after a Devot manner; Joyning in Prayer, and Pray'd to Almighty God in a very sensible manner with Contrition; acknowledgeing that God was Jnst and Righteouss.</p>
            <p>
               <persName id="OA16930308n19-1">
                  <interp inst="OA16930308n19-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16930308n19-1" type="surname" value="Shammell"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16930308n19-1" type="given" value="David"/>David Shammell</persName>, was very Ignorant as to to the concerns of his Soul, but was willing to hearken to Instructions; desiring all he Spectators to take warning by his untimely end, and particularly to beware of Whoredom, evil Company, and breach of the Sabbath.</p>
            <p>
               <persName id="OA16930308n20-1">
                  <interp inst="OA16930308n20-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16930308n20-1" type="surname" value="STEWARD"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16930308n20-1" type="given" value="JAMES"/>James Steward</persName>, and <persName id="OA16930308n20-2">
                  <interp inst="OA16930308n20-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16930308n20-2" type="surname" value="MACKGUIRE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16930308n20-2" type="given" value="PHILLIP"/>Phillip Mackguire</persName>, Declared that they Dyed in the <rs id="OA16930308-occupation-13" type="occupation">Roman Catholick Religion</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA16930308n20-1 n20-2 OA16930308-occupation-13"/>, (tho') when they were in <placeName id="OA16930308-geo-10">
                  <interp inst="OA16930308-geo-10" type="type" value="site"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA16930308n20-1 n20-1 OA16930308-geo-10"/>
                  <placeName id="OA16930308-geo-11">
                     <interp inst="OA16930308-geo-11" type="type" value="site"/>
                     <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                           targets="OA16930308n20-1 n20-2 OA16930308-geo-11"/>Newgate,</placeName> they always came to the Chappel</placeName>. Steward at last spake to this effect; Gentlemen, I am but a young Man, and by my sins, I have brought my Body to be Exposed before you, but I hope God will have Mercy upon my soul: I desire that all young Persons would take Example by me, that they may not be Disobedient to their Parents; I run from mine, and would not be ruled by them, they Indulged me and gave me Money, which spoiled me, I had good Edication, and might have lived honestly, but Pride and Lastness hath brought me to this shameful End, and now God is just; I spake this that all Parents may take heed, and breed their Children well; and in the fear of God, and that all men may be warned by my fatal End.</p>
            <p>Mackguire said but little, only desired all Men to take timely Warning by him; acknowledging that God had justly brought him to such severe Punishment.</p>
            <p>
               <persName id="OA16930308n22-1">
                  <interp inst="OA16930308n22-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16930308n22-1" type="surname" value="NOBLE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16930308n22-1" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Noble</persName>, behaved himself a little unseemly, being very unsensible, of his latter End; would not be perswaded to hear good Counsel, he seemed to be disturbed in his Brain.</p>
            <p>This is all the Account I can give of this Sessions.</p>
            <p>
               <persName id="OA16930308n24-1">
                  <interp inst="OA16930308n24-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16930308n24-1" type="surname" value="SMITH"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16930308n24-1" type="given" value="SAMUEL"/>Samuel Smith</persName>, <rs id="OA16930308-occupation-14" type="occupation">Ordinary</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA16930308n24-1 OA16930308-occupation-14"/>.</p>
            <p>Dated the 8th. March, 1693.</p>
            <p>ADVIRTISMENT.</p>
            <p>THere is lately Published a Book Entituled, Conversation in Heaven: Being Devotions consisting of Meditations and Prayers on several considerable Subjects in Practical Divinity; Written for the raising the Decay'd Spirit of Piety; very proper to be Read in the time of Lent: <persName id="OA16930308n27-1">
                  <interp inst="OA16930308n27-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16930308n27-1" type="surname" value="SMITH"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16930308n27-1" type="given" value="LAWRENCE"/>By Lawrence Smith</persName>, LL. D. <rs id="OA16930308-occupation-15" type="occupation">Fellow of St. John's College</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA16930308n27-1 OA16930308-occupation-15"/> in <placeName id="OA16930308-geo-12">
                  <interp inst="OA16930308-geo-12" type="type" value="site"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA16930308n27-1 OA16930308-geo-12"/>Oxford</placeName>. Price Two Shillings.</p>
            <p>Printed for <persName id="OA16930308n28-1">
                  <interp inst="OA16930308n28-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16930308n28-1" type="surname" value="Speed"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16930308n28-1" type="given" value="Tho"/>Tho. Speed</persName>, at the <placeName id="OA16930308-geo-13">
                  <interp inst="OA16930308-geo-13" type="type" value="site"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA16930308n28-1 OA16930308-geo-13"/>
                  <placeName id="OA16930308-geo-14">
                     <interp inst="OA16930308-geo-14" type="type" value="site"/>
                     <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                           targets="OA16930308n28-1 OA16930308-geo-14"/>
                     <placeName id="OA16930308-geo-15">
                        <interp inst="OA16930308-geo-15" type="type" value="street"/>
                        <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                              targets="OA16930308n28-1 OA16930308-geo-15"/>Three Crowns</placeName> near the Royal Exchange</placeName> in Cornhill</placeName>.</p>
            <p>WHereas a Picture was lost some time since being the Representation of <placeName id="OA16930308-geo-16">
                  <interp inst="OA16930308-geo-16" type="type" value="urban_centre"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA16930308n29-1 OA16930308-geo-16"/>Flushing</placeName>, one of the Provinces, or a Town in Holland, with a Sea incompassing it; a Packet-boat under Sail, a large Ship under Sail: and a little above the Ship it was torn about eight Inches, and but corsely swen up. At the Bottom, near the Frame, there is a yellow Streak, whereon was inscribed Ulisingen: It had a gilt Frame, and fit for a large Chimney-Piece Whoever gives Notice of it to <persName id="OA16930308n29-1">
                  <interp inst="OA16930308n29-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16930308n29-1" type="surname" value="Paige"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16930308n29-1" type="given" value="Edward"/>Edward Paige</persName>, <rs id="OA16930308-occupation-16" type="occupation">Surgeon</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA16930308n29-1 OA16930308-occupation-16"/>, in <placeName id="OA16930308-geo-17">
                  <interp inst="OA16930308-geo-17" type="type" value="street"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA16930308n29-1 OA16930308-geo-17"/>
                  <placeName id="OA16930308-geo-18">
                     <interp inst="OA16930308-geo-18" type="type" value="site"/>
                     <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                           targets="OA16930308n29-1 OA16930308-geo-18"/>Goat-Court</placeName> upon Ludgate-Hill</placeName>, shall be rewarded, and if bought their Money returned, and gratified for their Trouble.</p>
            <p>LONDON, Printed for L. Curtis, at Sir Edmundbury-Godfrey's-Head, near Fleet-Bridge, 1693.</p>
         </div0>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>