<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<TEI.2>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div0 type="ordinarysAccount" id="OA16790307">
            <interp inst="OA16790307" type="uri" value="ordinarysAccounts/OA16790307"/>
            <interp inst="OA16790307" type="date" value="16790307"/>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA167903070001"/>
            <p>THE Behaviour, last Speeches, Confessions, AND EXECUTION Of the Prisoners that Suffered at <placeName id="OA16790307-geo-1">TYBURN</placeName> On Fryday the7th of March 1678/9</p>
            <p>VIZ.</p>
            <p>
               <persName id="OA16790307n3-1">
                  <interp inst="OA16790307n3-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16790307n3-1" type="surname" value="COXE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16790307n3-1" type="given" value="THOMAS"/>Thomas Coxe</persName>, and <persName id="OA16790307n3-2">
                  <interp inst="OA16790307n3-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16790307n3-2" type="surname" value="SMITH"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16790307n3-2" type="given" value="CHARLES"/>Charles Smith</persName>, Who were drawn thither on a Hurdle, for TREASON.</p>
            <p>
               <persName id="OA16790307n4-1">
                  <interp inst="OA16790307n4-1" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16790307n4-1" type="surname" value="Augur"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16790307n4-1" type="given" value="Mary"/>Mary Augur</persName>,For Murther.</p>
            <p>AND</p>
            <p>
               <persName id="OA16790307n6-1">
                  <interp inst="OA16790307n6-1" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16790307n6-1" type="surname" value="ATKINS"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16790307n6-1" type="given" value="ANNE"/>Anne Atkins</persName>, For a Burglary, her Husband being hang'd for the like Offence but the very last Sessions before.</p>
            <p>With a true Account of their Carriage, and Discourses to Mr. Ordinary and others, both in Prison and at the place of Execution.</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA167903070002"/>
            <p>The Behaviour, last Speeches, Confessions, and Execution of the Prisoners, that Suffered at <placeName id="OA16790307-geo-2">Tyburn</placeName> on Fryday the7th of March 1678/9</p>
            <p>AT the last Sessions there were in all Nine persons received sentence of Death; Three men and Six women. (Not Six men and Three women, as a false and surreptitious Pamphlet, printed with the Letters D.M. did lately mention; which also said, there was Fourteen to be Transported: and several other notorious Untruths almost in every Line.) Of these unhappy Criminals one was respited for the present from Execution, being found by a Jury of Matrons to be quick with Childe: three other women and one man, the nature of whose Offences and Conversation had rendred them fitter Objects of Royal Mercy, obtain'd the favour of his Majesties gratious Reprieve after Judgment.</p>
            <p>The other Four came now to suffer; their Names and Crimes being as follows.</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA167903070003"/>
            <p>
               <persName id="OA16790307n11-1">
                  <interp inst="OA16790307n11-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16790307n11-1" type="surname" value="COXE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16790307n11-1" type="given" value="THOMAS"/>Thomas Coxe</persName> and <persName id="OA16790307n11-2">
                  <interp inst="OA16790307n11-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16790307n11-2" type="surname" value="SMITH"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16790307n11-2" type="given" value="CHARLES"/>Charles Smith</persName>, each of them found guilty of Treason on several Indictments, both for Coyning and Counterfeiting, and also for Clipping of Money.</p>
            <p>
               <persName id="OA16790307n12-2">
                  <interp inst="OA16790307n12-2" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16790307n12-2" type="surname" value="Augur"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16790307n12-2" type="given" value="Mary"/>Mary Augur</persName>, for Murthering her Bastard Child; and <persName id="OA16790307n12-1">
                  <interp inst="OA16790307n12-1" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16790307n12-1" type="surname" value="ATKINS"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16790307n12-1" type="given" value="ANNE"/>Anne Atkins</persName>, for a Burglary, whose Husband, for the like Offence, was Executed, but the very last Sessions, and she then turn'd out of <placeName id="OA16790307-geo-3">Newgate</placeName> on the account of her Poverty, having several Children; but was no sooner at liberty, but she sell to her told wickedness; and 'tis believ'd seduc'd a person, now Condemn'd with her, but Reprieved, into this Burglary, for which she suffered. So difficult it is for people, when they are once come to make a Trade of sin, to forsake, it though they have the saddest and most near related Warnings in the world to reclaim them.</p>
            <p>Coxe, in the hearing of the Ordinary, prayed very pathetically for himself; and being askt concerning what hopes he had of a future happy Estate, he declared, That the fear of Death was much abated, and as he trusted on a sound and firm foundation, because his sorrow for sin was more for offending God, and grieving his Holy Spirit, than for the dread either of that momentary Punishment he was justly to suffer here, or even for the fear of Hell and wrath to come. Adding, that if he were to live, he resolv'd and hopes in God's strength that he should never run into such Extravagances as he had formerly been guilty of. For he did not onely freely acknowledge the Crime for which he was Condemned, but said, there was scarce any Immorality or Sin (except Murther) which in the debauch'd Course of his Life he had not stain'd and polluted his Soul with.</p>
            <p>The Ordinary urg'd, that his Coyning counterfeit Money, was not onely a great Crime against the Kings Majesty, but an abuse to the whole Nation, especially the poor, whose wants could not be supplyed if they offered such bad Money in buying; so that the ill influence and consequences of his sin in this kind, would survive when he was dead, and the fraud he had knowingly put upon others, must needs in the loss or deceit, circulate to the prejudice of many innocent people. He replyed, that for that very consideration, his penitent grief was so much the greater; and being told, that he could not repent sincerely, if he made not restitution to his power, to such whom he had defrauded, He professed he would do all he could possibly on that account. by making distribution as far as able to the poor, because he knew not whom he had wronged in particular, nor now to send to any such. He expressed much grief, that he had omitted to observe the Lords day, and that he went not to the publick Worship, as also, that he neglected to pray Morning and Evening, for which remisness, he conceived the Lord justly left him to the temptations of bad Company, and in particular to be acquaint-</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA167903070004"/>
            <p>ed with a person, who drew him to the crime of Coyning, which he closed with, on a lwed principle, not being content with an honest Trade, viz. a <rs id="OA16790307-occupation-1" type="occupation">Gun-smith</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA16790307n11-1 OA16790307-occupation-1"/>, which he well subsisted by, being a single Man, but made hast to snatch at unlawful gain, that he might be at higher expences to gratifie his Lusts, which he the rather acknowledged, that it might be a warning to all others.</p>
            <p>Smith, the other Coyner of false Money, was well educated, and it grieved him that he had not answered those good Instructions which his Parents gave him. He was put forth in <rs id="OA16790307-occupation-2" type="occupation">Apprentiship to a Chandler</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA16790307n11-2 OA16790307-occupation-2"/>, after he came to his own disposal, he lost the government of himself, for he profan'd the Lords day, which he said was occasioned by neglecting to repair to Gods publick Service, because he thought out of the pride of his heart, that his cloaths were not fine enough, so natural it is for one sin to beget another.</p>
            <p>He bewail'd himself as a great sinner, and in particular very much lamented the Crime for which he was Condemned, which he said he ingaged in, out of a covetous disposition, but made not so much gain by it as some others; and that he had a resolution to desist from that wicked practise, not because it answered not his expectation of profit, but rather for the regret and trouble which he had in his Conscience concerning proceeding in it. He said that bad acquaintance first inticed him into it, and that he was justly by God left to the temptation, since he had neglected daily to guard himself by Prayer. He wisht had took the meanest lawful imployments, rather than so hainously transgresed against the Kings Majesty, and the Law of the Nation. But the Lord he said was righteous, in discovering his Crime, because he had lived securely in committing other sins; for had he not been apprehended as he was, there was provided for him an honest and creditable imployment. But (said he) the Lord in just in cutting me off in the prime of my years, that I might not proceed in a course of Iniquity; and if his Divine Majesty shall be gratiously pleased to sanctifie this stroke of death on my body, to bring me thereby to Repentance, I shall not dread to drink of that bitter cup, as believing the Lord will order it to my eternal happiness.He praid for himself very well in the Ordinaries hearing, and being questioned what hopes he had of Salvation, and on what foundation the same were grounded, he made such judicious answers, in a distinct difference of true Faith and Repentance from the false, as the Ordinary was well satisfied with the same, and doth verily believe, that his endeavours with him were blessed, to bring him as a Convert to God.</p>
            <p>As for <persName id="OA16790307n18-1">
                  <interp inst="OA16790307n18-1" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16790307n18-1" type="surname" value="Augur"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16790307n18-1" type="given" value="Mary"/>Mary Augur</persName>, she was very weak in body, not able to come on the Lords day in the afternoon into the Chappel; but the Ordinary several times attended her in her Chamber, and gave her many serious Exhortations: but her condition</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA167903070005"/>
            <p>Etc. very much obstructed the good effects he hoped for from such his pains, so that we can give little farther account of her.</p>
            <p>The other Woman wept bitterly, and very often, and seemed to be penitent for her sins, not denying the Crime for which he suffered, but seemed to have been bred up in a loose course of life, and very ignorant of the Mysteries of Religion, but the Ordinary took considerable, pains to instruct her therein, and it is charitably hoped God might bless his endeavours towards her.</p>
         </div0>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>