<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<TEI.2>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div0 type="ordinarysAccount" id="OA16970915">
            <interp inst="OA16970915" type="uri" value="ordinarysAccounts/OA16970915"/>
            <interp inst="OA16970915" type="date" value="16970915"/>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA169709150001"/>
            <p>A True Account of the Behaviour, Confessions, and last Dying Speeches of the Condemned Criminals, that were Executed at Tyburn on Wednesday the 15th of this Instant Sep. 1697.</p>
            <p>On the Lords-Day, after the Condemnation of the Condemned Criminals, a Sermon was Preached on this Text,</p>
            <p>Reve. 2. 21. I gave her a Space for Repentance; yet she Repented not.</p>
            <p>In these Words are three Observations</p>
            <p>1. THE Lord gives the worst of Sinners a suffficient Time for Repentance. I gave her, even Jesabel who seduced others to commit Spiritual Fornication, in grose Idoaitry.</p>
            <p>2. The Lord doth not only afford a sufficient Time for Repentance, but adds many advantageous Opportunities, and the assistance of his Spirit to compleat it.</p>
            <p>3. To Sin against all the advantageous Encouragements, which might promote Repentance, by persisting in Impenitency, deeply aggrevates the Sinners Condemnation. The necessary Ingredients which constitute and compleat the nature of Repentance; without which it cannot be available to Salvation, in. 1st. A strict search into the frame of the Heart; to find out the mistery of Iniquity in our most secret and indulged Lusts. There must be a deep Humiliation for the universal Corruption of the Sinners nature, and the peculiar Sins of every Age of his Life. 2ly. An universal hatred of the least Sin, because it offends God, as contrary to his Holy Nature; and for Ingratitude against all the endearing Obligations of divine Mercies, which should soften the Sinners Heart; yet usually these extinguish all good resolutions rf Amendment, and the flood of Afflictions more inflame and irritate Men's Lusts.</p>
            <p>3ly. Sincere Repentance includes not only an universal forsaking every evil Way, but also a watchful Circumspection and fixt Resolution to avoid all the occasions of Sinning.</p>
            <p>4ly. A turning to God with the whole Heart, in the constant practice of all those Christian Duties which the Lord requires of us.</p>
            <p>The second Query.</p>
            <p>What are the fittest and most advantageous Opportunities, wherein to promote the work of Repentance?</p>
            <p>1st. Whilst clear and strong Convictions are imprest upon the Conscience, before these be stifled or made ineffectual by the Sinners Corrupting or bribing the sentiments of right Reason; yet many Sinners strive to wear out the Convictions of their Consciences, so that they do no execution on their Lusts.</p>
            <p>2ly. When the fond Love of the World is imbittered by sharp Afflictions, now turn the Stream of this Worldly sorrow into the Channel of Sincere Repentance: I affirm that a gracious Person prefers the sharpest and longest Afflictions Sanctify'd, in impressing the divine nature deeper on the Heart, than if the Lord should heap the confluence of worldly injoyments, which usually are abused to Pride, Wantonness, or Slothfulness in his Duty.</p>
            <p>3ly. When by an Eye of Faith we behold our Redeemer Crucify'd a fresh in the Sacrament of the Lord's Supper, as a memorial of his dying Love, to make Sin more bitter to us; now let thine Heart be contrite with Godly sorrow, and pour out the blood of every Lust at the foot of the Altar, as an acceptable Sacrifice to the mortifying Spirit of Christ.</p>
            <p>4ly. Comply with the Lord's design, when he sets out other Sinners as the Monuments and Examples of his severity: The Lord will take this very ill when he writes our Duty in the blood and Destruction of other Sinners Less peccant. and yet such who are spared, have no Impression of an Holy Ingenuity to learn Righteousness in the amendment of their Lives.</p>
            <p>5ly. When the Lord makes deep Wounds in thine own Conscience, do not presume to heal them by a few slight Formalities in Relenting, neither let the fountanel of Godly sorrow dry up, which should drain ou the malignant ors of thy defiled Heart.</p>
            <p>6ly. When thou undertakest any great Service for God, attended with difficulties and discouragements, now is a Time to renew Godly Sorrow, for offending a gracious Lord who puts an eminent Honour on thee, in that he will employ thee in his Service.</p>
            <p>Also when thou desirest success in entring upon any new state of Life, thou can'st not expect any blessing from God unless thou cleanse thy self from all filthiness of Flesh and Spirit, contracted before in any part of thy Conversation.</p>
            <p>7ly. When thou observest the wickedness of other Men, mourn by a sad Reflection on thine own corrupt Nature: This is alike if the Lord had not renewed it by his Regenerating Spirit: Mourn that you have not been faithful in reproving Sinners; because hereby you have Adopted their Sins to become your own.</p>
            <p>8ly. When good Resolutions are formed up within us in any Duty of Religion, let us step presently into the Pool of Repentance, for our former not Compliance with the blessed motions of God's Spirit.</p>
            <p>Here a Case may offer it self to be stated. It is thus.</p>
            <p>Considering that God gives a fit space of time to the worst of Sinners, to accommodate their Repentance; What Time is requisit for the Magistrate to afford Condemned Criminals to prepare them for their Death?</p>
            <p>This cannot be stated Absolutely, so as to limit the Power of the Magistrate in this Case. Neither ought any Minister to repine or grudg at the length of Time, as being sparing of his utmost endeavours to save Souls: Yet some think that a compleat Weeks time at least is fit to be granted, if Criminals do not abuse it by being ungovernable, in attempting to break Prison. But much longer Time may make Condemned Persons more secure in presuming that they shall be Pardoned: Hereupon the means of Grace work not so effectually upon them: For when they have no hopes of Respiting their Death, their Convictions are usually the more strengthned, their Prayers more fervent, and their Resolutions to Repent the more settled and confirmed. It is an honourable remark of Piety, and Clemency in the Magistrates of England, that they allow a convenient Time for Reconciling the Souls of Condemned Persons unto God. Yet how strange and deplorable is this, that tho' a sufficient respiting the execution of the Sentence be indulged; Criminals draw on themselves deeper security in Sinning; a stroke far worse than Death, because not felt.</p>
            <p>Hopes of Life, Dead praying, and Men's promises of Improving the Space for Repentance, are blown away, when the fears of Death are abated. Impenitent Sinners abuse God's sparing Mercy; and as I have observed, are not so fit to dye upon a long Reprieve: They are more Solicitous in employing their Friends to make intercession for their Pardon, than themselves are careful to set forward their Repentance thereby, to be Reconciled to God, by whose Smiles or Frownes Men's Souls are disposed of in Happiness or Misery, throw all the Ages of Eternity.</p>
            <p>The conclusion was thus Directed to the Condemned.</p>
            <p>You have heard discrib'd unto you the fittest and most advantageous Opportunities to set Repentance on Work, that it may be compleated unto Salvation; also the dreadful pernicious Effects of willful Impenitency. Yet you have Presumptuously adventured to multiply Sinning, tho' this hath sharpned stinging reflections in your guilty Consciences. Your Ears have been very attentive to the Councils of ungodly Associates: But you have out done the deaf Adder, in stoping your Ears against all God's counter-charmings of your sensual Lusts, by the instructions of Heavenly Wisdom. Do not dare any longer to elude or frustrate the main design of God, in exhibiting the offers of Salvation. How durst any of you cast your Repentance into your last Accounts, which ought to have been the first and choicest Work of your whole Life.</p>
            <p>Oh! That you would duly consider that all Supernatural Probationary Acts of Grace, such as Repentance, and the severity of mortifying your corrupt Nature, ought to be swiftest toward the end of your Lives, because it is not pos</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA169709150002"/>
            <p>sible, and cannot be Available to renew them after Death in the rectifying, of any mistake. Consider that there is great difference 'twixt a Conscience legally wounded for the dreadful Shameful Punishments of Sinning, and a Conscience Evangelically contrite, out of an Holy ingenuity for offending a gracious God, who hath long waited to overcome the Sinners Stubornness with his Clemency. Fear, least after some short Anguish in your Consciences, you should perish in your delay to compleat Repentance.</p>
            <p>Consider the Spiritual benefits which sweeten the difficulties, and austerities of sincere Repentance: Tho' sensual Sinners despise a contrite Heart, as effeminacy and baseness of Spirit; yet it is the best Demonstration of love to God, and a genuine fear of his long suffering; not to Sin against it by vile ingratitude. It doth not dispirit Men's Courage in dying, but contemn Life when it cannot be prolonged with the safety of the the Souls integrity and loyalty to Christ's Laws; it casts forth the oppressing load of sensual Surfeits, which defiled the Souls heavenly Purity. In the midst of National amazing Confusions, penitential Converts to God shall be as safe as Salvation it self can make them: Yet consider how difficult it will be to unravel the Web of Sinning, when Men never Communed with their own Hearts, to search out those Iniquities which are confirmed by a long Custom in Sinning. Familiarize therefore to your selves the severities of sincere Repentance: Justify God in his sharpest Corrections of you, to reduce you from wandring in the Bewildring devices of Sinning, and condemn your selves for the minutest Errors of your Lives. Be not slow and slight in so solemn a work; your whole Life ought to have been a continual exercise of Repentance, and of mortifying your Lusts, as a meet disposition for Eternal Life.</p>
            <p>Take heed of dying in an obstinate contempt of God and Godliness, least the Lord harden his Heart against you, so that when you cry for Mercy, under the anguish of your Consciences, the least glance of it should be denied you.</p>
            <p>I proceed to give an Account of the Behaviour and Confessions of the Condemned Criminals.</p>
            <p>1. <persName id="OA16970915n33-1">
                  <interp inst="OA16970915n33-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16970915n33-1" type="surname" value="DEWIN"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16970915n33-1" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Dewin</persName>, Condemned for Counterfeiting the Coin of this Kingdom: Aged thirty four Years. He was born in <placeName id="OA16970915-geo-1">
                  <interp inst="OA16970915-geo-1" type="type" value="county"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA16970915n33-1 OA16970915-geo-1"/>Norfolk</placeName>: Was <rs id="OA16970915-occupation-1" type="occupation">Prentice to a Shoemaker</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA16970915n33-1 OA16970915-occupation-1"/> in the Northern parts. He kept Shop four or five Years; but left that Employment <rs id="OA16970915-occupation-2" type="occupation">to deal in Cheese and Bacon</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA16970915n33-1 OA16970915-occupation-2"/> at <placeName id="OA16970915-geo-2">
                  <interp inst="OA16970915-geo-2" type="type" value="parish"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA16970915n33-1 OA16970915-geo-2"/>Waltham-Abby</placeName>. He confest that tho' he had not wronged any Man in his Trading; yet, that he had not led a Religious Life towards God: For he neglected the Duty of Praying to him; kept the Sabbath very slightly; that he was guilty of Swearing; but seldom Drunk in excess. He wept and said, That it now grieves him that he hath in many things sinned against the Holy Trinity: And yet that he doth not Repent as he ought, for his being so negligent of his Duty to God. But he begs of him earnestly to change his Heart, and not only to pardon his Sins; and hopes that if he might be spared he should never return to any Customary provoking his most holy Creator, but become a reformed Man.</p>
            <p>II. <persName id="OA16970915n34-1">
                  <interp inst="OA16970915n34-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16970915n34-1" type="surname" value="Blount"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16970915n34-1" type="given" value="Isaac"/>Isaac Blount</persName>, Condemned for Stealing a Gelding: Aged twenty three Years. He was born in <placeName id="OA16970915-geo-3">
                  <interp inst="OA16970915-geo-3" type="type" value="street"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA16970915n34-1 OA16970915-geo-3"/>Gray's-Inn-lane</placeName>. He was an <rs id="OA16970915-occupation-3" type="occupation">Hackny Coach-man</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA16970915n34-1 OA16970915-occupation-3"/>, and drove as a Journy-man for some time, till he wrought for himself. He confest that he had many ways offended God, in prophaning the Lord's Day; in omitting often the Duty of praying that he might be kept from bad Company; that he had kept Company with bad Women, but not lately; that he was not addicted to Swearing nor Drunkenness, yet had at times committed these Sins. He said, that he now is sensible of his evil Courses, and mourns for offending God by them, and hopes that he will so soften his Heart, that the Convictions which are in his Conscience may work to a thorough Repentance.</p>
            <p>III. <persName id="OA16970915n35-1">
                  <interp inst="OA16970915n35-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16970915n35-1" type="surname" value="CHAMBERLAIN"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16970915n35-1" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Chamberlain</persName>, Condemned for Felony and Robbery: Aged twenty six Years: Born in <placeName id="OA16970915-geo-4">
                  <interp inst="OA16970915-geo-4" type="type" value="county"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA16970915n35-1 OA16970915-geo-4"/>Herefordshire</placeName>. He was <rs id="OA16970915-occupation-4" type="occupation">Journyman to a Butcher</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA16970915n35-1 OA16970915-occupation-4"/>. He left that Employment about three Weeks since; but was joyned to bad Company before. He denied not the Crime. He confest that he did not performe the Duties of the Lord's Sabbath, but walkt in the Fields with idle and vain Persons; that he was no much given to Swearing, and had somtimes been overcome with excessive drinking; yet he hopes that being now penitent for all his Sins, that God will pardon them. I stated for several days the nature of true and false sorrow for Sinning, also the nature of true saving Faith; wherein it differs from a presumptuous reliance on God's Mercy and Christ's Merits, and the danger of Sinning in hopes of future Repentance; so that they desired me to pray for them, that they might not deceive themselves with false hopes of Heaven.</p>
            <p>IV. <persName id="OA16970915n36-1">
                  <interp inst="OA16970915n36-1" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16970915n36-1" type="surname" value="TAYLOR"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16970915n36-1" type="given" value="MARY"/>Mary Taylor</persName>, Condemned for a Burglary. She was born in <placeName id="OA16970915-geo-5">
                  <interp inst="OA16970915-geo-5" type="type" value="street"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA16970915n36-1 OA16970915-geo-5"/>Chancery-Lane</placeName>. Was a <rs id="OA16970915-occupation-5" type="occupation">Servant</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA16970915n36-1 OA16970915-occupation-5"/> for eight Years to several Persons of Quality. She said, That altho' she knew her Duty to God, yet she had Sinned against the Convictions of her Conscience; whereby she had much wounded it. She confest that she had not taken former warning, altho' she had been punished for an evil practice, and that therefore God had justly inflicted this dreadful Scourge upon her, to bring her as she hoped to Repentance. She said, That now the chief trouble of her mind is for offending God her Creator and great Redeemer. She said, That she heartily desires that she may be cleansed with the Blood of Christ. O how merciful said she, is God! that he thus Corrects me, and moderates his Justice toward me, in this, that I am Respited from dying, for the space of six Months, till I am delivered of the Child I am quick with; hereby I have time to Repent of my Sins of Presumption, for I knew God's Will, but obeyed it not; such deserve a more terrible Condemnation.</p>
            <p>The other  Women Condemned, were also found with Child, as the Jury of Women affirmed; therefore they are reserved for a longer time before they suffer. I am sorry that they make so ill an use of it, that they grow secure; yea, obstinate, in refusing to come on the last Lord's Day, and at other times to receive Instruction, in order to bring them to a sensibleness of their evil Courses. Callow especially was obstinate, who is Condemned on two Indictments, for picking of Pockets.</p>
            <p>On Wednesday the 15th of September, 1697. <persName id="OA16970915n38-1">
                  <interp inst="OA16970915n38-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16970915n38-1" type="surname" value="DEWIN"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16970915n38-1" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Dewin</persName>, <persName id="OA16970915n38-2">
                  <interp inst="OA16970915n38-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16970915n38-2" type="surname" value="CHAMBERLAIN"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16970915n38-2" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Chamberlain</persName>, and <persName id="OA16970915n38-3">
                  <interp inst="OA16970915n38-3" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16970915n38-3" type="surname" value="BLUNT"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16970915n38-3" type="given" value="ISAAC"/>Isaac Blunt</persName>, were convey'd to <placeName id="OA16970915-geo-6">
                  <interp inst="OA16970915-geo-6" type="type" value="site"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA16970915n38-1 n38-2 n38-3 OA16970915-geo-6"/>Tyburn</placeName>; the first on a Sledge, and the other two in a Cart. But Flora alias Flower, he died in Prison the 12th of September. The Prisoners being brought to the Tree, were tied up. Dewin would not own his Crime, but desired all good People to take warning by him, how they led their Lives, least by their sinful Courses they should come to such untimely ends. <persName id="OA16970915n38-4">
                  <interp inst="OA16970915n38-4" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16970915n38-4" type="surname" value="BLUNT"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16970915n38-4" type="given" value="ISAAC"/>Isaac Blunt</persName> would not own his Crime, but said, he had been guilty of divers such Crimes; he did not shew any outward appearance of Repentance. <persName id="OA16970915n38-5">
                  <interp inst="OA16970915n38-5" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16970915n38-5" type="surname" value="CHAMBERLAIN"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16970915n38-5" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Chamberlain</persName> said, That he was a great Sinner, and had been drawn in by evil Company to do the Fact for which he now suffers; he desired all good Christian People to pray for him, and to take warning by him, and eschew evil Company, and have regard to the Sabbath; he said, That he was bred a labouring Man, and one that did use to work hard for his living; but forgetting God and following Idleness brought him to this untimely end. The Ordinary prayed with them for some considerable Time, and sung a Penitential Psalme. And afterwards they were turned off.</p>
            <p>This is all the Account that I can give of this Sessions.</p>
            <p>Dated Sept. 15.</p>
            <p>
               <persName id="OA16970915n41-1">
                  <interp inst="OA16970915n41-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16970915n41-1" type="surname" value="Smith"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16970915n41-1" type="given" value="Sam"/>Sam. Smith</persName>, <rs id="OA16970915-occupation-6" type="occupation">Ordinary</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA16970915n41-1 OA16970915-occupation-6"/>.</p>
            <p>LONDON, Printed for E. Mallet, in Nevil's-Court in Fetter-lane, 1697</p>
         </div0>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>