<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<TEI.2>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div0 type="ordinarysAccount" id="OA16980622">
            <interp inst="OA16980622" type="uri" value="ordinarysAccounts/OA16980622"/>
            <interp inst="OA16980622" type="date" value="16980622"/>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA169806220001"/>
            <p>A True Account of the Behaviour, Confessions, and last Dying Speeches of the Condemned Criminals, that were Executed at Tyburn on Wednesday the 22th, of this Instant June 1698.</p>
            <p>On the Lords-Day, after the Condemnation of the Condemned Criminals, a Sermon was Preached on this Text,</p>
            <p>I. John 3. 26. For if our heart condemn us, God to greater than our heart, and knoweth all things.</p>
            <p>THese Words demonstrate what is the Misery of a guilty defiled Conscience, not cleansed by the Blood of Christ from the condemning Verdict thereof, as not sanctified by Christ's Spirit. It  for a time be silent, in not accusing for Sin, but it  never, have any Ground of solid true Peace and Comfort, unless it be purified from the Pollution of Sinning, wilfully contracted. The falsly acquitting Conscience shall be convinced that it hath God, who is its Enemy, for its righteous Judge. And being conscious of its Guiltiness, it is very seldom quiet because God Omniscient hath a far quicker Sigh than any  into his own Heart and Ways as judging them with Strictness, yet in Rightsness. The very Light and Dictates of the natural Conscience, if attended unto by the reflex acts of the Understanding, will commn all unchaste, Desires all Contrivances of Injustice and Acts of Hypocrise in God's Service. Natural carnal Men strive to put Conscience (God's Spy and Deputy-Judge) out of in Office;  that it  altogether silent, or  a slight Sense of Sinning: yet there is no bribing of the Conscience altogether, because God is great or in Authority and Power omnipresent and omniscient to know the very Thoughts of the Heart. Even in this Life, the Conscience is  and armed with Christ's Authority, that it make to  within himself, and  But in the last universal: Judgment Conscience shall make Sinners at their Wits end, to wish for the Mountains to fall on them and to cover them from the Wrath of the incensed Lamb of God. Christ's  abused shall then turn to the Furiousness of his extremest Justice, to wrath unavoidable and intolerable.</p>
            <p>Now there are these Reasons why God hath given the Conscience the Power of Accusing or Excusing, of Acquitting or Condemning.</p>
            <p>I. That every Man any have something within himself to comfort terrifie him, when all things without fll to do this, that God's Proceedings with Men, may by themselves be confest to be just. Every Man's own Conscience is a proper fit Witness for or against him; because it keeps continually a Register within himself: Yea, this book of the Conscience is in every Man's own keeping, and therefore cannot be interlin'd or falsified. Christ in the last Judgment, will to lively and powerfully join with every Man's Conscience, as  set before the Sinner the breath of every Law of God or Men with the smallest Circumstances. The very Word of God, set home by the Authority of his Spirit, makes the most obstinate Sinner to fall flat, on his Face, and to acknowledge that God was in such a Truth, which discovered the very Thoughts of his Heart. Thus the Word of Christ is his Attorney General to draw up an Impeachment against the Sinner, yet Christ i the only Judge himself. And he is constituted such, by his Father a Constitution, in our very human Nature. For God the Father, would not be judge in his own Cause; but Christ as God, Man partakes of the Nature both of God and Man. And thus his Interest  to Right Indifferently and impartially betwixt God and Man. Let not Sinners grow presumptuous hereupon, That Christ as judge in their own Nature will, be more indulgent in his Sentence. He will be the more severe with such who despising the Dignity of Human Nature pervert the right the of their Reason, to Licentiousness in Sinning. Christ Book of Omnisciency in the Day of Judgment, and that of the Conscience being opened together, will most exactly agree: Therefore all things shall very speedily be cleared up, without troubling Juries or any other Witnesses. This could not be a Work speedily done, if God had not given this Power to Conscience to reflect and give Testimony, yea, to be more authentic than  thousand Witnesses besides; thus all Debasings  and  will be needless.</p>
            <p>The inference is this, Seeing that we have a troth in our own Bosoms wherever we o and whatever  do, who will make Report thereof to Christ the Judge of Heaven and Earth. Let us  over our  Words and Deeds, as those who desire to have the considerable Testimony of Conscience, for our Acquirement at the great Day of Account. Let us not suspend, ch less  the Mouth of Conscience accusing and impleading Th is crying Wickedness, to stab the Judge of all the World he sits on the Bench speaking Law and Justice  a very unnatural desperate and Devilish  Wickedness is incurable, because it  very  means of Conversion to God, which is the  sinful State.</p>
            <p>I shall now lay before you some Rules or  to get and preserve a good Conscience.</p>
            <p>Do not presume, that tho you delay  dying Hour, that God will save you by an gative on Mercy, contrary to his Holy Nature  his Sacred Word.</p>
            <p>2. Observe and preserve the natural and  of the Conscience, before sophistical  or corrupted them, as speaking false  about the least Circumstance of your Duty  neglected, amounts in God's Account to  Sin committed by the sudden Surprize  of  Do not slight the least Sin as if it would not  Damnation, hoping that it is pardonable  Grace shall attain  endeavouring after the highest Measures of Holiness as Happiness it self. Argue not your  good and happy, from the common Works of Christianity but inrr the Hopes of your Salvation from the Inhabitation of Christ's sanctifying Spirit  you.</p>
            <p> the rather insist on this Remark of a good  because S. Peter , That the Answer or such a Conscience as purified by the Merits of Christ's blood shed and raised from the death of Sin, to the life of Righteousness, is the only effect Baptism to rely upon for  On that the Spirit of Sanctification may descend this day upon you to baptize you with Fire,  Love to the Ways of Holiness! He is the Spirit of Bing to cons the Droness of our rrunt Nature that we may be  an every good Work. This is  manner to  the Festival of  we evidence that the Spirit of Christ hath was'd away  Pollution of our Sins by the  that we are cloathed with all Heavenly Graces.  may it and before the Throne of god,  to  as his Favorites; We need not search the Records  God's Decrees as to our eternal State;  into our selves, and narrowly search , the  Heart is, and the constant  in this World. I you can appeal to God's  that you  love  That you have not shaped  World according to the Politick  Wisdom,  you have walk'd is under the Eye of God's  being fearful of offending him, and ly careful to please him. ves for the minut Irregularities and  of your Lives: Then the Lord judge of  come your Advocate,  over  of justice. True  who judge  shall have  shall be admitted wh the  Mansions of Eternal Glory.</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA169806220002"/>
            <p> to give an Account of the Behaviour and Confessions of the Condemned Criminals.</p>
            <p>1. <persName id="OA16980622n14-1">
                  <interp inst="OA16980622n14-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16980622n14-1" type="surname" value="Audley"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16980622n14-1" type="given" value="Edmund"/>Edmund Audley</persName>, condemned for the barbarous murthering of Mrs. Bullevant, the Wife of Mr. Bullevant formerly an Apothecary in <placeName id="OA16980622-geo-1">
                  <interp inst="OA16980622-geo-1" type="type" value="parish"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA16980622n14-1 OA16980622-geo-1"/>Walbrook</placeName>: He pursued her and killed her in the Day time in the <placeName id="OA16980622-geo-2">
                  <interp inst="OA16980622-geo-2" type="type" value="street"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA16980622n14-1 OA16980622-geo-2"/>Street of St. Martins le Grand</placeName>, shooting her with a Pistol with two Bullets thorow the Back, so that she died immediately, I told him, that by this barbarous Murther he had stained the Profession of Christ's holy Religion. He replied, that People had great Apprehensions of the Bloodness of the Fact, but that himself thought otherwise of it: for he said, that he had a Strong Perswasion that Mrs. Bullevant was a naughty Woman and in Conspiracy against the present Government. I replied, that he being a private Person ought not to have kill'd her, but to have made his ill Thoughts of her appeared in some Court of Justice. He said, he counted not the Fact to be Murther, for his Conscience stirred him up to do it. I told him, that 'twas a very wicked and devilish Act: I askt him whether any Person did hire him to kill Mrs. Bullevant? He said no. I askt him what Grounds of Malice he had against her? He replied, with Surliness, that he would not give any Account of it more than what he had said before. Hereupon I left him, after he had refused that  should pray with him, as little concern'd for this Crime or any precedent part of an ill Life. Dr. Bedford, a City Minister, being appointed by the Lord Bishop of London to assist the Ordinary, did on Whitsunday, before the Doctor preach'd, endeavour to perswade him to join in the publick Worship at the Chappel, but he said he would only be directed by such who were of his own Opinion. He was conceited of his Knowledge, and discoursed not as a Phrentick Parson but behaved himself with a sullen Obstinacy at that time and since. The Omniscient God be pleased to perswade him to make a free and full Discovery of the whole Intrigue and Contrivance of this barbarous Crime.</p>
            <p>2. <persName id="OA16980622n15-1">
                  <interp inst="OA16980622n15-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16980622n15-1" type="surname" value="COOK"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16980622n15-1" type="given" value="WILLIAM"/>William Cook</persName>, condemned for Counterfeiting the currant Coin of this Kingdom. He was a Clock-maker, but wrought upon his Trade in a Chamber. He acknowledged that he had not lived up to that Knowledge which God had given him, which made his Sins the greater; yet said  nor been vicious in the Course of his Life.</p>
            <p>3. <persName id="OA16980622n16-1">
                  <interp inst="OA16980622n16-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16980622n16-1" type="surname" value="MORGAN"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16980622n16-1" type="given" value="NATHANIEL"/>Nathaniel Morgan</persName>, condemned for counterfeiting the currant Coin of this Kingdom. He was a <rs id="OA16980622-occupation-1" type="occupation">Doctor of Physick</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA16980622n16-1 OA16980622-occupation-1"/>, and said that he was brought up to that excellent Study at <placeName id="OA16980622-geo-3">
                  <interp inst="OA16980622-geo-3" type="type" value="urban_centre"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA16980622n16-1 OA16980622-geo-3"/>Leyden</placeName>, and that he had good Practice on his Profession at <placeName id="OA16980622-geo-4">
                  <interp inst="OA16980622-geo-4" type="type" value="urban_centre"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA16980622n16-1 OA16980622-geo-4"/>London</placeName>, and that for his Sins God had exposed him to the Sentence of Death: He was of considerable Knowledge in the Concernments of Religion, and wish'd that he had led a Life sutably. He was not negligent in preparing for his Death, having little Hopes of being pardoned. He took much Pains in instructing the other Criminals in the close Dungeon, who told me that they received much benefit by him. I hope that he was truly penitent.</p>
            <p>4. <persName id="OA16980622n17-1">
                  <interp inst="OA16980622n17-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16980622n17-1" type="surname" value="MORGAN"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16980622n17-1" type="given" value="THOMAS"/>Thomas Morgan</persName>, Brother to Nathaniel, condemned for counterfeiting the currant Coin of this Kingdom. He said, that it grieved him that he had not lived a stricter Life, yet he hoped that by the Sentence of Death God had brought him to a deep Sense of his Sins, and that upon the searching of his Heart he hoped that he truly repented, and had made his Peace with God his eternal Judge. He was tractable to good Counsel.</p>
            <p>5. <persName id="OA16980622n18-1">
                  <interp inst="OA16980622n18-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16980622n18-1" type="surname" value="Price"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16980622n18-1" type="given" value="Aubrey"/>Aubrey Price</persName>, condemned fot ocunterfeiting an Excheque. He was a Gentleman of God Parentage, and said, that he had an Estate sufficient to maintain himself and Family; that he was very Sorry for the foolish and unjust Fact for which he is condemned. He kept the Lord's Days in the publick Worship at the Chappel constantly from the time of his Commitment. He mist not any Opportuty to prepare him for his Death, and said, if my Life may be spared, I am resolved by God's Grace to live strictly, and not to break again any known Law of the Nation. I hope he was truly penitent.</p>
            <p>6. <persName id="OA16980622n19-1">
                  <interp inst="OA16980622n19-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16980622n19-1" type="surname" value="BROWN"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16980622n19-1" type="given" value="ROBERT"/>Robert Brown</persName>, condemned for breaking the House of <persName id="OA16980622n19-2">
                  <interp inst="OA16980622n19-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16980622n19-2" type="surname" value="FREEMAN"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16980622n19-2" type="given" value="EDWARD"/>Edward Freeman</persName>, <rs id="OA16980622-occupation-2" type="occupation">Gentleman</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA16980622n19-2 OA16980622-occupation-2"/>, and stealing Goods thence. He is aged 26 Years, was born in <placeName id="OA16980622-geo-5">
                  <interp inst="OA16980622-geo-5" type="type" value="urban_centre"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA16980622n19-1 OA16980622-geo-5"/>Lyn Regis</placeName>; he said, that from 8 Years of Age he <rs id="OA16980622-occupation-3" type="occupation">went to Sea</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA16980622n19-1 OA16980622-occupation-3"/>, had been in the <placeName id="OA16980622-geo-6">
                  <interp inst="OA16980622-geo-6" type="type" value="region"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA16980622n19-1 OA16980622-geo-6"/>West-Indies</placeName> and in the Streights; he said, that he was drawn into Fact, that he was disobedient to his Parents, broke, the Sabbath, and had known bad Women carnally, was addicted two Swearing, Cursing and Drunkenness.</p>
            <p>On the 22d. of June, <persName id="OA16980622n20-8">
                  <interp inst="OA16980622n20-8" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16980622n20-8" type="surname" value="Price"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16980622n20-8" type="given" value="Aubry"/>Aubry Price</persName>, <persName id="OA16980622n20-1">
                  <interp inst="OA16980622n20-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16980622n20-1" type="surname" value="BROWN"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16980622n20-1" type="given" value="ROBERT"/>Robert Brown</persName>, and <persName id="OA16980622n20-2">
                  <interp inst="OA16980622n20-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16980622n20-2" type="surname" value="AUDLEY"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16980622n20-2" type="given" value="EDMUND"/>Edmund Audley</persName> were carried in one Cart, and <persName id="OA16980622n20-3">
                  <interp inst="OA16980622n20-3" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16980622n20-3" type="surname" value="MORGAN"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16980622n20-3" type="given" value="NATHANIEL"/>Nathaniel Morgan</persName>, <persName id="OA16980622n20-4">
                  <interp inst="OA16980622n20-4" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16980622n20-4" type="surname" value="MORGAN"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16980622n20-4" type="given" value="THOMAS"/>Thomas Morgan</persName>, and <persName id="OA16980622n20-5">
                  <interp inst="OA16980622n20-5" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16980622n20-5" type="surname" value="COOK"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16980622n20-5" type="given" value="WILLIAM"/>William Cook</persName>, in one Sledge, from <placeName id="OA16980622-geo-7">
                  <interp inst="OA16980622-geo-7" type="type" value="site"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA16980622n20-1 n20-2 n20-3 n20-4 n20-5 n20-8 OA16980622-geo-7"/>Newgate</placeName> to <placeName id="OA16980622-geo-8">
                  <interp inst="OA16980622-geo-8" type="type" value="site"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA16980622n20-1 n20-2 n20-3 n20-4 n20-5 n20-8 OA16980622-geo-8"/>Tyburn</placeName>, and being all placed in one Cart, were assisted by two Reverend Divines, besides the Ordinary, who continued a long time with the Prisoners in the Cart. And being tied up, <persName id="OA16980622n20-9">
                  <interp inst="OA16980622n20-9" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16980622n20-9" type="surname" value="Price"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16980622n20-9" type="given" value="Aubry"/>Aubry Price</persName> said, he would make no publick Confession, he having before discharged his Conscience, as to the Matter for which he died, to the Divines who visited him in Prison. He further said, he did not come there to detect either Judge, Jury or Evidence; he was seemingly very penitent, desired Absolution from the Ministers, who told him they had given him that in Prison. <persName id="OA16980622n20-10">
                  <interp inst="OA16980622n20-10" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16980622n20-10" type="surname" value="Brown"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16980622n20-10" type="given" value="Rob"/>Rob. Brown</persName> said, that he had been guilty not only of the Felony and Burglary for which he was to die, but of two others; That he had been drawn in by one Moody, who was with him at all the three Burglaries, declared he knew of no other Gang, and seemed very penitent. <persName id="OA16980622n20-11">
                  <interp inst="OA16980622n20-11" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16980622n20-11" type="surname" value="Audley"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16980622n20-11" type="given" value="Ed"/>Ed. Audley</persName> seemed somewhat sullen, continued mute a long time, and being askt his Reasons for killing the Gentlewoman? said, he did it for the Common Good, but would make no other Confession as to that point; and being told, that it was supposed it was upon the Account of his being prevented in marrying a young Gentlewoman, said, it was false: He persisted in his old Fancies of a Plot against the King's Life, and to introduce the late King James, and wished he had an Opportunity to declare his Mind to the King, adding, that he knew several of the Plotters, and being desired to declare who they were? said, he would do it to none but the King. Upon his being askt in what Profession he died? Said, he died in the Faith of a Christian as revealed in Scripture, and desired to be left to his Ejaculations to God and himself; did not join in Prayer with the Ordinary, but was observed to move his Lips, but not to any articulate Utterance, however died seemingly very penitent. <persName id="OA16980622n20-12">
                  <interp inst="OA16980622n20-12" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16980622n20-12" type="surname" value="Morgan"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16980622n20-12" type="given" value="Nathaniel"/>Nathaniel and</persName> 
               <persName id="OA16980622n20-6">
                  <interp inst="OA16980622n20-6" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16980622n20-6" type="surname" value="MORGAN"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16980622n20-6" type="given" value="THOMAS"/>Thomas Morgan</persName> said, they were very much trembled at the breaking of several Resolutions they had made, reflected extreamly upon the Evidence, and declared, that what they had further to say they had imprted to the Warden of the Mint. <persName id="OA16980622n20-7">
                  <interp inst="OA16980622n20-7" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16980622n20-7" type="surname" value="COOK"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16980622n20-7" type="given" value="WILLIAM"/>William Cook</persName> said, that he had lodged at a bad House, where the Trade of Coining was  he had seen practised, but did not coin himself; but exprest himself very faintly as to the latter, and owned he knew several Persons concerned in that wicked Trade, but declined to discover them. All the Persons desired the Ordinary to give Warning to the Spectators to avoid the Sins of Sabbath breaking, keeping of bad Company, excessive Drinking, which was the Occasion of many Mens being perswaded to use unlawful Means for Gain, and to live a godly and pious Life, which he did accordingly. The Ordinary continued a long time with them upon the Cart, in praying for and with them. The Cart drew away and they were turned off.</p>
            <p>This is all the Account I can give of this Sessions.</p>
            <p>Dated June 22.</p>
            <p>
               <persName id="OA16980622n23-1">
                  <interp inst="OA16980622n23-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16980622n23-1" type="surname" value="Smith"/>
                  <interp inst="OA16980622n23-1" type="given" value="Sam"/>Sam. Smith</persName>, <rs id="OA16980622-occupation-4" type="occupation">Ordinary</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA16980622n23-1 OA16980622-occupation-4"/>.</p>
            <p>ADVERTISEMENT.</p>
            <p>The Vertues and Uses of the Water for the Teeth and Gums, truly prepared by W. Elmy, at the ew-ball in Whalebone Court at the lower end of Bartholomew-lane, by the Royal Exchange.</p>
            <p>IT cures the Scurvy in the Mouth, and makes a good Pallate, and sweetneth the Breath, by dipping a Liquorish Stick sharpned at the end in this said Water, and rub your Gums there with as oft as need shall require: It whitens black and yellow Teeth, by rubbing your Teeth and Gums with a Tooth-brush dipp'd in this Water it fallens loose Teeth, and prevents their decaying, by holding half a Spoonful or more on that side of the Mouth which is afflicted, by causing the Rheum which falls upon the Nerves that lie under the Roots of the Teeth to come away to Admiration. It is good for young Children in breeding their Teeth, and fit to be taken inwardly for Fevers: In short, it is good for all Diseases incident to the Teeth or Gums.</p>
            <p>The Glasses are of several Prices.</p>
            <p>LONDON, Printed for E. Mallet next the King's Arms Tavern near Fleet-Bridg, 1698.</p>
         </div0>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>