<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<TEI.2>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div0 type="ordinarysAccount" id="OA17350922">
            <interp inst="OA17350922" type="uri" value="ordinarysAccounts/OA17350922"/>
            <interp inst="OA17350922" type="date" value="17350922"/>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA173509220001"/>
            <p>THE ORDINARY of NEWGATE, His ACCOUNT of the Behaviour, Confessions, and Dying Words, OF THE MALEFACTORS, Who were EXECUTED at TYBURN, On Monday the 22d of September.</p>
            <p>BEING THE Fifth EXECUTION in the MAYORALTY OF THE Rt. Hon. <persName id="OA17350922n3-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n3-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n3-1" type="surname" value="BELLAMY"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n3-1" type="given" value="EDWARD"/>Sir EDWARD BELLAMY</persName>, Knt.</p>
            <p>Number V. For the said YEAR.</p>
            <p>LONDON:</p>
            <p>Printed and Sold by <persName id="OA17350922n6-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n6-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n6-1" type="surname" value="APPLEBEE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n6-1" type="given" value="JOHN"/>JOHN APPLEBEE</persName>, in Bolt-Court, the Leg-Tavern, Fleet-street. M.DCC.XXXV.</p>
            <p>[Price Six-Pence.]</p>
            <p>[Missing page image]</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA173509220003"/>
            <p>THE ORDINARY of NEWGATE, His ACCOUNT of the Behaviour, Confession, &amp;c.</p>
            <p>AT the King's Commission of Oyer and Terminer, and Goal-Delivery of Newgate, held (before the Rt. Hon. <persName id="OA17350922n9-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n9-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n9-1" type="surname" value="BELLAMY"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n9-1" type="given" value="EDWARD"/>Sir Edward Bellamy</persName>, Knt. Lord Mayor of the City of London; the Honourable Mr. Baron Thompson, Recorder of the City of London; the Worshipful Mr. Serjeant Urlin, Deputy-Recorder of the said City; and others of his Majesty's Justices of Oyer and Terminer, and Goal-Delivery for the City of London, and Goal-Delivery of Newgate, holden for the said City and County of Middlesex) at Justice-Hall in the Old-Bailey, on Thursday, Friday, Saturday, Monday, Tuesday, and Wednesday, the 11th, 12th, 13th, 15th, 16th, and 17th of September, in the Ninth Year of his Majesty's Reign.</p>
            <p>Twelve Men, viz. <persName id="OA17350922n10-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n10-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n10-1" type="surname" value="LEWIS"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n10-1" type="given" value="WILLIAM"/>William Lewis</persName>, <persName id="OA17350922n10-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n10-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n10-2" type="surname" value="DEAN"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n10-2" type="given" value="JOSHUA"/>Joshua Dean</persName>, <persName id="OA17350922n10-3">
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n10-3" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n10-3" type="surname" value="DENNIS"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n10-3" type="given" value="ISAAC"/>Isaac Dennis</persName>, <persName id="OA17350922n10-4">
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n10-4" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n10-4" type="surname" value="GAFFNEY"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n10-4" type="given" value="PATRICK"/>Patrick Gaffney</persName>, <persName id="OA17350922n10-5">
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n10-5" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n10-5" type="surname" value="TOGWELL"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n10-5" type="given" value="EDWARD"/>Edward Togwell</persName>, <persName id="OA17350922n10-6">
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n10-6" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n10-6" type="surname" value="MATTHEWS"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n10-6" type="given" value="PETER"/>Peter Matthews</persName>, <persName id="OA17350922n10-7">
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n10-7" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n10-7" type="surname" value="CONNOR"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n10-7" type="given" value="CHARLES"/>Charles Connor</persName>, <persName id="OA17350922n10-8">
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n10-8" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n10-8" type="surname" value="PHILLIPS"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n10-8" type="given" value="WILLIAM"/>William Phillips</persName>, alias Clark, alias Matthews, <persName id="OA17350922n10-9">
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n10-9" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n10-9" type="surname" value="WHITNEY"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n10-9" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Whitney</persName>, <persName id="OA17350922n10-10">
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n10-10" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n10-10" type="surname" value="FARREL"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n10-10" type="given" value="JAMES"/>James Farrel</persName>, <persName id="OA17350922n10-11">
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n10-11" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n10-11" type="surname" value="HOOPER"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n10-11" type="given" value="CHARLES"/>Charles Hooper</persName>, and <persName id="OA17350922n10-12">
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n10-12" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n10-12" type="surname" value="HOLLOWAY"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n10-12" type="given" value="GEORGE"/>George Holloway</persName>, and a Girl, about 10 Years of Age, viz. <persName id="OA17350922n10-13">
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n10-13" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n10-13" type="surname" value="WOTTON"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n10-13" type="given" value="MARY"/>Mary Wotton</persName>, were by the Jury convicted of capital Crimes, and received Sentence of Death.</p>
            <p>While under Sentence, I seriously exhorted them to consider their Ways, and turn their Feet unto God's Testimonies, more especially considering the heinous Crimes they had committed, and for which they then suffer'd the height of Disgrace and Calamity; they having been guilty of Murder, Rapes, Forgery, Robbery,</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA173509220004"/>
            <p>House-breaking, Privately-stealing, and such other most enormous Crimes, as justly brought them under then fatal Sentence, and made them liable to God's Wrath and Curse, both in this Life, and that which is to come: Therefore I press'd 'em to fly from the Wraththat is to come to lay hold upon eternal Life, and to embrace the Offers and Calls which are given to us in the everlasting Gospel; since upon the due Improvement of the few Moments allow'd them in this World, no less depended than their future Happiness and Bliss, in that glorious Place of eternal Rest and Peace, prepared for the Saints and Children of God.</p>
            <p>I shew'd to them the Excellency, the Beauty, the Delightfulness of our holy Christian Religion, how that it is the only Scheme most adapted to the Manifestation of God's Glory, and the Salvation of lost Men; in the Contrivance and Execution whereof, the infinite Wisdom of the Divinity is visibly display'd.</p>
            <p>I desir'd them to reflect upon their past ways, how vicious, how diabolical, how impious they had been, and that however pleasant they might have apprehended a sinful Course of Life to be, yet in the Consequence they found it terrible, and in the Digestion bitter, as then appear'd by the great Hardships and Inconveniencies which they endur'd, which verified the Apostle's Reasoning, That the Wages of Sin is Death, but the Gift of God is eternal Life, through Jesus Christ our Lord.</p>
            <p>From this I took Occaso to shew them, what Pleasure and Delight there is in the Practice of Piety and Virtue; for although ungodliness may sometimes triumph over depress'd Virtue, yet certain it is, That Godliness hath the Promise of the Life that now is, and that which is to come; and that the Reflections upon a good Life is the only Thing which can give us Peace of Conscience, inward Tranquility of Mind, and an assured Confidence of attaining to the End of our Faith, even the eternal Salvation of our Souls. &amp;c.</p>
            <p>I exhorted them to a diligent Preparation for receiving the blessed Sacrament of our Lord's last Supper, from these Words, The Cup of Blessing which we bless, is it not the Communion of the Blood of Christ? The Bread which we break, is it not the communion of the Body of Christ? For we being many, are one Bread, and one Body: For we are all Partakers of that one Bread. 1. Cor x. 16, 17.</p>
            <p>While many such Instructions and Exhortations were given, they attended in Chapel, and all of them were very attentive and serious at the Devotion and other Duties, having behav'd much better and more decently than those miserable People frequently do under the like Misfortune. The little Girl Mary Wooton, came to Chapel, but once or twice being very ill; till the Reprieve came, which</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA173509220005"/>
            <p>of them making a most pitiful and dismal Appearance, like unto the black, horrid, vile and unaccountable Action they had been going about. The Constables took particular Notice of them, and getting their Names, they got a Warrant from a Justice of Peace; upon which they made diligent Search, and took them up as they could find them, and now three of that notorious Gang are Executed, and made a publick Example of Infamy, for attempting such a vile, abominable, inhuman Action. Togwell behav'd well under his Misfortunes, was careful in his Duty, and attentive to Prayers and Exhortations. He own'd. That the Wickedness of his Life call'd for such a severe Judgment. He declar'd his Faith in Christ; that he was a sincere Penitent for all his Sins; and died in Peace with all Men.</p>
            <p>5. <persName id="OA17350922n19-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n19-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n19-1" type="surname" value="MATTHEWS"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n19-1" type="given" value="PETER"/>Peter Matthews</persName>, 22 Years of Age, born at Dublin, of honest Parents, who educated him to Read, Write, and cast Accmpts; and when of Age, he was put to a Shoe-Maker, to which Trade he serv'd out his Time, and afterwards liv'd there by his Business in an honest way for some Time, till about two or three Years ago, he listed himself a Soldier, in one of the Irish Regiments in France, commanded by General Dillon, where he served above a Year; but weary of the last Year's tedious and laborious Campaign upon the Rhine, he deserted from the Siege of Phillipsburg; though he own'd that the French treated them with abundance of Kindness and Civillity, and that they liv'd well enough upon their Allowance; but many of them being of a roving Temper, of which Number he was one, could not be contented, but lov'd to change about; and accordingly desirous to see England, where he had not been before, he came over hither, to follow his rakish and loose Courses, for which he met with his deserved Fate. He confess'd that he was very wicked in his Life; he was sick, and confin'd to his Cell for a Day or two; when I visited him, he appear'd deeply affected with a Sense of his Sins, and lamented over them, crying to God for the Pardon of them. He had not been guilty of any capital Crimes before, neither was he ever taken up upon any Account whatsoever. But being acquainted with this unhappy Company, who ravish'd the Woman, and complying, assisting or going with them, the same prov'd the Occasion of his untimely End. He hop'd for Salvation through the Mercy of God in Christ; was Penitent for his Sins; and forgive all Men.</p>
            <p>
               <persName id="OA17350922n20-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n20-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n20-1" type="surname" value="WHITNEY"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n20-1" type="given" value="JAMES"/>James Whitney</persName>, alias Pugsnose, was indicted for ravishing the above Margaret Mackullough, Widow, on the 6th of July last.</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA173509220006"/>
            <p>6. <persName id="OA17350922n21-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n21-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n21-1" type="surname" value="WHITNEY"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n21-1" type="given" value="JAMES"/>James Whitney</persName>, 29 Years of Age, born in Buckinghamshire, of mean Parents, who gave him little or no Education at School, so that he had not much Knowledge of Religion. When of Age, he was put to a Coach Tiremaker, and having serv'd his Time honestly, he liv'd by his Business, and married a Wife, by whom he had two Children. He was a wicked young Man among Women, a Swearer, and Blasphemer, and mightily given to drinking and keeping of idle Company, which was the Cause of his falling into those miserable Misfortunes, which ended in his Destruction. Rapes, it seems, were destin'd to be his Ruin; for about a Year or little more ago, he was present at a Rape of a Woman by Glare Market, about Midnight, where he receiv'd a Cut in his Arm. And this Rape upon Margaret Mackullough by Long-Acre, or Drury-Lane, he was also a Witness to, being in the Court where and when it was committed, and beholding the whole Tragedy as it was acted. But all this, he alledg'd, was by Accident, which at least proves, that he kept very ill Hours; and as improper Company, having spent too much of his Time in Night-Cellars and bad Houses, so that these Disorders could not happen in the Streets, at unseasonable Hours, without his seeing of them. He was very ignorant of Religious Principles, which I endeavour'd to instil into him, in the most easy and familiar way.</p>
            <p>He was most attentive in Chapel, and profess'd a real sincere Repentance for the Sins of his Life, crying and lamenting over his wicked Courses. He spoke of one cast for Transportation, who told him that he was one of them that ravish'd the poor Woman. He owned that he was concerned in the Rape, but was not willing to confess Particulars. He had a strong Confidence in the Mercy of God through Christ, was a true Penitent for all the Sins of his Life, and forgave all Offences as he expected Forgiveness from God.</p>
            <p>This Rape upon Margaret Mac Culloch was committed by a Set of Ruffians, who had been drinking all Saturday Night, the 5th of July last, and all of them being mad with Drink, and intent upon Mischief, they went into Long-Acre, and abus'd every Body, Men and Women, who came in their Way, as appeared upon their Trial; for they beat a Man and a Woman and knock'd them down, only for asking what they meant by such Rudeness? Having come into the Court, Margaret Mac Culloch came out at the Door of the House where she lodged, designing to go and buy some Mackerel; when they saw her, they immediately formed a Resolution to Ravish her; accordingly they took her into a Necessary-house at the end of the Court, which having a Partition in it they tore it down in their Madness, to expose</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA173509220007"/>
            <p>their Sin and Shame in a Manner not to be express'd; this was between the Hours of Two and Three of the Sunday Morning following. They there threw her down, but she not being willing to comply with their devellish Intentions, one of them held her right Thigh, who was Matthews, as they swore against him, another held the left Thigh, two others held her two Arms, and a fifth held down her Head, till <persName id="OA17350922n24-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n24-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n24-1" type="surname" value="TOGWELL"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n24-1" type="given" value="EDWARD"/>Edward Togwell</persName> abu'd her first, there being a great Number of them, they held her down in this barbarous Posture, until six others successively after Togwell ravished her, having left her half dead, and abused her in such a manner, that it is doubted if ever she can recover her Health again. Having done all this, some propos'd to throw her into the Dirt and murther her, they having stopt her Mouth with a Handkerchief that they had taken off her Neck, by cramming it therein with a Colley-Flower Stalk; but the rest kept them from doing Murder; they then run out to Long-Acre, cursing, swearing, blaspheming and quarrelling, till at length they fell a fighting together. And thus they spent that Lord's Day, which is consecrated to the Service of God, in Town and Country, as is already told, till at length they were taken up, and three of them brought to condign Punishment for their Villanies, (and as we hear) three more of their notorious wicked Companions are taken up and in Custody. The Particulars of this Tragedy as it was acted, a Woman looking out at her Chamber Window saw, and declared upon Oath, in Confirmation of what the Prosecutrix had sworn, and which several others also gave in Evidence against them.</p>
            <p>
               <persName id="OA17350922n25-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n25-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n25-1" type="surname" value="PHILLIPS"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n25-1" type="given" value="WILLIAM"/>William Phillips</persName>, alias Clark, alias Matthews, was indicted for stealing a grey Gelding, value 15 l. the Property of Mr. <persName id="OA17350922n25-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n25-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n25-2" type="surname" value="WINTER"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n25-2" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Winter</persName>.</p>
            <p>7. <persName id="OA17350922n26-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n26-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n26-1" type="surname" value="PHILLIPS"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n26-1" type="given" value="WILLIAM"/>William Phillips</persName>, alias Clark, alias Matthews, whose right Name was Clark, 35 Years of Age, of honest Parents in Dublin, who educated him at School, to Read, Write and cast Accompts, to fit him for Business, and had him instructed in Christian Principles. When of Age, he serv'd his Time honestly to a Taylor, and afterwards liv'd for some Time by his Business in his own Country. Some Years ago he came to London, and married a Wife, by whom he had three Children alive, when his Misfortunes befel him. He was acquainted with Mac Creigh, and many of his Companions. As for the stealing of Mr. Winter's Horse, he complain'd on the Evidence of the Boy, who saw him take him away at the Back of the Coach in St. Paul's-Church-Yard, alledging that he might be in a Mistake, and seemed uneasy at some other Things; but behav'd always with abundance of Submission and Devotion. He alledg'd, that he had very good Business as a Master</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA173509220008"/>
            <p>Taylor at Limehouse, keeping commonly 7 or 8 Men at Work, and that he had no Occasion of going on the Highway, his Business having been still upon the growing Hand; and as to his Acquaintance with Mac Creigh, it was only upon Account of the Country, he having employ'd him sometimes, and wish'd him to the Employment of others; and that he only lodg'd at his House for 7 or 8 Days, as to his private Affairs, he did not enquire after them: And as to himself, he did not use to ride out, but to visit a Friend about Plaistow, commonly with his Wife, and an Acquaintance; and his Friend used to return the Visit, and stay a Night or two with him. He appeared very penitent, grave and devout. He declar'd his Faith in Christ; his Repentance for his Sins; that he suffer'd justly at the Hands of God for the Errors of his Life; and died in perfect Charity with all the World.</p>
            <p>The following is a true Account given to the Printer of the Robberies committed by him, with Mac Creigh.</p>
            <p>IN the Year 1728, he and another laying for Transportation in the Master's-Side of Newgate, found Means to break out from thence, and made their Escapes through the Turner's House adjoining thereto.</p>
            <p>He said that he was the Person mentioned by Mr. Mac Creigh to be concerned in robbing the Rt. Hon. the Countess of Strafford, and also Sir Henry Hankey's Son, and Mr. Coverley - and that about twelve Months ago he became acquainted with him in the following Manner. Being on the Road between London and Barnet, he met Mr. Mac Creigh, very well dress'd, on a fine Gelding, whom he stop'd, and demanding his Money, he said, I am one of your Profession; on which he replied, D-m ye, Sir, don't trifle with me, for I will have your Money, and to convince him Mac Creigh produced a Pistol out of each Pocket, and likewise a Crape; he then said, if you are one of us, go and rob that Coach, which was near them; accordingly he did, and returned; and said now, I hope you are satisfied, from which Time they contracted an Intimacy- and agreed to go out together.</p>
            <p>After they had committed this Robbery, they met a Grazier and a Butcher, the former had been in Town to sell Cattle; Mac Creigh said to Phillips, you have always had a Notion of robbing these Fellows called Graziers, I could never make any thing of them to any Purpose; go and try what you can make of that old Fellow, and in the mean time I will go and see what I can make of the Butcher; accordingly they agreed, Mac Creigh went and robb'd the Butcher of a small Matter, and Phillips went to the Grazier, and took from him between 30 and 40 Shillings which he said was all he had, and desired him at the same time to return him a small Marter to bear his Charges; Phillips replied he must first search him, which on doing he found a great Lump under his Ham; honest Grazier said he, have you had any Misfortune that you have such a Lump, who replied I have had it some Years, it is a Wen; O! says Phil</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA173509220009"/>
            <p>lips I'll immediately cure it for you, which he did, by making the Grazier unbutton the Knees of his Breeches, and took from under his Ham in a leather Purse about 60 Guineas; now says he I have eas'd you of your Wn, let me see how you can walk, which the poor Grazier was obliged to do without his Money.</p>
            <p>After they had committed this Robbery they made off, and by a round about Way came to Kingston upon Thames, when they laid all their Plunder on a Table to examine it, which was to the Value of 100 l. in Cash, besides Watches, Rings and other things of Value.</p>
            <p>He and Mac Creigh robb'd one Mr. Sherrard, a noted Scarlet-Dyer in Southwark and his Son, of their Watches and some Money, which he own'd since his Condemnation; and Mr. Sherrard's Son was with him on Saturday last, and he informed him where the Watches were pawn'd, and desired his Wife to go with him, that he might have them, which she accordingly did.</p>
            <p>He likewise robb'd one Mr. Dansey an eminent Surgeon in Grace-church-street, and Mr. Bateman who keeps the Globe and Crane Tavern at Islington, in the Lower-street, there they took from Mr. Dansey about 15 s. and from Mr. Bateman about 3 or 4 s. and then rode off.</p>
            <p>On Sunday, between Five and Six o'Clock, Phillips's Wife by his desire brought his Son to th Press-Yard, that he might take his last Farewell of him; and as soon as he saw him, he took him in his Arms, and cried over him; and begg'd of his Wife to train him up in the Fear of God, and never let him neglect the Service of his Creator; and particularly to take Care when grown up, what Company he kept; which if he had done, had not brought himself to this unhappy Misfortune, nor to suffer such an ignominious Death. After which, he turn'd again to his Wife and said, he hop'd she wou'd regard what he said, and oblige him, it being his last Request, to bring both his Children (having another) up in the Fear of God. After he had done speaking, he took the Child again in his Arms, and kiss'd it, as he did likewise his Wife, with Tears in his Eyes, and said, Pray God bless you, and preserve you, and my dear Children.</p>
            <p>
               <persName id="OA17350922n37-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n37-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n37-1" type="surname" value="CONNOR"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n37-1" type="given" value="CHARLES"/>Charles Connor</persName>, was indicted for the Murder of his Wife, <persName id="OA17350922n37-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n37-2" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n37-2" type="surname" value="CONNOR"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n37-2" type="given" value="ISABELLA"/>Isabella Connor</persName>, by beating her on the Head, Shoulder, Arms, Breast, and otherwise treating her barbarously and unmercifully, of which mortal Wounds and Bruises she died; and he was, by the Jury capitally convicted of Murder for the same.</p>
            <p>8. <persName id="OA17350922n38-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n38-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n38-1" type="surname" value="CONNOR"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n38-1" type="given" value="CHARLES"/>Charles Connor</persName>, 37 Years of Age, born in Shoreditch, of honest Parents, who gave him a little Education at School, to read God's Word, Write and Cypher, and instructed him in Religious Principles. He was bred a Sawyer, which Business he constantly follow'd, and provided very well for his Wife and Children that way. He was two or three Voyages at Sea in his Majesty's Ships of War; having been in the Baltick, Mediterranean, and other Places. He married a Wife, who (to his Grief) prov'd the Occasion of his Death, and who bare him several Children, three of whom are now living, and on the Parish to be provided for. He liv'd in Shoreditch-Parish, where he was born, being belov'd in the Neighbourhood, and employ'd in his Business by all that knew him. His Wife was an honest Woman, and</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA173509220010"/>
            <p>abundantly tender of and loving to her Children, and her Husband also; but her Misfortune was, as he alledg'd, to be addicted to drinking, and what Money he brought Home, being, 15, 16, or 17 Shillings per Week, he always gave it to her; but she was always wanting, and scarce made it serve his Family; upon this Account he reflected on her, alledging that she drank, and was too much inclined to Company. This she denied, affirming that she could not manage better; however, from Words upon this Head, they frequently came to Blows, which made her Life a Burthen. Sometimes she promis'd to rectify what was amiss, but never perform'd; and upon that Score he never neglected to beat her.</p>
            <p>She lately being brought to Bed, he complain'd, that he could not maintain an idle Woman and four Children, she being but seven Days lain in Bed, said, in a few Days she hoped, as she recover'd Strength, to help him in doing for the Family. He had no Patience, but in his Passion dragg'd her out of the Bed and treated her so ill, that she never recover'd the Hurts she then receiv'd.</p>
            <p>Not long after that, coming Home one Evening, she complain'd of her Son of Seven Years of Age, that he had been calling her B-h, whereupon he took something to throw at the Boy, but with it he gave the Mother a Blow on the Breast, of which she languish'd 'till the next Day and then died.</p>
            <p>She told some of the Neighbours, that her Husband had murder'd her; but spoke to him very kindly, expressing her great Dislike that some threatened to cause him to be taken up for Murder, hoping that the Neighbourhood would spare him for the Sake of his Children, and freely, and in a very friendly, loving Manner, forgave him.</p>
            <p>I told him, that her privately forgiving him, did not oblige the Law of God, and of the Land, to forgive him for the Sin of Murder; and therefore I exhorted him to repent, as a Murderer ought to do, and not to pretend in the least to extenuate his Crime.</p>
            <p>He was very calm and submissive, promising, by the Grace of God, to reform and make his Peace with God. He confess'd that he was a great Sinner, and beg'd Pardon of God and all Men. He was very sedate, and mightily troubled for what he had done, and particularly the sad Calamity he had brought upon his poor Children and Family.</p>
            <p>He behav'd with very much Seriousness and Devotion. He believ'd in Christ, hoping for Mercy from God through the Merits of Jesus Christ; he repented of all his Sins; and was in Charity with all the World.</p>
            <p>On Saturday Evening, about six o'Clock, his Mother and Sister came to see him; and as soon as they saw him, they both hung about his Neck; his Mother crying over him, and saying, Oh! my Dear Child, must I part with you for ever? Oh! What have you brought yourself to, and your poor innocent Babes, whom will be depriv'd of both Father and Mother. He reply'd, I hope God of his infinite Mercy will assist them; and if they put their Trust in him, he will be both. Dear Mother and Sister, I never intended to hurt my Wife, as I am a dying Man; therefore I hope God will have Mercy on my poor Soul. His Mother and Sister crying all the Time, and hanging about his Neck, and with some Difficulty they were got from him, repeating the following Words, viz Lord have Mercy on you, Christ have Mercy on you, and receive your poor Soul.</p>
            <p>The following is a Copy of a Letter he sent to Mr. <persName id="OA17350922n47-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n47-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n47-1" type="surname" value="BLIZARD"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n47-1" type="given" value="EDMUND"/>Edmund Blizard</persName>, living at the Sign of the London Apprentice, near Hoxton-Square, in Shoreditch.</p>
            <p>September, the 18th, 1735.</p>
            <p>Mr. Blizard.</p>
            <p>THIS from your humble Servant Charles Conner, Sir, I return you a thousand Thanks for all your great Kindness to me and mine, which I hope God will Recompence you for it, the Prayers of Almighty God be with</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA173509220011"/>
            <p>you, and yours, hoping the Lord will make you Recompence and yours; and I pray God Prosper you and yours, as long as you live for the extraordinary Favour done unto me, and mine; my Prayers to God for all Friends and Neighbours, hoping that they won't Reflect upon my poor Friends and Children, for my Misfortune that has befell me, which I never intended, nor did I ever think of coming to such a shameful End, which, I hope God in his Great Power will have Mercy on my poor Soul, and forgive me all my Sins as I put my Trust in him; and I begg of all Love that you would desire all such Friends, that shall come to see me Dye, that they will be so good as not to let the Surgeons have my Body, but to give me their Assistance, for my Brothers and other Friends have promised me so to do, which I hope in God they will, for my Desire is to lay by my Wife if possible I can; I begg of all Love that my Acquaintance that comes, that they will be so good as to assist my <persName id="OA17350922n51-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n51-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n51-1" type="surname" value="HOME"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n51-1" type="given" value="BODY"/>Body Home</persName>, which I hope in God they will, and in so doing I shall be thankful for it. So to the Lord I recommend my Soul, and the blessing of Almighty God be with you and yours for ever, Amen I pray God.</p>
            <p>But as for Elizabeth Also, and Mrs. Williams, I hope God will forgive them, for falsly ccusing of me in Court, saying I palled my Wife out of Bed the first Week she lay Inn, and made her Rise to dress my Sundays Dinner, which is as false as God is true, for I never offered any such Thing to her, nor have I ever struck her for a long while before she lay Inn, nor since till she told me the Boy called her B - h, which she desired I would beat him for his Sauciness. She seeing me in a great Passion, she was set on the Bd, and the Boy on the other side of her and rising to save him, by that means I struck her, but not with any design to her at all; but some Neighbours hearing that I had struck her, presently said that I had kill'd her; my Wife hearing of this, sent for me Home, telling me, she was Sorry that they should Charge me with any such Thing, and that she believed her Time was come, had it not happened so, and said, if she thought any Body should Reflect upon me, she should never rest in her Grave at Peace; and begged of God, I would be both Father and Mother to the Children when she was gone I promised her so to do, then she desired of me, that I would give her a little Wine, which I accordingly did; she desir'd me to drink to her, which I did; she then took me about the Neck and Kissed me, begging of God to preserve me and my Children, and said she did not Question my Care over them; and so I conclude in the Name of God, begging of all Friends to pray for me and mine, and in so doing, I hope God will Requite you for it.</p>
            <p>It is a sad Thing to be left Friendless, and had such Friends appeared as see, and knew the whole Nature of the Action, I think I never should have Suffered this shameful Death, which I now must Suffer. Mr. Blizard, I beg of all Love that you will come and see me before</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA173509220012"/>
            <p>I Dye. I desire that you would let your Neighbours read this for Satisfaction.</p>
            <p>Is from, Your Humble Servant,</p>
            <p>
               <persName id="OA17350922n56-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n56-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n56-1" type="surname" value="CONNER"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n56-1" type="given" value="CHARLES"/>Charles Conner</persName>.</p>
            <p>
               <persName id="OA17350922n57-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n57-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n57-1" type="surname" value="FARREL"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n57-1" type="given" value="JAMES"/>James Farrel</persName>, and <persName id="OA17350922n57-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n57-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n57-2" type="surname" value="HOOPER"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n57-2" type="given" value="CHARLES"/>Charles Hooper</persName>, were indicted for robbing <persName id="OA17350922n57-3">
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n57-3" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n57-3" type="surname" value="WOOD"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n57-3" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Wood</persName>, of his Hat, Wig and a pair of Buckles, on the Highway, near White-Chappel Mount.</p>
            <p>James Farrel Eighteen years of Age, of honest respected Parents, who educated him well at School, in every thing he was willing to learn, to prepare him for Business, and instructed him in Christian Principles. He did not go to any Trade, trusting to his Father, who had some little Estate or Business. He got into bad Company, who advised him to vicious Courses, particular of his Companion Hooper, and this proved his utter Ruin. He married a Wife without the Consent of his Friends, which was no small Disadvantage to him. He owned the Fact he was convicted of, but would not acknowledge any other Theft or Robbery, having had no Pretence of Dishonesty, since his Parents wanted not to supply him plentifully. They took the Hat Peruke and Buckles of Mr. Wood, as in the Indictment, and that the Buckles were found upon him, which made the Robbery clear upon them, without doubt. He was a poor young unthinking Lad. He behaved very well and christianly under his Misfortunes, declaring that he believed in Jesus Christ, hoping for Salvation in and through him; he sincerely repented of his Sins, and was in Peace with all the World.</p>
            <p>10 <persName id="OA17350922n59-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n59-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n59-1" type="surname" value="HOOPER"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n59-1" type="given" value="CHARLES"/>Charles Hooper</persName>, nineteen years old, of honest Parents in Town, who educated him at School, to read, write and cast Accompts; and when of Age they put him to a Baker; but he not loving Confinement, in two or three years time left his Master, and took to idle Company. He sold sometimes Hankerchiefs about the Streets, and generally cheated and imposed upon Strangers; in this Way he got Money; but was so idly inclined, that he only went about two or three Days in a Week, dedicating the rest of his Time to loose and profligate Conversation. He confest the Robbery he died for, and two or three more, and that he intended to prosecute that manner of Life, tho' in this Justice prevented him He also owned, that he was of a very wicked Disposition, having been addicted to all those Vices, those unfortunate Creatures are liable to. Farrel and Hooper imputed the Misfortunes of young, until ing People about the Town, in a great Measure, to the Gin-Shops, where they meet with the vilest of Company, who altogether corrupted their Morals, and made them good for nothing. He acknowledged the Justice of his Sentence. When he received the Sacrament in the Chapel, the Morning they were executed, Hooper fainted away, as I gave him the Cup, but instantly recovering, he desired it again, and his Request was granted. These two last were Brethren in Iniquity, and did not seem so much affected as the rest, but when I spoke to them they behaved with the utmost Submission, and gave all the Satisfaction that could be desired. <persName id="OA17350922n59-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n59-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n59-2" type="surname" value="HOOPER"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n59-2" type="given" value="CHARLES"/>Charles Hooper</persName> declared his Faith in Christ; that he sincerely repented of all his Sins, and freely forgave all Men, as he expected Forgiveness from God.</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA173509220013"/>
            <p>At the Place of EXECUTION.</p>
            <p>BEtween 9 and 10 o'Clock they were brought out of Newgate, and conveyed to Tyburn in four Carts, viz. Whitney, Matthews and Togwel, for the Rape in the first Cart; Farrel, Hooper and Lewis, (the first for robbing the Man near White-Chapel Mount, and the latter for a Burglary) in the second Cart; Gaffney and Phillips in the third; and Connor for the Murder of his Wife, and Dennis for a Street Robbery in the fourth Cart.</p>
            <p>They all appeared very devout and serious, both at Prayers and singing of Psalms. <persName id="OA17350922n62-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n62-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n62-1" type="surname" value="GAFFNEY"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n62-1" type="given" value="PATRICK"/>Patrick Gaffney</persName> and <persName id="OA17350922n62-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n62-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n62-2" type="surname" value="MATTHEWS"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n62-2" type="given" value="PETER"/>Peter Matthews</persName> were of the Romish Communion. They desired their Friends might not be reflected on, upon their Account, as did all the rest. Connor own'd that his frequent abusing and striking his Wife had killed her, and that he was heartily grieved for the same. <persName id="OA17350922n62-3">
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n62-3" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n62-3" type="surname" value="PHILLIPS"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n62-3" type="given" value="WILLIAM"/>William Phillips</persName>, alias Clark, &amp;c. hoped the World would not make his Wife and Children suffer upon his Account. <persName id="OA17350922n62-4">
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n62-4" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n62-4" type="surname" value="LEWIS"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n62-4" type="given" value="WILLIAM"/>William Lewis</persName> desired, that the Woman in New-Prison who past for his Wife, might be admonished to reform and mend her evil Ways and turn to God. And also said, he had been a very great Sinner, and desired the Spectators to pray for him. And calling upon a Person whom he saw there, he said to him, You have deceived me; and one End of the Halter of the next Person that was tyed up with him touching his Face, he said two was too much, for that one was enough to hang him.</p>
            <p>They all went off the Stage crying out, God have mercy on our Souls; Lord Jesus receive our Spirits. After all Devotions were ended, <persName id="OA17350922n63-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n63-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n63-1" type="surname" value="WHITNEY"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n63-1" type="given" value="JAMES"/>James Whitney</persName> desired me to give them one short Prayer more; accordingly I repeated a Prayer, earnestly beseeching Almighty God to have Mercy upon them, to give them his holy Spirit, to guide them through the dark Valley of the Shadow of Death, and to commit their Souls unto the Hands of Angels, to carry them into Abraham's Bosom, that Place of eternal Rest and Peace, which is prepared for the Saints and Children of God. Amen.</p>
            <p>This is all the Account given by me,</p>
            <p>
               <persName id="OA17350922n65-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n65-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n65-1" type="surname" value="GUTHRIE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n65-1" type="given" value="JAMES"/>JAMES GUTHRIE</persName>,</p>
            <p>Ordinary of Newgate.</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA173509220014"/>
            <p>APPENDIX.</p>
            <p>The following is an Account of all the Robberies committed by <persName id="OA17350922n68-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n68-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n68-1" type="surname" value="LEWIS"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n68-1" type="given" value="WILLIAM"/>William Lewis</persName>.</p>
            <p>HE said that about four or five Years ago, he and two more broke open a House in the City of Hereford, they having been in the Shop several times on frivolous Errands, on Purpose to find where the Money lay; which being acquainted with, they one Night broke the Brick-work under the Shop-window, and entered into the Shop, and took out of the Till about 5 or 6 l. but being discovered, and a Pistol fired, they made off, without proceeding further in robbing the House; for this Burglary he and one of his Companions were taken, and he persuaded to be an Evidence against him, which he refusing, his Companion was admitted, who accused two innocent Persons, whom were tried and acquitted, and his Companion being held in Custody, at the next Assizes was found guilty of the Felony only; for which he was whipt.</p>
            <p>About three or four Months after this, he and another stop't a Man on Horseback, within ten Miles of Bristol, who they had seen at an Inn, where they had been drinking, receive sixty Guineas; they went out sometime before him, and having come to a proper Place, stripped themselves to their Shirts by way of Disguise, and waited his coming, when he took hold of the Horse's Bridle, while the other demanded his Money; but the Man giving him only some Half-pence and a little silver, he said to him D - n you, you Rogue, what do you mean? I will have your Bit, (meaning his Purse) or I will shoot you, and shewing him a Brass-barrell'd Pistol without a Lock, it so surprized the Man that he let him put his Hand into his Pocket, and take out the Purse with the Money in it; which done he ordered him to ride on, or else he would shoot him. They afterwards went to the Place where they had left their Cloths, and he sewed the Money in the Waistband of his Breeches; they then went</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA173509220015"/>
            <p>for Bristol, where the Person who had been robbed seeing him, got him apprehended, and being brought before the Mayor of Bristol, the Man not being possitive to him he was discharged.</p>
            <p>After his Discharge at Bristol, he went to France, where he listed himself a Soldier in the French King's Service, from which he deserted, and travelled 'till Night, when he came to a House near a Wood, and asked whether he could lodge there. The Woman of the House asked him what Country he was, he desired to know her Reason; she told him she had been informed that an Englishman had deserted from the French Army; he then told her he was an Irishman, upon which she bid him ask in Irish for a Lodging, his Reply to her was, Hyke up to the Gigger, and undubb it, and Wittle to the Cove of the Ken, and ask him for a Doss, (that is, go up to the Door and unlock it, and ask the Landlord for a Bed) on which she said, now English it, which he did, saying, Pray Madam, can I have a Lodging here? She answered him, it was very good English, and Irish too she believed. The next Morning he went from thence, and concealed himself in the Woods 'till Evening, not thinking it convenient to travel in the Day-time, for fear of being taken for Desertion; from thence he got to the Sea-side, where a Vessel going off, he shipp'd himself on Board her, and came to England, where he followed Picking of Pockets, and other trivial Robberies; and if he met with a Dossy Cull (that is, a Man asleep) he Bit him (that is, Robbed him.)</p>
            <p>Some Time ago he listed himself a Soldier in the East-India Company's Service, for which he received Five Guineas Entrance, and being put on Board, he took an opportunity of escaping from thence, by tying his Cloaths to a Board that belonged to the Ship, which he threw over-board, and jumpt after it himself, and swam to Shore.</p>
            <p>About a Year and a half ago he stabbed a Man in St. James's Hay-Market, for which he was committed to Newgate, where he continued 'till the next Sessions at Hicks's-Hall, and being tried for the same, was found guilty, and ordered to Clerkenwell-Bridewell to hard Labour for twelve Months; his Time of Confinement being near expired, his Grandmother dying, left him her Effects, which amounted to 40 Pounds and upwards, which he lodged in the Keepers Hands; the best Part of which he took away with him when discharged; but being at Liberty he soon spent it, and took to his old Course of Picking Pockets. That some Time in May last he knocked a Woman down in St. James's Hay-Market, intending to rob her; but she crying out Murder and Thieves, some People coming out of a Night-Cellar, he ran away, but being pursued, he drew a Hanger, and striking at them, they avoiding his Blow, he cut his own Shoe quite through, and</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA173509220016"/>
            <p>one of them jumping upon him, took him; for this Fact, he was committed to the Gatehouse, where he continued for some Time.</p>
            <p>A little before this intended Robbery, he pick'd up a Woman of the Town, who took him to her Lodgings, and after their being in Bed some Time, finding her asleep, he strip'd her and the Lodgings, and threw the Things out of the Window, and jump'd after them, and carried them off.</p>
            <p>A few Days after his Discharge from the Gatehouse, he and another broke open the House of Mr. Lee, in Short's-Gardens near Drury-lane, between 12 and 1 o'Clock, by wrenching two wooden Bars out of the Cellar Window, from whence they took three silver Tankards that were in a little Cupboard over the Cellar Stairshead; he said he went into the Cellar while his Companion staid in the Street to tipp Tommy, (that is to keep in if any Body came by) while he was in the Cellar, a Woman of the Town came up to his Companion and would have persuaded him to go along with her; but upon his giving her Sixpence and bidding her go, and he would follow her, she went away; after she was gone he came out of the Cellar with the Tankards, making a little whistle to his Companion as an Item that he had spoke (meaning he had got them) they then put them under their Coats, and carried them to the Longfields near Bloomsbury, where they tied them up in their Handkerchiefs, and from thence went to the Sign of the Cock at the Brill near Pancrass, where knocking at the Door, the Woman of the House looked out of Window and asked who was there, he answered Will. Lewis, I have got three Clinks to sell (meaning the Tankards) upon which she replied she would have nothing to do with them. From thence they carried them to Mrs. Morris's in Eagle-Court in the Strand, where they broke them to pieces and melted them down in Crucibles, which being weighed by her old battered Weights, which she kept for such Purposes, amounted to no more than 46 Ounces, though there were near eighty Ounces, and for which she gave them upwards of nine Pounds.</p>
            <p>The Sunday following, about Two o'Clock in the Afternoon, he and his Companion having agreed to take a Walk in the Fields, and coming thro' Crown-Court, Sohoe, seeing a Man in Liquor, he went up to him, and picked his Pocket of his Watch, which they pawned the next Day for 35 s.</p>
            <p>The next Day he and his Companion, with two Women of the Town, went down by Water to Greenwich in a Boat, with other Passengers in it, when perceiving a Gentleman to pull out a Silver Snuff-Box, they resolved to have it, and on the Gentleman's landing at Deptford, he got up with a Pretence of ballancing the Boat, and picked his Pocket of it, and sold it for 12 s. 6 d. at the best Hand. Af</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA173509220017"/>
            <p>ter they had been at Greenwich they came to Deptford, and took Lodgings at the Red-Hart-Inn, where they stayed two or three Days; but the Ladies thinking the Lodgings too mean for them, they returned to Greenwich, where they took Lodgings, in a Place called Back-Lane, to their Satisfaction, having agreed to pay 5 s. a Week for 'em; they had not been there above a Night before the People of the Neighbourhood came to desire their Custom, upon which he replyed, Aye, withal his Heart, provided they would use them kindly; and then ordered them to send in a Kilderkin of Beer, three Bushels of Coals, and a Peck of Small-Coal, which was accordingly done (though never paid for) They had not been many Days there, before a Butcher of the Town knowing one of their Ladies, came to the House, and acquainted the Landlord what they were, and said he would have the Lodgings search'd, for though they went for Gentlefolks, he was sure they were Whores and Thieves; upon which they thought proper to pack up their Implements, which were a dark Lanthorn, and other Instruments fit for their Purpose (which if Opportunity had permitted they intended to make use of) and went off the next Morning early, without taking Leave of their Landlord, or paying any Rent; and coming to London, not having any Money, their Ladies were obliged to shift for themselves.</p>
            <p>In a Night or two after they came from Greenwich, they went towards Hide-Park, where meeting a Gentleman, they bid him Stand, his Companion holding up a Rule to the Gentleman, which touching his Face, it so surprized him (thinking it was a Pistol) he turned his Head from it, and said, Gentlemen, don't misuse me, and you shall have all I have; upon which his Companion trembling very much, took from him his Hat, and about 6 s. in Money, they then lost him, and went into the Fields towards Grosvenour-Square, and in or near Grosvenour-Street, they stop'd a Gentleman with the same Rule (they having at that Time no other Weapon) who not being willing to be robbed, beat them with his Cane, and crying out, Murder and Thieves, they ran away, having taken his Hat from him; he taking to the Fields again, and his Companion, through the Square, walking soberly (with a Bag under his Arm with the Persons Hats in it which they had just robbed before) without being suspected by the Chairmen, whom he was obliged to pass by. In about an Hour after, his Companion met him by chance, at a Chandler's Shop in Shug-Lane, where he was treating a Woman of the Town with a Dram, and from thence went to their Lodgings at the Grayhound-Inn in Drury-Lane.</p>
            <p>The next Day they met again, and sold the Hats for 5 s. 6 d. in Chick-Lane, near Saffron-Hill; but having</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA173509220018"/>
            <p>spent their Money that Evening, they went towards Kensington, and near the Gore there, about Eleven o'Clock at Night, they met Mr. Durrant, a Cook, belonging to the King's Kitchen, whom they stop'd and robbed of a Silver Watch, half a Crown, and a Silver Pocket-Piece, which Mr. Durrant desiring them to return him, they refused; while they were rifling him, he desired they would not use him ill; they told him they would not, and that it was mere Necessity that obliged them to rob him; he said, they sold the Pocket-Piece the next Day for 4 s. 6 d. in Rag-Fair.</p>
            <p>From thence they came to Clerkenwell-Bridewell, his Wife laying there for her Fees, they discharged her, and went to Sir John Oldcastle's, where they staid drinking 'till Evening, and having parted with her, they went towards Knightsbridge (having provided themselves with Hangers and Pistols) where they stop'd a Man, from whom they took about 28 s. and a Bunch of Keys, which he desiring them to return, they gave him no Answer; he had not been gone from them a few Yards, but his Companion called after him, and bid him stop, who replying, What do you want? He said his Buckles; the Person replied, don't hinder yourselves, and thereupon came back, and his Companion took the Buckles out of his Shoes (which were Silver) and in lieu thereof returned him the Bunch of Keys, and bid him good Night, and made off; and came to a House near St. Clement's-Church, where they shared the Booty. And about Two o'Clock in the Morning, coming down Fleet-street, near Chancery-Lane End, they overtook a Gentleman in Liquor, whom they followed 'till they came near Water-Lane, where they pushed him down, and his Companion took his Hat from off his Head; but the Gentleman crying out, and the Watchman being near, he ran up Wine-Office-Court with it, imagining that the Passage at the upper End had been open, but finding to the contrary he endeavour'd to get over some iron Pallisades, at the corner House on the left Hand, but stuck by the Foot and Thigh (having thrown the Hat and a Hanger into the Yard) and not being able to quit himself, the Watchman came up to him, and seeing him, asked what Business he had there; and told him that if he did not come down he would knock him down with his Staff; but on his telling him that he lodged at Mr. Carman's, and it being late, was willing to make as little Noise as he could to get in, least he should disturb the Neighbourhood; this Excuse, and being well dressed, deceived the Watchman; who said to him, Sir, you appear like a Gentleman, but there being a Gentleman robbed in Fleet-street, and the Person that robbed him seen to come up this Court, I must desire you to go with me to him, to see whether he knows you or not; to which he readily complied, who being asked by the Watch</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA173509220019"/>
            <p>man, whether he would charge him as the Man that robbed him, he answered, Aye, I think I will; but he telling him that if he had done him any Injury, he would make him Satisfaction, and at the same Time pulling out of his Pocket near a Handful of Gold and Silver, and shewing it, the Gentleman said, No Sir, I will not say you are the Man, you look too much like a Gentleman; upon his being discharged, he insisted the Gentleman should not go Home bare-headed, therefore took the Hat off of his own Head, and made him accept of it; after which he came to me in Fleet-street, and telling me where he had left the Hat and Hanger, I went and fetch'd them. We then went into Holbourn, and on a Bulk, near Gray's-Inn-Gate, divided that Night's Booty, which while we were doing, a Chairman came by, and said, Brave Boys, you have made a good Night's Work on't don't cheat one another; we then parted, and did not go out again for 2 or 3 Days, my Companion-being lamed by the Spikes.</p>
            <p>His Companion being recovered, they went to Berkley-street in Piccadilly, where they stop'd a Gentleman; but a Coach going by, they insisted he should go down the Street with them, which he did, saying, Gentlemen, don't use me ill, and I will go with you; from him they took half a Guinea in Gold, and 14 Shillings in Silver, and shook him by the Hand, and bid him good Night. From thence they came to Town, and parted for that Night. The next Night they went to Vigo-Lane, near Swallow-Street, where they stop'd a Gentleman, and took from him a Purse, in which was a Guinea, a Key of a Watch, and a Steel Seal, and about 8 Shillings in Silver loose in his Pocket, after which they made him sit on the Step of a Door, and take his Silver Buckles out of his Shoes, which they took from him, and bid him go down the Street, telling him, if he spoke a Word they would shoot him.</p>
            <p>The next Night about 12 o'Clock they went the same way again, and near the Duke of Queensborough's, they stopped a Gentleman, from whom they took a silver Watch, five Guineas, and a Coat and Breeches, which he had under his Arm, but he desiring them to be returned they refused him, and after having left him he cried out stop Thieves; upon which they threw the Cloaths away over the Rails, fearing if they were taken to be discovered by them, and a Chairman imagining that the Cry was Chair, ran and cried, who calls Chair, they then made off, and in a short time returned and fetched the Cloaths, which they found to be only part of a Livery Suit, which they had imagined to have been better, they being lined with Scarlet.</p>
            <p>The next Robbery they committed, was on Dr. Barker, whom they saw stand with two more Gentlemen at Slaughter's Coffee-house Door, in St. Martin's-Lane, near 12 o'Clock at Night, where waiting till they parted, they followed the Doctor to Thrift-street, where he laid hold of him on the left Arm, and the Doctor drew his Sword with his Right, and going</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA173509220020"/>
            <p>to make a push at him with it, he retreated about a yard or two, and presented a Pistol at him, which his Companion seeing pushed him on one Side, and with his Hanger cut the Doctor over his left Eye, the Doctor having with his Sword cut a Bit of his Finger off, they then threw him down, and he saying Gentlemen save my Life, I'll give you my gold Watch; but his Companion insisting to have his Sword, also he refused it, saying, he would deliver the Hilt provided they would let him have the Blade; but being denied, they took the Sword away from him, his Companion telling him he would break the Blade himself and return it; after they had got the Sword they robbed him of his gold Watch and three Pence half-penny, and a Pocket Piece. While they were robbing the Doctor, a Woman looking out of a Window of the House where they stopt him, cryed out, are you not ashamed to rob a Man at my Door, on which he replied, you B - if you speak another Word I'll shoot you. Tey then made off. The next Night they met a Gentleman in New-port-street about 1 o'Clock whom they stopt and demanded his Money, he being surprized cryed, ha', ha' (being an Outlandish Man) and taking out his Watch himself by the Chain, his Companion took hold of the Watch, and the Person robbed by the Chain, when pulling he let go the Chain, and he seeing his Companion reel, thought he was running away; whereupon he run, and the Person robbed run after them a little way; but his Companion turning short with his Hanger in his Hand, soon made him go about his Business.</p>
            <p>The next Night they went to Little Chelsea, having Intelligence of a Linnen-Draper's Shop, which they intended to break open; but finding they had not Tools sufficient they came back to London, and in Leicester-Fields, the next Door to Justice Deveil's they stopt a Gentleman, thinking it to be the Justice, but found to the contrary; they robbed him of a silver Watch and 25 Shillings and 5 Pence 3 Farthings; then taking his Cane from him threw it away, and ordered him to go and fetch it while they went off another way; he said to his Companion D - n seize me, if it had been the Justice he would have shot him, for sending him to Newgate, from whence he was by an Order of the Court at the next Sessions at Hick's Hall carried up there, and tried, and sentenced to remain in Clerkenwell-Bridewell to hard Labour, for twelve Months. They then came home to his Lodgings in Brown's-Gardens near Monmouth-street, and shared the Booty, and his Companion taking up the odd Farthing, it put him into such a Rage that he took up a Pistol, and swore if it had been Six-pence he would have shot him.</p>
            <p>A few Nights after they met a Gentleman at the End of Crown-Court, near St. Ann's Sohe, whom they stopt, and took from him a silver Watch; but a Link-Boy and a Watchman comeing near, they made the Person come</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA173509220021"/>
            <p>into the Court, not having compleated the Robbery, and there they took from him 9 s. but the Person telling them he did not know where he was, followed them, on which he shewed him a Pistol, and told him if did not go back again he would shoot him, on which he turned back quietly, and they made off.</p>
            <p>A Night or two after, finding nothing would answer their Purpose, coming through James-street, they observed a Peuke-maker's Shop with no Body in it, upon which they lifted up the Sash, with an Intent to take some Wigs away, but on his Companion's making an Entry, he hit his Head against the Sash, and only took away three or four Razors, and went away fearing the Noise he had made would alarm the House. This Booty they made a Present of.</p>
            <p>The Monday before they were taken they stopt Mr. Bathurst in Fetter-lane, near Fleet-street; the Watch just having gone the Hour of Two, from whence they took a silver Watch, 2 s. 6 d. in silver and some Half-pence, telling him if he offered to cry out they would shoot him; they also took from him a Handkerchief and Snuff-Box, which they returned him again, and he said they might return him any thing else if they would, for he would receive it; they then bid him go down the Lane, but he begging to go up, saying it was all the same, they permitted him, and heard him Ring about two Doors higher after having left him.</p>
            <p>The next Night they broke open a House in Gerrard-street, which they had been to view under a Pretence of Drinking; but having seen several silver Tankards in a Cupboard in the Bar, were resolv'd to have them: From whence they took only a Great Coat, the Tankards being removed, which they believ'd to be on the Woman's taking Notice of their Curiosity, they having over heard her speak to a Person the Day before, that she had some Suspicion of them.</p>
            <p>The next Night they stopt a Gentleman in North-street near Red-Lyon-Square, who resisting them with his Cane, his Companion cut him over the Head with his Hanger, and he supposing the Man to be too strong for him fired a Pistol, not knowing where the Ball might hit; shot him in the Back, but the Wound not being mortal, he turned about and ran after him, crying Stop Thief: Finding himself so closely pursued by the Gentleman and the Watch, who struck at him, he threw away his Fire Arms and made his Escape, his Companion having taken another Way, and hid his Hanger and Pistol in Queen-square; and coming up Gloucester-street, where hearing a Woman cry out Watch, was afraid to stir any further, for fear she should suspect him; but on the Watchman's asking what she would please to have, she said a Surgeon, and desired him to get one, for the Gentleman was sadly wounded, having had a Ball taken out of his Back by the People of the House, and that they were afraid there were more in his Body: Another Person at the same Time crying out, Are</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA173509220022"/>
            <p>any of the Rogues took, and being answered No; he went back to the Place where he had hid the Hanger and Pistol and took them, and found me in Holbourn sorrowful, fearing I had shot him. He went Home that Morning, and acquainted his Wife with the ill Success they had met with, and that he had lost his Pistol, and desired her to pawn her Gown to buy another, but she refusing, he jumpt out of Bed, and cut it to Pieces.</p>
            <p>The next Night being Thursday, they stopt a Man near the New-Inn in Holbourn, who seem'd to them to be a Gentleman, (being very well dress'd,) but on his telling them that he was reduced, and upon any Enterprize would be willing to go with them, having told them where he liv'd; but not being satisfied they search'd him, and found what he had said was true. From thence they proceeded to Chancerylane, where seeing two Men part at the End of Cursitors-street; they followed the Person that went up that Street, taking it to be the Privatest, whom he stopt, but letting him loose after he had collar'd him, he made a Resistance with his Cane, when his Companion coming up they struck at him with their Hangers, not being willing to fire their Pistols for fear of Murder: He received several Cuts from them having defended himself with his Cane, and crying out, Watch and Murder; they were both forc'd to leave him, the Watch coming up from several Places, least they should be taken, making off with their Pistols and Hangers in Hand.</p>
            <p>From thence they went to King's Coffee-house in Covent-Garden Market, where they drank two Dishes of Coffee and then parted, it being Five o'Clock in the Morning, his Companion giving him his Hanger, telling him he was going into the Strand, where he should stay till about 12 or 1 o'Clock, and if he wanted any thing with him he would find him there. He said the Quarrel that he had had with his Wife two Nights before, in Relation to the cutting of her Gown, with the Persuasions of her Maid, occasion'd her to take out a Warrant for him, under the Pretence of going in Danger of her Life; but I found it was the contrary, upon which I was committed to Tothilfields-Bridewell for further Examination; about six Hours after his Wife having made an Information went with the Constable to the House of his Companion, who was also taken, and being carried before Justice De Veil, he told him, That he was a young Fellow that had lived in good Reputation till about six Weeks past, when he was seduced away by the said Lewis, for which he was very sorry, and would, without Hesitation, discover all he knew, if the Justice would make him an Evidence, which was accordingly granted; whereupon he discovered 9 or 10 Street-Robberies and Burglaries committed in the said Space of six Weeks, discovering also most of the People that had been robbed, which his Wife Margery Williams knew nothing of, but only in general, That they were Thieves.</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA173509220023"/>
            <p>The Account of the intended Escape which the following Persons did dedesign to make out on the Master-side of Newgate, before the last Sessions.</p>
            <p>ON the 16th of July last, one <persName id="OA17350922n101-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n101-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n101-1" type="surname" value="DEAN"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n101-1" type="given" value="JOSHUA"/>Joshua Dean</persName> (who was last Sessions capitally convicted, for counterfeiting the Impressure of Stamps on Paper, whom her Majesty hath been most graciously pleas'd to reprieve, in Order for Transportation during Life) was removed from the Common-side of Newgate to the Master's-side of the said Goal; where he had not been long, before his fellow Prisoners understood that he had an extraordinary Knowledge in Mechanicks; on which the following Persons did inform him that they had a Design to make their Escape, and hoped he would be so kind as to assist them, viz. <persName id="OA17350922n101-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n101-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n101-2" type="surname" value="HUTCHENSON"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n101-2" type="given" value="GEORGE"/>George Hutchenson</persName>, <persName id="OA17350922n101-3">
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n101-3" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n101-3" type="surname" value="BYROM"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n101-3" type="given" value="WILLIAM"/>William Byrom</persName>, <persName id="OA17350922n101-4">
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n101-4" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n101-4" type="surname" value="MACDONAL"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n101-4" type="given" value="CHARLES"/>Charles Macdonal</persName>, Thomas Macreigh and <persName id="OA17350922n101-5">
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n101-5" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n101-5" type="surname" value="JONES"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n101-5" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Jones</persName>, who were the chief Actors in the said Design; at which Time they shewed the said <persName id="OA17350922n101-6">
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n101-6" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n101-6" type="surname" value="DEAN"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17350922n101-6" type="given" value="JOSHUA"/>Joshua Dean</persName> that they could take of their Irons when they pleas'd, and also shewed him a Steel frame Saw, which was to cut the Barrs of the Windows; and likewise were endeavouring by several indifferent Ways to break out, particularly Htchenson attempted to get up the Chimnies, and in the Attempt he hurt his Breast and Shoulders, and informed the rest, that it was impracticable, by Reason of the Barrs that went a-cross the Chimnies; upon which Byrom replied, that he could cut the Barrs? Dean told them at the same Time the Difficulties they would meet with, and endeavoured to persuade them from their Enterprize, which he said, he thought on his Reasons, they had laid entirely aside.</p>
            <p>But soon after this they came to Dean again, and told him they had another Scheme, and said, Tho' you will not go with us, we beg you will be so kind as to give us your Opinion, for as it is not your Ward, it will no Ways affect you? Upon their Intreaties he went with them into the upper Ward, and there they shewed him a Window which looks into the Gateway; he told them, That it was impossible for them to make their Escape thro' that Window, altho' the Barr' were cut.</p>
            <p>After this they attempted to have made a Way into the Womens-side, and there to break thro' a Window, which some of the Women informed them it was very easie to do: But while this was in agitation, Mac Creigh (who was at that Time a Prisoner there) had contrived another Scheme for his Escape, which was unknown to the rest of his fellow Prisoners till he was gone, being in double Irons, and had so ordered it, that he could drop his Irons off when he pleas'd, he being best part of the Days drinking with some Company in the Cellar, a Person was in the Dusk of the Evening to come and see him, and while the Turnkey was opening the Door, Philips, alias Clark, alias Matthews, who was his Companion in his Robberies, was to come behind him and knock him down, and let out Mac Creigh, and thrust in the Turnkey, and lock the Door upon him at the same Time; but this was luckily prevented, for that very Evening it was to have been put in Practice, Mac Creigh was carried to the New-Goal in Southwark.</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA173509220024"/>
            <p>After this Dean said he thought they would be easie and quite lay aside any Thoughts of attempting it again; but Mac Creigh had not been long gone, but Byrom, Hutchenson and Jones one Night were cutting the Barrs of the Window in the Ward were Dean lay, they making such a Noise, Dean got out of his Bed, and said, He would discover them if they did not desist, upon which they did, and went to Bed.</p>
            <p>Soon after this a noted Woman of the Town, being committed for several Misdemeanors, she had contrived to dress Byrom up in Women's Cloathes and to paint his Face, and when the Keeper came to lock him up in his Ward, he was to come down thro' a Hole which was made for that Purpose, and a Company was to be provided below in the Cellar to wait for him, that he might promiscuously go out with them unsuspected; but she or some of them she rely'd on, fell from their Promises.</p>
            <p>A few Days after this, Philips alias Clark, alias Matthews, was committed to Newgate and brought over to the Master's-side, on Suspicion of Horsestealing, when they began another Scheme by his Contrivance, which was the most effectual of any that ever was thought on, viz. Having cut a Way down into a Place call'd the Hall, which is under the Wards they lie in, and also a Way up into the Womens Ward, that is over the Mens Ward, they could get up and down without the Knowledge of any other Prisoner that come in after, and not be privy to their Design. Being provided with proper Tools, they could have made Way to get clear off, and  would never have been so much  suspected, because the Keeper did not imagine that any one could come into the Hall in the Night, they being lock'd up in their Wards, it being a Story higher; and there being no one to hear or see, they could do what they would at their Leisure, and was to have been furnished with Pistols by some of Philip's, alias Clark's, ali Mathews's Friends against the Night they were to make their Escape.</p>
            <p>Philips a few Days before having sent a Person to have something flatte at Mr. James's in Giltspur-street, on purpose to view his Yard, and the rest of his Neighbourhood that laid adjoining to him; his Shed where his Men work, being just under the Window of the Goal, which was the Place for their intended Escape, and if any did oppose them, they were resolved to shoot them dead on the Spot.</p>
            <p>The Keepers having Intelligence of their Escapes, went over to the Master's-side one Evening (with proper Assistance,) and found several Tools, as a Saw, a Chissel, and some Steel, which the Watch-makers use for Springs of Watches, and several other Things for their Design; after they had examined the Places about the Master's-side, they brought over the chief Contrivers, and put them in the Old Condemn'd Hold, and chain'd them down, and there they lay  last Sessions.</p>
            <p>FINIS.</p>
         </div0>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>