<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<TEI.2>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div0 type="ordinarysAccount" id="OA17250104">
            <interp inst="OA17250104" type="uri" value="ordinarysAccounts/OA17250104"/>
            <interp inst="OA17250104" type="date" value="17250104"/>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA172501040001"/>
            <p>THE ORDINARY of NEWGATE his ACCOUNT, Of the Behaviour, Confession, and last Words of <persName id="OA17250104n2-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17250104n2-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17250104n2-1" type="surname" value="TOWERS"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17250104n2-1" type="given" value="CHARLES"/>Charles Towers</persName>, who was Executed at <placeName id="OA17250104-geo-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17250104-geo-1" type="type" value="parish"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA17250104n2-1 OA17250104-geo-1"/>
                  <placeName id="OA17250104-geo-2">
                     <interp inst="OA17250104-geo-2" type="type" value="parish"/>
                     <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA17250104n2-1 OA17250104-geo-2"/>Wapping</placeName> in the Parish of St. Paul Shadwell</placeName>, on Monday the 4th of this Instant January: And also of <persName id="OA17250104n2-3">
                  <interp inst="OA17250104n2-3" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17250104n2-3" type="surname" value="ANDERSON"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17250104n2-3" type="given" value="WILLIAM"/>William Anderson</persName>, who was Executed at <placeName id="OA17250104-geo-3">
                  <interp inst="OA17250104-geo-3" type="type" value="site"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA17250104n2-3 OA17250104-geo-3"/>Tyburn</placeName> on Tuesday the 5th of the aforesaid Month.</p>
            <p>AT the KING'S Commission of the Peace, and Oyer and Terminer and Goal-Delivery, &amp;c. Held (before the Right Honourable Sir <persName id="OA17250104n3-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17250104n3-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17250104n3-1" type="surname" value="Merttins"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17250104n3-1" type="given" value="George"/>George Merttins</persName> 
               <rs id="OA17250104-occupation-1" type="occupation">Knt</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17250104n3-1 OA17250104-occupation-1"/>. <rs id="OA17250104-occupation-2" type="occupation">Lord Mayor</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17250104n3-1 OA17250104-occupation-2"/>, the Right Honourable the Lord Chief Justice King, Mr. Justice Dormer, Mr. Baron Page, Mr. Serjeant Raby, and several of His Majesty's Justices of the Peace, for the City of London and County of Middlesex) at Justice-Hall in the <placeName id="OA17250104-geo-4">
                  <interp inst="OA17250104-geo-4" type="type" value="site"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17250104n3-1 n2-1 n2-3 n4-1 n4-2 OA17250104-geo-4"/>Old Baily</placeName>, on Friday, Saturday, Monday, Tuesday and Wednesday, being the 4th, 5th, 7th, 8th and 9th Days of December last, four Men were by the Jury found guilty of Capital Offences, and received Sentence accordingly.</p>
            <p>Two of the Persons, so sentenced, having obtained His Majesty's Reprieve, viz. <persName id="OA17250104n4-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17250104n4-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17250104n4-1" type="surname" value="SWANSON"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17250104n4-1" type="given" value="ROWLAND"/>Rowland Swanson</persName> and <persName id="OA17250104n4-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17250104n4-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17250104n4-2" type="surname" value="HERBERT"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17250104n4-2" type="given" value="THOMAS"/>Thomas Herbert</persName>; the remaining two, viz. <persName id="OA17250104n4-3">
                  <interp inst="OA17250104n4-3" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17250104n4-3" type="surname" value="TOWERS"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17250104n4-3" type="given" value="CHARLES"/>Charles Towers</persName> and <persName id="OA17250104n4-4">
                  <interp inst="OA17250104n4-4" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17250104n4-4" type="surname" value="ANDERSON"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17250104n4-4" type="given" value="WILLIAM"/>William Anderson</persName> were appointed for Execution.</p>
            <p>Though they at first (especially <persName id="OA17250104n5-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17250104n5-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17250104n5-1" type="surname" value="TOWERS"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17250104n5-1" type="given" value="CHARLES"/>Charles Towers</persName>) were incapacitated as to the performance of their Duty, by the Anger and Resentment their Condition had fill'd them with, (<persName id="OA17250104n5-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17250104n5-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17250104n5-2" type="surname" value="TOWERS"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17250104n5-2" type="given" value="CHARLES"/>Charles Towers</persName> in particular, at the same time that he acknowledged the rescuing the Prisoner West from the Hands of <persName id="OA17250104n5-3">
                  <interp inst="OA17250104n5-3" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17250104n5-3" type="surname" value="ERRINGTON"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17250104n5-3" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Errington</persName>, affirming he was no way designedly disguised and that he no way apprehended he had any occasion to disguise himself, any more than had Tims, Bowler, Tibbs, Fencote, or any other upon the same Enterprize)</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA172501040002"/>
            <p>Yet they afterwards became sensible of the Folly of their Resentment; and as the Friends and Relations of Towers refused to give him any Hopes of a Reprieve, or Expectations of Life, he changed his Passion into Grief and Sorrow, that he had lost, by his neglect, the Use of Letters and Reading. As <persName id="OA17250104n6-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17250104n6-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17250104n6-1" type="surname" value="Swanson"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17250104n6-1" type="given" value="Rowland"/>Rowland Swanson</persName> of the Four was alone able to Read, he very industriously assisted his Fellow Prisoners, and call'd upon them to listen to the Scriptures early each Morning, and before they went to Rest at Night. They were all very frequent and regular in their Devotions, when alone by themselves, as well as constant attendants at the Chapel; and 'twas thought apparent they never had any Designs of making an escape from Justice, and the execution of the Sentence that was pass'd upon 'em.</p>
            <p>Immediately after their Conviction, the Words they were first instructed from were taken out of the xiv of St. Luke, verse 26.</p>
            <p>If any Man come to Me, and hate not his Father and Mother, and Wife and Children, and Brethren and Sisters, yea and his own Life also, he cannot be my Disciple.</p>
            <p>The Prisoners who were under the Sentence and Conviction of the Law, appeared to be very serious and attentive while they were directed to postpone every Engagement to God and Religion; to let go the Thoughts of the World, Friends, Kindred, and of Life itself, and place their Hearts upon Heaven, and those Treasures, which Moth and Rust cannot corrupt, and where Thieves do not break through and steal. Because the Folly of those is great, who say, To-day or to-morrow we will go into such a City, and continue there a Year, and buy and sell and get Gain: The Apostle tells them as follows, Whereas ye know not what shall be on the Morrow; for what is your Life? it is even a Vapour that appeareth for a little time, and then vanisheth away, James iv. ver. 13, 14. It were better therefore to say with the Psalmist, How amiable are thy Tabernacles O Lord of Hosts. Blessed are they that dwell in thy House, they will be still praising thee. Blessed is the Man whose Strength is in thee, in whose Heart are thy Ways, who passing through the Valley of Baca, make it a Well. For a Day in thy Court is better than a Thoasand: I had rather be a Door-Keeper in the House of my God, than to dwell in the Tents of Ungodliness. For the Lord God is a Sun and a Shield; the Lord will give Grace and Glory; no good thing will he withhold from them that walk uprightly, Psalm lxxxiv.</p>
            <p>They were next instructed from the following Words of the Psalmist.</p>
            <p>Let the sighing of Prisoners come before thee; according to the greatness of thy Power, preserve thou those who are appointed to die.</p>
            <p>In considering the three sorts of Prisoners who ought to pray and to lament their Condition, that their sighing might come before God, we especially directed the third sort, who were under Bondage and in Adversity, for evil Doings and vicious Practices: As in Baruch, Chap. iii. Verses 1st and following, O Lord Almighty, God of Israel, the Soul in Anguish, the troubled Spirit, cryeth unto thee. Hear O Lord and have Mercy; for thou art mercifull; and have pity upon us, because we have sinned before thee. For thou</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA172501040003"/>
            <p>endureth for ever, and we perish utterly. Remember not the Iniquities of our Forefathers; bur think upon thy Power and thy Name, now at this time. For thou art the Lord our God, and thee O Lord will we praise.</p>
            <p>In observing that God is the most proper Being for Prisoners, and all who are under Misfortunes and in Distress to apply to, as he is most Powerful, and as he is most Compassionate, we mentioned Baruch iii. ver. 14 and following. Learn where is Wisdom, where is Strength, where is Understanding; that thou mayest know also where is Length of Days, and Life, where is the Light of the Eyes, and Peace. Who hath found out her Place? or, Who hath come into her Treasures? Where are the Princes of the Heathen become, and such as ruled the Beasts upon the Earth, they that hoared up Silver and Gold wherein Men trust? They are vanish'd and gone down to the Grave, and others are come up in their steads. As for the Lenity and Compassion of Almighty God, it is amply illustrated in Ezekiel, Chapters xviii and xxxiii. If the Wicked will turn from all his Sins that he hath committed, and keep all my Statutes, and do that which is lawful and right, he shall surely live, he shall not die. All his Trangressions that he hath committed they shall not be mentioned unto him; in his Righteousness that he hath done shall he live. Have I any pleasure at all that the Wicked should die, saith the Lord God; and not that he should return from his Ways and live. Cast away from you all your Trangressions whereby ye have transgress'd, and make you a new Heart and a new Spirit; for why will ye die O House of Israel. For I have no pleasure in the death of him that dieth, saith the Lord God, wherefore turn yourselves and live ye. Again, the Prophet is commanded by God, Chap. xxxiii, when the Children of Israel lamentingly enquired how they should live, when their Trangressions were upon them, and they pined away in them, to answer, As I live, saith the Lord, I have no pleasure in the death of the Wicked. If the Wicked restore the Pledge, give again that he hath robbed, walk in the Statutes of Life without committing Iniquity, he shall surely live he shall not die.</p>
            <p>The Sunday immediately before the Execution of those two Malefactors, who were appointed to suffer Death agreeable to the Sentence passed upon them, the Words they were instructed from in the Morning, are contained in the xix Chapter of the Book of Job, verses 25, 26.</p>
            <p>For I know that my Redeemer liveth, and that he shall stand at the latter Day upon the Earth; and tho' after my skin Worms destroy this Body, yet in my Flesh shall I see God, &amp;c.</p>
            <p>In considering the Resurrection of Christ to Glory, and of Men as the Consequence thereof, we mentioned Romans vi. 9. Christ being raised from the Dead, dieth no more; Death hath no more Dominion over him; For in that he died he died unto Sin once, but in that he liveth he liveth unto God: Likewise reckon ye also your selves to be dead indeed unto Sin but alive unto God, through Jesus Christ our Lord. And also 1 Corinth. xv. 20. Christ is risen from the Dead and become the first fruits of them that slept; for since by Man came Death, by Man came also the Resurrection of the Dead: For as in Adam all die, even so in Christ shall all be made alive.</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA172501040004"/>
            <p>The Account of these Persons under Sentence of Death.</p>
            <p>
               <persName id="OA17250104n19-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17250104n19-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17250104n19-1" type="surname" value="TOWERS"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17250104n19-1" type="given" value="CHARLES"/>CHARLES TOWERS</persName>, sometime Inhabitant near <placeName id="OA17250104-geo-5">
                  <interp inst="OA17250104-geo-5" type="type" value="site"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA17250104n19-1 OA17250104-geo-5"/>St. James's Market</placeName>, <rs id="OA17250104-occupation-3" type="occupation">Butcher</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17250104n19-1 OA17250104-occupation-3"/>, was Indicted, for feloniously appearing, with several others, arm'd with Guns, Swords, Staves, or other offensive Weapons, and having his Face Black'd, or being otherwise disguised, on the Highway called <placeName id="OA17250104-geo-6">
                  <interp inst="OA17250104-geo-6" type="type" value="street"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA17250104n19-1 OA17250104-geo-6"/>Wapping Wall</placeName>; on the 21st of June last; to the Terror of His Majesty's Subjects, against the Peace of our Sovereign Lord the King, and against the Form of the Statute made and provided, and which was to take effect, after the first of June, in the tenth Year of His Majesty's Reign. Upon the Indictment he was Tryed, and it appearing that on Sunday Morning at eleven of the Clock, June the 20th, C. Towers, with seven others, rush'd into the House of <persName id="OA17250104n19-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17250104n19-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17250104n19-2" type="surname" value="ERRINGTON"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17250104n19-2" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Errington</persName>, (with a large Stick, like a Quarter-Staff in his Hand, his Hair clipt off, without Hat, Wig, or Shirt, only with a blue pea-Jacket, which flying open before, show'd his Breast, as well as his Face, Black, and besmear'd as with Soot and Grease;) whence they rescued J. West, affirming that they were sworn thereto, for his Name was set down in their Book kept at the seven Cities of Refuge; and offering (as the Prisoner was with loud Acclamations carrying off) to strike D. Taylor, Waterman, and G. Errington, Brother to the King's Evidence; And the Prisoner's allegations, that he never was in any Riot, but only defending himself against the Baylffs, &amp;c. not being thought of any force, he was by the Jury found guilty of Felony without Benefit of Clergy.</p>
            <p>As this unfortunate Person, after his Apprenticeship, marry'd young, before he was possest of a Competency, and Children and the Charges of a Family encreas'd upon him, he then judged that Gaming was a proper Method to retrieve himself and support his Family; but by Cards he lost that little he was then possest of. His Circumstances being desperate, he engag'd for a Friend, in a very large Sum of Money; which soon oblig'd him to fly into the <placeName id="OA17250104-geo-7">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA17250104n19-1 OA17250104-geo-7"/>Old Mint</placeName>. When most distrest, he said, he refused all Solicitations to Rob or Thieve: Denying that he ever was guilty of any notorious Offence, except one, which was unfaithfulness to his Wife's Bed; for which, he added, he must acknowledge he deserved Death, tho' Adultery is so seldom punish'd in this Kingdom. As for the robbing Mr. Huggins of a silver Spoon, of the taking whereof he was convicted, some time ago, and ordered for Transportation, he denyed his seeing any such Spoon. And as for the picking the Pocket of Mr. Westwood, an Officer, and taking 3 s. with which Fact he was lately charg'd, he said he believed the Money might fall out of the Officer's Pocket, as they Ditch'd him in a sad and shameful manner, but that he never saw any Silver or Copper. He farther said that their way was, as he must then acknowledge, very cruel and unbecoming Christians, for, during his Time, twelve or more were sentenc'd to be Whip'd, by a Judge, who was chosen from among them, for the Day, and sat in State: He added, that during his Confinement, some Persons had abused and insulted him, who were Friends to Mr. Jones, Bailiff; but he protested he was not Judge when Jones was sen</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA172501040005"/>
            <p>tenc'd, but one who was formerly an Officer in the Army: Nor had he ever any Designs against <rs id="OA17250104-occupation-4" type="occupation">Sir</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17250104n21-1 OA17250104-occupation-4"/> 
               <persName id="OA17250104n21-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17250104n21-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17250104n21-1" type="surname" value="TILLIARD"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17250104n21-1" type="given" value="ISAAC"/>Isaac Tilliard</persName>, or his House. He dwelt four Years in the <placeName id="OA17250104-geo-8">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA17250104n19-1 OA17250104-geo-8"/>Old Mint</placeName>; but owing to one Man 70 l. was forc'd to harbour in the <placeName id="OA17250104-geo-9">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA17250104n19-1 OA17250104-geo-9"/>New Mint, and took an House in <placeName id="OA17250104-geo-10">
                     <interp inst="OA17250104-geo-10" type="type" value="street"/>
                     <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                           targets="OA17250104n19-1 OA17250104-geo-10"/>Gravel-Lane</placeName>
               </placeName>; for Prisons were all so full, that Men, as he said, died like rotten Sheep, and he had rather go to the Place whither he was going, than dwell under that Tyranny.</p>
            <p>He acknowledged the Fury and Violence he had used against innocent Men; and observed how contrary it was to Christian Levity and Mildness; we may suppose, that originally he was perswaded to it, as being strong and nimble; and afterwards had all Encouragement and Commendation; which Incitements coincided with the natural Warmth and Vivacity of his Temper. He confest he had been by much too Enterprizing and Rash; but at the same Time added, he thought the Officers were before his Misfortunes fully reveng'd of the Minters; for, among others, a Carpenter's right Arm was so Hack'd and Chop'd, that the Surgeon was forced to take it off; as for himself, he show'd how dangerously his Head was Cut, even six Weeks ago, the large Scars whereof appear'd.</p>
            <p>He denyed that he was ever in Disguise with design to do Mischief; but he said they had Mock-Masquerades, and particularly one in <placeName id="OA17250104-geo-11">
                  <interp inst="OA17250104-geo-11" type="type" value="parish"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17250104n19-1 OA17250104-geo-11"/>
                  <placeName id="OA17250104-geo-12">
                     <interp inst="OA17250104-geo-12" type="type" value="street"/>
                     <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                           targets="OA17250104n19-1 OA17250104-geo-12"/>Meeting-House Alley</placeName>, Wapping</placeName>, where Men and Women met, under the Number of Twenty, and he in particular was in a Miller's Habit and his Face cover'd over with White. He directed his Wife to offer this to the Consideration of his Majesty, in a Petition; and also to insert her having two Children, besides one in her Body, which must come to Misery if the Father was taken from 'em; which Petition she delivered at the Council-Chamber Door.</p>
            <p>He was happy in having his Health continued entire, from the first Beginning of his Misfortunes; and in having R. Swanson, with him, who was able and ready to Read the Scriptures. When R. Swanson, had been Sick, in the Night, and could not Read and Pray at One of the Clock in the Morning, as was their constant Practice; Towers, the next Day, much condoled the Misfortune, saying he wished he was wealthy enough to employ and reward some Person who should sit up each Night and awaken them to Prayers as soon as Midnight was pass'd. The Day before his Death, he seem'd more chearful than before, saying, This was decreed for me, and I am easy and contented under it; and how should I be otherwise, for I am going from a Life of Trouble and Noise and Confusion, to a World of Quiet.</p>
            <p>
               <persName id="OA17250104n25-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17250104n25-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17250104n25-1" type="surname" value="ANDERSON"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17250104n25-1" type="given" value="WILLIAM"/>WILLIAM ANDERSON</persName>, of <placeName id="OA17250104-geo-13">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17250104n25-1 OA17250104-geo-13"/>Aldgate</placeName>, was indicted for assaulting <persName id="OA17250104n25-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17250104n25-2" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17250104n25-2" type="surname" value="RICKABY"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17250104n25-2" type="given" value="HANNAH"/>Hannah Rickaby</persName>, near <placeName id="OA17250104-geo-14">
                  <interp inst="OA17250104-geo-14" type="type" value="street"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17250104n25-1 n25-2 OA17250104-geo-14"/>Burr-street</placeName>, on the 27th of October last, putting her in fear, and taking a Pocket, an Handkerchief, and 26 s. in Money; and it being proved by <persName id="OA17250104n25-3">
                  <interp inst="OA17250104n25-3" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17250104n25-3" type="surname" value="Thompson"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17250104n25-3" type="given" value="Eliz"/>Eliz. Thompson</persName>, who was walking with the Prosecutor, that the abovenam'd Prisoner (who was stopt by W. Cuthbeard as he ran away) was the Person who snatch'd the Prosecutor's Pocket; the Jury found him guilty of the Indictment.</p>
            <p>'Tho' this Prisoner did not seem to be so sedulous in his Duty as the foregoing; yet after the Warrant for Execution was sent to the City, his Behaviour was not amiss. He hoped that God would pardon his roving Mind, for many Opportunities had been offer'd him of settling and living soberly, which he slighted; particularly observing that he refused to settle in the Plantations abroad, tho' a Court of Justice had legally sent him thither for thieving. Tho' a very young Man, he was an old Offender, and before he was of Years to distinguish Good from Ill, fell into the way of picking Pockets, which he acknowledged made his Mind susceptable of any Vice.</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA172501040006"/>
            <p>He mourn'd when Towers was taken from him, and wish'd he was then to have died along with him. As the Hour of his Death approach'd, his Devotion encreas'd; and he earnestly apply'd to Heaven for the pardon of his Crimes.</p>
            <p>The Behaviour, &amp;c. of C. Towers at the Place of Execution.</p>
            <p>THIS Prisoner, (who was carryed in a Cart, to the Gallows erected by <placeName id="OA17250104-geo-15">
                  <interp inst="OA17250104-geo-15" type="type" value="parish"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA17250104n2-1 OA17250104-geo-15"/>Wapping</placeName>, through a very great Concourse of People, many of whom with Tears lamented his Condition) appear'd with uncommon Intrepidity; and tho' the Evening before, he wept very much when he took leave of his Wife and one of his Children, the immediate prospect of his own Suffering no way shock'd him; but in a very loud and exclaiming Voice he asserted his Innocence to the Spectators, after the Conclusion of the Prayers, &amp;c. and to make all who were there believe, that he was not disguised when he rescued Mr. West, unless the dirty Condition he was commonly in, could be so term'd. That Capt. Buckland, sentenc'd Mr. Jones, the Bailiff, when he was used in so cruel and unchristian a manner that he Swooned, &amp;c. That the others who were apprehended in the new Mint, and confin'd on the same Account, were not Guilty of going Arm'd in Disguise, or of any thing else that could nearly affect them; and named Mr. Saintloe, in particular. That he did not rob Mr. <persName id="OA17250104n29-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17250104n29-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17250104n29-1" type="surname" value="BROOKSBANK"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17250104n29-1" type="given" value="HENRY"/>Henry Brooksbank</persName>, of any Brandy, Tobacco, or Pipes, as he had been charg'd, though the House was threatn'd and design'd against. To this he added, that lest his Words should be mistaken, he had most of the substance of 'em down in Writing; and pull'd out a Paper, written by an Acquaintance, for he could not write himself. He afterwards said, If the Sheriff or the High Constable must of necessity have the Paper, pray at least grant that it may be now read before all these People, for 'tis not against any Court: The Paper was according to his Desire read before the People; but it did not contain any Discovery, or any Confession of the Disguise, or the like, but was to the following Purport or Effect: That as he was in other matters a great Sinner (and had for other things deserved Death, he underwent the Punishment with Patience; and humbly hoped that Almighty God would be merciful to him for the sake of Jesus Christ, in whom he trusted; that he did not know of any Disguise he was in; that he did never commit Theft or Robbery; did not steal a Silver Spoon, or any Money; did not rob any Bailiff, &amp;c. that he was forced and obliged to take Sanctuary in the Place call'd the Mint, in order to avoid his Creditors, because his Debts were so large that it was not possible for him ever to pay them. This was the Substance, but 'twas branch'd into many Words and Sentences. He also inveigh'd against the Bailiffs; but declared that he died in Charity with all Mankind. After the Paper was read, he return'd to his usual Composure and again grew calm. As the Cart began to move forward, he with the loudest Cries and Exclamations cry'd out to God to receive his Soul, till his Breath was stopt, wringing his Hands in a passionate manner; after which, the strength of his Constitution appear'd in the extream and surprizing Difficulty with which he died.</p>
            <p>The Behaviour of <persName id="OA17250104n30-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17250104n30-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17250104n30-1" type="surname" value="ANDERSON"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17250104n30-1" type="given" value="WILLIAM"/>William Anderson</persName> at the Place of Execution.</p>
            <p>WHEN arriv'd at the Tree, the lifting up of his Hands, with Tears in his Eyes, demonstrated to the World a deep sence of his repeated Crimes, and apprehensions of his near approaching Suffering for them; his Behaviour, in a Word, was such as satisfy'd those around him of his sincere Repentance. The interval between the Service he employ'd in making a generous Confession of the Crime for which he suffer'd, and many others antecedent to it; and when he was to be finally dismiss'd, he required proper Expressions from us to recommend his departing Soul to God, which he made use of till his Breath was stopt.</p>
            <p>This is the Account that is given by me, T. PURNEY Ordinary and Chaplain.</p>
            <p>N. B. A Paper was given by Towers at the Place of Execution to one Hinton, but was commanded out of his Hands by the High-Constable, and deliver'd accordingly; it was yesterday offered to Mr. Applebee; but as it was read to the Spectators, and the Contents already mentioned in the above Account of the Behaviour, &amp;c. the Paper sign'd by Towers we shall not publish; People may therefore judge whether the Paper printed by Hinton, and published by Warner, is not an Imposition on the Town, altho' witness'd by the two condemn'd Men: As to what Hinton publish'd, as follows, Towers publickly declar'd he would not deliver any Paper to the Ordinary or Mr. Applebee, &amp;c. 'tis a direct Falsity, for Towers never mention'd either of them to the Publick.</p>
            <p>
               <placeName id="OA17250104-geo-16">
                  <interp inst="OA17250104-geo-16" type="type" value="urban_centre"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17250104n34-1 OA17250104-geo-16"/>LONDON</placeName>: Printed by <persName id="OA17250104n34-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17250104n34-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17250104n34-1" type="surname" value="APPLEBEE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17250104n34-1" type="given" value="JOHN"/>JOHN APPLEBEE</persName>, below <placeName id="OA17250104-geo-17">
                  <interp inst="OA17250104-geo-17" type="type" value="parish"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17250104n34-1 OA17250104-geo-17"/>
                  <placeName id="OA17250104-geo-18">
                     <interp inst="OA17250104-geo-18" type="type" value="site"/>
                     <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                           targets="OA17250104n34-1 OA17250104-geo-18"/>Bridewell-Bridge</placeName>, in Black-Fryers</placeName>.</p>
         </div0>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>