<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<TEI.2>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div0 type="ordinarysAccount" id="OA17340308">
            <interp inst="OA17340308" type="uri" value="ordinarysAccounts/OA17340308"/>
            <interp inst="OA17340308" type="date" value="17340308"/>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA173403080001"/>
            <p>THE ORDINARY of NEWGATE, His ACCOUNT of the Behaviour, Confessions, and Dying Words, OF THE MALEFACTORS, Who were EXECUTED at TYBURN, On FRIDAY the 8th of this Instant March, 1734.</p>
            <p>BEING THE THIRD EXECUTION in the MAYORALTY OF THE Rt. Hon. <persName id="OA17340308n3-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n3-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n3-1" type="surname" value="BILLERS"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n3-1" type="given" value="WILLIAM"/>Sir WILLIAM BILLERS</persName>, Knt.</p>
            <p>Number III. For the said YEAR.</p>
            <p>LONDON:</p>
            <p>Printed and Sold by <persName id="OA17340308n6-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n6-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n6-1" type="surname" value="APPLEBEE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n6-1" type="given" value="JOHN"/>JOHN APPLEBEE</persName>, in <placeName id="OA17340308-geo-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17340308-geo-1" type="type" value="street"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA17340308n6-1 OA17340308-geo-1"/>
                  <placeName id="OA17340308-geo-2">
                     <interp inst="OA17340308-geo-2" type="type" value="site"/>
                     <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA17340308n6-1 OA17340308-geo-2"/>Bolt-Court</placeName>, near the <placeName id="OA17340308-geo-3">
                     <interp inst="OA17340308-geo-3" type="type" value="site"/>
                     <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA17340308n6-1 OA17340308-geo-3"/>Leg-Tavern</placeName>, Fleet-street</placeName>. M.DCC.XXXIV.</p>
            <p>[Price Four-Pence.]</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA173403080002"/>
            <p>This Day is publish'd, PROPOSALS For PRINTING by SUBSCRIPTION, SELECT TRIALS,</p>
            <p>FOR Murders, Robberies, Rapes, Sodomy, Coining, Frauds, and other Offences, at the Sessions-House in the Old-Baily, from the Year 1720, to the Present Time. Chiefly transcrib'd from Original Notes taken in Court. With genuine Accounts of the Lives, Behaviour, Confessions and Dying Speeches of the most Eminent Convicts.</p>
            <p>CONDITIONS,</p>
            <p>I. The Book will be printed on the same Paper and Letter as the Specimen annex'd to the Proposals.</p>
            <p>II. While the Book is printing, it is proposed to deliver weekly five Half-Sheets in Octavo (which is more than six Sheets in Folio) at the Price of Six-pence.</p>
            <p>III. That the General Title, Index, Preface, &amp;c. will be given Gratis at the End of the First Volume.</p>
            <p>IV. That the First Number will be publish'd on Saturday the 13th Day of April next.</p>
            <p>Proposals are deliver'd, and Subscriptions are taken in, by J. Wilford, over-against the Chapter-House in St. Paul's Church-yard.</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA173403080003"/>
            <p>THE ORDINARY of NEWGATE, His ACCOUNT of the Behaviour, Confession, &amp;c.</p>
            <p>AT the King's Commission of Oyer and Terminer, and Gaol-Delivery of Newgate, held (before the <persName id="OA17340308n17-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n17-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n17-1" type="surname" value="BILLERS"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n17-1" type="given" value="WILLIAM"/>Right Honourable Sir William Billers</persName>, Knt. Lord Mayor of the <placeName id="OA17340308-geo-4">
                  <interp inst="OA17340308-geo-4" type="type" value="urban_centre"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA17340308n17-1 OA17340308-geo-4"/>City of London</placeName>; the Honourable Mr. Baron Carter; the Honourable Mr. Baron Thompson, Recorder of the City of London; the Worshipful Mr. Serjeant Urlin, Deputy-Recorder of the City of London; and others his Majesty's Justices of Oyer and Terminer for the City of London; and Justices of Gaol-Delivery of Newgate holden for the said City and County of Middlesex,) at Justice Hall in the Old-Bailey, on Wednesday and Thursday, the 27th and 28th of February, and Friday the 1st. of March, 1733-4, in the Seventh Year of his Majesty's Reign.</p>
            <p>Six Men, viz. <persName id="OA17340308n18-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n18-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n18-1" type="surname" value="DAVIS"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n18-1" type="given" value="WILLIAM"/>William Davis</persName>, <persName id="OA17340308n18-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n18-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n18-2" type="surname" value="TUDOR"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n18-2" type="given" value="EDWARD"/>Edward Tudor</persName>, <persName id="OA17340308n18-3">
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n18-3" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n18-3" type="surname" value="CHARLESWORTH"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n18-3" type="given" value="CALEB"/>Caleb Charlesworth</persName>, <persName id="OA17340308n18-4">
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n18-4" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n18-4" type="surname" value="CRANE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n18-4" type="given" value="HENRY"/>Henry Crane</persName>, <persName id="OA17340308n18-5">
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n18-5" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n18-5" type="surname" value="HOLBROOK"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n18-5" type="given" value="RALPH"/>Ralph Holbrook</persName> and <persName id="OA17340308n18-6">
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n18-6" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n18-6" type="surname" value="DITTON"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n18-6" type="given" value="JOSEPH"/>Joseph Ditton</persName>; and one Woman, viz. <persName id="OA17340308n18-7">
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n18-7" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n18-7" type="surname" value="Leford"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n18-7" type="given" value="Judith"/>Judith Leford</persName>, <persName id="OA17340308n18-8">
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n18-8" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n18-8" type="surname" value="Defour"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n18-8" type="given" value="Judith"/>otherwise Defour</persName>, <persName id="OA17340308n18-9">
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n18-9" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n18-9" type="surname" value="Defoy"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n18-9" type="given" value="Judith"/>or Defoy</persName>, were convicted of capital Crimes, and receiv'd Sentence of Death.</p>
            <p>Most of them having been Young, and all of them unacquainted with, or not accustom'd to religious Duties and Exercises, I shew'd them that those performances are so far from being an impossible task, (as wicked dispos'd People would represent them to be) that they are not extreme difficult when Men set about them in earnest. By the grace of God, and care of pious Parents, several good Souls are train'd up as soon as may be, to the keeping of Baptismal innocence,</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA173403080004"/>
            <p>and performance of their Solemn engagements. They are taught to know God, and to fear him, to know good and ill; and in reverence to God, to do the good, and refuse the ill, as soon as they are capable of knowing any thing. Now here religion grows up with them, and corrupt Passions and evil Customs (which are other Peoples great complaints and difficulties) are stifled and prevented from the first, and never come to grow headstrong, or have any Power to reign in them; so that what difficulties they find in religion, are chiefly the Pains and Services of religious Actions; not those self denials, and mortification of corrupt Lusts and evil Habits, which create so much trouble to other Persons.</p>
            <p>But the greatest Part, among the chief of whom they are to be reckon'd, have alas given way to their Lusts, and subjected themselves to wicked Customs, and their Work is not retaining innocence, but recovering it, and rectifying and amending transgressions; now in amending our Lives, and obeying God after we have made ourselves thus averse to his Obedience, there is difficulty and pains at first. Our former courses and customs generally must be alter'd, our Friends sometimes disoblig'd our temporal interest cross'd and thwarted, and our natural Lusts formerly indulged, now gain-said and conquer'd. All this is against our inclination, which is a force upon any Man, and that while it lasts, will make an uneasiness in Religion. But to cure this, God's grace will be working in us, and new moulding of our Natures; and by use we shall grow perfect and inclinable to good Things, which we set our selves to Practice; so that after God's grace and our own virtuous usage have gone on for some due Time, the case will be alter'd, and religion will appear not only a reasonable and beneficial, but likewise an agreeable Thing. Divine Aids, and good Customs, will give us a new Sence of all our Duties, and make them almost always fairly tolerable, and usually delightful Things. And thus our Lord encourages us to his Service. Take my Yoke upon you, and learn of me, for my Yoke is easy, and my Burthen light, Matt. 11. 29, 30. And St. John speaking of keeping his Commandments, for our comforts adds, that those Commandments are not grievous. 1. John. 5. 3.</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA173403080005"/>
            <p>Some indeed reply, that there are Severities in religion, expressed, By cutting off right Hands, and plucking out right Eyes; to take up the Cross, and patiently suffer Persecutions; to watch and strive, and wrestle against Spiritual enemies, and that these are hard things, which they cannot comply with; but it must be observ'd that these and the like places of Scripture, speak only the difficulties of Religion in some less common cases, as Persecutions, in which the increase of difficulty is so answered by a proportionable increase of Strength, as makes it a tollerable Task to encounter them, or the hardships of it, at Mens new entering on it, after they had done much to unfit themselves for it; at which time, as is said, it doth call for more Pains. Or lastly, such diligent and just care, and watchfulness afterwards, as admits of comfort and delight, enough to Sweeten it to us, &amp;c.</p>
            <p>
               <persName id="OA17340308n23-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n23-1" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n23-1" type="surname" value="DEFOUR"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n23-1" type="given" value="JUDITH"/>Judith Defour</persName>, having been convicted for the cruel Murder of her own Child: I expos'd to her the unnaturalness, and barbarity of the horrid crime of Murder, more particularly as committed upon her own Infant, between two and three years of Age, not capable of giving any manner of provocation to any Person; whose tender Years pleaded for Pity and Compassion, at the Hands of all Mankind. I exclaim'd against the Sin of uncleanness, to which she was habitually addicted, which prov'd the occasion of her after misfortunes, and of her committing Murder upon her own Child; and this I shew'd her to be almost the same, as committed upon herself, since the Child was a part of herself: And therefore I seriously exhorted her to repent of that heinous Sin, which prov'd her to be void of all bowels of Pitty and Compassion, and to cry incessantly unto God for Pardon, that she might be wash'd in the blood of Christ, the Lamb of God, who came to do away the Sins of the World, from the guilt of innocent Blood, and all her other Sins.</p>
            <p>They were also instructed in the Nature of true Repentance, how necessary it was to repent of all their Sins, particularly of Theft and Robbery, a Crime so destructive of all human Society, and therefore liable to the highest Punishment, in all civiliz'd and polite Nations, to which they ought to submit, as a just Chastisement for their Sins, acknowledging the Afflictions they met with, to be infinitely less than what they deserv'd; for why should a living Man complain, a Man for the Punishment of his Sins?</p>
            <p>I shew'd them the Nature of the Christian Sacraments, that they were dedicated to God in Baptism, and that having broken their Baptisma Engagements in a grievous Manner, it was requisite to renew their Vows of Obedience to the Laws and Gospel of Jesus Christ, by receiving the Sacrament of the Lord's Supper, wherein all the Blessings of the new Covenant are made over, and confirmed to them who truly believe.</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA173403080006"/>
            <p>When these and many other Instructions were given, they who could read made regular Responses, and all of them behav'd well, and were apparently devout and serious, and attentive both to Prayers and Exhortations. Most of them, especially Crane and Holbrook wept pretty often, but it may be suspected, that it was more for fear of Death, than an Effect of true Repentance. <persName id="OA17340308n26-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n26-1" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n26-1" type="surname" value="DEFOUR"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n26-1" type="given" value="JUDITH"/>Judith Defour</persName> was very hard-hearted, once she wept when I spoke of Murder; but afterwards, when I preach'd upon that Subject, she sat quiet and did not appear concern'd, though I expos'd her Crime in the most moving and plain Terms: She was altogether ignorant of God and Religion, and could remember nothing I told her, so that in such pitiful Circumstances, I have not seen one more stupid, nor less thoughtful. They behav'd better and more modestly, than such unhappy Creatures use frequently to do.</p>
            <p>Upon Tuesday, the Fifth of March, Report was made to his Majesty in Council, of the seven Malefactors under Sentence of Death, lying in the Cells of <placeName id="OA17340308-geo-5">
                  <interp inst="OA17340308-geo-5" type="type" value="site"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17340308n27-1 n27-2 n27-3 n27-4 n27-5 n27-6 n27-8 n27-9 n27-10 OA17340308-geo-5"/>Newgate</placeName>; when <persName id="OA17340308n27-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n27-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n27-1" type="surname" value="DITTON"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n27-1" type="given" value="JOSEPH"/>Joseph Ditton</persName>, for robbing his Fellow-Servant <persName id="OA17340308n27-7">
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n27-7" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n27-7" type="surname" value="Heughs"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n27-7" type="given" value="Hugh"/>Hugh Heughs</persName>, by breaking open his Trunk, and stealing thence Ten Guineas and a gold Ring; and <persName id="OA17340308n27-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n27-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n27-2" type="surname" value="DAVIS"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n27-2" type="given" value="WILLIAM"/>William Davis</persName>, for robbing his Master, a Gentleman who lives nigh the Town, by going into his Bed-Chamber, while the Gentleman was asleep, and stealing out of his Breeches-Pocket Forty Guineas, receiv'd his Majesty's most gracious Reprieve: The remaining Five, viz. <persName id="OA17340308n27-3">
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n27-3" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n27-3" type="surname" value="TUDOR"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n27-3" type="given" value="EDWARD"/>Edward Tudor</persName>, <persName id="OA17340308n27-4">
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n27-4" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n27-4" type="surname" value="CHARLESWORTH"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n27-4" type="given" value="CALEB"/>Caleb Charlesworth</persName>, <persName id="OA17340308n27-5">
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n27-5" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n27-5" type="surname" value="CRANE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n27-5" type="given" value="HENRY"/>Henry Crane</persName>, <persName id="OA17340308n27-6">
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n27-6" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n27-6" type="surname" value="HOLBROOK"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n27-6" type="given" value="RALPH"/>Ralph Holbrook</persName>, and <persName id="OA17340308n27-8">
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n27-8" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n27-8" type="surname" value="Leford"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n27-8" type="given" value="Judith"/>Judith Leford</persName>, <persName id="OA17340308n27-9">
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n27-9" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n27-9" type="surname" value="Defour"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n27-9" type="given" value="Judith"/>alias Defour</persName>, <persName id="OA17340308n27-10">
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n27-10" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n27-10" type="surname" value="Defoy"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n27-10" type="given" value="Judith"/>or Defoy</persName>, were order'd for Execution.</p>
            <p>
               <persName id="OA17340308n28-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n28-1" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n28-1" type="surname" value="Leford"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n28-1" type="given" value="Judith"/>Judith Leford</persName>, <persName id="OA17340308n28-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n28-2" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n28-2" type="surname" value="Defour"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n28-2" type="given" value="Judith"/>alias Defour</persName> 
               <persName id="OA17340308n28-3">
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n28-3" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n28-3" type="surname" value="Defoy"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n28-3" type="given" value="Judith"/>or Defoy</persName>, was indicted for the Murder of her own Child on the 29th of January last, an Infant between two and three Years of Age, by strangling it with a Handkerchief, after she had stript it naked, and then throwing her into a Ditch, near <placeName id="OA17340308-geo-6">
                  <interp inst="OA17340308-geo-6" type="type" value="parish"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17340308n28-1 n28-2 n28-3 OA17340308-geo-6"/>Bethnal Green</placeName>, wounding her in the Head, and leaving her to perish there.</p>
            <p>She was a second Time found guilty upon the Coroner's Inquest. Death.</p>
            <p>1. <persName id="OA17340308n30-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n30-1" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n30-1" type="age" value="30"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n30-1" type="surname" value="Leford"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n30-1" type="given" value="Judith"/>Judith Leford</persName>, <persName id="OA17340308n30-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n30-2" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n30-2" type="age" value="30"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n30-2" type="surname" value="Defour"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n30-2" type="given" value="Judith"/>alias Defour</persName> 
               <persName id="OA17340308n30-3">
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n30-3" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n30-3" type="age" value="30"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n30-3" type="surname" value="Defoy"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n30-3" type="given" value="Judith"/>or Defoy</persName>, about thirty Years of Age, of honest, but mean Parents in <placeName id="OA17340308-geo-7">
                  <interp inst="OA17340308-geo-7" type="type" value="site"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17340308n30-1 n30-2 n30-3 OA17340308-geo-7"/>Spittle-Fields</placeName>, who gave her no Education at School, and as little did they instruct her in the Christian Religion, of which she was intirely ignorant. Her Father having been a French Weaver, she was employ'd in serving the Weavers, in <rs id="OA17340308-occupation-1" type="occupation">winding Silk</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17340308n30-1 n30-2 n30-3 OA17340308-occupation-1"/>, and such like Business, and in this way she served one Mistress eleven Years honestly, and with Reputation, and then leaving her, she went to a Master, with whom she liv'd four Years, was his <rs id="OA17340308-occupation-2" type="occupation">House-keeper</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17340308n30-1 n30-2 n30-3 OA17340308-occupation-2"/>, and <rs id="OA17340308-occupation-3" type="occupation">winded Silk</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17340308n30-1 n30-2 n30-3 OA17340308-occupation-3"/> for him. In this Service she fell into bad Company, and had a Bastard-Child, which died; and then she had another, the unfortunate Child lately murder'd by her, of which Crime she</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA173403080007"/>
            <p>was convicted, and for which she was to suffer an ignominious Death, which she very justly deserv'd for such a barbarous Murder. The Account she gave of the Murder was to this Effect:</p>
            <p>The Child was kept in a Work-House, and she used sometimes to visit her, and make much of her, and to carry her out into the Fields to give her the Air; accordingly, upon the 29th Day of January last, she went to the Work-House, and tho Keepers and Nurses suspecting no manner of Harm, but that before Night she would bring back the Child, as she used to do, they allow'd her to carry out her Daughter, with whom she went into the Fields, and another Woman in Company, which was one of the most vilest of Creatures in or about the Town. She blamed her for the Murder, alledging, that such an execrable Villainy never enter'd into her Head; but as they were walking along, this Woman propos'd to strip the Child, being pretty well cloathed, and having new Stays, which she told her would fell well; the Mother spoke faintly against it, but when they came to a Ditch by <placeName id="OA17340308-geo-8">
                  <interp inst="OA17340308-geo-8" type="type" value="parish"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17340308n30-1 n30-2 n30-3 OA17340308-geo-8"/>Bethnal-Green</placeName>, the barbarous, unnatural Mother yielded to the most wicked Proposal made by the other Woman, whom she allow'd to strip the innocent Child, smiling at the same Time in the Mother's Face, and calling out, Mammy; for she could speak no more, having neither come to the use of her Tongue, nor Feet: Then they drew a Handkerchief about its Neck, each of them pulling the Ends of it, in order to strangle the Child; and lastly they threw her into the Ditch and left her, but the other Woman observing Life in the Child, upon which the Mother of it went back and struck her on the Head with a Stone or Brick-brat, which gave the finishing Stroke. This she was not willing to confess, but when told of the Wound in the Head, she could not with confidence deny it, but held her Peace.</p>
            <p>They came to Town, and the other Woman sold the Coat and Stays for a Shilling, and dispos'd of the rest of the Cloaths for Four-pence, which she said they equally divided, and afterterwards join'd for a Quartern of Gin with this Sukey (which was the other Woman's Name) who was concern'd with her; and she hearing that the Child's Mother was taken up, she fled, as not doubting but she would have deservedly undergone the same Fate.</p>
            <p>When all this was a doing, her Conscience sting'd her most severely, and she own'd she was in the greatest Agonies and Tortures imaginable: I ask'd her, if it was in her Power to hinder her? She said it was, but she only forbid her to do it faintly, in the mean Time suffering her to do what she pleas'd. The People of the Work-House asking after the Child, she confess'd the Fact to them, and to her Mistress, upon which they</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA173403080008"/>
            <p>caus'd her to be taken up, and she went with her Mistress, and shew'd her the Child lying naked and dead in the Ditch, who was mightily mov'd with Compassion at so horrid a Sight.</p>
            <p>I represented to her the dreadful Barbarity and Cruelty of such a monstrous unnatural Action, where no Provocation could be given. She did not in the least pretend any Excuse, only that the other Creature contriv'd, and mostly executed the whole Tragedy. She was very stupid and had little to say upon any Head. I have scarce ever seen one so grosly ignorant of Religion, and after all the Pains I took to inculcate some first Principles, she minded nothing. On Sunday Afternoon the third Instant, when I insisted upon Murther, she wept a little; and upon Tuesday following, <persName id="OA17340308n36-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n36-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n36-1" type="surname" value="DITTON"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n36-1" type="given" value="JOSEPH"/>Joseph Ditton</persName>; one of the Criminals under Sentence, who always behaved very decently, and is now repriev'd sitting by her, before I came in, observing her very careless and indifferent, desired her to repent and to think upon the dangerous State she was in; she lamented that she was never taught any thing about God and Religion, and added, O! that my Parents had taught me something of the Knowledge of God, which I was never instructed in, till now when (it may be fear'd) its out of time; and sometimes I heard her fetch grievous Sigh and Groans; these were the only outward Signs of Repentance I took notice of in her, all the time she lay under Sentence; only she said, she was very sorry for what was done, that she never was at Peace since it happened, that she scarce desired to live; and therefore she made a voluntary Confession she had been always of a very surly Disposition, and untractable Creature, a Despiser of Religion, negligent in her Duty to God and Man, and would take no good Advice of her Friends, nor of any good or sober People. She drank and swore much, and was averse to Virtue and Sobriety, delighting in the vilest Companies, and ready to Practice the worst of Actions. She acknowledged the Justice of her Sentence, and died in Peace with all Mankind.</p>
            <p>
               <persName id="OA17340308n37-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n37-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n37-1" type="surname" value="CRANE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n37-1" type="given" value="HENRY"/>Henry Crane</persName>, was indicted for assaulting Mrs. <persName id="OA17340308n37-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n37-2" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n37-2" type="surname" value="GREGORY"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n37-2" type="given" value="ALICE"/>Alice Gregory</persName> and <persName id="OA17340308n37-3">
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n37-3" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n37-3" type="surname" value="WILLIAMS"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n37-3" type="given" value="MARTHA"/>Martha Williams</persName>, on the King's Highway near Pancras, putting them in fear, and taking from Mrs. Gregory 5 s. 6 d. and some Farthings, upon Tuesday the 29th of January last.</p>
            <p>2. <persName id="OA17340308n38-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n38-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n38-1" type="age" value="27"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n38-1" type="surname" value="CRANE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n38-1" type="given" value="HENRY"/>Henry Crane</persName>, twenty-seven Years of Age, of mean Parents nigh the Town, had Education at Free-Schools in Reading, Writing and Cyphering, to fit him for Business, and was instructed in the Christian Religion. When of Age, he was <rs id="OA17340308-occupation-4" type="occupation">put to a Chairmaker</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17340308n38-1 OA17340308-occupation-4"/>, and serv'd out his Time honestly and with Approbation. Afterwards he liv'd by his Business in working <rs id="OA17340308-occupation-5" type="occupation">Journey-work</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17340308n38-1 OA17340308-occupation-5"/>; and two or three Years ago he married a Wife, and when he followed his Employment,</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA173403080009"/>
            <p>he got enough to maintain himself and Family, having gain'd the Good-will of some Shop keepers about <placeName id="OA17340308-geo-9">
                  <interp inst="OA17340308-geo-9" type="type" value="site"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA17340308n38-1 OA17340308-geo-9"/>St. Paul's Church Yard</placeName>, who did not let him want Business when he was willing to work; particularly one Mistress, whom he serv'd two or three Years, who commended him for his Honesty and the Care he took in her Service; but the Cause of his ruin was, a strong Inclination he had to Idleness, Drinking, Gaming, and keeping of bad Company.</p>
            <p>At first he denied the Fact of which he was convicted, pretending that he had been to see his old Father and Mother that Afternoon, and some little Evasions of that kind. But when the Dead Warrant came to <placeName id="OA17340308-geo-10">
                  <interp inst="OA17340308-geo-10" type="type" value="site"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17340308n38-1 OA17340308-geo-10"/>Newgate</placeName>, and he saw that there was no hopes of Mercy to be expected, then he came to me undesired and confess'd all.</p>
            <p>That he having been sick, as his Wife also was at that time, and unprovided in every thing; it came into his Head, without acquainting any Body with his Design, to go on the Foot-Padd and see what he could purchase in that way of Life; accordingly with a Stick in his Hand, and no other offensive Weapons; he went out in the Evening towards <placeName id="OA17340308-geo-11">
                  <interp inst="OA17340308-geo-11" type="type" value="site"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17340308n38-1 OA17340308-geo-11"/>Pancras-Church</placeName>, and by the Barns at the further End of the narrow Path by the Posts, seeing two Gentlewomen, he waited till they came up, and as soon as they came nigh him commanded them to deliver; accordingly Mrs. Gregory gave him 5 s. 6 d. and he other Gentlewoman not having Money about her, he made off. Not being accustomed to such dangerous Adventures, and his Conscience checking him dreadfully, for he knew better things, having been pretty well instructed, and knowing much more than such unhappy Creatures commonly do; he trembled all the while he was robbing of them; and some People coming along the Road, the Gentlewomen cry'd our, Highwayman, Stop Thief. Crane trembled, and his Legs fail'd him, so that he could not make that hast as he could at another Time, which otherwise he might easily have done, and made his escape to the Town, so he was taken immediately, and brought to condign Punishment. He declared, as he was a dying Person, that this was the first and last Attempt he ever made on the Highway, and that he never was a Thief in any respect whatsoever, but liv'd honestly and wrought very hard at his Trade to maintain himself and his Family in an industrious Way, and that the particular Occasion of his going out that Afternoon, was the Landlady's teazing him for the Rent, which by Reason of the distressed Condition of his Family, had impoverish'd him for some time.</p>
            <p>He own'd that he was a very wicked Sinner, as in Drinking, Whoing, idling away his Time, breaking the Lord's Day, neglecting the private and publick Worship of God, &amp;c. for</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA173403080010"/>
            <p>which and many other Sins, he was most justly afflicted, and God had brought him very justly to this unhappy Condition which he now laid under.</p>
            <p>He profess'd a deep Penitence, was very careful of publick and private Duties, while under Sentence; and to outward Appearance he seem'd truly penitent. He declar'd, that if he had been spar'd, he would not have committed any more Robberies, but liv'd honestly. That he believed in Christ his only Saviour; sincerely repented of all his Sins, and died in Peace with all the World.</p>
            <p>
               <persName id="OA17340308n45-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n45-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n45-1" type="surname" value="HOLBROOK"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n45-1" type="given" value="RALPH"/>Ralph Holbrook</persName> was indicted for assaulting <persName id="OA17340308n45-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n45-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n45-2" type="surname" value="READ"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n45-2" type="given" value="GEORGE"/>George Read</persName> on the Highway, in <placeName id="OA17340308-geo-12">
                  <interp inst="OA17340308-geo-12" type="type" value="site"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17340308n45-1 n45-2 OA17340308-geo-12"/>Stepney-Fields</placeName>, putting him in fear, and taking from him a Cap, a Handkerchief, a Cloth-Coat, a dimity Waistcoat, a Pair of Shoes, and a Pair of Buckles, on the 15th of November last.</p>
            <p>3. <persName id="OA17340308n46-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n46-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n46-1" type="age" value="19"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n46-1" type="surname" value="HOLBROOK"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n46-1" type="given" value="RALPH"/>Ralph Holbrook</persName>, Nineteen Years of Age, of honest Parents in the <placeName id="OA17340308-geo-13">
                  <interp inst="OA17340308-geo-13" type="type" value="urban_centre"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17340308n46-1 OA17340308-geo-13"/>City of Canterbury</placeName>; his Mother died when he was but Six Years old, and the Mother-in-Law was very unkind to him (as he said) which made him take to the Streets, and brought him to a Habit of vile Company-keeping, and to several other Inconveniencies, which at last wholly ruin'd him.</p>
            <p>His Father put him to School, but being of a cross Temper he would not keep to it, but rambled along the Streets with wicked Boys, neglected his Schooling, and learned nothing. Afterwards he might have been taught his Father's Business of a Taylor, but would not hear of going to any settled Employment.</p>
            <p>About three Years ago he came to <placeName id="OA17340308-geo-14">
                  <interp inst="OA17340308-geo-14" type="type" value="urban_centre"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17340308n46-1 OA17340308-geo-14"/>London</placeName>, where he was a <rs id="OA17340308-occupation-6" type="occupation">Post-Boy</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17340308n46-1 OA17340308-occupation-6"/>, and kept in that Business above two Years, 'till last Bartholomew-tide falling in with bad Company, he never could settle himself to any manner of Business, but was quite abandon'd to all manner of Wickedness; since that Time, having had no way to subsist himself, but by picking, stealing, and thieving.</p>
            <p>By the Advice of these abandon'd Wretches he had ingag'd with, forsaking all Business, and all honest Company, he pick'd Pockets, and stole every Thing he could</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA173403080011"/>
            <p>lay his Hands upon in Bartholomew-Fair, and likewise in Tottenham-Court-Fair, since which Time, he indur'd much Misery, having been taken up, and harrass'd in a miserable Manner, with nakedness, Cold, Hunger, and other Calamities, so that his Life was a Burthen to him. The Highway Robbery in <placeName id="OA17340308-geo-15">
                  <interp inst="OA17340308-geo-15" type="type" value="site"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17340308n46-1 OA17340308-geo-15"/>Stepney-Fields</placeName>, for which he died, is the only Fact of that kind he was ever guilty of, but if he had not been taken up, it would not have been the last; for he own'd his Resolution of continuing in such wicked Courses, if Providence had not disappointed him.</p>
            <p>He said he was very sorry, that when he rob'd the Prosecutor that he should use him so barbarously, in cutting him a-cross his Hand twice with a Knife, because he did not pull off his Cloaths so readily as he expected, and likewise for binding him, and then afterwards in throwing him into a Ditch; but he says Abbot, one of his Accomplices, who was an Evidence against him, and was likewise in the same Robbery, said, that He threatened to cut his Throat if he did not bind him; as he was very shortly to appear before Almighty God, to answer for his wicked Offences both to God and Man; he does not remember he said any such Expression: He beg'd Pardon of the Gentleman for using him so ill, and he hoped he would be so good a Christian as to forgive him, which he freely forgave all the World: And likewise he hoped Abbot the Evidence, who swore against him, wou'd take warning by his untimely Death, and not go on in his wicked course of Life, if he did, he said, he was afraid he would not be long after him.</p>
            <p>Abbot, who informed, and was Evidence against him, was the first who led him aside to those desperate enterprizes, and his constant Companion till he led him to the Halter.</p>
            <p>He never broke Houses, nor stole out of Shops, but sometimes got plenty of Money by picking Pockets and stealing privately, and that he spent in a most profuse, prodigal and foolish Manner; so that he always wanted, and (which is worse) was constantly attended with troubles of Mind, and gnawings of Conscience, like Prometheus's Vulture gnawing and feeding upon his Liver.</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA173403080012"/>
            <p>He confess'd that he was very wicked in Drinking, Swearing and Blaspheming; keeping company with lewd Women, and such other Vices as never fail to be the bane of those unhappy young Men, who forsaking God, are justly deserted by Him, and given up to those impieties, which always end in their utter Ruin and Misery.</p>
            <p>He repented very much for the follies of his Life, and after the dead Warrant came out, he cried and howled aloud in the Chappel, several Times, saying, O! what will become of my poor Soul, O! that God would have Mercy upon me! I desir'd him to be compos'd, since Death was no strange Thing, but a Debt which all Men must Pay; and therefore he being to die for his Crimes, by the Laws of the Land, ought to submit to the will of God, and take it as a just chastisement and punishment for his Sins. He was very Poor and Naked, and very ignorant of religious Matters, but willing to receive instruction. When I spoke to him privately, he always cried bitterly and express'd a deep sence of his Sin, and a fear for the Wrath to come; and this he gave for the reason of his crying so lamentably in Chapel. I comforted him with the promise of God's mercy in Christ. He declar'd his Faith in Christ; that he was a true Penitent, and forgave all Men, as he expected forgiveness from God.</p>
            <p>
               <persName id="OA17340308n56-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n56-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n56-1" type="surname" value="TUDOR"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n56-1" type="given" value="EDWARD"/>Edward Tudor</persName>, was indicted for breaking the House of <persName id="OA17340308n56-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n56-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n56-2" type="surname" value="HENEAGE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n56-2" type="given" value="THOMAS"/>Thomas Heneage</persName>, and stealing four Firkins of Butter, January the 27th, between Two and Three in the Night.</p>
            <p>He was a second Time indicted, for breaking and entring the House of <persName id="OA17340308n57-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n57-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n57-1" type="surname" value="OSBORN"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n57-1" type="given" value="FRANCIS"/>Francis Osborn</persName>, with an Intent to steal his Goods, January the 7th, between Twelve and One at Night.</p>
            <p>And a third Time indicted, for breaking and entring the House of <persName id="OA17340308n58-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n58-1" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n58-1" type="surname" value="SPENCER"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n58-1" type="given" value="SARAH"/>Sarah Spencer</persName>, and stealing a half Anchor of Brandy, a Gallon-Pot, and a two Quart-Pot, January the 6th, between Twelve and One in the Night.</p>
            <p>4. <persName id="OA17340308n59-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n59-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n59-1" type="age" value="20"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n59-1" type="surname" value="TUDOR"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n59-1" type="given" value="EDWARD"/>Edward Tudor</persName>, 20 Years of Age, of mean Parents, by <placeName id="OA17340308-geo-16">
                  <interp inst="OA17340308-geo-16" type="type" value="street"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17340308n59-1 OA17340308-geo-16"/>London-Wall</placeName>, had little Education at School, and what he had, he improv'd to no good Purpose; and as for religious Matters, he never car'd</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA173403080013"/>
            <p>much to be instructed that Way, having been a naughty, perverse, disobedient Boy.</p>
            <p>He was <rs id="OA17340308-occupation-7" type="occupation">bound Apprentice to a Blacksmith</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17340308n59-1 OA17340308-occupation-7"/> in <placeName id="OA17340308-geo-17">
                  <interp inst="OA17340308-geo-17" type="type" value="parish"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17340308n59-1 OA17340308-geo-17"/>White-Chappel</placeName>, to whom he serv'd out his Time, and then he wrought at his Trade for some Time, and married a Wife, a Year or two ago, who (as he said) was honest, and knew nothing of his villainous Actions, by whom, if he had been rul'd, he had not come to such a fatal End: This he desir'd to be publish'd, in Vindication of the young Woman.</p>
            <p>He might have liv'd by his Trade, and kept his Family, like one of his Station, but was too much addicted to Idleness, and lov'd wicked Company, who led him upon such Adventures, as speedily prov'd his Ruin.</p>
            <p>He confess'd the Facts he was convicted of, that he broke open Mr. Osborn's House, and took a Firkin of Butter, which they sold and divided the Money; and that he also broke into the other House, both in the Night-Time, and stole thence a half Anchor of Brandy, which, when they expos'd to Sale, a Waiter coming in, seiz'd it, and carry'd it off, for want of a Trasire, and they did not think fit to seek after it any more.</p>
            <p>He own'd these two Burglaries as sworn against him, only he alledg'd, That the Evidence was not just in relating some Circumstances, but these Things were not material.</p>
            <p>He confess'd, That he had committed a great Number of other Burglaries, but the Houses being none of the Richest, they got but poor Plunder; and that he was alwise a most flagitious, good for nothing Boy, having been a notorious Swearer, Drinker, Company-Keeper, with the vilest Women, and that he was wholly corrupted in his Morals, inclin'd to Evil, and averse to every Thing that's Good.</p>
            <p>He behav'd very well under his Misfortunes, and came to me in a Flood of Tears, confessing, That in every Respect, he was a most flagitious, and one of the Chief of Sinners, having been disobedient to his Parents, a Breaker of the Lord's Day, scarce going to Church at any Time; for when his Father, or Master, sent him to Church, he went into the Fields, with his</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA173403080014"/>
            <p>wicked Companions, and was employ'd in Drinking, Stealing, Cursing and Swearing, and came Home with a Lie in his Mouth; for when he was a Prentice, he spported his Pocket, and maintain'd his Extravagancies, with Pilfering and Thieving; and when out of his Time, he join'd to a Gang of Thieves, whose main Business it was, to break Houses, and do other base Actions, as they had Opportunity.</p>
            <p>I represented to him the infinite Mercy of God in Christ, that he is a God merciful and gracious, &amp;c. He declar'd his Faith in Christ, that he sincerely repented of all Sins, and died in Peace with all Mankind.</p>
            <p>
               <persName id="OA17340308n69-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n69-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n69-1" type="surname" value="CHARLESWORTH"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n69-1" type="given" value="CALEB"/>Caleb Charlesworth</persName>, was indicted for burglariously breaking and entring the House of <persName id="OA17340308n69-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n69-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n69-2" type="surname" value="MORGAN"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n69-2" type="given" value="DAVID"/>David Morgan</persName>, and stealing three Quart, three Pint, a half Pint, a Quartern, and half Quartern Pewter-Pots, a Table-Cloth, a Mantle, and an Apron, November the 16th, about the Hour of Twelve in the Night.</p>
            <p>5. <persName id="OA17340308n70-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n70-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n70-1" type="age" value="17"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n70-1" type="surname" value="CHARLESWORTH"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n70-1" type="given" value="CALEB"/>Caleb Charlesworth</persName>, near 17 Years of Age, of mean Parents, about the Town, who were willing to give him such Education at School, as they were able, but that was what he no Ways minded, thinking upon nothing, but to spend his Time idly with blackguard Boys, who taught him all Manner of Wickedness from his Cradle: And as for Religion, he altogether neglected the same.</p>
            <p>His father being a labouring man, could not have a very strict eye over him, but never neglected to give him good advice, and often pray'd for him, but all these things he little minded, being taken up with his companions, who made him go out upon thieving and pick-pocketting, by which indirect Methods, he never got much, for he was afraid to venture, and was always very much troubled in Mind, at his leading such a wicked course of life.</p>
            <p>He acknowledg'd the Burglary as sworn against him,</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA173403080015"/>
            <p>only he blam'd the Evidence as a principal Instrument of his Ruin. He was wretchedly poor and naked. He always behav'd well, and was very attentive to Prayers and Exhortations. He was very ignorant, but desirous of Instructions. He said, That he never knew what became of the Money unlawfully purchas'd, but that it dwindl'd away among the vile creatures he convers'd with, and that he was never the better for it; adding, That one Halfpenny well gotten, was better than Half-a-crown obtain'd in such a wicked Manner, which never fail'd to be attended with Remorse of conscience, and inward convulsions of the mind. He declar'd, That he hop'd for salvation through the Mercy of God in christ; that he repented of all his sins, and forgave all Men, as he expected Forgiveness from God.</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA173403080016"/>
            <p>At the Place of EXECUTION.</p>
            <p>THEY all appear'd very Serious, desirous of and attentive to Prayers. <persName id="OA17340308n75-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n75-1" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n75-1" type="surname" value="DEFOUR"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n75-1" type="given" value="JUDITH"/>Judith Defour</persName>, own'd the great Crime she committed, in cruelly Murdering her innocent Babe, and hop'd (these were her Words) that the Lord Almighty would have Mercy upon her. <persName id="OA17340308n75-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n75-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n75-2" type="surname" value="CRANE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n75-2" type="given" value="HENRY"/>Henry Crane</persName> said, he had been a very great Sinner, and seeing some young Men of his own Trade standing near by, who had often wrought with them in the same Shop; he spoke to them to this effect, viz. To beware of idleness, Drinking and bad Company, which had brought him to this shameful Death, to take example from him, and to live in the fear of God. <persName id="OA17340308n75-3">
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n75-3" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n75-3" type="surname" value="TUDOR"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n75-3" type="given" value="EDWARD"/>Edward Tudor</persName>, Spoke much to the same purpose; and both of them said, their Wives were innocent of their Robberies and Thefts, and hop'd the Word would not reflect on them, for</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA173403080017"/>
            <p>they was utter Strangers to our wicked course of Life. <persName id="OA17340308n76-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n76-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n76-1" type="surname" value="HOLBROOK"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n76-1" type="given" value="RALPH"/>Ralph Holbrook</persName>, and Charlesworth said, they had been very great Sinners, and rely'd upon the mercy of God. They all desir'd the Prayers of all Christian People. They went off crying out to God to have mercy upon their Souls, and that the Lord Jesus would receive their Spirits. All of them behav'd much better, than frequently these unfortunate People us'd to do.</p>
            <p>This is all the Account given by me</p>
            <p>
               <persName id="OA17340308n78-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n78-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n78-1" type="surname" value="GUTHERIE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n78-1" type="given" value="JAMES"/>JAMES GUTHERIE</persName>,</p>
            <p>
               <rs id="OA17340308-occupation-8" type="occupation">Ordinary and Chaplain</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17340308n78-1 OA17340308-occupation-8"/> of <placeName id="OA17340308-geo-18">
                  <interp inst="OA17340308-geo-18" type="type" value="site"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17340308n78-1 OA17340308-geo-18"/>Newgate</placeName>.</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA173403080018"/>
            <p>ADVERTISEMENTS.</p>
            <p>To be Sold by AUCTION,</p>
            <p>At Craven-House in Wytch street, on Thursday the 14th Instant and the following Days, beginning at Eleven o Clock each Day,</p>
            <p>ALL the rich Furniture of <persName id="OA17340308n83-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n83-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n83-1" type="surname" value="WOLLEY"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n83-1" type="given" value="RICHARD"/>Richard Wolley</persName>, Esq; <rs id="OA17340308-occupation-9" type="occupation">Merchant</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17340308n83-1 OA17340308-occupation-9"/>, late one of the Warehouse keepers belonging to the Charitable Corporation: Consisting of curious Needlework, Damask and Camblet Beds, with all Sorts of fine Redding, Chairs, Tables, Window Curtains, Carpets, Screen, Sconces, Plt and Chimney Glasses, a fine Parcel of Houshold Linnen, Plate, China, Paintings and Curiosities, his Coach, Charriot and Books, with all Sorts of Kitchen Furniture, a Parcel of Leaden Figures on Stone Pedestals belonging to his Garden.</p>
            <p>The Goods above-mention'd were brought from his Country Seat at <placeName id="OA17340308-geo-19">
                  <interp inst="OA17340308-geo-19" type="type" value="parish"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17340308n83-1 OA17340308-geo-19"/>Hornsey near Highgate</placeName>, to the House aforesaid for conveniency of Sale, and are all in good Condition.</p>
            <p>The Goods to be view'd from Tuesday the 12th, till the Time of Sale, Catalogues whereof will be timely dispers'd,</p>
            <p>By <persName id="OA17340308n86-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n86-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n86-1" type="surname" value="Jones"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n86-1" type="given" value="Tho"/>Tho. Jones</persName>, <rs id="OA17340308-occupation-10" type="occupation">Broker and Auctioneer</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17340308n86-1 OA17340308-occupation-10"/>.</p>
            <p>This Day is publish'd, Vol. II.</p>
            <p>(Price 3 s. 6 d.)</p>
            <p>With a Frontispiece of <persName id="OA17340308n89-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n89-1" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n89-1" type="surname" value="HAYES"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n89-1" type="given" value="CATHERINE"/>Catherine Hayes</persName>, of the Contrivance of the Murder of her Husband <persName id="OA17340308n89-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n89-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n89-2" type="surname" value="HAYES"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n89-2" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Hayes</persName>,</p>
            <p>THE Lives of the most remarkable Criminals who have been condemned and executed, either for the Highway, Street Robberies, Burglaries, Murders, or other capital Offences, from the Year 1720, to the present Time: Containing particularly the Lives of the famous <persName id="OA17340308n90-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n90-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n90-1" type="surname" value="WILD"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n90-1" type="given" value="JONATHAN"/>JONATHAN WILD</persName>, <persName id="OA17340308n90-7">
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n90-7" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n90-7" type="surname" value="Burnworth"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n90-7" type="given" value="Edward"/>Edward Burnworth</persName>, <persName id="OA17340308n90-8">
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n90-8" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n90-8" type="surname" value="Frazier"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n90-8" type="given" value="Edward"/>alias Frazier</persName>, Blewit, Berry, Dickenson, Majorum and Higgs, for the Murder of Mr. Ball in <placeName id="OA17340308-geo-20">
                  <interp inst="OA17340308-geo-20" type="type" value="site"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17340308n90-1 n90-7 n90-8 OA17340308-geo-20"/>St. George's Fields</placeName>; <persName id="OA17340308n90-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n90-2" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n90-2" type="surname" value="HAYES"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n90-2" type="given" value="CATHERINE"/>Catherine Hayes</persName>, for the barbarous Murder of her Husband; <persName id="OA17340308n90-3">
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n90-3" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n90-3" type="surname" value="SNOW"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n90-3" type="given" value="FORSTER"/>Forster Snow</persName>, for the Murder of a Man in his House in <placeName id="OA17340308-geo-21">
                  <interp inst="OA17340308-geo-21" type="type" value="parish"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17340308n90-3 OA17340308-geo-21"/>Holborn</placeName>; <persName id="OA17340308n90-4">
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n90-4" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n90-4" type="surname" value="BILLINGS"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n90-4" type="given" value="THOMAS"/>Thomas Billings</persName>, concern'd with <persName id="OA17340308n90-5">
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n90-5" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n90-5" type="surname" value="HAYES"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n90-5" type="given" value="CATHERINE"/>Catherine Hayes</persName>, in the Murder of Mr. Hayes; <persName id="OA17340308n90-6">
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n90-6" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n90-6" type="surname" value="SMITH"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n90-6" type="given" value="THOMAS"/>Thomas Smith</persName>, a Highwayman, and Capt. Jean, for the Murder of his Cabin-Boy, &amp;c. &amp;c. &amp;c.</p>
            <p>Printed and sold by <persName id="OA17340308n91-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n91-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n91-1" type="surname" value="APPLEBEE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n91-1" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Applebee</persName> in <placeName id="OA17340308-geo-22">
                  <interp inst="OA17340308-geo-22" type="type" value="street"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17340308n91-1 OA17340308-geo-22"/>
                  <placeName id="OA17340308-geo-23">
                     <interp inst="OA17340308-geo-23" type="type" value="site"/>
                     <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                           targets="OA17340308n91-1 OA17340308-geo-23"/>Bolt-Court</placeName>, Fleet-street</placeName>; A Bettesworth and C. Hitch, at the Red Lyon in Pater-noster-Row; J. Pemberton, at the Golden Buck against St. Dunstan's Church; J. Isted, at the Golden Ball near Chancery-Lane, Fleet-street; E. Symon, at the Royal Exchange; R. Ware, at the Bible and Sun in Amen-Corner, near Pater-noster Row; W. Mears, at the Lamb, the Corner of Bell-Savage Inn on Ludgate-Hill; <persName id="OA17340308n91-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n91-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n91-2" type="surname" value="WELLINGTON"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n91-2" type="given" value="RICHARD"/>Richard Wellington</persName>, at the <placeName id="OA17340308-geo-24">
                  <interp inst="OA17340308-geo-24" type="type" value="site"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17340308n91-2 OA17340308-geo-24"/>Dolphin and Crown</placeName>; and Mrs. Dodd, at the Peacock without Temple-Bar.</p>
            <p>Where may be had, Vol. I.</p>
            <p>N. B. Vol. III. is in the Press, and will be publish'd with all convenient Expedition.</p>
            <p>The Publick may depend on the Accounts publish'd in this Work, as containing a just and faithful Narration of the Conduct of these unhappy Persons, and a true State of their respective Crimes, without any Additions of feigning and romantick Adventures, calculated meerly to entertain the Curiosity of the Reader.</p>
            <p>ELectuarium Mirable; or the Admirable Electuary, which infallibly cures all Degrees and Symptoms of the Secret Disease, with more Ease, Speed and Safety, than any Medicine yet published. Any old Running, &amp;c. tho' of several Years standing, whether occasion d by an Overstrain, Weakness of the Seminals or the Relicts of a former Infection, is certainly cured in a short Time, without a Minutes Confinement, Suspicion, or the Use of Astringents; being a Medicine so wonderfully pleasant and easy in its Operation, that the nicest Palate, or weakest Constitution may take it with Delight. Two Pots are generally sufficient to compleat a Cure in most Cases. To be had (with Directions at large) only of the Author, Dr. C A M, a graduate Physician, who has published it Thirty Years, and is constantly to be advised with at his House, at the Golden Ball in Bow-Church-yard. Cheapside, a Half a Guinea the Pot.</p>
            <p>N. B. Since nothing is more requisite, in the Cure of any Distemper, than for a Patient to have free access to his Physician; therefore beware of buying Medicines from Toy-shops, Book-seller's-shops, &amp;c. the Authors of which are always conceal'd, and not to Spoke with on any Occasion. And tho' by their specious Pretences) you are promised a Cure, you'll certainly find it very Dear in the End.</p>
            <p>Verbum sat sapienti.</p>
            <p>See his Books lately publish'd, viz. His Rational and Useful Account of the Secret Disease. Price 1 s. His Practical Treatise; or Second Thoughts on the Consequences of the Venereal Disease, in Three Parts, viz. I. On the Simple Gonorrhaea, Gleets and other Weaknesses, whether from Venereal Embraces, Self-pollution, improperly call'd Onanism, or Natural Imbecility. II. On the Virulent Gonorrhaeas or Clap. III. On the Venereal Lues, or Grand Pox, &amp;c. Price 2 s. His Essay on the Rheumatism and Gout, Price 6 d. His Discourse on Convulsions. Price 6 d. And his Dissertation on the Pox. Dedicated to <persName id="OA17340308n98-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n98-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n98-1" type="surname" value="SLOANE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17340308n98-1" type="given" value="HANS"/>Sir Hans Sloane</persName>. Price 1 s. 6 d. All sold by G. Strathan in Cornhill; J. Wilford behind the Chapter-Coffee-House, St. Paul's Church-yard, and at the Author's House before mention'd.</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA173403080019"/>
            <p>D. R. NELSON, being well known to have made tho Cure of SEMINAL and GENITAL Imbecilties his chief Study and Practice for above 30 Years, does recommend his most Noble Cleansing and Strengthning Elixir, which Thousands of People (many of them of a high Rank) have happily experienced, and is by Numbers of Physicians and Surgeons approv'd, as the only BALSAMICK HEALING and RESTORING Medicine to be depended upon in the World.</p>
            <p>For GLEETS and WEAKNESES,</p>
            <p>THE Bane of Virility or Manhood, in the one Sex, and Destroyer of Fertility on the Bearing of Children in the other, whether from ill cur'd Venereal Infections (than which nothing is more common or from inordinate Coition, or Self-Polution that cursed School Wickedness, which spoils all our Youth, by nipping their Manhood in the Bud) or from involuntary Emissions a nights in the Sleep, or in the Day Time, upon Stool, or with the Urine; or from Falls, Blows, Strains, Wrenches, or the like, which drain and dry up the Seminals, and whither, as it were, the Generative Faculties, causing Impotency in Men, the Fluor Albus, or Barrenness in Women (or but a weakly, sickly Offspring if any); and in the long Run (by impoverishing the Blood and Spirits) Melancholly, Vapours, Decays of Nature and Consumptions.</p>
            <p>No Medicine can be more pleasant to take, nor any Thing upon Earth more effectual for the Purpose; for let the Imbecility be ever so great, or of ever so long standing, and be either in the Parts, Spermatick Vessels, or Back, with Pain or without, it certainly Cures, by reviving and enriching the Blood and Spirits, comforting, nourishing, and replenish the Reigns and Seminals, and strengthening, and restoring the Genital Parts in both Sexes, how much soever weakned, rendered cold, or deadned, and bringing them to their natural Force, Warmth, and Vigour, by thickening and fertilizing the Seed, which before was thin, waterish, or yellowish, and consequently insufficient, either for Procreation or the Act of it.</p>
            <p>All Disorders of the Urine, as Difficulty in the making or retaining it, or its dribbling away hot or smarting, or foul, slimy, thready, greasy, or stinking, whether from Gravel, Stone, Strangury or a Venereal Cause, are likewise speedily cured by it, and the Waer made to be held as strongly, and yet brought away as freely, easily, full stream'd, and clear as ever.</p>
            <p>These are the real Vertues of this great Medicine, which could all who stand in need of it, (but have not yet tried it) be made as sensible of, as those Numbers of People are, who have tried it, they would gladly, and quickly too, have recourse to it.</p>
            <p>Price 5 s. a Bottle. Prepared by the abovesaid Author, and sold only (sealed up with Directions how to take it, and how to discover whether the Gleet or Weakness be Venereal or not) at Mr. ISTED's, a Book seller, at the Golden-Ball, between St. Dunstan's Church and Chancery-Lane End in Fleet-Street, asking only for a 5 s. Bottle of Elixir.</p>
            <p>Dr. NEWMAN's Famous ANTI-VENEREAL PILL,</p>
            <p>WHICH to the Surprise of all that take it, cures all Degrees of the Venereal Disease. It gives immediate Ease in painful Bubos, Tumors, Durnal or Nocturnal Pains. Speedily removes the Running, Cordee, Heat of Urine, and Inflamation of the Parts, without an Hour's Confinement; nay, If you have Blotches and Scabs from Head to Foot, with tumified Testicks, Shankers, Pockey Warts, Phymoses, Paraphymoses, Ulcers in the Mouth, Nose, Throat or Palate, in a short Time you will be well, two or three being sufficient in a fresh Infection; but if it has been long upon the Patient, or in the Blood, a few more is Required for a Cure. They are sold at so easy a Price as only two Shillings each. Note, these Pills will be readily sent to any Part of England, if they write to the Author. They are the Bigness of a small Pea, and pleasant to take.</p>
            <p>N. B. I likewise have peculiar Medicines for the Rheumatism, Agues of Long-Standing, Old Gleets, Fits, and an Ointment which perfectly Cures any Itchy Breaking Out. Attendance is given every Day by the Author, at his House at the Blue-Ball in Hand-Court, almost over-against Great Turn-Stile, Holbourn.</p>
            <p>N. B. I have likewise an admirable Electuary, which cures all Diseases of the Breast and Lungs, as Coughs, Colds, Weesings, Phthysick, Asthma's, Shortness of Breath; restores lost Appetite, purifies the Blood, and procures a good Complection, and a strong vigorous Habit of Body; enlivens the Faculties and Memories. Sold at One Shilling the Gally-Pot with Directions.</p>
            <p>Advice Gratis.</p>
         </div0>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>