<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<TEI.2>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div0 type="ordinarysAccount" id="OA17190608">
            <interp inst="OA17190608" type="uri" value="ordinarysAccounts/OA17190608"/>
            <interp inst="OA17190608" type="date" value="17190608"/>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA171906080001"/>
            <p>THE Ordinary of NEWGATE HIS ACCOUNT OF The Behaviour, Confessions, and Last Speeches Of the Malefactors Executed at Tyburn, On Monday the 8th of June 1719.</p>
            <p>AT the Sessions held at <placeName id="OA17190608-geo-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17190608-geo-1" type="type" value="site"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17190608n30-99 n32-1 n32-2 n33-1 n34-1 n34-2 n34-3 n35-1 n35-3 n35-4 n36-1 n38-1 n38-2 OA17190608-geo-1"/>Justice Hall in the Old-Baily</placeName>, on Thursday, Friday, and Saturday, the 14th, 15th, and 16th of May, 1719, among the Persons then and there Try'd, Ten (that is, 7 Men and 3 Women) who were found guilty of divers Capital Crimes, did accordingly receive Sentence of Death: But Five of them being Repriev'd, viz. 2 of the Women upon account of their Pregnancy, and the other Woman, with two of the Men, by the Mercy of THEIR EXCELLENCIES THE LORDS JUSTICES (which Mercy I hope and heartily wish they may duly improve.) Five are now order'd for Execution.</p>
            <p>While they were under this melancholy State of Condemnation, I constantly visited them, and had them twice every day brought up to the <placeName id="OA17190608-geo-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17190608-geo-2" type="type" value="site"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17190608n30-99 n32-1 n32-2 n33-1 n34-1 n34-2 n34-3 n35-1 n35-3 n35-4 n36-1 n38-1 n38-2 OA17190608-geo-2"/>Chapel of Newgate</placeName>, where I read Prayers, and expounded the Word of God to them, endeavouring to perswade them now to live agreeably to it, who hitherto (as it appear'd) had highly offended. against it.</p>
            <p>On the Lord's Day the 24th of May last, I preached to them and others there present, both in the Morning and Afternoon, upon Psal. 86. 12, 13. Of which Text having given an Account in my Paper concerning <persName id="OA17190608n5-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17190608n5-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17190608n5-1" type="surname" value="WHEELER"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17190608n5-1" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Wheeler</persName>, who suffer'd on the Day immediately following, I shall not need say any more of it here: But proceed to the next.</p>
            <p>On Friday the 29th of the same Month, being the Anniversary Day of K. CHARLES the IId's Blessed Nativity and Happy Restauration: I preached on part of the Gospel appointed for the Service of that Day, viz. St. Matth. 22. 21, 22. Then saith He unto them, Render therefore unto Caesar, the Things which are Caesar's; and unto GOD, the Things that are GOD's. When they had heard these Words, they marvelled, and left Him, and went their way.</p>
            <p>Those Words of our Blessed Saviour to the Pharisees Disciples, and the Herodians, I first explain'd in general with their Context; and then consider'd in particular these three Things chiefly, viz.</p>
            <p>(Price Two Pence.)</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA171906080002"/>
            <p>I. The Question propos'd to CHRIST at the 17th Verse, thus worded, Is it lawful to give Tribute unto Caesar, or no?</p>
            <p>II. CHRIST's wise Answer to that Captious and insnaring Question, Viz. Render unto Caesar the Things which are Caesar's; and unto GOD the Things that are GOD's.</p>
            <p>III. Ult. The admirable Effect of that Answer; which was, That when they had heard these Words, they marvelled, and left him, and went their way.</p>
            <p>After I had enlarged upon those Points, and distinctly explained them, I endeavour'd to make my Auditory sensible of the indispensable Obligation incumbent on all of us to be Thankful to ALMIGHTY GOD for the Blessing, which by our Church, is this Day commemorated, and which (through a Series of Providences) has brought in this greater, viz. that of our having now on the Throne, so Wise, so Just, and so Excellent a MONARCH (Our Most Gracious KING GEORGE, Whom GOD long preserve) to rule over us. When I had done discoursing upon this Subject, I concluded the Whole with suitable Admonitions to the Condemn'd Prisoners; exhorting them to consider, How they had broke the Laws of GOD and of the KING, and how it behoved them therefore to repent and amend their Lives, before their Dissolution (now approaching) should come.</p>
            <p>On the Lord's Day the 31st of the said Month of May, I preached again to them, and others there present, both in the Morning and Afternoon; and this was my Text. 1 Joh. 3. 3. Every man that hath this Hope in him, purifieth himself, even as He is Pure.</p>
            <p>From which Words, first explained in general, I shew'd in particular.</p>
            <p>How a Man may know, whether he shall go to Heaven; and that is by treading in the Paths that lead thither; which are these, viz.</p>
            <p>I. A just Conformity to CHRIST's Purity and Holiness.</p>
            <p>II. A continual Striving after the Attainment of the utmost Perfection thereof (as far as possible) in the due Exercise of Christian Love.</p>
            <p>III. And lastly, A constant Perseverance therein; being perswaded of this comfortable Truth; That the more we love GOD and our Neighbour, the clearer Vision and the fuller Fruition we shall have of the DIVINE MAJESTY, when we come to Heaven; and, the more we are like to CHRIST in Grace here, the higher we shall sit by Him in Glory hereafter.</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA171906080003"/>
            <p>And Yesterday, being the 7th of this instant June, and the Second Sunday after Trinity, I Preached to them again, both in the Forenoon and Afternoon; taking my Text out of the Gospel appointed for that Day, viz. St. Luke 14. 16, 17. Verses, and part of the 18th Verse. Then saith He unto him, A certain Man made a great Supper, and bad many: And sent his Servant at Supper-time to say to them that were bidden, Come; for all things are uow ready. And they all with one Consent, began to make excuse.</p>
            <p>From this Text and the Context, wherein our Blessed Saviour sets forth His Parable of the great Supper, I observ'd, these Chief Things; viz.</p>
            <p>I. The Person Inviting.</p>
            <p>II. The Thing He Invites to.</p>
            <p>III. The Company Invited.</p>
            <p>IV. The Place of Invitation.</p>
            <p>V. Ult. The unworthy Refusal made by them that were Invited.</p>
            <p>In my Explanation of those several Particulars, I shew'd How in that Parable Our Blessed Saviour sets forth this great Truth, viz. That ALMIGHTY GOD lovingly invites Men to His Kingdom of Glory and Happiness, and They often unworthily reject His most gracious Invitation, as being more taken with the Things of the Earth here below, than with those infinitely better Things that are in Heaven above.</p>
            <p>Having enlarged upon all those Points, and endeavour'd to incline the Hearts of my Hearers to obey CHRIST's Call, and accept of the Felicity they were invited to, by HIM in whose Presence is fulness of Joy, and at whose Right Hand there are Pleasures for evermore; I did, for a Conclusion of the Whole, in a special manner apply my self to the Persons Condemned, whom I exhorted, more and more to take an impartial Survey of their past vicious Lives, seriously to consider their present dismal Condition because they had Sinned, and effectually labour to prevent their future miserable State, and obtain (through CHRIST's Merits) a Life of Endless Happiness in the next World, by making a wise Use of their few remaining (and therefore precious) Moments in this; that they might be at Peace with GOD, with their Neighbour, and with their own Consciences, before their Great Change came, which was now so near at hand.</p>
            <p>As they were attentive to my publick, so likewise to my private Instructions and Admonitions, wherein I represented to them the Deformity, Odiousness, and lamentable Consequences of Vice on the one hand, and the Beauty, Loveliness, and blessed Effects of True Religion and Virtue on the other; shewing them, that according as they now lived and dy'd, they should be either Happy, or Miserable for ever. In these they were fully taught, and seem'd to be very clear: And I hope they were most (if not all) of them well dispos'd.</p>
            <p>The respective Accounts which they gave me of Themselves are as follow.</p>
            <p>1. <persName id="OA17190608n30-99">
                  <interp inst="OA17190608n30-99" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17190608n30-99" type="surname" value="Broom"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17190608n30-99" type="given" value="Henry"/>Henry Broom</persName>, condemn'd upon Five Indictments, viz. First, For breaking open the House of Mr. <persName id="OA17190608n30-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17190608n30-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17190608n30-1" type="surname" value="RUSSEL"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17190608n30-1" type="given" value="SAMUEL"/>Samuel Russel</persName>, and taking thence 6 Pair of Holland Sheets, 11 Holland Shirts, 11 China Plates, and other Goods, on the 15th of December last. Secondly, For a like Burglary by him committed in the House of Mr. <persName id="OA17190608n30-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17190608n30-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17190608n30-2" type="surname" value="LAMB"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17190608n30-2" type="given" value="JAMES"/>James Lamb</persName>, stealing thence a Sett of Crimson Damask-Window-Curtains, a Sett of other Window-Curtains of Straw-Colour, a Silver Tea-Pot, a Silver-Mug, a Silver-Porringer, 5 Silver-Spoons, 15 Gold-Rings, and</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA171906080004"/>
            <p>other Things, amounting to a considerable Value, on the 21st. of that Month of December: Thirdly, For another Burglary (much of the same Nature with the former) which he committed in the House of Mrs. <persName id="OA17190608n31-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17190608n31-1" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17190608n31-1" type="surname" value="JACKSON"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17190608n31-1" type="given" value="MARY"/>Mary Jackson</persName>, taking thence 7 Silver-Spoons, some Silk-Window-Curtains, &amp;c. on the 9th of April last: Fourthly, For a like Burglary in breaking open the House of Mrs. <persName id="OA17190608n31-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17190608n31-2" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17190608n31-2" type="surname" value="GORDON"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17190608n31-2" type="given" value="ELIZABETH"/>Elizabeth Gordon</persName>, and stealing thence 4 yellow Silk-Curtains, a China Bason, a Sugar Dish, and other Goods, on the 19th of the said Month of April last: And Fifthly, For breaking, in like manner, the House of Mr. <persName id="OA17190608n31-3">
                  <interp inst="OA17190608n31-3" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17190608n31-3" type="surname" value="HAYS"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17190608n31-3" type="given" value="CLAUDE"/>Claude Hays</persName>, and taking thence 57 pound Weight of wrought Turkey-Silk, value 50 l. &amp;c. of all which Facts, and of many more, he confess'd he was guilty, particularly of that (not yet discover'd) which a little before last Christmas, he committed in Mr Webb a Weaver's House over-against the <placeName id="OA17190608-geo-3">
                  <interp inst="OA17190608-geo-3" type="type" value="parish"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17190608n30-99 OA17190608-geo-3"/>
                  <placeName id="OA17190608-geo-4">
                     <interp inst="OA17190608-geo-4" type="type" value="street"/>
                     <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                           targets="OA17190608n30-99 OA17190608-geo-4"/>Broad way</placeName> in Spittlefields</placeName>, which he broke open about 2 or 3 in the Morning, and stole from thence 5 Pieces of Garden Sattin, 2 Piece of plain Sattin, 57 Yards of white Mantue-Silk, and other Silks, amounting together to a great Value, which he sold for 30 l. only to two Women, that now keep out of the way. He said, That though he had done many ill Things, yet he never was punished by the Hand of Justice before now but once, when he received a Whipping for a small Felony; for all other Criminal Facts he had committed, came but lately to be made known. And further, this Account he gave of himself. He said, he was 23 Years of Age, born in the Parish of <placeName id="OA17190608-geo-5">
                  <interp inst="OA17190608-geo-5" type="type" value="parish"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17190608n30-99 OA17190608-geo-5"/>St. Ann in Westminster</placeName>; and <rs id="OA17190608-occupation-1" type="occupation">brought up to the Sea</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17190608n30-99 OA17190608-occupation-1"/>: That in the last Reign he serv'd two Years on Board the Sea-Horse, a 6th Rate Ship, whereof Captain Arundel was then Commander: That when he was discharged from his Sea Service, he lived at Land, and continued without any Employment for a considerable Time: That not knowing what Shift to make for a Livelihood, he betook himself (by the Instigation of other wicked Men) to very ill Courses, and had within these 4 Years past, committed several Burglaries and Robberies; and in those pernicious Practices, was so far engag'd, that though he more than once resolved against them, yet could not leave them off. Upon which I told him, That this must needs arise from his not using diligently the proper Means, by which he might have obtained Spiritual Strength to resist all Temptations to Sin. What those Proper Means were, and what he should now do in order to have all his Sins Pardon'd and his Soul sav'd, I laid before him, and I hope he follow'd my Directions herein. He told me, that he daily was endeavouring to make Satisfaction to the Persons he had robb'd, by giving them such Informations as he could, of their Goods; of which (he said) the Evidence against him, now in <placeName id="OA17190608-geo-6">
                  <interp inst="OA17190608-geo-6" type="type" value="site"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17190608n30-99 OA17190608-geo-6"/>New-Prison</placeName>, might give better; if not, he fear'd those Goods could not be had again, and he was sorry for it. He begg'd Pardon of God for all his Transgressions, which he declar'd to be no other, than such as most Men were subject to, saving the Crimes beforementioned, which he also pray'd Them, whom he had thus wrong'd, to forgive him.</p>
            <p>2. <persName id="OA17190608n32-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17190608n32-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17190608n32-1" type="surname" value="WOOD"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17190608n32-1" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Wood</persName>, condemned with <persName id="OA17190608n32-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17190608n32-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17190608n32-2" type="surname" value="MARGROVE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17190608n32-2" type="given" value="STEPHEN"/>Stephen Margrove</persName>, hereafter mention'd, for an Assault and Robbery by them jointly committed on the Person of <persName id="OA17190608n32-3">
                  <interp inst="OA17190608n32-3" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17190608n32-3" type="surname" value="SMITH"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17190608n32-3" type="given" value="GEORGE"/>George Smith</persName>, taking from him 22 Shillings on the 18th of January last, He said he was 22 years of age, born at <placeName id="OA17190608-geo-7">
                  <interp inst="OA17190608-geo-7" type="type" value="urban_centre"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17190608n32-1 n34-2 OA17190608-geo-7"/>Winchester</placeName>; That he came up to <placeName id="OA17190608-geo-8">
                  <interp inst="OA17190608-geo-8" type="type" value="urban_centre"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17190608n32-1 n34-2 OA17190608-geo-8"/>London</placeName> when very Young: That soon after he got into <rs id="OA17190608-occupation-2" type="occupation">Service</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17190608n32-1 n34-2 OA17190608-occupation-2"/>, and lived several Years (alternately) with divers Honourable Persons, by whom he was entertain'd, sometimes in the Capacity of a <rs id="OA17190608-occupation-3" type="occupation">Footman</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17190608n32-1 n34-2 OA17190608-occupation-3"/>, at other times in that of a <rs id="OA17190608-occupation-4" type="occupation">Butler</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17190608n32-1 n34-2 OA17190608-occupation-4"/>, and often in both those Capacities at once; and, That the last Service he was in, he quitted about 9 Months ago on account of his Lady's disliking of him. He protested, That he was Innocent of the Fact he stood Condemned for, but at the same time freely confess'd he had been (otherwise) an Ill-liver, as having frequently profaned the Lords-day, much neglected the Service of God, both publick and private, and often yielded to the Devil's Temptations, by which he was brought to the Commission of those Sins so common among Men, and so heinous withal, viz. Swearing, Cursing, Drinking, Adultery, Fornication, &amp;c. All. which he said he now abhorr'd, and truly repented of; praying God to for</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA171906080005"/>
            <p>give him all his Sins of what degree or nature soever. And here (after he had long persisted in his Denial of the Crime he was to suffer for) he at last acknowledged it, and the Justice of his Sentence upon it; adding, That of late he had made it his Wicked Practice, by using some undecent Gestures, to induce Men to Sodomy, whom he fancy'd might be inclinable that way, as if he would have yielded his Body to that foul Act; but when he had taken the Money agreed upon beetween them for it, he deceived them, and told them, that he was not for their Sport; and he must have more of their Money, or else he would accuse them, and defame them When he now came to himself, and consider'd this, and other his heinous Offences, he express'd great grief for them, as <persName id="OA17190608n33-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17190608n33-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17190608n33-1" type="surname" value="MARGROVE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17190608n33-1" type="given" value="STEPHEN"/>Stephen Margrove</persName>, (hereafter mention'd) did for his, who had committed the like Undecency and Cheat.</p>
            <p>3. <persName id="OA17190608n34-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17190608n34-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17190608n34-1" type="surname" value="MARGROVE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17190608n34-1" type="given" value="STEPHEN"/>Stephen Margrove</persName>, condemned for the same Fact, committed with the said <persName id="OA17190608n34-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17190608n34-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17190608n34-2" type="surname" value="WOOD"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17190608n34-2" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Wood</persName>. He said, he was 21 Years of Age, born in <placeName id="OA17190608-geo-9">
                  <interp inst="OA17190608-geo-9" type="type" value="parish"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17190608n32-2 n33-1 n34-1 n35-4 OA17190608-geo-9"/>
                  <placeName id="OA17190608-geo-10">
                     <interp inst="OA17190608-geo-10" type="type" value="street"/>
                     <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                           targets="OA17190608n32-2 n33-1 n34-1 n35-4 OA17190608-geo-10"/>Catherine-Wheel-Yard</placeName> in the Parish of St. James in Westminster</placeName>: That he had been 6 Years a <rs id="OA17190608-occupation-5" type="occupation">Servant</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17190608n32-2 n33-1 n34-1 n35-4 OA17190608-occupation-5"/> in a Coffee-house near <placeName id="OA17190608-geo-11">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17190608n32-2 n33-1 n34-1 n35-4 OA17190608-geo-11"/>Charing-Cross</placeName>; and afterwards lived with a Gentleman for sometime: That having quitted this Service, he got into another, which was that of <rs id="OA17190608-occupation-6" type="occupation">waiting on a Cornet</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17190608n32-2 n33-1 n34-1 n35-4 OA17190608-occupation-6"/> in the Regiment of Dragoons then at <placeName id="OA17190608-geo-12">
                  <interp inst="OA17190608-geo-12" type="type" value="urban_centre"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17190608n32-2 n33-1 n34-1 n35-4 OA17190608-geo-12"/>Worcester</placeName>: That the said Regiment being broke, his Master the Cornet, who had no further occasion for him, discharg'd him about a Twelve-month ago: That from that time he remain'd without any Employment, saving, that (now and then) he did <rs id="OA17190608-occupation-7" type="occupation">some Business for One that kept a Toy-shop</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17190608n32-2 n33-1 n34-1 n35-4 OA17190608-occupation-7"/> at <placeName id="OA17190608-geo-13">
                  <interp inst="OA17190608-geo-13" type="type" value="urban_centre"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17190608n32-2 n33-1 n34-1 n35-4 OA17190608-geo-13"/>Tunbridge</placeName>; and that, when out of Service, he lived mostly upon his Friends; some giving him Victuals, others Lodging, and others Washing. He deny'd the Fact he stood condemn'd for, and said, he never was guilty of any such Crime, nor any other; and, That he was not in the least addicted to the common Vices of Swearing, Cursing, Drinking, keeping Company with lewd Women, &amp;c. But after his loud Protestation of Innocence as to this Robbery, he at last confess'd his being concern'd in it; adding, That he had often allured Men (whom he supposed to be given) to Sodomy, but never suffer'd them to proceed to that foul Act with him, his Intent being only to get some Money, which he extorted from them by threatning them, much in the same manner as <persName id="OA17190608n34-3">
                  <interp inst="OA17190608n34-3" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17190608n34-3" type="surname" value="WOOD"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17190608n34-3" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Wood</persName> did. He acknowledg'd this was a great Offence, and therefore humbly begg'd Pardon of God, and all he had offended, to whom he could make no other Satisfaction.</p>
            <p>4. <persName id="OA17190608n35-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17190608n35-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17190608n35-1" type="surname" value="WILLIAMS"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17190608n35-1" type="given" value="RICHARD"/>Richard Williams</persName>, condemned for Assaulting and Robbing Mr. <persName id="OA17190608n35-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17190608n35-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17190608n35-2" type="surname" value="COURTNEY"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17190608n35-2" type="given" value="RALPH"/>Ralph Courtney</persName>, taking from him 42 Shill. on the 9th of April last. He said, he was 21 Years of Age, born in the City of <placeName id="OA17190608-geo-14">
                  <interp inst="OA17190608-geo-14" type="type" value="urban_centre"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17190608n35-1 OA17190608-geo-14"/>Hereford</placeName>, and lived there with his Father 'till about 6 Years ago, at which time he came up to <placeName id="OA17190608-geo-15">
                  <interp inst="OA17190608-geo-15" type="type" value="urban_centre"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17190608n35-1 OA17190608-geo-15"/>London</placeName>, and was bound <rs id="OA17190608-occupation-8" type="occupation">Apprentice to a Brazier</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17190608n35-1 OA17190608-occupation-8"/>: That after he had served two Years of his Apprenticeship, his Master dying, he got into another Service, and always behav'd himself honestly. He at first deny'd the Fact he stood condemn'd for, but afterwards confess'd he was guilty of it: And further declar'd, That for these two Years past he had been acquainted with <persName id="OA17190608n35-3">
                  <interp inst="OA17190608n35-3" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17190608n35-3" type="surname" value="WOOD"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17190608n35-3" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Wood</persName> and <persName id="OA17190608n35-4">
                  <interp inst="OA17190608n35-4" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17190608n35-4" type="surname" value="MARGROVE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17190608n35-4" type="given" value="STEPHEN"/>Stephen Margrove</persName> (beforementioned) and used their filthy and cheating Practices; but said he never committed that foul Sin of Sodomy, though he made a Shew, as if he would have inticed other Men into it; but it was only to get their Money. He said, he was sensible this was a great Offence, and therefore begg'd Pardon for it; as likewise for the Sins of Swearing Drunkenness, Profanation of the Lord's Day, and neglecting of all Holy Duties, &amp;c. of which, he told me, he repented from his Heart, and that he hop'd, GOD for CHRIST's sake (as he humbly implored) would be merciful to him, and forgive him.</p>
            <p>5. <persName id="OA17190608n36-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17190608n36-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17190608n36-1" type="surname" value="WOOD"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17190608n36-1" type="given" value="ABRAHAM"/>Abraham Wood</persName>, condemned for Assaulting Mr. <persName id="OA17190608n36-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17190608n36-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17190608n36-2" type="surname" value="BROWN"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17190608n36-2" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Brown</persName> on the High-way, and taking from him a Hat, a Silver Buckle, 2 Handkerchiefs, and 8 Shill. in Money, on the 10th of May last. He said, he was 19 Years of of Age, born at <placeName id="OA17190608-geo-16">
                  <interp inst="OA17190608-geo-16" type="type" value="county"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17190608n36-1 OA17190608-geo-16"/>
                  <placeName id="OA17190608-geo-17">
                     <interp inst="OA17190608-geo-17" type="type" value="urban_centre"/>
                     <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                           targets="OA17190608n36-1 OA17190608-geo-17"/>Epping</placeName> in Essex</placeName>: That his Father dying when he was very young, and leaving his Mother very poor, with 6 small Children; <rs id="OA17190608-occupation-9" type="occupation">the Parish bound him Apprentice for 14 Years to a Shoemaker</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17190608n36-1 OA17190608-occupation-9"/> in <placeName id="OA17190608-geo-18">
                  <interp inst="OA17190608-geo-18" type="type" value="parish"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17190608n36-1 OA17190608-geo-18"/>
                  <placeName id="OA17190608-geo-19">
                     <interp inst="OA17190608-geo-19" type="type" value="street"/>
                     <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                           targets="OA17190608n36-1 OA17190608-geo-19"/>Little George-Ally</placeName> in Spittlefields</placeName>: That he serv'd 8 Years of his Time, and then went from him, grew very loose, and had been so for these 2 or 3 Years past: That after he had thus left his Master, he served a <rs id="OA17190608-occupation-10" type="occupation">Drover</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17190608n36-1 OA17190608-occupation-10"/>; but indeed his chief Employ</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA171906080006"/>
            <p>ment within that Time, was that of Pilfering and picking of People's Pockets. He further confess'd, That he had altogether neglected the Service of God, had profaned the Lord's Day, and been too much given to Swearing, Drinking, and Whoring. And as to the Fact he stood Condemned for, he did in effect confess it; saying, That he follow'd Mr. Brown with an Intent to rob him, but did not do it himself; his two Companions (not yet taken) he suppos'd, did it. He was very ignorant, and could not so much as read, and seemed at first very little concern'd; but afterwards he became more serious, and express'd great Sorrow for his Sins, which he pray'd God to forgive him for CHRIST's sake.</p>
            <p>At the Place of Execution, to which they were carry'd from <placeName id="OA17190608-geo-20">
                  <interp inst="OA17190608-geo-20" type="type" value="site"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17190608n30-99 n32-1 n32-2 n33-1 n34-1 n34-2 n34-3 n35-1 n35-3 n35-4 n36-1 n38-1 n38-2 OA17190608-geo-20"/>Newgate</placeName> (in two Carts) this Day, I attended them for the last time; and two of them, viz. <persName id="OA17190608n38-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17190608n38-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17190608n38-1" type="surname" value="WOOD"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17190608n38-1" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Wood</persName> and <persName id="OA17190608n38-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17190608n38-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17190608n38-2" type="surname" value="WILLIAMS"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17190608n38-2" type="given" value="RICHARD"/>Richard Williams</persName>, declar'd to me (as they had done twice before) That <persName id="OA17190608n38-3">
                  <interp inst="OA17190608n38-3" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17190608n38-3" type="surname" value="IRONS"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17190608n38-3" type="given" value="EDWARD"/>Edward Irons</persName>, who is accused to have robb'd a Porter on the Highway, and taken from him a Neckcloth and two Shillings and Six Pence in Money, is innocent of that Fact: That themselves, with another lately gone into the Country, were the only Persons who did it; and, That the said <persName id="OA17190608n38-4">
                  <interp inst="OA17190608n38-4" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17190608n38-4" type="surname" value="IRONS"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17190608n38-4" type="given" value="EDWARD"/>Edward Irons</persName> was no ways concern'd with them in it. After they had made this Declaration, I pray'd by them, and desir'd them all to clear their Consciences in every thing. To which they answer'd, They had no more to say, but that they died in Charity with all Men; and desired the Spectators would pray for them, and that all (young Men especially) might take Warning by them. Which they having said, I pray'd for them again, and sung some Penitential Psalms with them: I also made them rehearse the Apostles Creed, and wish'd they might obtain that Life Everlasting, which they had now profess'd to believe; and, That the LORD JESUS CHRIST would please to say to every one of their Souls (as He once did to the Penitent Thief on the Cross) To day shalt thou be with me in Paradise. Thus having recommended them to the DIVINE GOODNESS and MERCY, I withdrew, and left them to their private Devotion, for which they had some time allotted them; and just as the Cart was drawing away, each of them earnestly cry'd to GOD for Pardon and Grace, in these and the like Ejaculations. LORD, have Mercy upon me! LORD, comfort thou me with thy Spirit! LORD JESUS, wash away my Sins in thy most precious Blood! LORD, he thou my Helper! LORD, I come, I come! LORD JESU, receive my Soul! &amp;c.</p>
            <p>This is all the Account here to be given of these Dying Malefactors by me,</p>
            <p>
               <persName id="OA17190608n40-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17190608n40-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17190608n40-1" type="surname" value="LORRAIN"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17190608n40-1" type="given" value="PAUL"/>PAUL LORRAIN</persName>, <rs id="OA17190608-occupation-11" type="occupation">Ordinary</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17190608n40-1 OA17190608-occupation-11"/>.</p>
            <p>Monday, June 8th. 1719.</p>
            <p>ADVERTISEMENT.</p>
            <p>
               <persName id="OA17190608n43-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17190608n43-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17190608n43-1" type="surname" value="WHITLEDGE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17190608n43-1" type="given" value="ROBERT"/>ROBERT WHITLEDGE</persName>, at <placeName id="OA17190608-geo-21">
                  <interp inst="OA17190608-geo-21" type="type" value="street"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17190608n43-1 OA17190608-geo-21"/>
                  <placeName id="OA17190608-geo-22">
                     <interp inst="OA17190608-geo-22" type="type" value="site"/>
                     <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                           targets="OA17190608n43-1 OA17190608-geo-22"/>the Bible and Ball</placeName> in Ave-Maria-lane</placeName>, Selleth all sorts of Bibles and Common Prayers, viz. The Three new large Folio Bibles, printed at Oxford: The English and French Common Prayer: All sorts of Common Prayer-books, illustrated with Sturt's Cuts, Vander Gucht's best Cuts or painted Cuts rul'd or unrul'd) or without; bound in Shagrine, with Silver Work or without, or in any other manner of Binding: Neat Pocket Bibles, with the Cambridge Concordance, Books of Devotion, the Sacrament, History, &amp;c. And all sorts of Bibles, Common Prayers, and other Books for the Use of Charity (and other) Schools. Likewise the Statutes at large, Books of Homilies, Duty of Man, &amp;c. and Letter-Cases of all sorts, by Wholesale and Retail. Note, Also Welsh Bibles and Common Prayers.</p>
            <p>Next Week will be Published, printed for <persName id="OA17190608n44-99">
                  <interp inst="OA17190608n44-99" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17190608n44-99" type="surname" value="Briscoe"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17190608n44-99" type="given" value="Sam"/>Sam. Briscoe</persName>, at <placeName id="OA17190608-geo-23">
                  <interp inst="OA17190608-geo-23" type="type" value="street"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17190608n44-99 OA17190608-geo-23"/>
                  <placeName id="OA17190608-geo-24">
                     <interp inst="OA17190608-geo-24" type="type" value="site"/>
                     <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                           targets="OA17190608n44-99 OA17190608-geo-24"/>the Bell-Savage</placeName> on Ludgate-Hill</placeName>.</p>
            <p>THE Works of Mr. <persName id="OA17190608n45-99">
                  <interp inst="OA17190608n45-99" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17190608n45-99" type="surname" value="Brown"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17190608n45-99" type="given" value="Tho"/>Tho. Brown</persName>, Serious, Moral, and Comical, in Prose and Verse, with his Amusements: Adapted to the Meridian of London, at the present Time: And Letters from the Dead to the Living, corrected from the Errors, of the former Impression. Adorned with beautiful Cuts, newly designed and engraved by the best Masters. To which is added, The Life and Character of Mr. Brown and his Writings. Now recommended to the Publick by <rs id="OA17190608-occupation-12" type="occupation">Sir</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17190608n45-1 OA17190608-occupation-12"/> 
               <persName id="OA17190608n45-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17190608n45-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17190608n45-1" type="surname" value="STEEL"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17190608n45-1" type="given" value="RICHARD"/>Richard Steel</persName>. In Four neat Pocket Volumes, on a new Elziver Letter.</p>
            <p>London: Printed for <persName id="OA17190608n46-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17190608n46-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17190608n46-1" type="surname" value="BRISCOE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17190608n46-1" type="given" value="SAMUEL"/>Samuel Briscoe</persName>, at <placeName id="OA17190608-geo-25">
                  <interp inst="OA17190608-geo-25" type="type" value="street"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17190608n46-1 OA17190608-geo-25"/>
                  <placeName id="OA17190608-geo-26">
                     <interp inst="OA17190608-geo-26" type="type" value="site"/>
                     <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                           targets="OA17190608n46-1 OA17190608-geo-26"/>the Bell-Savage</placeName> on Ludgate-Hill</placeName>. 1719.</p>
         </div0>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>