<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<TEI.2>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div0 type="ordinarysAccount" id="OA17601025">
            <interp inst="OA17601025" type="uri" value="ordinarysAccounts/OA17601025"/>
            <interp inst="OA17601025" type="date" value="17601025"/>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA176010250001"/>
            <p>THE ORDINARY of NEWGATE&#8217;S ACCOUNT of the Behaviour, Confession and Dying Words OF <persName id="OA17601025n2-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17601025n2-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17601025n2-1" type="surname" value="McCARTY"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17601025n2-1" type="given" value="PATRICK"/>PATRICK McCARTY</persName>, Who was executed at <placeName id="OA17601025-geo-1">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA17601025n2-1 OA17601025-geo-1"/>Russel-street</placeName>, <placeName id="OA17601025-geo-2">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA17601025n2-1 OA17601025-geo-2"/>Covent-Garden</placeName>, On SATURDAY the Twenty-fifth October, 1760.</p>
            <p>For the Murder of <persName id="OA17601025n3-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17601025n3-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17601025n3-1" type="surname" value="TALBOT"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17601025n3-1" type="given" value="WILLIAM"/>WILLIAM TALBOT</persName>.</p>
            <p>BEING THE Sixth EXECUTION in the MAYORALTY OF THE Rt. Hon. <persName id="OA17601025n4-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17601025n4-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17601025n4-1" type="surname" value="CHITTY"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17601025n4-1" type="given" value="THOMAS"/>Sir THOMAS CHITTY</persName>, <rs id="OA17601025-occupation-1" type="occupation">Knt</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17601025n4-1 OA17601025-occupation-1"/>. <rs id="OA17601025-occupation-2" type="occupation">LORD-MAYOR</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17601025n4-1 OA17601025-occupation-2"/> of the <placeName id="OA17601025-geo-3">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA17601025n4-1 OA17601025-geo-3"/>CITY OF LONDON</placeName>. NUMBER V. for the said YEAR.</p>
            <p>LONDON: Printed and sold by J. DIXWELL, in St. Martin&#8217;s-Lane, near Charing-Cross,for the AUTHOR: Also Sold by M. COOPER, in Pater-nosfter-Row.[Prince Six-PENCE.]</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA176010250003"/>
            <p>INTRODUCTION.</p>
            <p>- Et virgo cde madentes Ultima clestum terras Astra reliouit. Ovid. Metam. Lib. I.</p>
            <p>From blood-stain'd Earth, untainted justice slies, Last of the Gods, and claims her native Skies.</p>
            <p>The heinous crime of murder carries so many high aggravations in the name and idea of it, that it can scarce admit of any heightening. So strong and deep is the native colour of this guilt, that no tongue, no pencil, no instrument of human imagination can strike it deeper; it mocks all description; it can only be felt; and may none who read this, ever feel it! So keen, so intolerably pungent is the sense of it, to those who are not past feeling.</p>
            <p>An immortal spirit driven sudden from his earthly house, unprovided, unprepared for, unsecured of, that better, that heavenly mansion, for which it is formed by the Father of Spirits; and out of which celestial abode it can never find true and permanent felicity: his lot cast for all eternity, in the midst of a thousand follies, frailties, and faults, which cannot dwell with celestial happiness; but must depress the spirit, and, if not supported by the consolation, and raised with the hope of healing peace and heavenly pardon, from the supreme judge, must sink it (as sure as bodies gravitate to their center) to that abyss of misery prepared for the destroyer of his angels. What lot more terrible? what thought more amazing and alarming than this?</p>
            <p>The poet from whom the motto is borrowed, is justly thought by the best critics, to have derived his notions and description of the creation, the deluge, the gradual degeneracy of mankind, and decay of piety, (which provoked that deluge, and which are well represented in his four ages of the world) from a higher source than heathen mythology, even from the writings of Moses, to which his poetical rhapsodies are in many instances so conformable. In proof of this, consider the sentiments delivered by Moses in the sacred oracles. Gen. iv. 10, 11. The voice of thy brother's blood crieth unto me from the ground, and now art thou cursed from the earth, which hath opened her Mouth to receive thy brother's blood from thy band, &amp;c. And again, Gen. vi. 11. The earth also was corrupt before God; and the earth was filled with violence, &amp;c. v. 12, 13. And behold I will destroy them with the earth.</p>
            <p>After the flood, the fame crying sin is forbidden, and guarded against with the wisest cautions, and the surest and severest sanctions of Divine vengeance, Gen. ix. v. 3 - 6. At the same time that the royal grant of animal food is given from heaven, without which charter man has no right to the life of the meanest living creature, blood and murder are warned against and warded off. But flesh which is the life thereof, which is the blood thereof shall you not eat. And surety your blood of your lives will I require, &amp;c. Whoso sheddeth man&#8217;s blood, by man shall his blood be shed: for in the image of God made he man. The like precepts and sanctions are conveyed by the law and the prophets; and with greater authority by him who came not to destroy but to save life.</p>
            <p>On this supposition, 'tis no wonder if the goddess of justice be represented in the stile of heathen poetry, as flying from earth to heaven, detesting the horrors of a world drenched in blood; strongly conveying, and beautifully insinuating, this great truth, that murder is against every rule of natural right, most offensive to the deity and his</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA1760102520004"/>
            <p>attribute of justice; and in consequence that the disposal and resuming of life is a prerogative royal of the sole giver of life, which none should presume to invade without a warrant from the supreme power conveyed thro' the channels of proper and regular authority: - that he communicates his power for the purposes of his universal kingdom, the good of the whole, to his vice-gerents on earth; since by him Kings reign, and Princes decree justice, Prov. viii. 15. Rom. xiii. 4. Whose sword is put into their hands, not to be wielded in vain; and through them conveyed to the ministers of their just and lawful commands, from the highest to the lower ranks of men, whether in the civil or military line; who by these direct means derive their authority over the life of a transgressor, or a public enemy, from the Fountain of all power.</p>
            <p>The argument, therefore, against murder, whether of self, or another, drawn from this principle, is valid and impregnable; and "great pity it is" that the niblers at it, in a late Magazine, did not seriously and sagaciously consider this before they began to shew and apply their teeth to that file: because,</p>
            <p>- Fragili qu</p>
            <p>rens illidere dentem, Offendet silido.</p>
            <p>HOR. L. II. Sat. 1.</p>
            <p>This attack came from a quarter, whence by the shew and the colours they hang out, it should be least expected. The Gentleman's Magazine should keep up to its title, by giving more gentleman-like treatment, by exhibiting proofs of an extensive knowledge, of candid thoughts and behaviour, becoming a gentleman's education.</p>
            <p>But if to curtail, misrepresent, and then abuse a performance; if to plunder and maim a traveller, and then sneer at him, become the assumed character of a gentleman, it must be owned, that in this instance, the compiler, like Mackh - th, has top'd his Part.</p>
            <p>The better morals and sentiments of the heathen poet, will one day rise in judgment against those who disgrace the more venerable name we bear, and the superior degrees of light, of grace and truth, which are daily offered to us.</p>
            <p>With some out-lines of the same poet's description of the iron age, applicable to the tragic scene before us, I beg leave to close this introduction.</p>
            <p>-"De duro est ultima serro</p>
            <p>Protinus irrumpit ven pejoris in vum</p>
            <p>Omne nesas; fugere pudor, verumque fidesque</p>
            <p>In quorum subiere locum, fraudesque dolique,</p>
            <p>Insidique &amp; vis, &amp; amor sceleratus habendi."</p>
            <p>- Hard steel succeeded then;</p>
            <p>And stubborn as the metal were the men.</p>
            <p>Truth, modesty, and shame the world for sook;</p>
            <p>Fraud, avarice, and force, their places took.</p>
            <p>"Jamque nocens ferrum, ferroque nocentius aurum</p>
            <p>Prodierat; prodit bellum quod pugnat utroque;</p>
            <p>Sanguineaque manu crepitantia concutit arma.</p>
            <p>Vivitur ex rapto."</p>
            <p>Thus cursed steel, and more accursed gold,</p>
            <p>Gave mischief birth, and made that mischief bold;</p>
            <p>And double death did wretched man invade,</p>
            <p>By steel assaulted, and by gold betray'd.</p>
            <p>Now brandish'd weapons glitt'ring in their hands,</p>
            <p>Mankind is broken loose from moral bands.</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA176010250005"/>
            <p>THE ORDINARY of NEWGATE'S ACCOUNT of the Behaviour Confession, and Dying Words; &amp;c.</p>
            <p>By virtue of the King's commission of the peace, and oyer and terminer, for the city of London, and at the general sessions of gaol delivery of Newgate, holden for the city of London and county of Middlesex at Justice-hall in the Old Baily, before the <persName id="OA17601025n43-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17601025n43-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17601025n43-1" type="surname" value="CHITTY"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17601025n43-1" type="given" value="THOMAS"/>Right Honourable Sir Thomas Chitty</persName>, <rs id="OA17601025-occupation-3" type="occupation">Knt</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17601025n43-1 OA17601025-occupation-3"/>. <rs id="OA17601025-occupation-4" type="occupation">Lord Mayor</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17601025n43-1 OA17601025-occupation-4"/>, the Honourable Mr. Justice Clive, one of the Judges of his Majesty's court of Common Pleas; <persName id="OA17601025n43-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17601025n43-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17601025n43-2" type="surname" value="SMYTHE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17601025n43-2" type="given" value="SIDNEY STAFFORD"/>Sir Sidney Stafford Smythe</persName>, <rs id="OA17601025-occupation-5" type="occupation">Knt</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17601025n43-1 OA17601025-occupation-5"/>. one of the Barons of his Majesty's court of Exchequer; <persName id="OA17601025n43-3">
                  <interp inst="OA17601025n43-3" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17601025n43-3" type="surname" value="MORETON"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17601025n43-3" type="given" value="WILLIAM"/>Sir William Moreton</persName>, <rs id="OA17601025-occupation-6" type="occupation">Knt</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17601025n43-3 OA17601025-occupation-6"/>. <rs id="OA17601025-occupation-7" type="occupation">Recorder</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17601025n43-3 OA17601025-occupation-7"/>, and others his Majesty's Justices of oyer and terminer for the said city and county; on Wednesday the 22d, Thursday the 23d, and Friday the 24th of October, in the 34th Year of his [late] Majesty's reign, <persName id="OA17601025n43-4">
                  <interp inst="OA17601025n43-4" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17601025n43-4" type="surname" value="M'CARTY"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17601025n43-4" type="given" value="PATRICK"/>Patrick M'Carty</persName> was capitally convicted for the willful murder of <persName id="OA17601025n43-5">
                  <interp inst="OA17601025n43-5" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17601025n43-5" type="surname" value="TALBOT"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17601025n43-5" type="given" value="WILLIAM"/>William Talbot</persName>.</p>
            <p>
               <persName id="OA17601025n44-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17601025n44-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17601025n44-1" type="surname" value="M'CARTY"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17601025n44-1" type="given" value="PATRICK"/>Patrick M'Carty</persName>, otherwife <persName id="OA17601025n44-3">
                  <interp inst="OA17601025n44-3" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17601025n44-3" type="surname" value="Carty"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17601025n44-3" type="given" value="Patrick"/>Carty</persName>, was indicted for the murder of <persName id="OA17601025n44-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17601025n44-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17601025n44-2" type="surname" value="TALBOT"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17601025n44-2" type="given" value="WILLIAM"/>William Talbot</persName>, by striking and stabbing him in the left bread, and giving him one wound of fix inches deep, and three quarters of an inch wide, on the 11th of October in the parish of <placeName id="OA17601025-geo-4">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17601025n44-1 n44-2 n44-3 OA17601025-geo-4"/>St. Giles in the Fields</placeName>, of which wound he instantly died.</p>
            <p>He was also indicted for the same, on the statute of stabbing, and on the Coroner's jury of inquest.</p>
            <p>The nature and circumstances of the crime were pathetically, and in strong terms, but with candour, laid before the court, and jury, by the learned council, for the prosecution, to this effect: that the prisoner at the bar had <rs id="OA17601025-occupation-8" type="occupation">kept the King&#8217;s-head</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17601025n44-1 n44-3 OA17601025-occupation-8"/>, at the corner of <placeName id="OA17601025-geo-5">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17601025n44-1 n44-3 OA17601025-geo-5"/>Prince's-street</placeName>, in <placeName id="OA17601025-geo-6">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17601025n44-1 n44-3 OA17601025-geo-6"/>Drury-lane</placeName>, about six months ago; but having failed, and kept out of the way, an execution was awarded against him in</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA176010250006"/>
            <p>the palace court for a debt, which, with the costs, amounted to 4 l. and upwards; that most of the officers of that quarter being afraid to apprehend him, this attempt unhappily fell to the lot of the deceased, who being apprehensive of an escape, sent for four or five officers to prevent it. The prisoner being in custody, demanded what was due? The deceased put his hand to his pocket to find the execution, and tell the exact sum; during which, the prisoner lifted up his hand with a knife eight or nine inches long, like a cook's knife; and while Talbot, (spying it,) strove to defend his head with his left arm, stab'd him under it, in the left breast, cut the great tendon of his heart; he only said, Oh! He has done for me, and expired. The prisoner brandish&#8217;d his weapon, made several pushes at others who stood at some distance in the room, clear'd his way, walk'd down <placeName id="OA17601025-geo-7">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17601025n44-1 n44-3 OA17601025-geo-7"/>Prince's-street</placeName> with the bloody knife in his hand, was pursued to <placeName id="OA17601025-geo-8">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17601025n44-1 n44-3 OA17601025-geo-8"/>Vere-street</placeName>, and <placeName id="OA17601025-geo-9">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17601025n44-1 n44-3 OA17601025-geo-9"/>Clare-street</placeName>; and the cry of murder being at his heels, was stopt, surrounded by a soldier, and one or two more; and he having still the instrument of death in his hand, it was with hazard and difficulty wrested from him, and being seized and taken before Justice F - G was committed to <placeName id="OA17601025-geo-10">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17601025n44-1 n44-3 OA17601025-geo-10"/>Newgate</placeName>.</p>
            <p>All this, with other aggravating circumstances, was proved by seven or eight witnesses on the trial; and what is remarkable, by a ninth witness also, who was called in the prisoner's behalf to prove what provocation he received from the deceased. The trial continued about an hour and a quarter, and the jury brought in their verdict in a few minutes, without going out of court. At his arraignment, and during his trial, his behaviour was better than could be expected from several gloomy symptoms of a disordered mind, which appeared during his consinement; whether real, or affected, let others determine, as they see cause. But at this, juncture he seem'd composed and quite free from any such symptoms, resolute and unconcern'd, except when the evidence was given about the manner in which he struck the mortal blow, attended with an expression of his breath, like that of a paviour beating down the pavingstones with his rammer. His countenance changed, some say, into a convulsive motion like a laugh, others say he wept, but which foever it was, he put up his handkerchief to his face, to hide it, and wiped his eyes. During the trial, he was observed also to change handkerchiefs with his brother, who stood very near him at the bar; on which various furmises and conjectures were raised, either that poison was conveyed thereby to the prisoner, or else that the prisoner had therein delivered something valuable to his brother; he was therefore afterwards questioned by me, concerning the reason of this exchange, and he said, it was only to return his brother's, and get his own handkerchief from him.</p>
            <p>Immediately after conviction, sentence of execution was pronounced against him in a very awful, solemn and affecting manner, with an earnest exhortation to him, and prayer for him, that he might by true and hearty repentance be entitled to that mercy in a better world, which could not be extended to him here; and that for this purpose, he might make the best use possible of the very few hours he had to live. And instead of being executed at the usual place, and then delivered to be anatomized, it was judged expedient, in order to deter other desperate debtors, or offenders, especially in that part of the</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA176010250007"/>
            <p>town, where it is said to be too prevailing, from offering any violence to the officer of law and justice, in the discharge of their duty, to execute him at the crossing of several streets between Dury-lane and Covent-garden, nearly within fight o his late house, where the perfidious and bloody deed was perpetrated, and afterwards that his body should be hung in chains at Finchley-common.</p>
            <p>Having thus thrown together what seemed material and striking, concerning his trial, conviction and execution, the reader is desired to accept of the following brief narrative of his behaviour after his commital. When brought to Newgate, on the day of the fact, and within an hour or two after it, as he fat in the tap-room, he is said to have imputed this rash deed to an unguarded passion, and seem'd to relent. When visited next morning, being Sunday, October 12, he lay on his bed in a room on the press-yard side, which he had paid for; but appeared quite restless and uneasy. I could not forbear expressing my great concern to see him in that sad situation, tho&#8217; a stranger to him and his case; he answer'd without hesitation, that "his case was very bad; for he had killed a man yesterday." I replied, may God give you grace, to repent of this your crime, and of all those evil courses and steps which have betrayed you to so desperate a. deed; but rise quickly and come up to chapel: he forthwith consented and complied, and was at prayers sooner than I could expect. observing him in chapel, to behave awkwardly, sitting when he should kneel, and making no responses, nor reading the Psalms, he was beckon'd to, and directed to open and use a Prayerbook, which he did, being assisted by some other of the prisoners in turning to the psalms and prayers, to which he seemed to give some attention, though with manifest disturbance and confusion, and without any appearance of composure and comfort. This brought to mind that heavy threatning of the Almighty, by the prophet Ifaiah (i. 15.) When ye spread forth your hands, I will hide mine eyes from you: yea, when ye make many prayers, I will not hear, YOUR HANDS ARE FULL OF BLOOD.</p>
            <p>Yet through this thick and dark cloud, a gleam of light and hope seems to break, to prevent utter despair, in the words immediately following, v. 16, 18. Wash ye, make ye clean, put away the evil of your doings from before mine eyes, cease to do evil, learn to do well, - though your sins be as scarlet, they shall be as white as snow, though they be red like crimson, they shall be as wool.</p>
            <p>The lessons also for the morning service were read, open'd and explain'd, and some proper doctrines and uses raised from them, and applied to this and the rest of the prisoners.</p>
            <p>It was not without a particular felicity, that Nebuchadnezzar's setting up the golden image to be worshipped in the empire of Babylon, a type of the corruptions of the church of Rome, (Dan. iii.) fell in for the first lesson; on which occasion were set before them, the general corruption and prostitution of the consciences of all ranks and conditions of men, in submitting to it; except the three Israelites, true servants of the living God, who made a noble stand against this impious and idolatrous decree; the reward of their brave resolution in suffering patiently, for obeying the will of God, rather than the impious command of man, by passing unhurt through the burning fiery furnace: being preserved by the Divine</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA176010250008"/>
            <p>presence of the Son of God, as this mighty king himself saw and confessed; in consequence of which, he made a decree against dishonouring, or blaspheming the true God; because there is no other God that can deliver after this fort; and promoted his well-tried and faithful servants. These were subjects that should affect the heart of a murderer, bred up in the tenets of persecuting idolatry in that church, which, while it continues unreformed from such doctrines and practices, will ever be a scandal to the laws of God, and the religion of Christ. These proofs should strike him with the strongest and clearest conviction, that he was hitherto in the wrong way; and for the present he really seem'd strongly affected, lifting up his eyes for mercy, when these subjects were touched upon, and when to awaken him to a sense of his guilt, the contrary cause of his expected punishment was laid before him.</p>
            <p>The 2d lesson, St. Mark xiv. was also explained and applied, setting before him the great end of Christ's appearance and sufferings in our nature, and the blessed hope of pardon and salvation he might by true repentance, and a lively faith derive to his soul from this most merciful and amazing dispensation of divine love; especially considering what farther occurred in this chapter; viz. Peter's rash deed of cutting off an ear; the dental of his master, with many aggravating circumstances; and yet his conversion and repentance. These were insisted on for an example and admonition to the most heinous offenders not to fall into despair, but like Peter, to think on their own crimes with hearty contrition, to weep and pray for pardon; and that, believing, they should receive it, and become everlasting monuments of the Divine mercy, after the example of this fallen but recover'd and restored disciple of the blessed Jesus, recorded in the gospel for the direction and consolation of the most rash and unguarded sinners.</p>
            <p>Notwithstanding he seem'd deeply affected with what was spoken to him on this subject and occasion, yet when applied to after prayers, he declared himself of the church of Rome, desired he might not be hindered from having a gentleman of that persuasion come to him; (a request he had no occasion to make to me, for I never knew them excluded) for that he freely acknowledged he should be directed by him; though in the mean time he should be glad of my assistance; which, while in his right mind, he accepted of to the last. On this occasion he was answered, that I was sensible how difficult it is to get clear of the prejudices, and even errors of education, but that he had now a fair opportunity for it; that his present dreadful circumstances, if duly improved, might be the occasion of saving his soul; that for this end, every help in my power should be chearfully and heartily given to him, with the same zeal and sincerity as for my own soul: and as to his request for other assistance, he well knew he was now my proper charge; that if the gentlemen whose help and direction he desired, had the power over us, no such favour would be indulged to our people in the like case. This he fairly owned to be true; and from thence (he was told) he might see we had that badge and character of the true disciples of Christ; charity, mutual forbearance, and meekness of spirit, which they wanted; and by this alone he might distinguish this true living branch of the Catholic-church, from all false and dead branches: 'by this shall all men know</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA176010250009"/>
            <p>that ye are my disciples, if ye love one another.' Adding several other marks and proofs, both at this time, and in the afternoon service, which he attended; that we are a sound part of the Catholic-church, and that they are fallen from it; warn'd him also of the consequence of putting himself under another's direction, which I have so often known by experience, that he would be forbidden any farther intercourse with me. However, as he could read, I put a Bible, and other proper tracts into his hands, pointed out the most proper places, and having again warned and directed him, left him to his choice. His brother, with another visitor, were frequently with him; and one or two of the runners were constantly to be left with him, to prevent his offering any violence to himself, according to a caution and order given concerning him, by the justice who committed him. In a day or two he was visited by a gentleman of his own perswasion, as he had desired; but about the same time he began to behave and speak as if mad: when I saw him in the press-yard, he was fingering his irons, asked one of his keepers to let him out, said the affair of the crime he was charged with was got over very well, that the man was recovered, for he had given him fifteen guineas and paid for his cure. The same afternoon he committed several outrages, having given a violent stroke on the nose to James, one of the runners, and beat his head against the wall; in consequence of which he was moved by four men into a cell, and there chained down to a floor. A lay gentleman, Mr. H -, who visited him once or twice in this situation, spoke seriously to him, bid him think of employing his time better, and read good books. He thanked him for his advice, and said he would do so. However, he gave but awkward proofs of his performing his promise, for he kept singing aloud, thus chained as he was, and said he did not value it, nor any thing else they could do-owned his father told him ten years ago that he should be hang'd! [Hear this ye undutiful children! ye obdurate sinners! who provoke and rebel against those who love you, and care most for your happiness, and anxiously forewarn you of your misery, that ye may escape it. Hear this and tremble!] He added, but I am determined I will not be hanged. On this a fresh caution was given to the keepers to watch him more closely, and admit none to him without being present. On his continuing several days to behave like a madman, the Bible, and other books and tracts which I had lent him, were by me ordered to be gathered up and restored. They were all found and returned, except one, which I had first carefully read to him, and instructed him more fully in the contents of it, and then lent to him to be perused in private: this was missing, and could never be recovered. The purport of it is, to shew in few and plain words, the essential and primary articles of the Christian Faith, wherein we agree with the church of Rome, and those twelve articles, superadded, introduced, and imposed, within a few centuries past, by that church, contrary to scripture and antiquity, wherein we therefore differ from them. The tract is entitled, A View of the Articles of the Protestant and Popish Faith: To which is added, An Address to the Laity. This was unluckily sunk, or possibly underwent the flames, as its author might have done in worse times, for bearing witness to truths disagreeable to zealots who are wilfully blind. But alas! why should we be deemed and treated as their enemies, for</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA176010250010"/>
            <p>telling them the most necessary and salutary truths? M'Carty being asked by me, at his last day but one, whether he had read this, and what he had done with it? he said he could give no account of it, for he had read very little of it, and that he had left it in his room: but there it was not to be found, as before-mentioned, tho' more valuable books were.</p>
            <p>On the day intervening between sentence and execution, he was again visited by me in his cell, where he lay in his bed reading, and seemed tolerably well composed and resigned: having again condoled with him, he was reminded that his present sad condition was what he had too much reason to expect for some time past, hoped therefore it did not surprize him unprepared: that it is my duty to assist and comfort him under it, and endeavour to prepare him for a speedy change for a better place. He thanked me; but "owned he had been visited by another gentleman, who had done whatever was necessary for him; that he was easy in his mind, and would not change his condition with any one."</p>
            <p>But is there not an opium for souls as there is for bodies? a spirit of slumber and delusion that is deadly poison to the soul? We are assured by the best authority that there is, and are warned against it. I therefore earnestly beseeched him to attend to a word of exhortation, and join in prayers, in which I told him I should urge nor offer nothing in either, but matters in which Christians of every denomination do, or may, safely agree. On these terms I visited him twice this day, for above an hour each time, which he seemed thankfully to receive, and heartily to join in the prayers offered up. In the intervals of which time we had some conversation: he seemed to resent the strict guard kept over him left he should destroy himself by poison, or otherwife; saying, that because Stirn had been possessed with the devil, and made away with himself, they imagined it was so with him too; but, he added, God forbid I should have any such thought.</p>
            <p>He was instructed in a proper exhortation concerning the heinous and hardening nature of his crime; and that without holiness no man shall see the Lord; earnestly warned, therefore, not to rest in a superficial repentance, or slight endeavour, after that true peace and holiness, but to cry mightily for pardon before he be forever excluded from the hope of it. He was sensibly touched; he complied; he kneeled down on the ground, prayed with his face bowed down to the bed, wept, sob'd and cried earnestly for mercy. Thrice at one visit we repeated this exercise, wherein proper prayers, relative to his crime, were offered up; also for true and hearty contrition, charity and grace to forgive all whom he apprehended to have injured or offended him in any wife, and for those whom he had wronged and injured, especially the widow and orphans whom he had deprived of a husband and a father, and his creditors, to all whom he was incapable to make any satisfaction; beseeching God, of his rich mercy in Christ Jesus, to recompence them with his manifold blessings, and to do them good for the evil he had done them. We prayed also for resignation to the Divine Will, such a servent love of God as should inspire him with an utter abhorrence of sin, and all other graces necessary for a dying person.</p>
            <p>In conversation he told me, that the fact he was to die for, was occasioned by an affair that happened the 17th of march last, when Mrs. L - D, (the wife of one of the witnesses against him, at whose suit</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA176010250011"/>
            <p>he was arrested by Talbot) came into his house with two men, had some liquor, and a reckoning to pay, for which they offered a ring to pledge, instead of money, and laid it on the bar; that his wife being then in the bar, refused it; and referring it to him, he also said he would take no pawns, as she had once before pledged a silver spoon with them, which proved to be stolen: - That upon this, one of the men took up the ring again, and carried it off; and in a few days after they served him with a writ for the value of the said ring; and he being then, or soon after, under a cloud, banished from his house and business, the suit was carried against him in the court, and run to an execution. - That Mr. Talbot, who knew all the affair, had been his schoolfellow and old acquaintance, yet took it upon himself to arrest him for it. He declared that when he drew his knife he did not intend to murder, but to fright him away by a cut on the head or shoulder that he might make his escape. It was asked, why did you carry such a desperate weapon about you? he answered, he had usually carried it, when in business, as a cook's knife. Are you a cook then? he said he understood a good deal of it: it is said that you were a baker by trade; he answered, he never served his time to it. It is known, however, by his acquaintance, that he has followed that business during the former part of fifteen years that he has been in London; after which he kept the house (in which the fact was done) for three or four years; during most part of which time he served as a parishofficer, or headborough, and is said to have behaved well in that office: he had r the nick-name of laughing Carty, from a propensity to that habit.</p>
            <p>Being farther questioned, whether he had not declared and resolved to kill any man who should attempt to arrest him; he said, no: but owned he had threatened hard. It was then gently hinted to him, that, besides the fact of which he was convicted, the world took great liberties with his character in another very tender point, of which it behoved him to clear himself if he could: he desired to know what that was; and was answered, that it was said by some of his neighbours that he was the cause of his wife's death; tho' it must be acknowledged at the same time that others of them deny it. He wished to know who charged him with such a thing, for if he were abroad and at liberty, he could soon convince them to the contrary, adding, that he was in exile, and at a distance from his wife when she died, and that it was only a malicious report; and being easy in his own mind about it, he cared not what the world said.</p>
            <p>Another charge was mentioned to him, which I told him I should be glad to set in a true light, that of tricking his brewer out of a sum of money which had been paid into his hands, in part of a much greater debt.</p>
            <p>Of this matter he gave the following account: About the 15th of April last he was arrested for 27 l. at the suit of his coal-merchant; he had only 111. in the house, the goods and stock of which were then appraising, in order to be sold to his successor, Mr. C - ns: he desired the officer, P - p W - r, to take his word for an hour till he should receive more money; but this he refused. He then applied to Robson, his own appraiser, then in the house, settling the appraisement, to take his sum of 111. and make it up 27 l. but neither would he do it. He sent his brother to W - m B - n, a publican, in Little Wild-street, to borrow 21 l. of him:</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA176010250012"/>
            <p>this sum Mr. B - n sent him immediately, (tho' he owed him twenty-five guineas before) telling him he must repay it punctually, being his brewer's money; which M'Carty promised to do. With this, and part of his own, he paid the 27 l. and had his liberty. About ten minutes after, his wife sent for him to a neighbour's house, and asked him for some money; he gave her three guineas and a handful of halfpence, about two shillings, which the said was sufficient.</p>
            <p>Before he could return to his house again, Mr. T - n, his brewer, was there, with his clerk, Mr. A - ms, and his two coopers, who told him the appraisement was ended, and bid him come and take his money; Mr. Y - g, the appraiser for his successor, was telling down the money, about 103 l. in notes and cash: a proper receipt was drawn for it, and given to be read and signed by M'Carty. This done, the brewer's clerk snatched up the notes, cash, receipt, and put all in his pocket. To this, Y - g the appraiser, objected, and said, you have nothing to do with the receipt, that is for Mr. Cummins, who paid for the goods. M'Carty stood still, affrighted for Mr. B - n, who must be broke if he did not repay him the forty-five guineas borrowed of him: at the same time Mr. T - n's officers were waiting in the tap-room to arrest him for the remainder of his debt, over the sum now expected. M'Carty stood and paused, thought it was better one should be bankrupt than two; that he should prevent this by paying his debt of honour for cash advanced him first, and that his other creditors should have their dividend as well as his brewer, who, he thought, had gained more by him than any of the rest. His brandy-merchant and his distiller, who had been kind to him, and got little by him, were to be considered. The house was his brewer's; he had paid him 3000 l. in the time he had lived there. His brother was present, weeping; his wife gone out, and liquor, as she too often, used to be. M'Carty resolutely stood up and told them they had robbed him, and he would prosecute them all if they did not restore the receipt or money. They stared at one-another. He dispossessed Mrs. Cummins of the bar, and goods, which she had entered into before payment. They gave him fair words, asking, if they should return the cash, whether he would repay it to them. Here he owns he told a lye in promising that he would. They then laid down all but 10 l. which they stopped, left any taxes should be due on the house; for which not above three or four pounds were due. He took up 93 l. and put it in his waistcoat pocket; then sitting at the room door, he locked it, and swore bitterly that no officer should come in to arrest him; but had first given possession to his successor. He then said openly it was better to go to gaol with money than without; but called for a sheet of paper to settle accounts with his brewer; to which they readily complied. Mean time he begged the officers might not arrest him while he went about the house to do his business: this was agreed to. One who had a writ against him was not in the way; but his followers were watching him. His brother discovered that the cooper was dispatched for the officer to arrest him, contrary to promise; of which he apprised him; and then pushing out of the door, said, you will be arrested as soon as you have paid that money; get you gone: he tuck'd up his skirt, and went directly to his neighbour Br - n's, paid, and settled with him for</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA176010250013"/>
            <p>the forty-five guineas borrow'd; paid his brother twenty guineas more for his service of above three years, during which, he acted for him as his clerk, and did any other business he put him to. Now, said he, if I must go to gaol Br - n is safe, and will give me a meal while he is at liberty. He was not now master of above thirty pounds. He left his wife at her sister's in Drury-lane; the expences of whose funeral came upon him in a week after; when her friends, who had lived upon him, raised this report of his being the occasion of her death; which, he declares, was rather occasioned, as he believed, by her excessive drinking. He still kept out of the way; but in a week or two wrote to his creditors, an offer of four shillings in the pound in a month's time, if they would sign his letter of licence: all were willing except the brewer, who said he would not give him a day. He owed in all about 600 l. and had debts to the amount of 100 l. due to him; but his debtors hearing that his creditors would not compound, nor give him liberty to sue for and recover his debts, refused to pay; saying, let him come for it.</p>
            <p>Being particularly asked, he declared he never saw any evil practices going forward in his house from the time he enter'd into it, and first banished the bad company which had frequented it. - Also that he never made an ill use of his office of <rs id="OA17601025-occupation-9" type="occupation">headborough</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17601025n44-1 n44-3 OA17601025-occupation-9"/>, but applied himself only to prevent riots, and disperse bad company in his neighbourhood; and the like character in that respect, is attested by gentlemen of credit in that neighbourhood. Thus having spent an hour or two with him the night before his execution, he bless'd and thank'd me for the consolation and assistance given him; but insinuated at the same time, his spiritual guide had said as much as that there was no occasion for my visits or assistance.</p>
            <p>When visited next morning, the priest of his own persuasion had been with him, and performed the duties and requisites of his office for him. This he told me. And also that he had particular directions from him, what prayers to use, and seem'd determined to adhere to those directions only; hinting withal, that he neither desired nor expected any other from me: however, I reminded him of an advice which I had often repeated to him, viz. to offer up all his prayers to God, only thro' the all-sufficient merits of our only mediator and advocate Jesus Christ. To this he seemed to assent. I offered up a short mental prayer for him, and told him I should continue to do so while he lived and it could avail him. He was decently dressed, and ready to go into the court when we parted. He was carried out about half an hour after eight in the morning, being handcuffed with iron, and his arms pinion'd with a rope: he seemed resigned and calm, and lifting up his face to prayer. He continued reading and praying both going to the place of execution and at it; for which purpose he made use of two books alternately; and was assisted in changing and turning to the prayers he was directed to by the executioner, as his own hands were bound. He is said to have continued in prayer a considerable time at the place or execution, and appeared penitent and resigned.</p>
            <p>This is all the Account given by me.</p>
            <p>
               <persName id="OA17601025n74-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17601025n74-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17601025n74-1" type="surname" value="ROE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17601025n74-1" type="given" value="STEPHEN"/>STEPHEN ROE</persName>,</p>
            <p>
               <rs id="OA17601025-occupation-10" type="occupation">Ordinary</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17601025n74-1 OA17601025-occupation-10"/> of <placeName id="OA17601025-geo-11">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17601025n74-1 OA17601025-geo-11"/>Newgate</placeName>.</p>
         </div0>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>