<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<TEI.2>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div0 type="ordinarysAccount" id="OA17240904">
            <interp inst="OA17240904" type="uri" value="ordinarysAccounts/OA17240904"/>
            <interp inst="OA17240904" type="date" value="17240904"/>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA172409040001"/>
            <p>THE ORDINARY of NEWGATE his ACCOUNT, Of the Behaviour, Confession, and last dying Words of the Two Malefactors, Executed at Tyburn on Friday the 4th, of this Instant September, 1724.</p>
            <p>AT the King's Commission of the Peace, and Oyer and Terminer, &amp;c. held at Justice-Hall in the <placeName id="OA17240904-geo-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17240904-geo-1" type="type" value="site"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17240904n3-1 n3-2 OA17240904-geo-1"/>Old-Baily</placeName>, before the <persName id="OA17240904n3-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17240904n3-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17240904n3-1" type="surname" value="DELME"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17240904n3-1" type="given" value="PETER"/>Right Honourable Sir Peter Delme</persName>, <rs id="OA17240904-occupation-1" type="occupation">Knt</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17240904n3-1 OA17240904-occupation-1"/>. <rs id="OA17240904-occupation-2" type="occupation">Lord Mayor</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17240904n3-1 OA17240904-occupation-2"/> of the <rs id="OA17240904-occupation-3" type="occupation">City of London</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17240904n3-1 OA17240904-occupation-3"/>, <persName id="OA17240904n3-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17240904n3-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17240904n3-2" type="surname" value="THOMPSON"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17240904n3-2" type="given" value="WILLIAM"/>Sir William Thompson</persName>, <rs id="OA17240904-occupation-4" type="occupation">Knt</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17240904n3-2 OA17240904-occupation-4"/>. Mr. Sergeant Raby, and several of His MAJESTY'S Justices of the Peace, for the City of London, and County of Middlesex; on Wednesday, Thursday, and Friday, being the 12th, 13th, and 14th, of August, Five Men and one Woman were convicted of Capital Offences, and accordingly receiv'd Sentence of Death, three of which were respited (as we are inform'd) in order for Transportation; the other two for Death, were for a Week or ten Days so visited with Sickness, that they could not give their constant Attendance on the publick Service in the Chapel; but behav'd in their respective Apartment, as Men preparing for their great Change, being admonish'd thereto by all the Motives perswasive to so indispensible, and needful a Work.</p>
            <p>The Sermon preach'd on Sunday last to those under Condemntaion was bottom'd upon the 5th Verse of the 6th Chapter of St. Paul's Epistle to the Galations, For every Man shall bear his own Burden. From which Words, we took occasion to show the Effect of Sin in this Life, and the Misery of the Sinner. We show'd that the genuine Consequent of an uninterrupted Sinful course of Life is a Burden; and that this Burden will certainly lye hea</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA172409040002"/>
            <p>vy on the Shoulders of the Thoughtless inconsidering Sinner; that he, and he alone who commits the Crime, should undergoe the Punishment due unto it. For (were it not so) we show'd that Justice must lye dormant; and suffer the Children to smart for their Father's Sins; the Innocent for the Guilty; but we gave them to understand that the old Jewish Proverb should no more be made use of in this our Spiritual Israel, viz. That the Children's Teeth should be set on Edge, when their Parents had eaten the sower Grapes; and at the same time we appeal'd to the Experience of the dying part of our Audience, for the Confirmation of this great Truth. We consider'd, Secondly. How the Sinner carries his Burden in this Life; And that was two ways, in his Body, and his Mind. As to the former; We produc'd the Drunkard to give an Account of that load of pain he carries for his Night's Debauch an Excess. The Wanton and Incontinent we call'd in to give us the Reason of the Nakedness of his once richly array'd Body; of the visible Decay of his Quondam robust and flourishing Constitution, and (in a Word) of the emptiness of his Purse: To which they Answer, Our Sins have been the fruitful Parents of this deplorable and shameful Off-spring. And to prove what a Burden the conscious Sinner carries in his Mind; we had recourse to Cain with his Brother's Blood upon him; to David watering his Couch with his Tears; to Peter weeping bitterly, &amp;c, and at the last to the convicted Consciences of our Hearers. Thirdly, We directed and mov'd the Audience to quit the Business (the shameful fatal Business) of being Porters for Hell; to thro' the load of their Sins, (especially those of a crimson die) at the Feet of Christ; by a deep Sorrow, and impartial Confession, and an unalterable Resolution of utterly forsaking of them; and that by so doing, they would make their Passage sweet and easy, through the Gate of Death; and have no intollerable Burden to sweat under, during an everlasting Life. And then, Lastly, we concluded with an Application of the whole, to those who were the more immediate Objects of our Pity and Concern.</p>
            <p>The ACCOUNT of the Lives of these MALEFACTORS.</p>
            <p>1. <persName id="OA17240904n7-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17240904n7-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17240904n7-1" type="surname" value="WARD"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17240904n7-1" type="given" value="JOSEPH"/>JOSEPH WARD</persName>, late of the Parish of <placeName id="OA17240904-geo-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17240904-geo-2" type="type" value="parish"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA17240904n7-1 OA17240904-geo-2"/>Pancrass</placeName>, convicted of two Capital Offences, viz. Assaulting <persName id="OA17240904n7-3">
                  <interp inst="OA17240904n7-3" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17240904n7-3" type="surname" value="Vickery"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17240904n7-3" type="given" value="Jane"/>Jane Vickery</persName>, and taking from her a Gold Ring, value 20 s. and <persName id="OA17240904n7-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17240904n7-2" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17240904n7-2" type="surname" value="BARKER"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17240904n7-2" type="given" value="ELIZABETH"/>Elizabeth Barker</persName> taking from her a Gold Ring, Set with Garnet, and accordingly receiv'd Sentence of Death. Said, he knew not the Place of his Nativity; giving to understand, that his Parents were (at the Time of his Birth) People travelling a-round the Country, dealing in Pewter</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA172409040003"/>
            <p>and other petty Commodities. He was furnish'd with a small competency of Learning, so as to Read tolerably well; and during the time he lay under Sentence (except when the failure of his Limbs, and Sickness detain'd him upon his Bed) he employ'd that Talent to the purpose design'd, in preparing himself, and his fellow Sufferers for their approaching Change. He said, he was bred up to no settled Trade or Employ; and that (his Parents dying when he about the Age of 14) he was laid under a necessity of Shifting for himself, and so came up to <placeName id="OA17240904-geo-3">
                  <interp inst="OA17240904-geo-3" type="type" value="urban_centre"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA17240904n7-1 OA17240904-geo-3"/>London</placeName>, and engag'd himself in <rs id="OA17240904-occupation-5" type="occupation">Seafaring business</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17240904n7-1 OA17240904-occupation-5"/>, and pursued it till May last; in which Month. He commenc'd that way of Life, which had now brought him to his shameful End: He own'd he had committed several Facts of the like nature with that for which he dy'd, and much about the same Spot of Ground: Robbing both Men and Women, of what Money, or valuable Things they had; but deny'd that he ever had any Accomplice or Assistant: He pray'd that the injur'd would forgive him, as well as his offended God; he was aged 27 Years, and said, that 17 of those were spent in a wicked vain way of Life: He was in all Appearance a Man conscious to himself of his Folly, and attoning for it by Self-punishment, and Condemnation. He own'd himself a Member of the Establish'd Church of Great Britain, and therein receiv'd the Holy Sacrament with <persName id="OA17240904n8-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17240904n8-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17240904n8-1" type="surname" value="UPTON"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17240904n8-1" type="given" value="ANTHONY"/>Anthony Upton</persName>, who suffered with him.</p>
            <p>2. <persName id="OA17240904n9-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17240904n9-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17240904n9-1" type="surname" value="UPTON"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17240904n9-1" type="given" value="ANTHONY"/>ANTHONY UPTON</persName>, convicted of Burglary, and stealing of Iron, and Sentenc'd accordingly; He was 27 Years of Age, and a married Man: He was born in a Village call'd <placeName id="OA17240904-geo-4">
                  <interp inst="OA17240904-geo-4" type="type" value="county"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA17240904n9-1 OA17240904-geo-4"/>
                  <placeName id="OA17240904-geo-5">
                     <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA17240904n9-1 OA17240904-geo-5"/>Yardley</placeName>, in the County of Northampton</placeName>; that his Father was a Tallow Chandler by Trade, but failing in the World was reduc'd from a Master to a Journeyman, in which Station he lives (when at Home) at Buckingham. He and his Wife now in <placeName id="OA17240904-geo-6">
                  <interp inst="OA17240904-geo-6" type="type" value="urban_centre"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA17240904n9-1 OA17240904-geo-6"/>London</placeName>, in order to make Provision for the Interment of their Son: Who at the Age of 17 took upon him a Military Life, entering into Brigadier Pocock's Regiment of Foot, in which he continu'd till the Regiment was Broke; after which (not being tired with that manner of Life) he Re-entered into the Service, and into Colonel Follett's Company of his Majesty's <rs id="OA17240904-occupation-6" type="occupation">2d Regiment of Foot Guards</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17240904n9-1 OA17240904-occupation-6"/>; who (he said) did Signalize himself to procure him a Respite from Death, to no purpose. He had a Wife and two Children, and his Wife near her Time with the Third. He imputed the Commission of this Fact to excess of Drink; being before that never inclin'd to Thieve or Pilfer; he hop'd that his Family and Parents would not be Reproach'd for the Errors he had committed. He said, (as did also <persName id="OA17240904n9-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17240904n9-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17240904n9-2" type="surname" value="WARD"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17240904n9-2" type="given" value="JOSEPH"/>Joseph Ward</persName>) that he gave up his Breath very chearfully, but that he was under Concern how, and which way his Wife and Children would shift in the World after his Decease; moreover, he said, that if it now was possible for him to recommence his Life and live an Hundred Years; he could not be better prepared to meet Death than now he was. His aged Mother came the Day before Execution to visit and take her final leave of him in the Chapel.</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA172409040004"/>
            <p>
               <persName id="OA17240904n10-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17240904n10-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17240904n10-1" type="surname" value="SHEPHERD"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17240904n10-1" type="given" value="JOHN"/>JOHN SHEPHERD</persName>, a notorious Thief and House Breaker, (whose Life should have been inserted in this Paper, had he not made his narrow Escape from Death on Monday last, (about six in the Evening) we think it may not be improper, but of Service to the Publick to remind them that he is got loose from his Chains, by an almost impracticable and unheard of Machine and Invention; and who has often said, that there was neither Lock nor Key ever made, that he should make any difficulty to open; him! (whom, well Guarded and strong Prisons cannot contain, and who is now upon his wicked and bloody Range in the World) we hope the Publick will Contribute their utmost to defend themselves against; especially such upon whom he has vow'd a bloodly Revenge. Had the Intention of his procuring his Liberty after the manner he did, been the Reformation of his Life, it had not been culpable in him; but when we have too true Assurances, even from his own Mouth and Pen, of the Reverse of it; when he has been heard to say, that if ever good Fortune should set his Heels at Liberty, he would so effectually make clean work of his Facts; that there should not remain an Evidence to Swear against him; that he would increase the Number, as well as heighten the Quality of his Crimes: That these, and no less wicked and cruel were the Designs and Intentions of this inhuman barbarous Thief and House-Breaker: When his Country is thus threat'ned by him; we hope it will not be wanting (in its own Preservation) in doing what it can to detect him; that so Mankind may be rid of this Enemy; the Innocent clear'd; and the Offender punish'd.</p>
            <p>And farther yet, to display our ingenious House-Breaker in his lively Colonrs; we shall inform you of a Robbery he committed on the 23d of October 1723, and the Confession he made of it.</p>
            <p>This Shepherd having deserted his Master's (Mr. Wood's) Service, took Shelter in the House of one Mr. Charles in <placeName id="OA17240904-geo-7">
                  <interp inst="OA17240904-geo-7" type="type" value="parish"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA17240904n10-1 OA17240904-geo-7"/>May-Fair</placeName> and there Lodg'd; and the Landlord (having an occasion for some Repairs in his House) engaga'd one Mr. Panton to undertake them; who did so; and this Shepherd (being there Lodg'd) was as a <rs id="OA17240904-occupation-7" type="occupation">Journeyman</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17240904n10-1 OA17240904-occupation-7"/> to the Person aforesaid; but e're the Repair was compleat, he took occasion to rob the People of the Things following, viz. Seven Pound Ten Shillings in Specie, 5 large silver</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA172409040005"/>
            <p>Spoons; 1 Fork ditto; 4 Tea Spoons, one Gilt, 6 plain Gold Rings, and a Stone ditto; 4 Suits of Wearing Apparel; Linnen to a considerable value.</p>
            <p>The Confession he made whilst under Sentence of this Fact, was, that he had committed it, and that his Master to whom he was an Apprentice was the Prime Cause of it; (as he said, the Truth of it, we know not) by obliging him to forsake his Service; and not suffering him to reside in any Place long: He thought it best to go off with a Sum; and as he knew there was Money and Effects of value in the House; and no difficulty to come at them, he attmptted and succeeded by taking the Things aforesaid, and going off clear with them; but he was sorry (as he said) that he had not taken a greater Sum, which he understood since lay in the next Drawer. When it was ask'd him, if he had Sold or Pawn'd any Part, or all of his Booty, he reply'd, they were sold, and nothing to be recover'd; and being ask'd how he could use poor People so; he reply'd, I wish that you and I were as Rich; thereby making it no Crime in him to steal from those in better Circumstances than himself. N. B. By this you may be admonish'd to Guard your selves against such Pests of Mankind.</p>
            <p>The Night before the Execution of these unfortunate Men, they compell'd themselves to Watch and Pray incessantly, abstaining from all Indulgence of Nature, in order to the preparing themselves for the Receiving of the Holy Sacrament. The Sight of Friends, who had promis'd (but not sincerely) wholly to reliquish them the preceding Day, was far from renerding them more compos'd, and more ready to acquiesce in the Loss of Life: But they were persnaded to resign themselves up to the Will of Providence, and patiently to bear it, since God thought fit to separate them from their nearest and dearest Friends, to force them from the Light of the Sun and innocent Enjoyments of Life, in the Prime of their Days.</p>
            <p>Before they receiv'd the Sacrament, <persName id="OA17240904n16-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17240904n16-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17240904n16-1" type="surname" value="UPTON"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17240904n16-1" type="given" value="ANTHONY"/>Anthony Upton</persName> desired to be inform'd, if it would prove any Offence to the Great God, that he had drank that Morning; as for eating, he had abstain'd from it. Afterwards, he seems as it were to throw off his Indisposition; he appeared the more chearful the nearer</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA172409040006"/>
            <p>his Suffering approached. It may be thought, that his severe Sicknesses, his dismal Abode, together with the Upbradings of certain of his Acquaintance, made him weary of the sad Condition he lay in; so that the Thoughts of Freedom and caelestial Liberty must necessarily revive his Mind. But the sad Distress of his aged Mother (when she again appeared) revived again his earthly Thoughts, and Tears, and all the signs of Sorrow evinced how hardly the most afflicted Wretch can part with a wretched Life.</p>
            <p>The Behaviour and Confession of these Malefactors at the Place of Execution.</p>
            <p>THEIR Behaviour, such as it was whilst under Sentence, in the Prison; tho' the one more unconcern'd seemingly than the other with Respect to his Departure out of this Life. They were ask'd if they had any Load to Unburthen themselves of, before their Exit; to which they reply'd, they had nothing to Offer to the World but what they had said in the Prison.</p>
            <p>But being admoinshed, That it was Necessary for them, and useful to their Spectators, to leave their departing Words to the World; they desir'd that I would Admonish the People to avoid their Misfortunes by the View of their Sufferings: And so they quitted the Stage of the World like Penitents.</p>
            <p>N. B. The Ordinary of this Place having been indispos'd, has appointed me his Substitute in his Absence.</p>
            <p>
               <persName id="OA17240904n22-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17240904n22-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17240904n22-1" type="surname" value="WAGSTAFF"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17240904n22-1" type="given" value="JAMES"/>JAMES WAGSTAFF</persName>.</p>
            <p>ADVERTISEMENT.</p>
            <p>AT the first House on the Right Hand in Crane-Court, near Fetter-Lane, in Fleet-street, a Golden Heart and square Lamp at the Door, you may advise with a regular Surgeon, of very great Experience, who has practised many Years in Spain and Africa, as well as in England, and having devoted most of his Time to the study of Physick and Surgery, has obtain'd so perfect and easy a Method of curing the Venereal Distemper, whether fresh contracted, or of long Continuance, as none else can boast of: He is no Pretender to what he does not understand, being regularly bred a Surgeon in London, and afterwards, by travelling into many Foreign Parts, and acquainting himself with the different Methods of Practice in those Countries, has acquired a never failing Remedy: His Preparations are very gentle, and agreeable to any Constitution; violent Medicines being more pernicious then profitable, (which is the real Cause so many miscarry in Cure) Let none be discouraged by the base and ignorant. Treatment they have met with from unskilful Pretenders, for he Promises a Cure in a little Time without Hindrance of Business, Confinement, Suspicion, or Salivation, even in the most desperate Degree of that loathsome Disease, else desires no Money. Several Persons of Figure have been lately cured by him, after they were given over, as incurable, by Physicians and Surgeons of the greatest Eminency, and been, by them, miserably tortured with Salivations, and other painful Operations. He cures Cancers of few Years standing; likewise any rotten Ulcers, the King's-Evil, or Fistulas, without manual Operation: The Itch he cures in four Days, and the Yellow Jaundice, in Old or Young, in twenty four Hours; as also the Leprosy and Rheumatism, with all other curable Distempers. His Hours are all the Morning till Twelve a-Clock, and from Three till Ten at Night. N. B. Crane-Court turns in betwixt the Sign of the Leg, a Hosier's, and the Ship, a Watch-Makers, near Fetter-Lane, Fleet-street.</p>
            <p>
               <rs id="OA17240904-occupation-8" type="occupation">LONDON</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17240904n25-1 OA17240904-occupation-8"/>: Printed by <persName id="OA17240904n25-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17240904n25-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17240904n25-1" type="surname" value="APPLEBEE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17240904n25-1" type="given" value="JOHN"/>JOHN APPLEBEE</persName>, a little below <placeName id="OA17240904-geo-8">
                  <interp inst="OA17240904-geo-8" type="type" value="parish"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA17240904n25-1 OA17240904-geo-8"/>
                  <placeName id="OA17240904-geo-9">
                     <interp inst="OA17240904-geo-9" type="type" value="site"/>
                     <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA17240904n25-1 OA17240904-geo-9"/>Bridewell-Bridege</placeName> in Black-Fryers</placeName>.</p>
         </div0>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>