<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<TEI.2>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div0 type="ordinarysAccount" id="OA17580701">
            <interp inst="OA17580701" type="uri" value="ordinarysAccounts/OA17580701"/>
            <interp inst="OA17580701" type="date" value="17580701"/>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA175807010001"/>
            <p>A REMARKABLE NARRATIVE OF THE Uncommon Behaviour, Life, and Character, <persName id="OA17580701n1-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17580701n1-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17580701n1-1" type="surname" value="ROMERT"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17580701n1-1" type="given" value="JACOB"/>OF JACOB ROMERT</persName>, WHO WAS</p>
            <p>Tried, Convicted, and received Sentence of Death, at the <placeName id="OA17580701-geo-1">Old Bailey</placeName>, 29June last, and was executed at <placeName id="OA17580701-geo-2">Tyburn</placeName> the 1July, Inst.</p>
            <p>For the MURDER of</p>
            <p>
               <persName id="OA17580701n4-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17580701n4-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17580701n4-1" type="surname" value="WENTWORTH"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17580701n4-1" type="given" value="THOMAS THEODORE"/>THOMAS THEODORE WENTWORTH</persName>: Being the Fourth EXECUTION in the MAYORALTY of <persName id="OA17580701n4-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17580701n4-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17580701n4-2" type="surname" value="ASGILL"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17580701n4-2" type="given" value="CHARLES"/>THE RIGHT HONOURABLE Sir CHARLES ASGILL</persName>, Knt. LORD-MAYOR of the City of LONDON.</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA175807010002"/>
            <p>INTRODUCTION.</p>
            <p>If thine Eye be Evil, thy whole Body shall be full of Darkness.If therefore the Light that is in thee, be Darkness; how great is that Darkness!</p>
            <p>AS in mathematical or physical reasoning, a proposition proved ex absurdo, or from involving you in absurdity, if you deny it, is allowed to be strictly demonstrated;So the same kind of argument holds good in trying moral or religious tenets: if by denying, them you are run into a contradiction or dangerous practice, they must be true.If by holding any set of tenets and acting thereon, you are drawn into contradictions and consequent practices, dangerous and destructive to mankind and yourself; they must be false.</p>
            <p>The case of the unhappy criminal now in view, may be tried by this test.</p>
            <p>The horrid Fact he was drown into, is as good as a demonstration of the falseness of the principle he was acted by, though he could not be persuaded to confess the falshood of the one, or the guilt of the other.</p>
            <p>In a nation where enthusiasm and obstinacy in false and dangerous opinions, has made such havock heretofore, and may cause as much more in the present or future times; an example like this should not be lost to the publick; should be set before them in its natural and strongest colours: and by engaging their attention on its deformity and danger, excite every sect; every individual among us to an examination, whether what he mistakes to be a light within him, be not a mere darkness, hiding from his all the genuine beauties of undoubted truth and unblemished virtue.</p>
            <p>The doctrine of immediate impulses, fancied to be derived from heaven, is now much advanced, cherished, propagated. and made a principle of action.If they are examined by this test of their absurd consequences and dangerous tendencies; they will prove themselves to be from the opposite quarter, from the spirit of darkness, disorder and misrule.</p>
            <p>What confusion, disorders, and miseries were actually brought on this nation, a little more than a century ago, by enthusiastic preachers and their followers; by enthusiasm let loose in all its frantic forms, and operating by a rebellious brood,If we were inclined to forget, or the monument of history were silent, and would suffer us to forget; the present scene of things; tending to act the same fatal tragedy over again, must strongly revive in our minds, and engage us to think seriously on the preceding signs, attending symptoms, and the mortal convulsions which ensued, and destroyed the most excellent constitution in the world.</p>
            <p>Principiis obsta,Sero medicina paratur, Cum mala per longas invaluere moras.</p>
            <p>When an unprovoked murder is pretended to be sanctified by an impulse from heaven, when it is obstinately denied to be a crime; and profession made that he should lie in the face of heaven, if he should say, that he was sorry for it: it is high time to try such spirits, and their impulses; because many false and deceiving spirits are gone out among us, from whose illusions and evil works, may the divine providence protect this nation, its Sacred Head, and all its parts, the simple, ignorant, and the unguarded; and reclaim and bring into the way of truth, all such as have erred and are deceived.</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA175807010003"/>
            <p>We are apt to despise the first errors of a sect, and look upon them as a set of harmless, speculative opinions; when if we could view them in their consequences, we should see them teem with monstrous productions, and lead to a field of blood and horrid confusion.</p>
            <p>Of all the fiery durts of the wicked, none are more dangerous, made whose wounds are more incurable than those headed with the word of God, wrested and perverted: with such fiery darts he area to assail Him that was more than man; whose safe example hath tought us how to vanquish and clude such assault; by weapons drawn from the same spiritual magazine, rightly understood, and fair by applied: for which purpose the honest and well meaning, the pious and obedient, are assured of never fairling assistance, on this most reasonable and indispensable condition, If any man will do the will of God, he shall know of the doctrine whether it be of God: it if men will extinguisand counteract the light that is in them, the original light of nature and right reason, which is the gift of God, ever consonant and in harmony with his revealed will that low of love and kindness, which is the sum of the law and the prophets, absolutely commanding us to do to others, as we would be done by; and not to do to others, what they would not have done to us;If they will swerve from this, and them seek for authorities and countenance for suchpractice, in the holy scripture, they are justly given up to those deluding spirits whom they have obeyed, and given themselves up to; deceiving and being deceived, till the light they fancy to be in them, is over-cast with total impenetrable darkness.</p>
            <p>When men presume themselves wiser than their teachers for the contrary reason to that of the psalmist not because they keep the commandments of God, but because they violate them; they themselves may be convinced, and all the world be assured they are under a most pernicious delusion, and that all the light they fancy to be in them, is palpable darkness.</p>
            <p>The enthusiasm of methodists and papists, have been compared by authentic documents drawn from their own writing, with learning, judgment, experience and sagacity, sufficient to warn the world against we dangerous infection of both their principles and practices.</p>
            <p>The following account presents a farther argument drawn from fact to the same purpose; and may heaven prosper these, and all good means to promote the precious blessing, of truth, peace, and rightethat every person may learn to abide in their calling, with sobriety and patience; be content with their condition, and, if under the present pressures of this life, wait with the up right and pious job, all the days of their appointed time, till their change come, that by patient continuance to well doing, they may see the felicity of his chosen, and rejoice with the gladness of his people, and give thanks with his inheritance.</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA175807010004"/>
            <p>A REMARKABLE NARRATIVE OF THE Uncommon BEHAVIOUR, LIFE, and CHARACTER, <persName id="OA17580701n20-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17580701n20-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17580701n20-1" type="surname" value="ROMERT"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17580701n20-1" type="given" value="JACOB"/>OF JACOB ROMERT</persName>.</p>
            <p>BY virtue of the king's commission of the peace, and Oyer and Terminer for the city of London, and at the general sessions of goal delivery of <placeName id="OA17580701-geo-3">Newgate</placeName>, holden for the <placeName id="OA17580701-geo-4">city of London</placeName>, and county of <placeName id="OA17580701-geo-5">Middlesex</placeName>, at <placeName id="OA17580701-geo-6">Justice-hall</placeName> in the <placeName id="OA17580701-geo-7">Old Bailey</placeName>, before the <rs id="OA17580701-occupation-1" type="occupation">right honourable</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17580701n21-1 OA17580701-occupation-1"/> 
               <rs id="OA17580701-occupation-2" type="occupation">sir</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17580701n21-1 OA17580701-occupation-2"/> 
               <persName id="OA17580701n21-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17580701n21-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17580701n21-1" type="surname" value="ASGILL"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17580701n21-1" type="given" value="CHARLES"/>Charles Asgill</persName>, <rs id="OA17580701-occupation-3" type="occupation">lord mayor;</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17580701n21-1 OA17580701-occupation-3"/> the <rs id="OA17580701-occupation-4" type="occupation">honourable</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17580701n21-1 OA17580701-occupation-4"/> 
               <rs id="OA17580701-occupation-5" type="occupation">sir</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17580701n21-2 OA17580701-occupation-5"/> 
               <persName id="OA17580701n21-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17580701n21-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17580701n21-2" type="surname" value="PARKER"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17580701n21-2" type="given" value="THOMAS"/>Thomas Parker</persName>, <rs id="OA17580701-occupation-6" type="occupation">knight</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17580701n21-2 OA17580701-occupation-6"/>, <rs id="OA17580701-occupation-7" type="occupation">lord chief baron of the exchequer</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17580701n21-1 OA17580701-occupation-7"/>; the honourable Mr. justice Wilmot; <rs id="OA17580701-occupation-8" type="occupation">sir</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17580701n21-3 OA17580701-occupation-8"/> 
               <persName id="OA17580701n21-3">
                  <interp inst="OA17580701n21-3" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17580701n21-3" type="surname" value="MORETON"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17580701n21-3" type="given" value="WILLIAM"/>William Moreton</persName>, <rs id="OA17580701-occupation-9" type="occupation">knight</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17580701n21-3 OA17580701-occupation-9"/>, <rs id="OA17580701-occupation-10" type="occupation">recorder</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17580701n21-4 OA17580701-occupation-10"/>, and others his majesty's justices of Oyer and Terminer for the said city and county, on Wednesday the 28th, and Thursday the 29th of June, in the 32d year of his majesty's reign, <persName id="OA17580701n21-4">
                  <interp inst="OA17580701n21-4" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17580701n21-4" type="surname" value="ROMERT"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17580701n21-4" type="given" value="JACOB"/>Jacob Romert</persName> was capitally convicted for the wilful murder of <persName id="OA17580701n21-5">
                  <interp inst="OA17580701n21-5" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17580701n21-5" type="surname" value="WENTWORTH"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17580701n21-5" type="given" value="THOMAS THEODORE"/>Thomas Theodore Wentworth</persName>, by stabbing him on the left breast between the second and third, rib, with malice aforethought, giving him one mortal would three inches deep with a penknife, on Tuesday the 25th day of April last, whereof he languished unto the 11th day of May, and then died.</p>
            <p>
               <persName id="OA17580701n22-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17580701n22-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17580701n22-1" type="age" value="29"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17580701n22-1" type="surname" value="ROMERT"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17580701n22-1" type="given" value="JACOB"/>Jacob Romert</persName> a native of <placeName id="OA17580701-geo-8">Christiana</placeName> in <placeName id="OA17580701-geo-9">Norway</placeName>, about 29 years of age, was bred a <rs id="OA17580701-occupation-11" type="occupation">jeweller</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17580701n22-1 OA17580701-occupation-11"/> there, and has been to work at his trade in <placeName id="OA17580701-geo-10">London</placeName> about eight years, speaks English intelligibly and currently. He was to have been apprentice to his father, who was a jeweller in Christiana, but he dying, was bound to another of the same trade, with whom he served his time honestly and faithfully, and with a very good character; in testimony of which there remains in the hands of his wife, his indentures, and a certificate of his good behaviour during his apprenticeship, recommending him as an able and honest workman: from <placeName id="OA17580701-geo-11">Norway</placeName> he went to <placeName id="OA17580701-geo-12">Sweden</placeName> where he wrought at his trade about half a year, with good reputation, and then came to <placeName id="OA17580701-geo-13">London</placeName>.</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA175807010005"/>
            <p>Before his departure from <placeName id="OA17580701-geo-14">Christiana</placeName>, taking leave of all his friends, he observed they made him no presents, as it is the custom of that country to do to friends going aborad; this perhaps was owing to their unwillingness to part with him, and his going without their consent; but he took it much to heart, saying he had been unhappy and ill treated from his infancy; so that when his mother offered him her present, which was only a book, he refused it, and went away; his mother seeing him go, called after him, "my dear Jacob let me take " my last leave of you;" but he refused to return. This I have heard he has of late been sensible of, and expressed great concern for it; and since his marriage he has written to her, asked pardon, and received a kind answer from her, with the book which she had first offered him, and a promise of farther favours when opportunity served. He is said to have four brothers in good credit; two of them chasers in gold and silver, and other metals; a third a master of a ship; and the fourth a minister in his own country.</p>
            <p>In London he has wrought with several master jewellers, and is said to be well approved for his diligent, sober, quiet behaviour, and for his skill and punctuality in his work: he wrought with Mr. Lavecourt two years, with Mr. Smeedle in <placeName id="OA17580701-geo-15">Great Suffolk street</placeName> four years, and about one year with Mr. Mazenough his last master, whose foreman Mr. D'Ingremont was a principal evidence against him. But his failing was that on any sudden dissrke or unaccountable fancy of his own, he would quit a master, and so disobliging him lose his favour, and a refuge for employment in time of need.</p>
            <p>About April was two years, he married a young woman of good character and behaviour, then lately come from the city of <placeName id="OA17580701-geo-16">Yark</placeName>, who was servant to one Mr. Rainbow his relation, who liked her better as a servant than a relation, and therefore resented this marriage, as did his two brothers; this was the beginning of his troubles; and though she was deservedly esteemed and loved by him, and proved a true helpmate to him in all his troubles, as he declared to his last day, yet his friends, refused to be reconciled to them, too much resembling him in an unhappy obstinacy of temper.</p>
            <p>An instance of her faithful care of him, which he himself told me the evening before he suffered, ought to be mentioned to wipe off any aspersions which may unjustly fall on her, as if she was the cause or occasion of his sufferings; viz. that she worked at her needle day and night, making caps at a penny or three halfpence a piece, in order to support him in the prison, and keep him from being turned down into the common side, among the filthy vermin, and more filthy conversation of the incorrigible and desperate part of the felons. She gives him the character of a kind and most loving husband, but that his singularity, and obstinacy in his own way, made her often very unhappy.</p>
            <p>Of this she relates an instance or two which by many will be deemed as incredible, as they are uncommon; but let her, and those whom she appeals to, answer for the truth of them.</p>
            <p>In the spring of the year 1757 he was arrested for board and lodging, and confined in the <placeName id="OA17580701-geo-17">Marshalsea prison</placeName>: and though his friends would have paid the debt and set him free, he refused it, and was there nine months, till at length, unknown to him, she beg'd his discharge of the creditor, who granted it. During his confinement she was delivered of a child, in a very distrest con-</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA175807010006"/>
            <p>dition, and a poor lodging which she had hired near his prison; but here follows the wonder: On the 25May, four days after her delivery, he began to fast, and obstinately refused all manner of sustenance for forty four days, except pumb water only. His fellow prisoners judging it was either for want, or that he was determined to finish his life by fasting, frequently offered to share their victuals with him, which he as often refused with indignation, as he did all his wife's offers and intreaties to the same purpose. Thus he continued till weakened and emaciated to a skeleton, he was freed and forgiven by his creditor; and then by his friends carried to <placeName id="OA17580701-geo-18">Paddington</placeName> for the recovery of his health and strength, where he boarded with one Mr. De Fleau, and after some sickness, recovered his strength and a very great appetite.</p>
            <p>The same kind of fast she asserts he kept during last Lent; yet going to his work every day, and staying there during meal times, and when asked about going to his meals, he pretended that he would eat at home in the evening with his wife, while to her he pretended he had eat breakfast and dinner abroad, and would not sup, that he might rise earlier to his work. Thus she avers he went on till the last day of Lent, when he came home sfaint and sick and was put to bed; she offered to prepare him some gruel and wine, but he would have nothing but a red herring or two, and that, not till the next morning; after which he craved for such relishers till he recovered, and was able to eat twice the quantity of a common allowance, for a considerable time after.</p>
            <p>Something concerning his long fasting was mentioned by the witness D'Ingrement, on his trial, in asnwer to a question of the courtWhat he thought of the state of his mind, whether he were lunatick or of found understanding? to which he replied, that when in Lent last he used extraordinary fasting, he was asked why he did so? to which Remert replied, ask me no questions. So that his wife's account has at least so much foundation, attested on the oath of a witness, not to be suspected of partiality towards either of them: and when she was pressed by me with questions, concerning the credibility, or even the possibility of it, expressed her readiness to confirm what she said, on oath and appealed to Mr. D'Ingremont and others for the truth of it.</p>
            <p>He was committed 11May to <placeName id="OA17580701-geo-19">Newgate</placeName>, by justice Cox, for the murder of one of his fellow-workmen in the same shop with him in <placeName id="OA17580701-geo-20">Craven street</placeName>.</p>
            <p>18May. Being sent for to prayers, he attended, and afterwards being questioned, said, that the fact was not done of a sudden, in a quarrel, or a passion, but in cool blood; that he had no malice against the man, but that he was perpetually teazing him as he sat at work with him, and would not let him rest, nor do his work quietly; that his circumstances in other respects were very uneasy and strait, his wife having resolved to go to service, was disappointed of her place; that he was promised a guinea a week by the master for whom he wrought, but was generally paid short of that sum; that however he knew not where to apply for work to better himself; and being made very uneasy, by the perpetual scoffs and foolish jestings of his shop-mates, he wished himself out of the world; and now that he had done something which he expected would bring that to pass, he said he had been ever since very easy and resigned.</p>
            <p>This account could not sail to strike any mind with horror, which was not under a delusion strong as his own. In order to clear him of which, and open his eyes, the</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA175807010007"/>
            <p>horrors of the sin of murder were represented to him, and the divine judgment denounced thereon, that whose sheddeth man's blood, by man shall his blood be shed; that the circumstances of this fact of his, instead of alleviating, were great aggravations, even by his own account; for as he killed him deliberately and in cool blood, he had not passion nor the heat and tumult of a quarrel to plead; that it must be malice prepense, and a strong delusion of him, who is a liar and a murderer from the beginning, to persuade him to believe he could he easy or happy, with the guilt of bloodshed on his soul; that, what he had insinuated of his being a sorry, worthless fellow, on whom the fact was perpetrated, was another aggravation of his crime, for that thereby he had sent a poor wretched sinner, without warning or time to amend, impenitent, and hardened out of the world.</p>
            <p>To the first charge he replied, he knew and believed there is a most Righteous Judge, who seeth our hearts, before whom he and all of us must appear, and that he was well satisfied to submit to his judgment; and seemed easy, indeed by far too easy and secure, about the event; that as to the second aggravation, the man had some time to repent; for that he was stabbed 25April, and did not die till 11May, during which, he the prisoner, lay in the <placeName id="OA17580701-geo-21">Gatehouse</placeName>, at <placeName id="OA17580701-geo-22">Westminster</placeName>; that during that time he had several messages of reconciliation and forgiveness passed between them; that the poor man proposed even to come to the Gatehouse to him, dying as he was, to shake hands and he reconciled, but that he answered he could have no pleasure in seeing a poor creature in misery.</p>
            <p>Being thus open to confess the fact in all its circumstances, it was hoped by attending prayers and proper discourses applied to him in private, he might gradually be brought to a sight and sense of his great guilt and strong delusion in perpetrating this murder, whether through splenetick malice, or fretful impatience, under the light and temporary afflictions of this life, which well endured, will entitle the patient sufferer to an exceeding weight of glary.</p>
            <p>But no! far from coming to such a temper, he refused the means; he refused to come to chapel, by any calls or invitations, except when moved by his own humour, which was very rarely, if at all, and then in a secret manner, unknown to me, as if on purpose to avoid farther conversation or instruction about his crime; nor did he admit of any, till after his trial, conviction and sentence, when removed to the press-yard, and more in my way. He had said indeed, that being a <rs id="OA17580701-occupation-12" type="occupation">Lutheran</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17580701n22-1 OA17580701-occupation-12"/>, and of the Danish congregation, he would send for their minister; but it has appeared since, that he was not visited by him; tho' to do him justice, it is said, he wrote to that gentleman, signifying, "if he came that way he " should be glad to see him;" in consequence of which, a visit was intended him, but dissuaded by some of Romert's relations.</p>
            <p>When brought to the bar to be arraigned, had heard his indictment read, and was asked, are you guilty, or not guilty? he answered, "guilty to be sure," and would have pleaded guilty, but that he was told by one standing near him, "you are not now "to be tried, what do you mean?"and so was prevailed on to say, "not guilty?" otherwise there could have been no trial, nor could the circumstances of the fact appear, nor the court and jury have had means to judge whether he was a lunatick or not; so as to enable them to give a verdict, and pass judgmentOn the trial his behaviour, temper, and character, appeared to be much the same, with what is describ-</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA175807010008"/>
            <p>ed and represented in this narrative; only whereas the witness D'Ingremont had said he was told, "he had been in prison once "for madness,"this his wife explained to me, to be no other than the <placeName id="OA17580701-geo-23">marshalsea</placeName>, where he was confined for debt, and kept his long fast in the manner before mentioned; she also related, that sometimes when her husband returned from working at his master's, he used to start un suddenly as if in agony, when thinking of Wehtworth, and say, I cannot work there any more I am so abused;his words are so wicked.Which seems as if he and great resentment against the deceased.His friends would have see'd counsel for him at his trial; but he declared "if any of them stood up to speak for him., he would speak against them." Thought it did not appear on the trial, that there was any quarrel between the deceased and the prisoner, yet, it was well known that the person stabbed was very culpable for having made a butt of this unhappy sufferer.It is an unlucky custom in most work-shops, where there is any number of hands, to have two characters to entertain the company and keep up the spirit of conversation, which may be called the butt, and the buffoon: where a heavy, splenetick, and ill tempered person is hit on for the former, it may prove of had consequence to the latter, or both.</p>
            <p>30June. Visited <persName id="OA17580701n41-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17580701n41-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17580701n41-1" type="surname" value="Romert"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17580701n41-1" type="given" value="Jacob"/>Jacob Romert</persName> before morning prayers, and discoursed with him on the heinous nature and aggravations of the sin of murder.As to its nature, That it is the willful and unlawful taking away the life of a man by any means whatsoever: That it is a sin, 1st. against God, who is the sole author and giver of life, and whose authority alone can take it away; and therefore it is an offence against him, and an invasion of his right to dispose of life. That it is also an offence against the King's Majesty, who is hereby deprived of a subject, and who derives his power of life and deash from the King of Kings: it is a manifest injury too, done to society, and to the friends and relations of the deceased.</p>
            <p>Though he could not deny the truth of what was spoken to him on this subject; yet, he declared when asked, that he was not sorry he had done it, and that he never would or could be sorry for it, that if he should say, he was, he should tell a lie in the presence of God.Being asked again if he believed murder to be a sin? he acknowledged it was made so. Quist. By whom? Ans. By God. Then how can you expect to be forgiven if you do not repent? he answered, I did repent of it before I committed it. Every one may see the absurdity of this: I said to him, that is impossible; for then you would not have done it.</p>
            <p>Being pressed again to declare his repentance for this crime, he said, "faith" he never would," and gave me to understand, he was persuaded he had done right, as having acted from an impulse, or commission from God. That the world was wholly in the dark as to him, and his motives of action, and should remain for at present; but it would appear hereafter.</p>
            <p>It was to little purpose to urge to him, that this was a delusion of the devil; that he might see by the effect and consequence of this fact that it was very wrong and wicked: that he had hurried that unhappy person out of the world, prehaps in the midst of his sins; and himself was now going to appear, and answer for this sin at the great and dreadful tribunal, without the least sorrow or concern for it, that he had shortened his own days, in not waiting for the call and time of divine providence.He answered, that was the very thing he had waited for, and complied with.</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA175807010009"/>
            <p>When urged to explain this, he insisted that he was not answerable for this opinion to any man; but was ready to answer it in judgment before the great God: but still insinuated that he had an impulse and immediate authority from heaven for what he did.It was then put to him, suppose every man should pretend so much impulses, and such revelations as you do; and in consequence of these pretensions, commit such actions, what a scene of blood and desolation must prevail over the world?To this he attempted not a direct answer, as indeed he could not; but said, no man could tell or understand what he had undergone, or suffered in the world, even from his infancy; and hinted that being weary of his miseries and sufferings, which he did not chuse now particularly to explain, he had taken this method to get out of this life.</p>
            <p>This reminded me of a practice reported by a gentleman of good credit to prevail among the Norwegians, Danes, and other neighbouring nations;when under difficulties and misfortunes, which make life a burden to them, they commit a murder, (generally by cutting some innocent child's throat) in order to suffer death, which they prefer to suicide, the practice of some other unhappy, misguided people; as judging it less dangerous to their salvation, and more possible to be repented of, than a death self-inflicted; though from the behaviour of the present criminal, his crime appears to be marked out as a presumptuous sin, and denied the grace of repentance.</p>
            <p>To confirm the above account, another creditable person assured me, he knew a man of the same nation imprisoned here for debt, who lying in a hammock, was by an unlucky fellow-prisoner cut down, and being burt by the fall, took this opportunity to let his bruises faster, and mortify, and by that means, with fasting and other neglect of himself, he died; and thus was delivered from his present troubles: alas! too evidently at the hazard of much greater to ensue.But to resume the conversation with the prisoner, he was told that he should patiently endure and improve his afflictions to quite other purposes, after the example of our blessed saviour, and of good and pious men, such as Job, who under the bitterest and sharpest sufferings in mind, body and estate,took up the holy and stedfast resolution to hold fast his integrity, and wait all the days of his appointed time.he answered, he had done so; and then broke off farther discourse.</p>
            <p>He expressed much uneasiness during this whole intercourse, said, it disturbed him, and made him worse; that he had longed for the day of his execution, for a hundred and more days, and that by such discourse his joy was interrupted, and it would be less happy to him; and that if I troubled him, I must answer for it.</p>
            <p>He was then desired to look into his books; (he had a Bible and a Prayer book in his hand) he would there find it was my duty to tell him the truth; to rescue him from the strong delusion he was betrayed into, and bring him to repentance, and salvation on sure grounds: shewing him at the same time, that God pardoneth, and absolveth only them that truly repent, Etc. in answer to this, he pointed out to me, Be ye merciful, Etc. Judge not.To which it was replied, this is mercy, to bring you to repentance and eternal life.This is judging righteous judgment.</p>
            <p>Friday in the afternoon, 30June, I visited him again, but as he sent me word he would not go up to the chapel any more, I</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA175807010010"/>
            <p>went to his cell, and found him with his Bible and Prayer book, and the Prisoner's Director before him.Told him, I was glad to see him so well employed, hoped he understood them, and made a good use of them, by chusing out proper portions for his own case.As he had all along denied his guilt and danger, I thought it hight necessary to set it before him in a strong light, and desired him to turn to some texts which I should point out to him: he complied, and read Revel. chap. xxi. v. 8. " But the fearful and unbelieving, and the " abominable, and murderers, and " whoremongers, and sorcerers, and idolaters, "and all liars, shall have their part in the "lake which burneth with fire and "brimstone; which is the second death."On reading this, he said, it was well enough, but not applicable to his case. Why so? don't you know that murderers among other criminals, have their part in the lake which burneth with fire and brimstone, Etc.Are you not convicted of murder?Did you not confess it?And ought you not confess it?And ought you not to repent and acknowledge you sorrow for it in order to obtain pardon, and escape this terrible sentence?All this he owned was very true, but he could not, or would not say, "that he was sorry for what he "had done," nor would he gave that satisfaction to me or the world; nor give any reason why he did the fact, or for this behaviour and resolution: for he said, it was not my business, nor did it concern the world.In vain was my labour to persuade him that it was my proper business and indispensable duty, to lead and conduct, and to admonish him; to be instant with him to repent, in these his last moments, that he might he pardoned in heaven, and give satisfaction to the world.That for this purpose, his repentance should be as publick as his crime, for his own sake, and a direction and good example to other sinners.All this he denied, saying, that was all between God and his own conscience.But to shew him his error in this respect, I pointed out to him Heb. xiii. 17. " Obey them that have the ride over " you, and submit yourselves: for they "watch for your souls, as they that must "give account, that they may do it with " joy and not with grief: for that is " unprofitable for you."</p>
            <p>He said, all I could say or do, could not save him without God.This was foreign and unnecessary for him to say, as no such matter was ever pretended to.He was then desired to read St. John chap. viii. ver. 44. which he did. " Ye are of your father " the devil, and the lusts of your father ye " will do. He was a murderer from the " beginning, and abode not in the truth, " because there is no truth in him. When " he speaketh a lie, he speaketh of his " own; for he is a liar and the father of " it."He then began to lose his temper, and resent the presenting this text to him, as if the text could hurt him, if he did not feel the application of it to himself by his own conscience.He told me, be understood the scriptures much better than any man could teach him, for he had his instruction from God only, and did not want it by the hand of man.This he often repeated, insisting on it, and that the world in general were all in the dark.</p>
            <p>In the morning he had been asked if he did not desire to prepare to receive the holy communion, as he told me he had before communicated with the church of England.</p>
            <p>This question was now repeated, and he was exhorted to it as a necessary duty, and the truest consolation he could receive.But here the deluded enthusiast strongly broke out and shewed itself; while repeating to him the requisites to come to the Lord's table, he interrupted me and said, while he could communicate inwardly and spiritually, he neither wanted nor desired to</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA175807010011"/>
            <p>perform it outwardly.It was in vain to repeat to him the express command of our saviour to do this: i. e. Eat bread and drink wine blessed and consecrated for this sacred use, in remembrance of him.This he evaded as he did the other texts by telling me, he best knew how to understand and apply them; and that no man could teach him better.</p>
            <p>On the whole he acknowledged this his behaviour was unaccountable, and not to be understood; nor did he think himself at all concerned to explain or account for it to the world.That he had reasons for what he did which satisfied him, and made his conscience easy; and that the time, labour, and words that I had spent on him, were so much lost, and thrown away.He talked confidently of answering for himself at the day of judgment, and that if I met him there, all would be clearly explained relating to him.When I urged him again to tell, whether he believed he had a commission from God for the fact, Etc. for which he died.He said if I tell, you will not believe me.I said, neither ought you to believe any spirit to that purpose; but to try the spirits whether they be of God; for the spirit of God cannot contradict himself, nor command things contrary to his own law.I then put the case; suppose others should imitate that example, and believe they had impulses or divine authority to commit murder; how dreadful must the consequences be to human life, and all society?Think on that, be abashed and repent of your error, and renounce your delusion!His patience would bear no more, he said, I did but interrupt his devotions and waste his time: having prevailed however to pray with him again; we parted in a friendly manner.</p>
            <p>Now let us suppose a man should be persuaded he had an impulse from heaven to command a regiment, or an army, or take upon him to be a civil magistrate; and in order to make way for himself, should stab the person, or blast the reputation of those in office, whom he would supplant or supersede, as some modern enthusiasts have long practiced the latter with impunity towards the officers of the church, what must be the consequences in the army or state? and is it safer or less hurtful in the church?</p>
            <p>On the morning of execution I sent to the criminal <persName id="OA17580701n58-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17580701n58-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17580701n58-1" type="surname" value="ROMERT"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17580701n58-1" type="given" value="JACOB"/>Jacob Romert</persName> to desire to know whether he would admit of a visit from me.He answered, provided I would ask him no questions, he had no objection to praying with me.But while I waited for the reverend Mr.the Danish clergyman to whom I had wrote to desire his assistance in behalf of the prisoner; he was so impatient to die, that the officers complied with his importunity (as the time was at hand) to put him into the cart, (in the mean time the messenger returned with an answer that the Danish minister was out of town,) on which I went immediately to the prisoner. He said to me at the gate, where I met him, you remember what I told you last night, (meaning I presume the conversation before related) I assented, and asked him if he desired any further offices or assistance, he said there is no occasion for it. Observing nothing but a nosegay in his hand,I also asked him, why he did not take a book with him? he answered I have a book within me, that is sufficient for me: knowing his temper I thought it in vain to dispute with him, or advise to any thing.</p>
            <p>He seemed rather to discourage than desire my assisting and praying with him at the tree.However I ventured to go, and there he joined with me in prayer for about half an hour; having repeated and required the same condition as before, that I should ask him no questions.</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA175807010012"/>
            <p>In the course of our devotions, he repeated the Belief once, and the Lord's Prayer a second time, at his own particular request.</p>
            <p>In was in vain for me to attempt to read those proper texts of scripture, which I knew most necessary, and adapted to his state and temper of mind.I had experimental proof from out last night's conversation as well as the former ones, that he would neither hear nor apply them to himself;I contented myself therefore to do for him what he would bear, and seemed capable of receiving, by praying with him servently; and therein intermixing and inculcating those thoughts and duties of contritition and repentance, which it was highly necessary he should perform.In one of those prayers, when I came to these words, "O God how have I hased instruction? "and my heart despised reproof? and have "not obeyed the voice of my teachers." Prov. v. ver. 12, 13, he interrupted me, and desired to hear no more of that prayer, we therefore proceeded to others.</p>
            <p>Having again and again recommended his soul to God; he was asked if he had any thing to say? he said, no; "he was very "weary of this world, and longed to get out "of it." he was reminded to warn the people around him against anger, hatred, malice, or any practice or opinion, any discontent or distrust in God, which might betray them into such a fact as brought him to this sad and untimely end.He said first, "if they "will not take warning by seeing ,me in this "place, and suffering this punishment, they "will much less regard any thing I can say." However, seeming to change his mind and comply; he added, "Good people glorify "God, and be thankful to him for all things; "eschew evil and do good, then you will "fare well;" (meaning you will prosper and be happy.</p>
            <p>In all his prayers, he appeared more heavy and unattentive; less hopeful, lovely and earnest, than any one in those circumstances hitherto observed by me. At last he said, "I trust in, and am sure of God's "mercy because he is good."He took his leave, with acknowledgments of his satisfaction for what I had done for him, we parted, and he was quickly launched out of this world.</p>
            <p>This is all the Account given by me.</p>
            <p>
               <persName id="OA17580701n65-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17580701n65-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17580701n65-1" type="surname" value="ROE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17580701n65-1" type="given" value="STEPHEN"/>STEPHEN ROE</persName>,</p>
            <p>
               <rs id="OA17580701-occupation-13" type="occupation">Ordinary of Newgate</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17580701n65-1 OA17580701-occupation-13"/>.</p>
         </div0>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>