<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<TEI.2>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div0 type="ordinarysAccount" id="OA17421118">
            <interp inst="OA17421118" type="uri" value="ordinarysAccounts/OA17421118"/>
            <interp inst="OA17421118" type="date" value="17421118"/>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA174211180001"/>
            <p>THE Behaviour, Confession, and Dying Words OF <persName id="OA17421118n1-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n1-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n1-1" type="surname" value="HOMAN"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n1-1" type="given" value="THOMAS"/>THOMAS HOMAN</persName>, Who was EXECUTED On THURSDAY the 18th of this Instant NOVEMBER, At the End of <placeName id="OA17421118-geo-1">Fetter-Lane</placeName> in <placeName id="OA17421118-geo-2">HOLBORN</placeName>, For the barbarous MURDER of Mrs. DIX;</p>
            <p>TOGETHER</p>
            <p>With a particular ACCOUNT of the said MURDER, after what Manner he committed it, and likewise a very remarkable Account of his Life, from his Birth to his fatal Exit: To which are some Letters sent to him while under Condemnation by some Methodists.</p>
            <p>Being the First EXECUTION in the MAYORALTY OF THE <rs id="OA17421118-occupation-1" type="occupation">Right Honourable</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17421118n4-1 OA17421118-occupation-1"/> 
               <persName id="OA17421118n4-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n4-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n4-1" type="surname" value="Heathcote"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n4-1" type="given" value="George"/>George Heathcote</persName>, <rs id="OA17421118-occupation-2" type="occupation">Esq</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17421118n4-1 OA17421118-occupation-2"/>; <rs id="OA17421118-occupation-3" type="occupation">LORD-MAYOR</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17421118n4-1 OA17421118-occupation-3"/> of the City of LONDON. LONDON Printed and Sold by J. APPLLEBEE, in Bolt-Court, Fleet-Street. (Price Six-Pence.)</p>
            <p>N.P. If any Account should be published by any other Person, it will be spurious and an Imposition on the Publick.</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA174211180002"/>
            <p>THE ORDINARY of NEWGATE, His ACCOUNT of the Behaviour, Confession, Etc.</p>
            <p>AS for Exhortations and Instructions, he had the same with the other Prisoners who were under Sentence with him, excepting with Reference to Murder, in common with him and <persName id="OA17421118n7-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n7-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n7-1" type="surname" value="BIRD"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n7-1" type="given" value="WILLIAM"/>William Bird</persName>, capitally convicted of the same Crime; but who, upon some special Reasons or Circumstances, was most graciously reprieved by his Majesty, and transported for Life. I was Informed by a Reverend Clergyman, who, after he had prayed and exhorted them in Chapel, was desired by Homan to speak with him, and he told him, that he was assaulted with black and furious Temptations, to despair of God's Mercy, and so neglect his Duty; the Gentleman spoke comfortably to him, and put him upon a better way of thinking; next Day, the 12th Instant, I spoke to him privately, and told him of what I was informed; he said he was much easier, and by the Grace of God, these violent Temptations were in a great Measure dispelled, and he hoped he had got the Victory. I likewise seriously advis'd him to be assiduous and important at the Throne of Grace, to deliver him from the Temptations of Satan, and his own wicked Heart; for however great and numerous his Sins were, yet the Blood of Christ was of infinite Value to attone the Justice of God the Father, not only for him, but the Sins of all Mankind.</p>
            <p>
               <persName id="OA17421118n8-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n8-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n8-1" type="surname" value="HOMAN"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n8-1" type="given" value="THOMAS"/>Thomas Homan</persName>, of <placeName id="OA17421118-geo-3">St. Andrew's, Holborn</placeName>, was indicted for the willful Murder of <persName id="OA17421118n8-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n8-2" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n8-2" type="age" value="74"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n8-2" type="surname" value="DIX"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n8-2" type="given" value="SUSANNAH"/>Susannah Dix</persName>, <rs id="OA17421118-occupation-4" type="occupation">Widow</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17421118n8-2 OA17421118-occupation-4"/>, by striking her with an Iron Bar, of the Value of one Penny, and thereby giving her one Mortal Wound on the Temple, on</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA174211180003"/>
            <p>the last Side of the Head, near the left Eye, of the Length of one Inch, and the Depth of half an Inch, of which Would she instantly died, August 2.</p>
            <p>
               <persName id="OA17421118n10-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n10-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n10-1" type="age" value="22"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n10-1" type="surname" value="HOMAN"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n10-1" type="given" value="THOMAS"/>Thomas Homan</persName>, 22 Years of Age, of honest Parents in <placeName id="OA17421118-geo-4">Hatton-Garden</placeName>, who gave him good Education at School, to read, write, and cast Accompts for Business, and instructed him in the Principles of our Holy Christian Faith, to which if he had been obsequious, probably he might have shunned the bloody Crime he died for.</p>
            <p>When of Age, he was put <rs id="OA17421118-occupation-5" type="occupation">Apprentice to a Baker</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17421118n10-1 OA17421118-occupation-5"/> in <placeName id="OA17421118-geo-5">Fetter-lane</placeName>, next Door where liv'd the unfortunate old Gentlewoman whom he villainously murder'd, and serv'd most of his Time, but not with such honesty and Integrity as was thought, he having tricked and cheated his Master out of a great many small Things; however, this he kept to himself till under Sentence of Death, when having lost all Hopes of Life, he told to me and some others, adding, that it was grievious upon his Conscience to have wronged an honest Man, not in the least suspecting any such treacherous dealing, and he was very desirous of seeing his Master, to beg his Pardon, and warn him to be very careful of unfaithful Servants, who might do him great Prejudice without his knowledge. He privately married his Master's Maid Servant, though at that Time an Apprentice, and has one Child living. He inclined to Sobriety, and was not much guilty of drinking to excess; but being straitned in his Way of Life, as having a Wife and Child, this occasioned bad Thoughts to come into his Mind, not knowing how to supply his Family concealed from the World. An old Widow Gentlewoman 74 Years of Age, lived by herself in a House next Door to his Master's, he imagined she might have Money or valuable Goods, and therefore formed a Resolution to strip the House, and the old Woman of what Money and Effects he could find; he was in a great Doubt and Perplexity how to perpetrate this, thinking to do it in the Night Time, but his Courage oftentimes failed him, and sometimes he over sleeped the Time; but at length the Power of Temptation prevailed upon him, and accordingly on the 2d of. August he fully resolved without Delay to execute the fatal Deed in the Day Time, having the Impudence and Boldness to go to the House to observe which Way he might have Entrance, he found it easy to get from his Master's Yard into hers, and thence into her Cellar; then he look'd about to see how he should contrive to get into the Gentlewoman's Room. and finding the Way after he had first wrench'd the Lock of some Door, he went to the Place, and while this was a doing, the old Woman hearing a Noise suspected it was Thieves, upon which she drew a Chest and a Chair to the Back of the Door, but this proving of little Effect, he came up and pressed the Door open, she took a Poker, and asked him what he wanted, knowing the young Fellow very well?</p>
            <p>He swore, and commanded her to deliver all her Money, she pretended to strike at him with the Poker, but this</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA174211180004"/>
            <p>he did not mind, it being of no Force to hurt him, then he struck at her with a little Iron Bar of a Window, which he found in some Cellar, and brought it along with him for that Purpose in case he should meet with any Opposition, with this Piece of Iron he gave her a Blow on the Temples, upon the left Side of the Head near the Eye, which was struck out, then he redoubted his Blows untill he left her for dead; notwithstanding the old Gentlewoman scream'd out Murder! Murder! Some People of the Neighbourhood over-hearing the Outcry; particularly one <persName id="OA17421118n13-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n13-1" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n13-1" type="surname" value="STAINER"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n13-1" type="given" value="MARY"/>Mary Stainer</persName>, who was at Mr. Raven's, next Door to Mrs. Dix, in <placeName id="OA17421118-geo-6">Petter-Lone</placeName>, she ran into the Yard and scream'd out, insisting that the House was broke open, and observ'd some Blood come against the Window, and likewise saw a Man in a Woolen Cap peep through the Window, but she could not discern who it was; upon which they broke the House open, went up, and found Mrs. Dix lying in a very deplorable Manner, all of a gore Blood; she did not live above two Hours after, being a Widow Gentlewoman of 74 Years of Age, and no Body living in the House with her. Being depriv'd of her Senses, she could give no Account who did it, only when the Surgeon and some others asked her, she said, O Lord! Lord! and at another Time said, Lord! Lord! Two Boys which was in the Street hearing something of this Noise look'd at the House, and had a Mind to have gone in, but being in Suspence they were for going off, but one of them considering with himself said; No, we'll go and see what's the Matter? Upon which he turn'd about, and went up the Ladder, and in at the Window, when he beheld the dismal Sight above related; they sought for the Murderer, and one of the Company found <persName id="OA17421118n13-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n13-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n13-2" type="surname" value="HOMAN"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n13-2" type="given" value="THOMAS"/>Thomas Homan</persName>, who had conceal'd himself under a Hamper in the Cellar, they asked him what induc'd him to murder the Gentlewoman? he said, he had no Intent to murder her, but only intended a Robbery, being in a horrid Confusion, he murder'd her to prevent a Discovery the Gentlewoman knowing him so well, and calling him by his Name Tom.</p>
            <p>He intended to have riffled the House after he had committed the Murder, but being in a dreadful Panic, by Reason of People coming upon him from all Quarters, he fled to hide himself. He was carried before a Justice of the Peace by the Constable , and immediately was committed to Newgate.</p>
            <p>All this and more he confessed to me and many others, with great Grief and Lamentation before he was tried. He likewise confessed the Fact before the Justice, but did not sign it. He turn'd very ill in the Gaol, and it was thought he would have died; a Brother of his, with four or five others, all Methodists, desir'd he might receive the Sacrament, being in eminent Danger of Life. He confessed his Sins, declared his Faith in Christ our only Saviour, his unfeigned Repentance for all the Sins of his Life, particularly that heinous Crime of Murder, upon which they all devoutly receiv'd with him. He recover'd of</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA174211180005"/>
            <p>this Illness, and slipping one Sessions was brought down, indicted and convicted in last October Sessions.</p>
            <p>This horrid Murder, with the Circumstances thereof he confessed to every Body who spoke to him before his Trial, and said he would plead Guilty; however he pleaded no Guilty, but he did not give the Honourable Court the Trouble of a long Trial, the Thing being of plain that no Person appear'd in his Favour. Most Part of the Time he behav'd as a Penitent, but having been long under Sentence, most of them turn'd too remiss, and often laugh'd and bred Disturbances in Chapel, for which they were very sharply reprov'd, especially Homan, whose Crime was more horrid than the rest; he own'd his great Fault, but that he was violently tempted thereto by his wicked, foolish Companions.</p>
            <p>A set of People came pretty often to him, and insisted upon his having the Faith of Assurance; an odd and strange Doctrine to so vile a Criminal, it would have been more proper to advise him Incessantly to cry to God for Mercy on so vile a Sinner, only for Christ's Sake. He confessed himself to have been a very wicked Boy, in defrauding his Master of many small Things, and constantly frequently Skittle-Grounds, playing at Cards and Other Games, likewise keeping the basest of Company, following which vile Courses occasion'd him not only to neglect his Master's Business, but was the Cause of his committing this execrable Murder upon an honest old Gentlewoman, which brought him to a base ignominious Death. He wept much, and declar'd himself sincerely Penitent; he professed Belief in Christ, repented of all his Sins, and died in Peace with all Men.</p>
            <p>At the Place of EXECUTION.</p>
            <p>THE Morning of his Execution he came to Chapel between 7 and 8 o'Clock, and was very devout at Prayers. declaring himself a sincere Penitent, and that he had some Ground of Hope, that God would freely forgive his Sin, upon his unfeigned Faith in Christ, and sincere Repentance for all his Sins, especially the horrid Crime of Murder.</p>
            <p>About half an Hour after Nine, he was carried to the Place of Execution in a Cart, a Gibbet being erected at the End of <placeName id="OA17421118-geo-7">Fetter-Lane</placeName>, in <placeName id="OA17421118-geo-8">Holborn</placeName>, which drew a vast Number of Spectators, and several Scaffolds erected, some, of which fell down, and it was reported to have killed and wounded several Persons. The Gibbet was placed as near to the House where the Gentlewoman was murdered as possible, in order to strike a Terror on the Minds of wicked disposed People. Homan was much concern'd, was serious at Prayers, and sung a suitable Psalm. He writ three Letters to his Master, to come and speak to him about some Confessions he had to make concerning his Injustice to him, and his other great Wickedness, and to beg Pardon of God, and likewise of him. He pray'd heartily to God to bless and prosper his Master, and went off the Stage crying to God, to have Mercy on him, and Lord Jesus receive my Spirit.</p>
            <p>After he had hung the usual Time, he was cut down and carried to one Mr. Power's an Undertaker, over-against <placeName id="OA17421118-geo-9">St. Andrew's Church</placeName>, and was Interred the same Evening in <placeName id="OA17421118-geo-10">St. Andrew's Churchyard</placeName>.</p>
            <p>This is all the Account given by me <persName id="OA17421118n23-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n23-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n23-1" type="surname" value="GUTHRIE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n23-1" type="given" value="JOHN"/>JOHN GUTHRIE</persName>, <rs id="OA17421118-occupation-6" type="occupation">Ordinary</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17421118n23-1 OA17421118-occupation-6"/> of <placeName id="OA17421118-geo-11">Newgate</placeName>.</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA174211180006"/>
            <p>APPENDIX:</p>
            <p>The following ACCOUNT <persName id="OA17421118n25-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n25-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n25-1" type="surname" value="Homan"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n25-1" type="given" value="Thomas"/>Thomas Homan</persName> gave of himself while under Sentence of Death, for the barbarous Murder of Mrs. <persName id="OA17421118n25-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n25-2" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n25-2" type="surname" value="DIX"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n25-2" type="given" value="SUSAN"/>Susan Dix</persName>, a few Days before his Execution.</p>
            <p>THE Crime of Murder is in itself so heinous, that some have doubted, whether human Laws could pardon it; and yet in the Case before us, this Crime is heightened by almost every kind of Aggravation one can think of; whether we regard the Person murder'd a Widow far in Years, and of unblemish'd Character, waken'd out of her Sleep by one Blow at her Chamber-door, and immediately dispatch'd into another World by repeated Blows on her Head; or whether we reflect on him who perpetrated this Fact, not hastily, or from a sudden Start of Passion, but with premeditated and with a theivish Design to possess himself of her Substance. The only Use that can be made of this Account of him, is to exhibit the Steps by which he gradually declined to this amazing Wickedness, that other young Men who are conscious to themselves of having gone part of this Road, may stop short in Time, and avoid coming to such a melancholy End as he made of his Journey.</p>
            <p>
               <persName id="OA17421118n27-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n27-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n27-1" type="surname" value="HOMAN"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n27-1" type="given" value="THOMAS"/>Thomas Homan</persName> was the Son of Mr. <persName id="OA17421118n27-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n27-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n27-2" type="surname" value="HOMAN"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n27-2" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Homan</persName>, a <rs id="OA17421118-occupation-7" type="occupation">Bricklayer</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17421118n27-2 OA17421118-occupation-7"/>, in <placeName id="OA17421118-geo-12">Hatton-Garden</placeName>. He was born in the Month of April, 1722, and it was thought remarkable, that he came into the World with two Teeth in his Head. Before he was two Years old, he lost his Father who died of a Fall from his Horse. About a Year after, his Mother died in a very odd Manner: She had a Servant Maid who robb'd her of several Things to a considerable Value, which put her into such a Passion, that going out to get Intelligence of her, she wish'd she might never return alive, if she did not find both the Wench and the Things. She was so unlucky as to miscarry in the Search, and taking a Hackney Coach to return home, upon opening the Door she was found dead.</p>
            <p>Thus deprived both of Father and Mother, when scarce three Years old, he was taken home by an Uncle of his a Carpenter, who lived at <placeName id="OA17421118-geo-13">St. James's</placeName> End of the Town, with whom he remain'd till he was between six and seven Years old, and then by the Interest of the late Sir <persName id="OA17421118n28-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n28-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n28-1" type="surname" value="Seawen"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n28-1" type="given" value="Thomas"/>Thomas Seawen</persName>, <rs id="OA17421118-occupation-8" type="occupation">Knight</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17421118n28-1 OA17421118-occupation-8"/> and <rs id="OA17421118-occupation-9" type="occupation">Alderman</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17421118n28-1 OA17421118-occupation-9"/>, he was admitted into <placeName id="OA17421118-geo-14">Christ's Hospital</placeName>, where he remain'd near nine Years, and where if he had made a proper Use of it, he had a good Education in ev'ry Respect, and at his coming out</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA174211180007"/>
            <p>of the School, was very well qualified for any kind of Trade.</p>
            <p>In 1736, he was put. <rs id="OA17421118-occupation-10" type="occupation">Apprentice to Mr. Raven a Baker</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17421118n27-1 OA17421118-occupation-10"/> in <placeName id="OA17421118-geo-15">Fetter-Lane</placeName>, where he was very kindly treated, and where he behaved tolerably well, till about two Years and a half ago; when, as he says a Journeyman using him very ill, both by Words and Blows, he began to entertain Thoughts of running away, to which he was encouraged by a Watchmaker's Apprentice in the same Neighbourhood. The Issue of their Consultations, was the usual Resolution of going to Sea, in order to which, they both went down to <placeName id="OA17421118-geo-16">St. Katherine's</placeName> to the Rendezvous, at <placeName id="OA17421118-geo-17">the Black-Boy and Trumpet</placeName>, and afterwards to the City of Bristol, and other Publick houses thereabouts, but were rejected at both Places: upon which they took a resolution of going down to <placeName id="OA17421118-geo-18">Portsmouth</placeName>, not doubting that they should easily find a Ship there. In this they were mistaken, for at that Time, there was none but the Royal George in Commission, where they would not admit two raw Boys, who could give but an indifferent Account of themselves; and thus this idle Expedition ended, in being forced to come back again to <placeName id="OA17421118-geo-19">London</placeName>.</p>
            <p>They had been absent five Days, and yet Mr. Raven, upon Homan's humble Application, and promise of better Behaviour for the future, took him again, and treated him as kind as ever. The unhappy Lad, instead of making good his Promises, sell from one Degree of Wickedness to another; he frequented Skettle Grounds, Shuffle-boards, and other such like Places, where he was doubly unfortunate in losing his Money, and gaining a very bad set of Acquaintance. To supply his Expences, to put himself upon a level with his lew'd Companions, and to answer the ravenous Demands of common Women, he first had recourse to pilfering small sums from his Master, and then fell upon another Expedient worse if possible than that, which was levying a Tax upon his Master's Customers, by false notching their Tallies, and then selling the Loaves, in which he was sometimes detected, and for which the unhappy Gentlewoman he murdered, was so kind as to reprove him, and endeavour to give him a true Notion of his Offence, which in all Probability, first suggest to him a thought of doing her a Mischief.</p>
            <p>About two Years ago he contrived a Scene of Trouble, for becoming famaliar with his Master's Maid, he got her with Child, and then in October. 1741, Married at the <placeName id="OA17421118-geo-20">Fleet</placeName>. Thus to all his former incidental Drains of Money he added a constant Expence. When thus involved, he was perpetually racking his Brains for Supplies, and about 4 Months ago, first harboured the Thoughts of doing that inhuman Act, which brought him to a shameful and violent Death.</p>
            <p>As for this Mrs. Dix, she was a Widow Gentlewoman, upwards of 3</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA174211180008"/>
            <p>Years of Age. She liv'd alone in the House next Door to his Master's, and being a Woman of good Family, unspotted Reputation, religious, and yet a chearful Conversation, she was extremely belov'd in her Neighbourhood, and particularly intimate at Mr. Raven's, where she often saw this Boy, and heard of his idle Tricks, of which she would sometimes talk to him with much earnnestness and sincere Desire of doing him Good. Yet there was something singular and which deserves Notice in the Apprehensions they entertain'd of each other. Mrs. Dix often said to her Acquaintance, that she never beheld this Boy without feeling a Sense of Tremor; and on the other Hand, he for a long Time entertained a fixed Aversion to her, before he form'd any Design against her Life. But what is more Surprizing is. that the Saturday Evening preceeding the Monday Morning on which she was murder'd, she went early to Bed, and dreat the whole Story of her own Murder exact'y as it happen'd, which she related the next Morning at Mr. Raven's where she breakfasted, and the Concern with which she told it affected the Whole Family very much. But it is now Time to come to the barbarous Fact itself.</p>
            <p>The Scheme this wrong headed young Fellow had formed, was to break into the House, kill the old Woman, poffess herself of her Effects, and then retire into the Country with his Wife and Child. Four Months this gloomy Project floated in his Brain before he executed it, and when he did it it was on a sudden, and without any Consideration of the Consequences The very last Execution he went to look upon the Criminals as they went to Death, among whom observing 3 or 4 Murders, he said he thought in his own Mind their Punishment was very just, and could not help wondering how they could be Guilty of so much Cruelty towards their Fellow Creatures. There humane Impressions it seems were very quickly forgot, since he could so soon after, work up himself to commit so Bloody and Act.</p>
            <p>The Sunday preceeding the Murder he went Aborad with his Wife, and some other Relations, and came Home to his Master's about 8 in the Evening, when he went to Bed. About 11 he rose to go to Work, and having finish'd his Business by 4 in the Morning, of Monday the2d August 1742, he then went up Stairs intending to go to Bed again; but a sudden Thought coming into his Head, that this was the properest Time to effect what he had so long contriv'd against Mrs Dix, he immediately without farther Reflection set about the Execution; in order to which he went into the Closet, and provided himself with a dark Lanthorn which stood there, then going down into the Bake-house, he arm'd himself with a Piece of Iron, which he had before laid by as a proper Instrument to break into the House withal. Thus furnish'd, he</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA174211180009"/>
            <p>went into his Master's Yard which join'd to that of Mrs. Dix, and from a Strack of Bavins which stood in the former, he easily got into the latter, and then breaking a Paine of the Cellar Window which was close indeed, but without Shutters, he got in without Difficulty, tho' he was apprehensive that the Noise of the broken Glass might alarm some of the Neighbours, yet hearing no Body stir, that Fear was soon over.</p>
            <p>About 6 o'Clock he had confirm'd himself so strongly in his wicked Purpose, that he fallied out of the Cellar, and with the Piece of Iron in his Hand went up one Pair of Stairs, where he began to break open the Door of the Room in which Mrs. Dix lay. She waking with the Noise, called out, upon which he left. off for some Time, and then fell to wrenching again. Upon this Mrs. Dix rose hastily, and catch'd up either a Poker or a Hammer, with which she went towards the Door. At this Instant <persName id="OA17421118n38-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n38-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n38-1" type="surname" value="Homan"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n38-1" type="given" value="Thomas"/>Thomas Homan</persName> forc'd it open with his left Hand, and with his Right gave her such a Blow, that her Blood flew up against the Window, while she cry'd out Murder! Murder! he repeating the Blows all the Time till he thought he had killed her.</p>
            <p>While this said Scene was transacting, one <persName id="OA17421118n39-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n39-1" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n39-1" type="surname" value="STAINES"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n39-1" type="given" value="SARAH"/>Sarah Staines</persName> who was <rs id="OA17421118-occupation-11" type="occupation">washing Cloaths</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17421118n39-1 OA17421118-occupation-11"/> for his Master Mr. Raven, came into the Yard, heard the Cry of Murder, and on looking up, saw some Blood by against the Windows. By this Time Homan believing Mrs. Dix to be dead, advanc'd towards the Window, to see if her Cries had raised any of the Neighbours, and by this Means his Woollen Cap was discover'd by <persName id="OA17421118n39-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n39-2" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n39-2" type="surname" value="STAINES"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n39-2" type="given" value="SARAH"/>Sarah Staines</persName>, who instantly alarmed all Mr. Raven's Family. Upon this, Notice was given to Mr. Cooch the Constable, who having got one <persName id="OA17421118n39-3">
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n39-3" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n39-3" type="surname" value="JEFFERIES"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n39-3" type="given" value="THOMAS"/>Thomas Jefferies</persName> to assist him, caused a Ladder to be set up against Mrs. Dix's Window, and Jefferies going up, saw her weltering in her Blood. Not being able to get in this Way they sent for a Smith, and broke open the Door, but had scarce enter'd the Parlour when the Blood dropp'd upon them through the Ceiling. Jefferies going up found Mrs. Dix still alive, though senseless, and indeed she continued breathing till about 11 o'Clock,</p>
            <p>As for <persName id="OA17421118n40-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n40-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n40-1" type="surname" value="HOMAN"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n40-1" type="given" value="THOMAS"/>Thomas Homan</persName>, he no sooner heard the People about the House, then he retir'd into the Cellar, and hid himself there under a Hamper, where he was quickly found by the Constable and his Assistants, to whom at first he denied, but soon after confessed the Murder, though with some Circumstances which appear'd afterwards not to be true. He was next carried before the sitting Alderman at Confession of the whole Affair, and all its Particulars, upon which the Alderman committed him to Newgate. He lay there one Sessions before he came to a Tryal, by Reason of extreme Sickness, but being tryed at the next, was convicted upon very full Evidence.</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA174211180010"/>
            <p>He was though in the 21st Year of his Age of a slow Understanding, sometimes stupid, and at others more sensible than could have been expected. In these Intervals he expressed very great Sorrow for the flagitious Crime of which he had been guilty: said that Mrs. Dix was a very pious Woman, and went every Day to St. Dunstan's Prayers, but that he hoped God would have Mercy upon him, tho' he had killed so good a Christian. He constantly affirm'd that no Creature but himself knew any Thing of his horrid Purpose, and therefore hoped that the World would not reflect upon his Wife, his Child or any other Relations. He was likewise Very desirous that young People of his own Age and Condition might be made acquainted with the Steps which had brought on his Ruin; in Hopes that his Example might deter them from doing what may render themselves Examples of the same Sort. On the whole, he appear'd as composed as could be expected from a Person of his Capacity, and seem'd very willing to expiate his enormous Offence, by yielding his Body to Death.</p>
            <p>Whereas it was currently reported that I was related to Mr. Raven my Master, this is to satisfy the Public, that the said Report is entirely false, I being no ways related to him.</p>
            <p>He was ask'd the Night before his Execution whither his Intent was to murder Mrs. Din, as well as to rob her, because, it was a common Report that the Thing had been long premeditated: To which, he replyed, that his only Design was to rob, and that he had no Thought of offering any Violence; but being disturb'd in his Attempt, by the Gentlewoman's crying out, Who's there? he was unhappily led by the Devil, to commit the Murther, in order to conceal the Robbery. He said, as before related, that Gaming was the first Step to the Commission of this bloody Crime; and that at the Time he committed the Murther, he wanted a little Matter to make up a small Sum of his Master's which he had lost in Gaming Being ask'd what Hopes he had of attaining Mercy from a much offended God? he replied with Tears, that he had endeavour'd to repent him truly of this, and all his former Sins, and therefore hop'd tho' with fear and trembling, that he should be accepted as a poor Penitent, through the infinite Mercies of God in Christ Jesus. He grounded his hopes of Acceptances on the alone Merits of a crucified Saviour, and with humble Considence, applyed these Words of the Prophet to his own unhappy Case. Come new, and let us reason together, saith the Lord: though the Sins be as Scarlet, they shall be as white as Snow; though they be red like Crimson, they shall be as Wool. He said, that the Concern left he had sent the Deceased into the other World unprovided for Eternty, sat heavy upon his Mind; and that he dreaded lest she should accuse him for that Thing also, before the Bar of Christ. When</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA174211180011"/>
            <p>the Ordinary gave him the Holy Sacrament, and was about to deliver the sacred Elements into his Hands, he said, he was so overwhelm'd with a Sense of his Unworthiness, that his Heart nigh sainted within him. A By-stander ask'd him, if he were willing to die, Yes, very willing, he said, for I have had no rest in this World by reason of my Sins, till within this Day or two, and I hope to enjoy everlasting Rest Tomorrow. One ask'd him, if it did not shock him to think of being executed in the Neighbourhood where he liv'd: Nothing Shocks me, says he, but my Sins.</p>
            <p>The Morning of his Execution, before he went out his CELL, he took his final Leave (with Tears trickling down his Cheeks) of his Fellow Prisoners, who was under the same Misfortune as himself, and are to suffer on Monday next; and desir'd them to pray for his poor Soul the few Moments he had to live. And said at the same Time, he was going to be made a publick Example of, which he very justly deserv'd, and he hoped it would be for the good of Mankind; more especially young Men.</p>
            <p>The following Letter, was sent to <persName id="OA17421118n46-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n46-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n46-1" type="surname" value="HOMAN"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n46-1" type="given" value="THOMAS"/>THOMAS HOMAN</persName>, while he was under Condemnation.</p>
            <p>Dear Mr. HOMAN!.</p>
            <p>'THERE are two grand Devices, where'by that hater of Souls (the Devil) gains 'Advantage on poor unhappy Men.</p>
            <p>'The one is PRESUMPTION, and the 'other DESPAIR.'</p>
            <p>'BY the former of these, he prevails upon 'all the World to live as you see they do, as 'careless and unconcerned about a future State, 'as if they were uncapable of a future Existence; 'as if there were no Judgment to come, no Souls 'of an immortal Nature, capable of being sav'd, 'or lost for ever and ever.Hence it is, that 'Men live in Pleasure, and Mirth, in Eating 'and Drinking, in grasping for Riches and Ho'nours; either as if the Lease of Life would 'never expire, or else, considering it is but short, 'and that Death is their final End, think it there'fore the greatest Wisdom to make the most of 'Life they can.</p>
            <p>' BUT, because there is Something in us, that ' witnesses the Certainty, or at least the Possi' bility of a future State, our subtle Enemy ' quiets the Mind of wretched Man, by making ' him hope the best. Accordingly, it is no un' common Thing for the greatest Profligate, to ' bind his Word with saying, As I hope to be sav'd, ' A sure Sign, that he known not what he ' means. For such a Man's Hope is grounded ' upon no better a Foundation than this, (to wit) ' That God will not be true to his Word: And ' thus being more and more hardened in the ' Ways of Sin, he grows indifferent about the ' Matter, and is satisfied with thinking it will ' sare as well with him, as with the rest of the ' World.</p>
            <p>' DESPAIR is another Method whereby ' he destroyeth Souls, and that is, when a Man ' thinks his Measure of Iniquity is too full ever ' to be empty'd, or that his Heart is too hard to ' receive an Impression, even by an Almighty ' Hand, and therefore entertains no Thought of ' any possible Help; or else, when a Man hath ' fallen into some great Sin, after tasting some' thing of the Love of God, in such a Case as ' this, the goodness of God to Sinners, which ' endureth yet daily, is such, that by his Spirit ' he reproves the Conscience of the SINNER, ' and fets before him the Things that he hath ' done. Upon which, his Soul is filled with ' Horror, and he feels remorse greater than he ' can express; so that he cries out with David, ' Fearfulness and Trembling are come upon me; and ' an horrible Dread hath overwhelmed me.' He reflects upon his Crimes with all the Aggra' vations that are brought to his Mind, what ' Grace, Mercy, and Love he hath abus'd! what ' Vows and Resolutions he hath broken! and ' what Glory and Happiness he hath forfeited!</p>
            <p>'Now</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA174211180012"/>
            <p>'no Comfort, for want of a lively Faith in Je' sus Christ. Faith in his Blood, giving a sure ' Trust and Confidence that God for Christ's Sake ' hath forgiven thee. Ephef. iv. 32.</p>
            <p>' I do believe that the Sorrows of your Heart ' are enlarg'd, and also that you do find Trouble ' and Heaviness; and write to you that nothing ' may discourage you from calling upon the ' Name of the Lord. Give no Place to the ' Devildon't let him persuade you that you ' are hopeless,but pray the more earnestly, 'confess all that terrifies your Conscience to ' be true,and if it be suggested that you de' nied the Lord Jesus by a false Plea upon your ' Tryal, own this to God likewise,and ' then tell him, Lord if thou Savest me, it will ' prove Thee to be a Saviour indeed; magnifie thy ' own Mercy therefore, and extend the Riches of thy ' Grace; so shall I declare thou dyedst to save Sinners, ' among whom I am Chief.</p>
            <p>' O! Look unto him, for his Countenance is ' full of Love,full of Beauty,full of Mer' cy,full of Forgiveness, to wounded, broken, ' contrite Sinners. Is your Condition more de' sperate than others? The more need you have ' of him, the more haste will he make to help ' you Sins! go to him empty handed, but taken ' you have, all that you can find of this Sort, ' and lay your Complaint incessantly before him. 'Is the Burden intolerable? then listen to his ' Voice,Come unto me all that travel and are ' heavy laden, and I will give you rest, Matthew. ' xi. 28.Listen to his dying Groans, when ' he pray'd for his own Murderers, Father forgive ' them. Do you think yourself worse than they? ' then plead that you have greater need of his ' Intercession on your Behalf.Plead your' self sinking,perishing,and cannot do ' without him.Confess yourself into his ' Wounds,plead yourself into his Arms,' persist in praying, hoping, believing untill he ' opens his Arms and receives you into Paradise. 'Continue in Prayer and fear no Denial. 'O look for him to comfort you; expect ' him to visit you, to give you a Hope full of ' Immortality, and the End everlasting Life.' And may the Lord perform all thy Petitions. ;So prays Yours. Etc. S.T.</p>
            <p>' P.S. I hope to see you when Opportunity ' serves.Pray without ceasing</p>
            <p>Oct 21 1742.</p>
            <p>The following LETTER was sent to him some few Days after he was committed to <placeName id="OA17421118-geo-21">Newgate</placeName>, by a Reverend Divine.</p>
            <p>Unhappy YOUNG MAN.</p>
            <p>' IT is natural for a Man in your unhappy ' Condition, to lament the fatal Causes of ' such a melancholy State, and to wish with Ri' vers of fruitless Tears, that the Thing he ' hath Done, could be again Undone; and that his ' mis-spent Time could be again recall'd. But ' alass! in his Lamentation, he cries, It is all ' in vain.The Deed is done (says he) for ' which I am worthy of Death, and it is a shame' ful,reproachful,ignominious Death! ' Blood, cries aloud for Blood, and hope of ' Pardon is entirely cut off! What shall I do? ' Oh! how little did I think of coming to such ' a direful End! Where are my Friends that ' loved me? and my own Flesh, who fell more ' of my Grief than I am able to tell! and lament ' the Condition of a Brother, or an Husband, ' that hath pull'd to dreadful a Judgment upon ' himself with his own Hands.</p>
            <p>' UNSPEAKABLE (to be sure) is the Grief of ' such a Man, unless he be entirely harden'd in ' Sin, having a Conscience soar'd as with a hot ' Iron; but if his Grief and Concern be only ' of a temporal Nature, it is more Melancholly ' still, for then the Design of GOD in Suffering ' such a Judgment to fall upon him is without ' Effect. He laments only the unpardonableness ' of his Crime, with regard to the temporal Judge,</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA174211180013"/>
            <p>without considering that the Execution of this Sentence, places immediately before the great ' Tribunal of HEAVEN, and that unless his Soul ' be wash'd from the Guilt of THAT, and all ' his other Sins in the Blood of Jesus Christ, he ' will there be sentenced to an everlasting Sepa' ration from the Presence of GOD, to abide un' der his Wrath, for Ever and Ever.</p>
            <p>' BUT now if your Conscience be awaken'd ' to consider the everlasting State of your Soul, ' it is well for yourGive GOD the Praise, ' for it is no little Thing to be concerned in good ' Earnest about Eternity.Give GOD the ' Praise. I says; For though by the LAWS of ' the Land, the Man that hath done this Deed ' must suffer Death; and no Repentance can pro' cure a Pardon from an Earthly Judge. Yet ' GOD is a sovereign KING, and hath Power to ' forgive the vilest Sinner, and watcheth every ' Moment to be gracious to him.He wait' eth till the Sinner be truly sensible of his Sins, ' and when they are a fore Burden to his Con' science, too heavy for him to bear, then let him ' call upon the LORD in the Time of Trouble, ' and he hath promised in his Word, So will I ' hear Thee, and thou shalt Praise me; it is as ' much as to say, I will hear Thee,and relieve ' Thee, and turn thy bitter Cyies into Songs of ' Praise.</p>
            <p>BUT perhaps, the Suggestions of the Devil, ' and your own foolish Heart, hath flatter'd you ' all along with the Goodness of GOD,That ' he is too good to punish Sinners with everlast' ing Banishment from his Presence; or perhaps ' you have thought there is no Hell, a Place of ' Torment to damned Spirits; or that it would ' fare as well with you, as with all the rest of ' the World; or perhaps, you never gave your' self leave to think above it,for there are ' some of those Ways whereby the Deceiver of ' our Souls lieth in wait to beguile as, and Youth ' are more especially apt to receive the Delusion, ' because it is baired with the Delight of the ' World, and the Pleasures of Sin, and these ' are the Things that suit their Taste</p>
            <p>' AND hath the evil Spirit dealt with you in ' any of these Ways? then you need not be at ' a loss to know, why so great an Evil is come ' upon you, for GOD in very faithfulness hath ' caus'd you to be troubled.</p>
            <p>' THE very Reason why the World perish in ' their Sins, is, because they resist that Spirit of ' God which convinceth them of Sin, for none ' are so qualified to receive a Pardon at GOD'S ' Hand, as those who are sensible they deserve ' his Wrath, and perhaps, nothing less than the ' bitter Cup which is now in your Hand, could ' so humble you, as to make you afraid of ever' lasting Death: And are you afraid of this? ' Then beg of GOD to humble you more and ' more, that you may be able to own from the ' bottom of your Heart, that you justly deserve ' it. And have you such a feeling Sense of your ' Sinfulness, as to own that you deserve the ever' lasting Wrath of GOD? Then consider what ' perhaps you never considered before.That ' GOD hath laid all thy Sins upon his own Son! ' That he was crusify'd with Malefactors, having ' himself done nothing amiss, that thy guilty Soul ' may be washed in his innocent Blood! Oh! ' cease not to call upon him, never give out, ' never sain till thou hast received a Sense of ' Forgiveness.Indeed! Indeed! you can' not call upon him in vain, for it is own ap' pointment, that Repentance and Forgiveness ' of Sins should be preach'd unto all Nations, be' ginning at Jerusalem, beginning at the most ' wicked Place first! The Place of his Cruci' fiers and Murderers! Are you the vilest of ' Sinners? O! think to Still, for thou canst never ' think too basely of thyself.Plead no Ex; cuses, for GOD will not receive them; but plead ' Jesus Christ, till the Wounds of Jesus are ' disclos'd to thy Heart.GOD the Father ' hath receiv'd at his Hand double for all thy ' Sins.Embrace the New! and let thy ' Heart rejoice at the TidingsJesus Christ ' is a City of Refuse; fly to his Blood, and it ' will wash out thy btain! He is the Attonement, ' the Sinner, the Sinner that hath received him ' is a pardoned Sinner! Pardoned already, I al' ready does he rejoice in the Hope of Glory. 'Here is Tidings, embrace them; wrestle ' with GOD, beg of him to give you Power to</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA174211180014"/>
            <p>believe them,to remove your Unbelief, and hardness of Heart, and blindness of Un' derstandingThat his Light,The ' Light of Free-Grace and Mercy; the Light ' of pardoning Love may shine in upon thy Soul, ' and be so subject unto thy distressed Spirit, as ' in make Thee willing to submit thy Life, and ' to rejoice in that a Door is opened, a Door of ' Mercy; a Door into the everlasting Kingdom ' of Jesus ChristAnd may the Lord perform ' all thy Petitions.and he will perform them, ' persist in Praying, let nothing divert you; the ' Day is far spent, the Night is at Hand,Pour ' not thy Heart unto GOD, and expect every ' Moment that he will pour out his loving ' Kindness and Mercy upon Thee, and that the ' Time o' Love may be hastened to thy Soul; ' is the earnest Prayer of one who sincerely de' sires the Salvation of your precious and im' mortal Soul.</p>
            <p>Aug 20 1742.</p>
            <p>T.R.</p>
            <p>The following Letter was sent to <persName id="OA17421118n71-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n71-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n71-1" type="surname" value="HOMAN"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n71-1" type="given" value="THOMAS"/>Thomas Homan</persName>, some few Days before his Execution.</p>
            <p>Dear Brother!</p>
            <p>' LET me desire you, by the Grace of God, ' to examine yourself with these Words, ' Do you find yourself a poor loft undone Sinner? ' if you do, hear what our blessed Lord said ' unto you. I came to seek those that are lost, ' to heal them; although your Sin be as Scarlet, ' they shall be as white as Snow; although they ' be like a Crimson, they shall be like Wool: ' So God loved the World that he gave his only ' Son to die for the worst of Sinners; what can ' you desire more than all these Things, which ' our Lord has declared: Seek and you shall ' find, Knock and it shall be open, Ask and it ' shall be given. My dear Brother, fear not, ' although you feel your Sins so heavy that you ' are not able to be bear. The Lord calls you ' know, Come unto me all ye that are heavy laden, ' and I will give ye rest unto your Souls. Let me ' me desire you by the Grace of God, to call ' upon him continually. O! do not rest Night ' nor Day, but pray unto the Lord, that he will ' have Mercy upon you, tell him that you are a ' poor lost Sinner, and he will have Mercy upon ' you; but let your Prayers arise up continually ' unto the Lord, and he will have Mercy upon ' you.</p>
            <p>' O! most merciful Lord God, look down upon ' this my Brother, who doth most humbly de' sire Pardon and Forgiveness from thee who are ' a merciful God, for thy only Son Jesus Christ's ' Sake, forgive him all that is past, after this Life ' to receive him into your Kingdom to praise the ; for evermore. Amen.</p>
            <p>' O most gracious Lord God, look down upon ' me, who are a poor loft undone Sinner. Lord ' I have finned against thee, have Mercy O Lord ' upon me, and forgive me all that is past, for ' thy Son Jesus Christ's Sake, who has died for ' poor Sinners; I am the Chiefest, O Lord turn ' thou unto me, and have mercy upon me, and ' forgive me all, and O Lord receive me into thy ' Kingdom to praise thee for evermore. Amen.</p>
            <p>' Dear Brother, I desire if you can write to ' me a few Lines, how you find yourself at this ' Time toward your Soul, by so doing, you give ' your unworthy Servant a great deal of Joy to ' hear of you, and I hope I shall hear that the ' Lord has been gracious unto you; my Soul at ' present mourns for you, and the Lord give ' unto you that Peace which the World cannot ' give, nor take away; let me desire you once ' more to remember what our blessed Lord said, ' Whatsoever you ask me in my Son's Name it shall ' be given you; so let me desire you to ask the ' Lord for those Things which you desire from</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA174211180015"/>
            <p>' his Hands; may the Blessing of God Almighty ' be upon you, and remain with you for ever' more. Amen.</p>
            <p>' So no more at present,</p>
            <p>' From your unworthy Brother,</p>
            <p>' <persName id="OA17421118n80-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n80-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n80-1" type="surname" value="POTTENGER"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n80-1" type="given" value="RICHARD"/>RICHARD POTTENGER</persName>,</p>
            <p>' At Mr. <persName id="OA17421118n81-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n81-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n81-1" type="surname" value="Plumsted"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n81-1" type="given" value="Thomas"/>Thomas Plumsted</persName>, in <placeName id="OA17421118-geo-22">Gracechurch' Street</placeName>, London.</p>
            <p>The following LETTER was wrote by a Methodist, to <persName id="OA17421118n82-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n82-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n82-1" type="surname" value="HOMAN"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n82-1" type="given" value="THOMAS"/>Thomas Homan</persName>.</p>
            <p>Dear Brother!</p>
            <p>I Should rejoice to hear from you, my Spirit being at this Time greatly concerned about your never dying Soul; but let me exhort you in the Name of our blessed Lord and Saviour Jesus Christ, who died for you, and all that will attept of him. I have finned against the Lord all my Days: How shall I expect Mercy from him, who has so long withstood his Grace, and the Calls of his Holy Spirit? O! how shall I come to the Knowledge of my Saviour, who died for lost Sinners; may the Lord of his great Mercy make you one if those lost Ones of Israel, and receive you into his Kingdom, to praise you for evermore, Amen.</p>
            <p>Dear Brother, you have nothing to bring unto the Lord but Sin, and the Lord wants all those that are Sinners, that he may forgive them all their Sins, and make them fit for his Kingdom: I should rejoice to hear that you know and feel your Sins so heavy, that you are not able to hear them; so that you may, by the Assistance of God's Holy Spirit, try out, Lord, what shall I do to be saved? And the Lord will answer for himself; Believe, Believe in me, and you shall be saved. Behold him, who stands with his Arms open wide to receive you. Come unto me all ye that are heavy laden, and I will give you rest unto your Soul.</p>
            <p>My dear Brother, if you should not find your self a poor Sinner, may the Lord of his great Mercy, work in you a true Repentance. O! that you may find the Spirit of the Lord working in you, to will and to do, according to his Pleasure, so that you may have great Reason to cry out unto the Lord, that he may have Mercy upon you, and unto you, and give you a true and sincere Repentance, and the Forgiveness of all your Sins, in the Blood of our blessed. Lord and Saviour Jesus Christ, who lov'd us, to give himself to die upon the Cross for you and me; and may the Lord of his great Mercy apply these Words by his Holy Spirit with Power unto your Soul; My Son be of good Cheer, thy Sins are forgiving thee. Look thou unto me, who are full of Truth and Grace for you, and may the Lord of his great Mercy, make you Holy, as he is Holy, before you go hence, and be no more seen by us, but to see him Face to Face, to rejoice in him for evermore.</p>
            <p>Dear Brother, this may be the last Time of my Writing to you, for the Lord only knows that we shall live this Night or not, and if it should be so, let these be taking from me as my last; and may the Lord of his great Mercy give them his Almighty Blessing unto your Soul, so that it may be not in vain; and without his Blessing we cannot do any Thing; but if you remember, the Lord has declar'd that he will bless them, through his Son Jesus Christ; if they he desired by Faith, they shall be granted unto us, and may</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA174211180016"/>
            <p>the Lord give you and me Faith to receive those Things which we now stand in need off; and let me desire you by the Grace. of God, to all upon his Name continually, and tell him what you stand in need off, and he will give unto you, these things which are pleasing in his Sight; and to conclude with the Words of God: May the Blessing of God Almighty be upon you, and evermore be with you, and so remain with you for evermore, Amen, Amen, so come Lord Jesus,</p>
            <p>So no more at present,</p>
            <p>From you unworthy Brother, 'till Death,</p>
            <p>Oct 20 1742.</p>
            <p>RICHARD POTTENGER,</p>
            <p>The following Prayer <persName id="OA17421118n93-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n93-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n93-1" type="surname" value="Homan"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n93-1" type="given" value="Thomas"/>Thomas Homan</persName> frequently read in his Cell, while under Sentence of Death.</p>
            <p>' O MOST gracious Lord God, look down ' upon me, who am a poor lost and undone ' Sinner; Lord I have finned against thee, have ' mercy O Lord upon me, and forgive me all ' that is past, for thy Son Jesus Christ's Sake, ' who hast died for poor Sinners. I am the ' Chiefest, O Lord turn thou unto me, and ' have mercy upon me, and forgive me all ' my Sins, and O Lord receive me into thy ' Kingdom to praise Thee for ever. O most ' merciful Lord God, look down upon me thy ' Servant, who doth most humbly desire Pardon ' and Forgiveness from Thee who are a merciful ' God, for thy only Son Jesus Christ's Sake; for' give all that is past, after this Life, and receive ' me into thy Kingdom to praise thee for ever.</p>
            <p>The following LETTER was found in his Cell, after he was gone to EXECUTION.</p>
            <p>To my good Master, Mr. RAVEN:</p>
            <p>THE Misery of my deplorable Condition, I am sensible came from the bad Use I made of all you Favours, and the ingratefull Return of so many undeserved Kindnesses. The beginning of my Misfortunes, was the wrnging you, and the End of them is the just Reward of a mis-spent Life, and ignominious and violent Death, the last and worst of Calamities.</p>
            <p>All I intend by writing this Scrawl, is to return you my useless Thanks for all your Goodness towards so unworthy a Creature, who wrong'd you while you gave me Bread, and have brought Disgrace on a House where I was so well treated.</p>
            <p>Have Pity, good Sir, on my most unhappy State, wherein Death is rather a Relief than an Addition to my Misfortunes; forgive me the Wrongs I have done you, and pray for me in my last Moments.</p>
            <p>Your DYING,</p>
            <p>And distress'd Servant,</p>
            <p>
               <persName id="OA17421118n102-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n102-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n102-1" type="surname" value="HOMAN"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n102-1" type="given" value="THOMAS"/>THOMAS HOMAN</persName>.</p>
            <p>From my Cells in <placeName id="OA17421118-geo-23">Newgate</placeName>, Nov 18 1742.</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA174211180017"/>
            <p>A PAPER left by <persName id="OA17421118n104-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n104-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n104-1" type="surname" value="HOMAN"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n104-1" type="given" value="THOMAS"/>THOMAS HOMAN</persName>, containing what he intended to have spoken at the Place of Execution,</p>
            <p>I Know it is expected from Persons in my Condition to say somewhat as to the Cause of their Deaths, and as to the Course of their Lives before their fatal Exits. But as I am very well that nothing I am say would deserve much Notice, I will only mention two Things which lie very much upon my Mind, as I hope they may be of more Service than my insignificant Reflections.</p>
            <p>First I confess my most heinous and harbarous Murder of Mrs. Dix, for which I justly suffer, and willingly lay down my Lift to attone for so abominable wicked a Crime, hoping God through Christ will accept my Repentance, and receive me to his Mercy, and I heartily thank all who have been so charitable as to comfort or advise me under my most heavy Misfortunes, from which God defend them and theirs.</p>
            <p>I next desire all young Persons to take Warning by my sad Fate, and to abstain from Skittle Grounds, and other Games, the frequenting of which, and taking base Ways to obtain Money for the Expences. they occasioned have been my Ruin. O if Youth would consider in all such Places, that they are travelling as I am to Shame and Pain, surely they would refrain such fatal Diversions. O God the Author of Life, and Giver of Grace, accept my imperfect Repentance, and for the Sake of Jesus Christ thy Son, receive my departing Spirit into that Celestial Kingdom. thou hast promised to such as believe in thee. Amen.</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA174211180018"/>
            <p>ADVERTISEMENT.</p>
            <p>This Day is Publish'd</p>
            <p>In Four neat Pocket Volumes, Printed on a good Letter and fine Paper, Price Bound 12s. The Second Edition, (with very large Additions, of the most remarkable Trials, down to the present Time) of</p>
            <p>SELECT Trials at the Sessions-House in the Old-Bailey for Murder, Robberies, Rapes, Coining, Sodomy, Frauds and other Offences; chiefly transcribed from Notes taken in Court. To which are added (not to be met with in any other Collection) Genuine Accounts of the Lives, Behaviour, Confessions, and Dying Speeches of the most eminent Convicts.</p>
            <p>Among others are the following:</p>
            <p>MURDER. <persName id="OA17421118n113-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n113-1" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n113-1" type="surname" value="MALCOLM"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n113-1" type="given" value="SARAH"/>Sarah Malcolm</persName>, <persName id="OA17421118n113-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n113-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n113-2" type="surname" value="PRICE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n113-2" type="given" value="GEORGE"/>George Price</persName>, <persName id="OA17421118n113-3">
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n113-3" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n113-3" type="surname" value="HALL"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n113-3" type="given" value="JAMES"/>James Hall</persName>, <persName id="OA17421118n113-4">
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n113-4" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n113-4" type="surname" value="MECHLIN"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n113-4" type="given" value="CHARLES"/>Charles Mechlin</persName>, <rs id="OA17421118-occupation-12" type="occupation">Major</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17421118n113-9 OA17421118-occupation-12"/> 
               <persName id="OA17421118n113-9">
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n113-9" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n113-9" type="surname" value="Houssart"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n113-9" type="given" value="Oneby Lewis"/>Oneby. Lewis Houssart</persName>, <persName id="OA17421118n113-5">
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n113-5" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n113-5" type="surname" value="HAYES"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n113-5" type="given" value="CATHERINE"/>Catherine Hayes</persName>, <persName id="OA17421118n113-6">
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n113-6" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n113-6" type="surname" value="SAVAGE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n113-6" type="given" value="RICHARD"/>Richard Savage</persName>, <rs id="OA17421118-occupation-13" type="occupation">Capt</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17421118n113-7 OA17421118-occupation-13"/>. <persName id="OA17421118n113-7">
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n113-7" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n113-7" type="surname" value="JANE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n113-7" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Jane</persName>, <rs id="OA17421118-occupation-14" type="occupation">Capt.</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17421118n113-8 OA17421118-occupation-14"/> 
               <persName id="OA17421118n113-8">
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n113-8" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n113-8" type="surname" value="Clough"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n113-8" type="given" value="Stanley James"/>Stanley, James Clough</persName>, and others.</p>
            <p>PRIVATELY STEALING. <persName id="OA17421118n114-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n114-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n114-1" type="surname" value="GAFFNEY"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n114-1" type="given" value="PATRICK"/>Patrick Gaffney</persName>, <persName id="OA17421118n114-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n114-2" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n114-2" type="surname" value="NOBLE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n114-2" type="given" value="PHILLIS"/>Phillis Noble</persName>, <persName id="OA17421118n114-3">
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n114-3" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n114-3" type="surname" value="WILD"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n114-3" type="given" value="JONATHAN"/>Jonathan Wild</persName>, <rs id="OA17421118-occupation-15" type="occupation">Sir</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17421118n114-4 OA17421118-occupation-15"/> 
               <persName id="OA17421118n114-4">
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n114-4" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n114-4" type="surname" value="BURTON"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n114-4" type="given" value="CHARLES"/>Charles Burton</persName>, Etc.</p>
            <p>HIGHWAY. Hawkins and Simpson, Spiggot that bore 350 Ib. wt. on his Breast, <persName id="OA17421118n115-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n115-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n115-1" type="surname" value="GORDON"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n115-1" type="given" value="WILLIAM"/>William Gordon</persName>, <persName id="OA17421118n115-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n115-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n115-2" type="surname" value="WREATHOCK"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n115-2" type="given" value="WILLIAM"/>William Wreathock</persName>, <persName id="OA17421118n115-3">
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n115-3" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n115-3" type="surname" value="CARR"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n115-3" type="given" value="THOMAS"/>Thomas Carr</persName>, <persName id="OA17421118n115-4">
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n115-4" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n115-4" type="surname" value="ADAMS"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n115-4" type="given" value="ELIZABETH"/>Elizabeth Adams</persName>, <persName id="OA17421118n115-5">
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n115-5" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n115-5" type="surname" value="BARKWITH"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n115-5" type="given" value="WILLIAM"/>William Barkwith</persName>, <persName id="OA17421118n115-7">
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n115-7" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n115-7" type="surname" value="Diver"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n115-7" type="given" value="Jenny"/>Jenny, Diver</persName>, <persName id="OA17421118n115-6">
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n115-6" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n115-6" type="surname" value="DALTON"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n115-6" type="given" value="JAMES"/>James Dalton</persName>, Etc.</p>
            <p>RAPES and Attempts to RAVISH. <rs id="OA17421118-occupation-16" type="occupation">Col</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17421118n116-1 OA17421118-occupation-16"/>. <persName id="OA17421118n116-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n116-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n116-1" type="surname" value="CHARTRES"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n116-1" type="given" value="FRANCIS"/>Francis Chartres</persName>, <rs id="OA17421118-occupation-17" type="occupation">Esq</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17421118n116-1 OA17421118-occupation-17"/>; <persName id="OA17421118n116-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n116-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n116-2" type="surname" value="WEST"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n116-2" type="given" value="WILLIAM"/>William West</persName>, <persName id="OA17421118n116-3">
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n116-3" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n116-3" type="surname" value="WHITE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n116-3" type="given" value="ADAM"/>Adam White</persName>, <persName id="OA17421118n116-4">
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n116-4" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n116-4" type="surname" value="ROBBINS"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n116-4" type="given" value="WILLIAM"/>William Robbins</persName>, <persName id="OA17421118n116-5">
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n116-5" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n116-5" type="surname" value="GRAY"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n116-5" type="given" value="ARTHUR"/>Arthur Gray</persName>, Etc.</p>
            <p>SODOMY and SODOMITICAL Practices. <persName id="OA17421118n117-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n117-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n117-1" type="surname" value="DUFFUS"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n117-1" type="given" value="GEORGE"/>George Duffus</persName>, <persName id="OA17421118n117-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n117-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n117-2" type="surname" value="DICKS"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n117-2" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Dicks</persName>, <persName id="OA17421118n117-3">
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n117-3" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n117-3" type="surname" value="KEDGER"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n117-3" type="given" value="GEORGE"/>George Kedger</persName>, <persName id="OA17421118n117-4">
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n117-4" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n117-4" type="surname" value="WRIGHT"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n117-4" type="given" value="THOMAS"/>Thomas Wright</persName>, <persName id="OA17421118n117-5">
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n117-5" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n117-5" type="surname" value="HITCHIN"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n117-5" type="given" value="CHARLES"/>Charles Hitchin</persName>, at that Time was <rs id="OA17421118-occupation-18" type="occupation">City-Marshal</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17421118n117-5 OA17421118-occupation-18"/>, <persName id="OA17421118n117-6">
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n117-6" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n117-6" type="surname" value="CLAP"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n117-6" type="given" value="MARGARET"/>Margaret Clap</persName>, Etc.</p>
            <p>FOGERY. <persName id="OA17421118n118-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n118-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n118-1" type="surname" value="HALES"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n118-1" type="given" value="WILLIAM"/>William Hales</persName>, Parson Kinnersley, <persName id="OA17421118n118-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n118-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n118-2" type="surname" value="NEWINGTON"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n118-2" type="given" value="WILLIAM"/>William Newington</persName>, <persName id="OA17421118n118-3">
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n118-3" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n118-3" type="surname" value="BRABANT"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n118-3" type="given" value="RICHARD"/>Richard Brabant</persName>, Etc.</p>
            <p>Printed by <persName id="OA17421118n119-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n119-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n119-1" type="surname" value="APPLEBEE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17421118n119-1" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Applebee</persName>, and Sold by J. Hodges, at the Looking-Glass, over-against St. Magnus-Church, London-Bridge.</p>
            <p>N.B. These Trials are not only necessary for all Lawyers, Justices of the Peace, Clerks of Indictments, and other Persons concerned in Prosecutions, Etc. but are useful and entertaining to the generality of Readers, containing more in Quantity as well as Cheaper than any Thing of the Kind yet published.</p>
         </div0>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>