<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<TEI.2>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div0 type="ordinarysAccount" id="OA17310514">
            <interp inst="OA17310514" type="uri" value="ordinarysAccounts/OA17310514"/>
            <interp inst="OA17310514" type="date" value="17310514"/>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA173105140001"/>
            <p>THE ORDINARY of NEWGATE, His ACCOUNT of the Behaviour, Confessions, and Dying Words, OF THE MALEFACTORS, Who were EXECUTED at TYBURN, On FRIDAY the 14th of this Instant May, 1731.</p>
            <p>BEING THE Third EXECUTION in the MAYORALTY OF THE Rt. Hon. <persName id="OA17310514n3-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n3-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n3-1" type="surname" value="PARSONS"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n3-1" type="given" value="HUMPHREY"/>HUMPHREY PARSONS</persName>, Esq;</p>
            <p>Number III. For the said YEAR.</p>
            <p>LONDON:</p>
            <p>Printed and Sold by <persName id="OA17310514n6-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n6-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n6-1" type="surname" value="APPLEBEE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n6-1" type="given" value="JOHN"/>JOHN APPLEBEE</persName>, in <placeName id="OA17310514-geo-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17310514-geo-1" type="type" value="street"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA17310514n6-1 OA17310514-geo-1"/>
                  <placeName id="OA17310514-geo-2">
                     <interp inst="OA17310514-geo-2" type="type" value="site"/>
                     <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA17310514n6-1 OA17310514-geo-2"/>Bolt-Court, near the <placeName id="OA17310514-geo-3">
                        <interp inst="OA17310514-geo-3" type="type" value="site"/>
                        <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA17310514n6-1 OA17310514-geo-3"/>Leg-Tavern</placeName>
                  </placeName>, Fleet-street</placeName>. M.DCC.XXXI.</p>
            <p>[Price Three-Pence.]</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA173105140003"/>
            <p>THE ORDINARY of NEWGATE, His ACCOUNT of the Behaviour, Confession, &amp;c.</p>
            <p>AT the King's Commission of Oyer and Terminer, and Gaol-Delivery of Newgate, held (before the Rt. Hon. <persName id="OA17310514n9-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n9-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n9-1" type="surname" value="PARSONS"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n9-1" type="given" value="HUMPHREY"/>HUMPHREY PARSONS</persName>, Esq; Lord Mayor of the City of London; the Rt. Hon. the Lord Chief Justice Raymond; the Hon. Mr. Baron Cummins; the Hon. Mr. Baron Thompson; the Hon. Mr. Justice Denton, and others of His Majesty's Justices of Oyer and Terminer, and GaolDelivery for the City of London, and Gaol-Delivery of Newgate, holden for the said City and County of Middlesex) at Justice-Hall in the Old-Bailey, on Wednesday, Thursday, Friday, Saturday, and Monday, being the 28th, 29th, and 30th, of April, and the 1st and 3d of May, 1731, in the Fourth Year of his Majesty's Reign.</p>
            <p>Nine Men, viz. <persName id="OA17310514n10-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n10-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n10-1" type="surname" value="BERRY"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n10-1" type="given" value="JAMES"/>James Berry</persName>, <persName id="OA17310514n10-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n10-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n10-2" type="surname" value="COOPER"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n10-2" type="given" value="RICHARD"/>Richard Cooper</persName>, <persName id="OA17310514n10-3">
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n10-3" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n10-3" type="surname" value="WOODMARSH"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n10-3" type="given" value="FRANCIS"/>Francis Woodmarsh</persName>, <persName id="OA17310514n10-4">
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n10-4" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n10-4" type="surname" value="TRAP"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n10-4" type="given" value="RICHARD"/>Richard Trap</persName>, alias Blue Dick, <persName id="OA17310514n10-5">
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n10-5" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n10-5" type="surname" value="PEAVERLY"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n10-5" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Peaverly</persName>, <persName id="OA17310514n10-6">
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n10-6" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n10-6" type="surname" value="BUTLER"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n10-6" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Butler</persName>, <persName id="OA17310514n10-7">
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n10-7" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n10-7" type="surname" value="LYNN"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n10-7" type="given" value="FRANCIS"/>Francis Lynn</persName>, <persName id="OA17310514n10-10">
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n10-10" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n10-10" type="surname" value="Glynn"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n10-10" type="given" value="Francis"/>alias Glynn</persName>, <persName id="OA17310514n10-8">
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n10-8" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n10-8" type="surname" value="OWEN"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n10-8" type="given" value="JAMES"/>James Owen</persName>, and <persName id="OA17310514n10-9">
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n10-9" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n10-9" type="surname" value="NEWPORT"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n10-9" type="given" value="AMBROSE"/>Ambrose Newport</persName>, were by the Jury found guilty of capital Crimes, and receiv'd Sentence of Death accordingly.</p>
            <p>After Sentence, they were instructed in the chief Articles of our most Holy Christian Faith: That it is necessary to know that there is one God, the Sovereign Lord of Heaven and Earth; who made all Things by the Word of his Power, and who preserves every Thing in its Being; " For in him " we Live, and Move, and have " our Being, as certain also of your " own Poets have said, for we are " also his Off-spring: " As saith the Apostle St. Paul, Acts. xvii. 28.</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA173105140004"/>
            <p>And as from the omnipotent Word of God, we have our first Existence, and by his powerful Providence we are preserv'd in our Being; so we ought to believe, that there are three Persons in this one God; the Father, who creates and preserves us; the Son of God, who redeems us by his Death and Sufferings, and thus purchases us to be an holy, peculiar, chosen People unto God, zealous of good Works; and God the Holy Ghost, who sanctifies the elect People of God, and who preserves them by the mighty Power of God, through Faith unto Salvation.</p>
            <p>And as we ought to believe in the Divine Unity, and that there is a Trinity of Persons in the Godhead; so are we to believe, that there is one Mediator or Intercessor between God and Man, according to the Holy Apostles Doctrine, 1 Tim. ii. 5, 6. For there is one God and one Mediator between God and Men, the Man Christ Jesus, who gave himself a Ransom for all, to be Testified in due Time. I exhorted them to believe in Christ, the Son of God, and only Saviour of Sinners, with an operative and lively Faith, moving us to Holiness in all manner of Life and Conversation, for Faith without Works is Dead being alone; as St. James says, Holiness is that which makes us like unto and resemble God, the Archetype of all Perfection, Purity and Virtue. And therefore, since they had been young Men void of Holiness and the Fear of God, which was the occasion of Gods forsaking them, since they had forsaken him, and knew nothing of his Ways, and giving them up to themselves, to their own Hearts Lust, to commit all Uncleanness and all manner of Wickedness with Greediness, I took occasion to offer them a serious Exhortation to Holiness in Heart and Life, to redeem their Time, because the Days are Evil, to improve the few Moments allow'd them upon Earth, in fearing and loving God, and endeavouring to keep his Commandments according to the Apostles Advice. " See then that ye walk Circumspectly, not as Fools, but as " wise Men; redeeming the Time, " because the Days are Evil. " Eph. v. 15, 16. And I desir'd 'em, to resolve, by the Grace of God, that if they had done Iniquity and Sin, they would do so no more: That whereas formerly they had been the Servants of Unrighteousness unto Sin, henceforth they would become the obedient Servants of rigteousness unto holi</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA173105140005"/>
            <p>ness; as the same Apostle adviseth us, " Neither yield ye your members as Instruments of unrighteousness unto Sin; but yield your " selves unto God, as those that " are alive from the Dead, and " your members as instruments of " righteousness unto God. " Rom. 6, 13. And I prest upon them to endeavour after habitual Holiness, because of the great Danger and Destruction ensuing upon a wicked Course of Life. As the Apostle also acquaints us, " For the Wages " of Sin is Death: But the Gift " of God is eternal Life through " Jesus Christ our Lord. Rom. " vi. 23.</p>
            <p>Two of them having been Convicted of Murder, I us'd many Motives and Arguments to convince them of the greatness of their Guilt. I show'd them that this was one of the blackest and most atrocious Crimes, Man was capable of committing, and that therefore, by all Laws Divine and Humane, the Punishment annext to this Sin is Death by the Sword of publick Justice. The History Moses gives us of the Creation and the antediluvian World, is Compendious, and the Account of the Flood itself, and the Times immediately following is but very short; yet that holy Man, inspir'd by the Spirit of God, in an extraordinary Manner, not making mention of other Laws and Customs proper to those very antient Times, takes particular Notice, no doubt as well knowing how prone Mankind is to prosecute Malice and Revenge, by extending their Resentment of suppos'd or real Injuries or Affronts too great a Length of Gods express Command, that the Murderer should by no Means pass unpunished, but that he should die a violent Death by the Hand of Justice. " And surely your Blood of your Lives will " I require: At the Hand of every Beast will I require it; and " at the Hand of Man, at the " Hand of every Mans Brother will I " require the Life of Man. Whosoe sheddeth Mans Blood, by " Man shall his Blood be shed: " For in the Image of God made " he Man. " Gen, ix. 5, . Yet notwithstanding the greatness of their Sins, I desired them to throw themselves upon the Mercy of God which is Infinite, and if with David and Manasseh, who were true Penitents for the same Sin and Crime, they truly and sincerely repented, even of this henious Sin of Murder, then God would receive them</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA173105140006"/>
            <p>into Favour, and Pardon that Sin, as he did remit the same to others; for Pardon is promis'd in general to a true Repentance for all his Sins without exception.</p>
            <p>I instructed them also in the most important Affair of the Lords Supper, as a special Means to avert their Thoughts from all sinful Appetites, to dispose their Minds for receiving the Grace of God, and to prepare them for the Glories of a future State.</p>
            <p>While these and many other good Instructions were given, all of them attended in Chapel; only <persName id="OA17310514n18-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n18-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n18-1" type="surname" value="BERRY"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n18-1" type="given" value="JAMES"/>James Berry</persName> was indispos'd for some Days, but behav'd Christianly, and show'd a great Desire to take the Sacrament, as did also some of the rest, and in general they behav'd with a better outward Decorum, than these unhappy Creatures use to do. Peaverly the poor Boy was also Sick for some Time, and carried himself always very decently. When I ask'd him, why he robb'd his Master of so great a Sum of Money as 48 Guineas, and what he intended to do with it, or if any Body advis'd him to such a Crime? He said he could not tell why he did it, that he knew not what to do with it, but to cram his Belly with good Victuals, and that no Body advis'd him, but that it was a Motion of his own wicked Heart. All of them made regular Responses; Butler and Lynn, although they declar'd themselves Romans, yet they gave close Attendance in Chapel, excepting one Afternoon, made Responces and comply'd with the Worship, as did the rest in time of Worship; they read a little too loud upon some Romish Manuals they had; but when I reprov'd them for it, and told them our Worship was such as no Christian could in Reason refuse to comply with, although there might be some other Differences, they did so no more, but were attentive with the rest.</p>
            <p>Upon Tuesday, the 11th Instant, the Report was made to his Majesty in Council, of the nine Malefactors under Sentence of Death in <placeName id="OA17310514-geo-4">
                  <interp inst="OA17310514-geo-4" type="type" value="site"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17310514n19-1 n19-3 n19-4 n19-5 n20-2 OA17310514-geo-4"/>Newgate</placeName>: When <persName id="OA17310514n19-3">
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n19-3" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n19-3" type="surname" value="Butler"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n19-3" type="given" value="John"/>John Butler</persName> and <persName id="OA17310514n19-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n19-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n19-1" type="surname" value="LYNN"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n19-1" type="given" value="FRANCIS"/>Francis Lynn</persName>, <persName id="OA17310514n19-4">
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n19-4" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n19-4" type="surname" value="Glynn"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n19-4" type="given" value="Francis"/>alias Glynn</persName>, of <placeName id="OA17310514-geo-5">
                  <interp inst="OA17310514-geo-5" type="type" value="parish"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17310514n19-1 n19-4 OA17310514-geo-5"/>St. Giles's in the Fields</placeName>, for assaulting <persName id="OA17310514n19-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n19-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n19-2" type="surname" value="DYER"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n19-2" type="given" value="EDWARD"/>Edward Dyer</persName> on the King's Highway, putting him in Fear, and taking from him a Hat, val. 5 s. and a Muslin Stock, val. 6 d. the 23d of August last; <persName id="OA17310514n19-5">
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n19-5" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n19-5" type="surname" value="Peaverley"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n19-5" type="given" value="John"/>John Peaverley</persName>, of <placeName id="OA17310514-geo-6">
                  <interp inst="OA17310514-geo-6" type="type" value="parish"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA17310514n19-5 OA17310514-geo-6"/>St. George's Hanover-square</placeName>, for feloniously 
stealing a Purse, val 2d. and 48 Guineas, in the Dwelling</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA173105140007"/>
            <p>House of <persName id="OA17310514n20-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n20-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n20-1" type="surname" value="DICKENSON"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n20-1" type="given" value="ROBERT"/>Robert Dickenson</persName>, the 25th of April last; and <persName id="OA17310514n20-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n20-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n20-2" type="surname" value="OWEN"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n20-2" type="given" value="JAMES"/>James Owen</persName>, of <placeName id="OA17310514-geo-7">
                  <interp inst="OA17310514-geo-7" type="type" value="parish"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA17310514n20-2 OA17310514-geo-7"/>St. Bartholomew's-Exchange</placeName>, for feloniously stealing a Bank-Note, value 100 l. the Property of <persName id="OA17310514n20-3">
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n20-3" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n20-3" type="surname" value="BUTLER"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n20-3" type="given" value="THOMAS"/>Thomas Butler</persName>, the 4th of February last, receiv'd his Majesty's most gracious Reprieve.</p>
            <p>The other Five, viz. <persName id="OA17310514n21-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n21-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n21-1" type="surname" value="BERRY"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n21-1" type="given" value="JAMES"/>James Berry</persName>, <persName id="OA17310514n21-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n21-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n21-2" type="surname" value="NEWPORT"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n21-2" type="given" value="AMBROSE"/>Ambrose Newport</persName>, <persName id="OA17310514n21-3">
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n21-3" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n21-3" type="surname" value="COOPER"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n21-3" type="given" value="RICHARD"/>Richard Cooper</persName>, <persName id="OA17310514n21-4">
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n21-4" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n21-4" type="surname" value="TRAP"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n21-4" type="given" value="RICHARD"/>Richard Trap</persName> and <persName id="OA17310514n21-5">
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n21-5" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n21-5" type="surname" value="WOODMARSH"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n21-5" type="given" value="FRANCIS"/>Francis Woodmarsh</persName> were order'd for Execution.</p>
            <p>
               <persName id="OA17310514n22-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n22-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n22-1" type="surname" value="WOODMARSH"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n22-1" type="given" value="FRANCIS"/>Francis Woodmarsh</persName>, of <placeName id="OA17310514-geo-8">
                  <interp inst="OA17310514-geo-8" type="type" value="parish"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA17310514n22-1 OA17310514-geo-8"/>St. George Hanover-Square</placeName>, was indicted for the Murder of <persName id="OA17310514n22-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n22-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n22-2" type="surname" value="ORMES"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n22-2" type="given" value="ROBERT"/>Robert Ormes</persName>, giving him one mortal Wound with a Sword, on the left Part of the Body, near the left Pap, the Length of half an Inch, and the Depth of six Inches, of which he instantly died, the 19th of April last.</p>
            <p>He was likewise indicted a second Time, upon the Coroners Inquest, for the Murder of the said <persName id="OA17310514n23-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n23-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n23-1" type="surname" value="ORMES"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n23-1" type="given" value="ROBERT"/>Robert Ormes</persName>.</p>
            <p>1. <persName id="OA17310514n24-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n24-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n24-1" type="surname" value="WOODMARSH"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n24-1" type="given" value="FRANCIS"/>Francis Woodmarsh</persName>, 33 Years of Age, born in North-, of honest respected Parents, who liv'd much in Y-, and gave him good Education at School, in reading, writing, Latin, and Accompts, to fit him for the World, and instructed him carefully in the Principles of our holy Christian Faith. He did not go to any particular Business, when of Age, but acted the Gentleman more than any Thing else; he serv'd some Time in the Army, and was advanc'd (as he said) to be an <rs id="OA17310514-occupation-1" type="occupation">Ensign in a marching Regiment</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17310514n24-1 OA17310514-occupation-1"/>, but soon left that Business; and afterwards not following any particular Trade of Life, 'tis to be feared he was too much addicted to Iddleness. He was married to a Wife, who appear'd to be a good, discreet Woman, whom he commended as such, and recommended to the Care and Kindness of his Friends, who were People of Respect. He had some Children, but they had all the good Fortune to Die before him. He said, he serv'd a Person of Prime Quality, till he went Abroad some Years ago, but without Hopes of returning in haste; and that some of his Friends serv'd that noble Family for some Generations past. He was a Kind of <rs id="OA17310514-occupation-2" type="occupation">Dealer in Wigs</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17310514n24-1 OA17310514-occupation-2"/>; when any great Man, whom he knew, wanted a Wig, he us'd to make or provide him One, and by that he sometimes made 2 or 3 Guineas, which was the mot he had to Live upon for some Time past. He said, that about the Time of the late Rebellion, he did several good Services, kept some Gentlemen from joyning in that unnatural Rebellion, and travail'd over best Part of <placeName id="OA17310514-geo-9">
                  <interp inst="OA17310514-geo-9" type="type" value="region"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA17310514n24-1 OA17310514-geo-9"/>England</placeName> and <placeName id="OA17310514-geo-10">
                  <interp inst="OA17310514-geo-10" type="type" value="region"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17310514n24-1 OA17310514-geo-10"/>Scotland</placeName> upon that Occasion.</p>
            <p>His Father had an Estate and a good Farm in the Country, bestow'd very liberally upon him, and gave him several Sums of Money, of which he never made any good Account, and for that Reason, he had not much left him by his Father, and was he</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA173105140008"/>
            <p>less esteem'd by his Relations. He said, that he was a sober Man, kept the Church, hated Cursing and Swearing, and other Vices, that he read his Book much, shunn'd idle Company, and lov'd a quiet, peaceable Life.</p>
            <p>The Account he gave of the Murder of <persName id="OA17310514n27-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n27-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n27-1" type="surname" value="ORMES"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n27-1" type="given" value="ROBERT"/>Robert Ormes</persName>, for which he died, was to this Purpose.</p>
            <p>On the 19th Day of April last, which was Easter-Monday, he walk'd out alone, as far as <placeName id="OA17310514-geo-11">
                  <interp inst="OA17310514-geo-11" type="type" value="parish"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17310514n24-1 OA17310514-geo-11"/>Chelsea</placeName>, for his Diversion: When he was upon his Return to Town, the Sun was pretty hot, and he being thirsty, went into on Ale house in <placeName id="OA17310514-geo-12">
                  <interp inst="OA17310514-geo-12" type="type" value="site"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17310514n24-1 OA17310514-geo-12"/>Chelsea-Fields</placeName>, where there was a Company of People, altogether Strangers to him, who Swore and Blasphem'd very much; he was impatient at the hearing of this, and gently reprov'd them, saying that there could be no Profit in using such execrable Oaths, and that it would be much better to be more Smooth in their Conversation, and not to provoke God, by such vain and very sinful Repetitions. They did not think him a proper Person to administer Reproof, but gave him Names, which he took to be opprobrious, and call'd them Scrubs; but insisted that he was a Gentleman and a Scholar, and repeated Si Deus est animas, &amp;c. They bid him pay his Reckoning and begone, and said, they doubted if he had any Money in his Pocket, &amp;c. several satyrical Expressions having past, he was weary of their Company, paid his Three-half-pence, for a Pint of Beer, and went off. The Deceas'd Mr. Ormes, his Wife, and the rest of the Company went out after him, and some of them swore, and cried out to dash out the I-n's Brains. Upon which they beat him unmercifully, with their Canes and Sticks, upon the Head and other Parts of the Body. He was confounded and knew not what to do, but thought upon nothing but his being murther'd: To save himself, he retir'd a good Way, till he came to the Garden hedge, then he drew his Sword to defend himself, and call'd out to hold off and beware of him, being upon his own Defence. At this Time, Mr. Ormes, (as he suppos'd) rush'd upon his Sword and was kill'd, which was the easier done, because his Breast was naked, as he said. And more than this he knew nothing of the Matter: Only to extenuate the Affair, he said, he was very short-sighted, and never saw Ormes, nor none of the Company.</p>
            <p>This is an Account, which contradicts the Evidence of the Prosecutor, and all who were against him, who swore possitively, that he stabb'd Mr. Ormes, without any Provocation, and that they did not see him receive any Stroaks with a Cane. I told him it was not probable, so many People would witness any Thing but Truth, without varying; but after all the Reasons could be us'd for an ingenious Confession, he never alter'd in his Narrative to me, nor to all those who</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA173105140009"/>
            <p>visited him in the Prison, under Sentence, to whom he always repeated the same Thing, with abundance of Tears trickling down his Cheeks. He said he commonly walk'd out with a Sword, (which was very unfortunate to him, on that unhappy Day); although contrary to the Advice of his nearest Friends.</p>
            <p>The Reason he gave for dressing like a Gentleman, was, because he had once been an <rs id="OA17310514-occupation-3" type="occupation">Officer in the Army</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17310514n24-1 OA17310514-occupation-3"/>, and he also expected to get into the Service of some great Man, to whom his fine Dress would be one Recommendation. He made no Reflections, but only said, he heard Mr. Ormes was Quarrelsome.</p>
            <p>He was Pusillanimous and of a mean Spirit, always wept and cried like a Child, when he told his Case to any Body, the Tears gush'd out in a very strange Manner, so that he could scarce speak because of his deep Sighs and Groans. I comforted him against the Fears of Death, but he remain'd inconsolable. I often told him, that his undiscretion, in medling with Strangers, of whom he knew nothing off, and with whom he had nothing to do, was the occasion of the unhappy Misfortune that happened; and therefore, laying aside all Pretences of Excuse, seeing he was legally Convicted, it was his Duty to repent of that grievous Sin of Murder: He said he did so, but it's to be fear'd, he had some Reserve; and it's certain, there could not be a Man more unwilling, and more afraid of Death than he was.</p>
            <p>He had been of a careless and idle Disposition, which exposed him to Temptations, and brought him to a violent and shameful Death. He behav'd well, and appear'd very penitent. He declar'd that he hop'd for Salvation thro' Christ, that he sincerely repented of all his Sins, and forgave all Injuries, as he expected Forgiveness from God.</p>
            <p>On Wednesday Evening, the second Day before their Execution, One in a Lay-Habit, whom they supposs'd to be a R-sh P-st, came to him and spoke silently in his Ear, That it was necessary for him to Turn, for that there was no Salvation out of their Church. Woodmarsh was but a weak Man in his Intellectuals, and he said this Assertion of that Stranger, put him into the greatest Agony and Perplexity immaginable, all the next Night. I told him, he need not be afraid to trust his Salvation upon the Mercy of God, through the Merits of Jesus Christ; and that their Way of Instruction was, to teach Men to confide in their own Merits, and the intercession of the Saints, which was an uncertain Way of obtaining the Favour of God, and contrary to Scripture-Revelation. He was content, and said he did not believe him; but that being so near Death, it put him in no little Confusion, to hear himself upbraided, as if he had liv'd in so gross an Error all his Life.</p>
            <p>This is a Freedom, which those of our Communion dare not take in some neighbouring Countries.</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA173105140010"/>
            <p>The following ACCOUNT of the Killing of Mr. Ormes, was delivered by <persName id="OA17310514n36-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n36-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n36-1" type="surname" value="WOODMARSH"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n36-1" type="given" value="FRANCIS"/>Francis Woodmarsh</persName>, to a Gentleman in the <placeName id="OA17310514-geo-13">
                  <interp inst="OA17310514-geo-13" type="type" value="site"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17310514n24-1 OA17310514-geo-13"/>Press-Yard, in Newgate</placeName>, the Morning before his Execution, (in the Sight of a great Number of People there present,) and by him requested to be delivered to Mr. Applebee, to be publish'd to the World.-</p>
            <p>As it is customary for Persons under my unhappy Circumstances to declare the Truth at their last Moments concerning the Fact for which they Suffer: I hope by this to satisfie the World as to the real Truth; tho' things have been much misrepresented, which have done me no small harm.</p>
            <p>ON Easter-Monday last, towards the Evening, calling at the <placeName id="OA17310514-geo-14">
                  <interp inst="OA17310514-geo-14" type="type" value="site"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17310514n24-1 OA17310514-geo-14"/>
                  <placeName id="OA17310514-geo-15">
                     <interp inst="OA17310514-geo-15" type="type" value="site"/>
                     <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                           targets="OA17310514n36-1 OA17310514-geo-15"/>Three Moor-Cocks</placeName> in Chelsea-Fields</placeName> (by my self) for a pint of Beer, I unluckily happen'd to go into the Room where Mr Ormes the Deceas'd was with his Friends, all Strangers to me, and all of them seem'd to be much in Liquor; and some of them talking very Profanely, I took the Liberty to Reprove them. At which the Wife of the Deceas'd was very Angry, and used me with a great deal of Ill manners, and gave me very abusive Language, and prompted Mr. Ormes her Husband to Quarrel with me; and her Expression was to knock my Brains out, with several other indecent Expressions, unbecoming her Sex; upon which I paid my Reckoning, and was going out of their Company; but to my great Surprize, Mr. Ormes push'd me out of Doors, and pursued me seven or eight Yards, giving me several Blows with his Cane, which at last obliged me to Draw my Sword in my own Defence, not with any Intention to Kill the Deceased, but only to make him desist from abusing me; but the Deceased-still pursuing me with his Blows, the unlucky Accident happened, for which I am immediately going to suffer Death.</p>
            <p>I had no premeditated Design against the Deceased, he being an utter Stranger to me, having never seen him before.</p>
            <p>Mrs. Middleton, the Landlady of the House, was in the Celler when I went out of the House, and so could not possibly see whether Mr. Ormes struck me or not, though she swore to the contrary; and likewise gave a false Description of the Ground, to discredit the Evidence of Mr. Bell, who appear'd as an Evidence for me: For which I pray God Almighty to Forgive her, as I do the rest of the Evidences that were then in Company, who I think aggravated Matters to the Court.</p>
            <p>As for Mr. Bell, he was an utter Stranger to me, I never having seen him to my Knowledge, till the Time of my Trial, he coming voluntarily to declare the Truth, which was to the same Effect as I have already re</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA173105140011"/>
            <p>lated, as to the Deceased's following and striking me; for which I have been inform'd, he has been reflected on: But to do him Justice, I have, by the Assistance of my Friends, obtain'd a Certificate, under the Hands of his Officers, in regard to his Character, which I have hereunto annex'd, and which if I had produc'd on my Trial, I believe might have been of Service to me; but my Trial coming on so soon after my Commitment, prevented me from making so proper a Defence for myself, as otherwise I might have done.</p>
            <p>I hope I have made my Peace with God Almighty, through the Merits of my Saviour Jesus Christ, for this and all other my past Offences.</p>
            <p>I die an unworthy Member of the Church of England, and beg the Prayers of all good Christians.</p>
            <p>May 14, 1731.</p>
            <p>
               <persName id="OA17310514n46-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n46-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n46-1" type="surname" value="WOODMARSH"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n46-1" type="given" value="FRANCIS"/>Francis Woodmarsh</persName>.</p>
            <p>A Copy of a Certificate of Mr. <persName id="OA17310514n47-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n47-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n47-1" type="surname" value="Bell"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n47-1" type="given" value="Edmond"/>Edmond Bell</persName>s Character, who was an Evidence for the Prisoner; (Sign'd by his Officers)</p>
            <p>WE whose Names are hereunto Subscribed, do Certifie, That we have known some Years <persName id="OA17310514n48-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n48-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n48-2" type="surname" value="Bell"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n48-2" type="given" value="Edmond"/>Edmond Bell</persName>, now a Corporal in Lieutenant Col. <persName id="OA17310514n48-3">
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n48-3" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n48-3" type="surname" value="Wingfield"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n48-3" type="given" value="Henry"/>Henry Wingfield</persName>s Company in his Majesty's First Regiment of FootGuards, Commanded by the Right Hon. <persName id="OA17310514n48-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n48-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n48-1" type="surname" value="WILLS"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n48-1" type="given" value="CHARLES"/>Sir Charles Wills</persName>, and that we have always found him to be a Person of Integrity and Honesty; and that we do believe he wou'd not Swear or Depose any thing but the Truth, upon any Account whatsoever.</p>
            <p>As Witness our Hands this 6th, day of May, 1731.</p>
            <p>H. Wingfield, Col.</p>
            <p>M. Rawlins, Capt.</p>
            <p>R. Walter, Ensign &amp; Adjutant.</p>
            <p>
               <persName id="OA17310514n53-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n53-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n53-1" type="surname" value="COOPER"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n53-1" type="given" value="RICHARD"/>Richard Cooper</persName>, of <placeName id="OA17310514-geo-16">
                  <interp inst="OA17310514-geo-16" type="type" value="parish"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17310514n53-1 OA17310514-geo-16"/>St. Catherine Creed-church</placeName>, was indicted for the Murder of <persName id="OA17310514n53-3">
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n53-3" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n53-3" type="surname" value="HARLE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n53-3" type="given" value="MARGARET"/>Margaret Harle</persName>, <persName id="OA17310514n53-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n53-2" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n53-2" type="surname" value="Hall"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n53-2" type="given" value="Margaret"/>alias Hall</persName>, by giving her one mortal Wound with a Pistol and leaden Bullet upon the right Part of the Bck, of the depth of five Inches, of which she instantly died, the 16th of April last.</p>
            <p>He was likewise indicted a 2d Time on the Coroners Inquest for the same.</p>
            <p>2. <persName id="OA17310514n55-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n55-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n55-1" type="surname" value="COOPER"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n55-1" type="given" value="RICHARD"/>Richard Cooper</persName>, 28 Years of Age, Born of honest Parents in the <placeName id="OA17310514-geo-17">
                  <interp inst="OA17310514-geo-17" type="type" value="street"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17310514n55-1 OA17310514-geo-17"/>Strand</placeName>, who gave him good Education at School, in Reading, Writing, casting Accompts, &amp;c. and instructed him in religious Principles. His Father, who was a Maker of Gold and Silver Lace, Died and left him Young; and when he was of Age, his Mother <rs id="OA17310514-occupation-4" type="occupation">put him to a Shoe-maker</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17310514n55-1 OA17310514-occupation-4"/>, and his Master dying in two or three Years, and he not liking that Employment, would not be turn'd over, but follow'd after that, (as he call'd it) publick Business in Taverns and Shops, by way of a <rs id="OA17310514-occupation-5" type="occupation">Servant</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17310514n55-1 OA17310514-occupation-5"/> or <rs id="OA17310514-occupation-6" type="occupation">Porter</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17310514n55-1 OA17310514-occupation-6"/>.</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA173105140012"/>
            <p>In this Station he <rs id="OA17310514-occupation-7" type="occupation">serv'd an Apothecary</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17310514n55-1 OA17310514-occupation-7"/> near <placeName id="OA17310514-geo-18">
                  <interp inst="OA17310514-geo-18" type="type" value="site"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17310514n55-1 OA17310514-geo-18"/>Covent-Garden</placeName> upwards of six Years; during which Time he was in Love with a young Woman, and was in Terms of Marriage with her: But after he had Spent all his Money in attending and treating her upon all Occasions, she gave him the Slip and married another young Man, with whom (as he observ'd) she liv'd but a miserable and comfortless Life.</p>
            <p>But this Disappointment prov'd still a greater Misfortune to him, for he being naturally inclin'd to Melancholy, and his Mother, who was left in pretty good Circumstances by his Father, having lost her Money by supporting a naughty Brother, who is gone beyond Seas, and an unlucky Sister, and he having advanc'd some Money upon their Account, he turn'd altogether discontented, and would not serve the Gentleman, who had been a very kind Master to him any longer, but came and engag'd in the Service of Mr. Day a Gentleman of the same Business in <placeName id="OA17310514-geo-19">
                  <interp inst="OA17310514-geo-19" type="type" value="street"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17310514n55-1 OA17310514-geo-19"/>Leaden-Hall-Street</placeName>, where he had the Misfortune to Murther the poor Girl <persName id="OA17310514n56-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n56-1" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n56-1" type="surname" value="Hall"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n56-1" type="given" value="Margaret"/>Margaret Hall</persName>, for which he died.</p>
            <p>At first he own'd that he kill'd the Maid, but said, it was only by Accident, by Reason of the Pistol being cock'd, and its going off as he took it out of his Pocket he knew not how; but before he died, he own'd that he did it purposely, and being ask'd Why? He said he knew no Reason, but the violent Temptation of the D-l. He denied that he had any premeditated Design, and that there ever was any Difference between them excepting some hasty Words, which may happen in any House, when Persons live together any considerable Time, as he liv'd with her seven Months. As to the cutting or hurting her Arm, he said it was only accidentally.</p>
            <p>His Master said, he lost two good Servants, he having been with him nine or ten, and she seven Months. He said, he was always very honest and obliging to his Masters, and that by Serving seven Years about. Apothecaries Shops, he had acquir'd some knowledge of the Business, could make up Drugs and understood Receipts. He had of a long Time thought upon doing away with himself, and some Years ago he threw himself into the Thames but was drag'd out alive; and some Time ago he bought a pocket Pistol for the same Purpose, and (as he said) he intended to shoot himself with it in the back Room, at the same Time he murdered the Maid, but his Master coming in interrupted him, and then he going to the Kitchen, he was tempted to Discharge it in the poor Maids Back, as she was throwing up Coals into the Fire, of which Wound she immediately died, only having gone some Steps into the Shop, she said, Richard had shot, kill'd or murther'd me.</p>
            <p>He was so indifferent about Life that he made no Application for save</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA173105140013"/>
            <p>ing it, as all of them commonly do. He said, there was no Reason for alledging that he Shot the Maid, because She would not allow off to great Familiarities, for he never intended, nor proposed any such Thing. He had been of a Peevish, Surly and melancholy Disposition; he spoke much and fast, and was of a Hasty passionate Temper; but was not Mad or out of his Senses as they represented him to have been. I represented to him the evil of Murder, especially, Self-murder, and desir'd him to Repent of those Sins particularly. He said he did so, and beg'd Grace of God to assist him. He was never much guilty of Cursing, Swearing, Drinking or Whoring, tho' not altogether free of those Vices. He had some good and virtuous Inclinations, and when he was not necessarily detain'd, he went to Church. He declar'd himself Penitent for all his Sins, that he hop'd for Salvation through the Merits of Jesus Christ his only Saviour, and that he died in Peace with all the World.</p>
            <p>
               <persName id="OA17310514n62-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n62-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n62-1" type="surname" value="BERRY"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n62-1" type="given" value="JAMES"/>James Berry</persName>, of <placeName id="OA17310514-geo-20">
                  <interp inst="OA17310514-geo-20" type="type" value="parish"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17310514n62-1 OA17310514-geo-20"/>St. Peter's-Poor</placeName>, was Indicted for Burglariously breaking the House of <persName id="OA17310514n62-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n62-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n62-2" type="surname" value="DE COSTA"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n62-2" type="given" value="JOHN MENDEZ"/>John Mendez de Costa</persName>, and feloniously taking 6 Silver Spoons value 40 Shillings, a Silver Tankard, value 7 l. the 29th of March last.</p>
            <p>3. <persName id="OA17310514n63-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n63-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n63-1" type="surname" value="BERRY"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n63-1" type="given" value="JAMES"/>James Berry</persName>, Sixty-five years of Age, born in <placeName id="OA17310514-geo-21">
                  <interp inst="OA17310514-geo-21" type="type" value="county"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17310514n63-1 OA17310514-geo-21"/>Lancashire</placeName> of honest Parents, who gave him Education at School according to their Ability, and had him instructed in religious Principles. They bred him to <rs id="OA17310514-occupation-8" type="occupation">House-painting</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17310514n63-1 OA17310514-occupation-8"/>, at which Trade he serv'd out his Time, and afterwards liv'd in a creditable, honest way; married a Wife, and had several Children, some of whom, both Sons and Daughters, are now married and following business in an honest way in the Country. He was a <rs id="OA17310514-occupation-9" type="occupation">Soldier</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17310514n63-1 OA17310514-occupation-9"/> in the Wars of <placeName id="OA17310514-geo-22">
                  <interp inst="OA17310514-geo-22" type="type" value="region"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17310514n63-1 OA17310514-geo-22"/>Flanders</placeName> seven Years, and serv'd there to the satisfaction of his Officers; and afterwards he <rs id="OA17310514-occupation-10" type="occupation">went to Sea</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17310514n63-1 OA17310514-occupation-10"/>, and was <rs id="OA17310514-occupation-11" type="occupation">Cook of a Ship</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17310514n63-1 OA17310514-occupation-11"/> two or three Years. In all the different Stations of Life he had been in (as he said) he behav'd himself well, and had still a good Character and Reputation. For a great many Years past he liv'd in or about <placeName id="OA17310514-geo-23">
                  <interp inst="OA17310514-geo-23" type="type" value="urban_centre"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17310514n63-1 OA17310514-geo-23"/>London</placeName>, and his late Wife Nurss'd a Son to Mr. De Costa whom he robb'd twenty Years ago, and liv'd after that for the most part in his House as a <rs id="OA17310514-occupation-12" type="occupation">Servant</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17310514n63-1 OA17310514-occupation-12"/>, and both he and she were very much oblig'd to that Family, for both of them had much of their Bread to eat. Him they employ'd to wash and Paint their House, and about other little Affairs, and her they kept as a Servant, so that he was very ungrateful in robbing his Benefactor. About a Year ago his Wife died, and in a very short Time, though he was pretty well advanc'd in Years, yet he ventur'd upon a second Wife; and not having to support her and keep up a Family, and his old Friend upon some Misbehaviour, having Discharg'd him his House, and he not being capable to Discharge some old Debts, his Creditors thought fit to take out an Exe</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA173105140014"/>
            <p>cution upon his Goods. The poor old Man could not tell what to do in this Extremity, but knowing perfectly the Situation of De Costa's House, without imparting his Mind to any Body whatsoever, he thought fit, by breaking softly with his Hand a Pane or Two of Glass, to open the KitchenWindows in the Night-time, and to take the Silver Tankard and six Silver Spoons, mention'd in the Indictment. He declar'd his Wife knew nothing of all this, but afterwards the Goods being once in their Possession, his Wife and he went in Company to Pawn the Plate, that they might have Money advanc'd to pay off a 4 l. Debt, for which he was then distress'd by the Landlord, who seiz'd his Goods. But the Pawn-Broker, and a Goldsmith employ'd to weigh the Plate finding them to be advertis'd, as stollen Goods from a certain Person, stopt them, and then Berry was taken up, imprison'd, convicted and Executed for the said Crime. He was always very Penitent while under Sentence, and behav'd with a deal of christian Submission, having never been guilty of any Dishonesty in his Life, as he said, excepting the Crime for which he died. He lov'd to keep the Church and follow'd a regular Life; only upon his Travels and the rambling Part of his Life, he had been sometimes Irregular, but not much as he told me. Two or three Days before he died, he was in a little Passion, but when I represented to him the unseasonableness of being so, he declar'd he was very Sorry and Penitent for it. He declar'd, that he firmly believ'd, that he should be Saved by the Mercy of God through Christ, that he sincerely Repented of all his Sins, in Evidence whereof he often shed Tears, and that, he forgave all injuries done him, as he expected forgiveness from God.</p>
            <p>
               <persName id="OA17310514n65-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n65-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n65-1" type="surname" value="NEWPORT"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n65-1" type="given" value="AMBROSE"/>Ambrose Newport</persName>, of <placeName id="OA17310514-geo-24">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17310514n65-1 OA17310514-geo-24"/>Thistleworth</placeName>, was Indicted for feloniously Stealing a black-brown Mare, value six Pound, the Property of <persName id="OA17310514n65-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n65-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n65-2" type="surname" value="CLINCH"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n65-2" type="given" value="CHARLES"/>Charles Clinch</persName>, the 26th Day of April last.</p>
            <p>4. <persName id="OA17310514n66-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n66-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n66-1" type="surname" value="NEWPORT"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n66-1" type="given" value="AMBROSE"/>Ambrose Newport</persName>, Twenty-one Years of Age, born in a Country Town in <placeName id="OA17310514-geo-25">
                  <interp inst="OA17310514-geo-25" type="type" value="county"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17310514n66-1 OA17310514-geo-25"/>Wiltshire</placeName>, of honest Parents, who educated him at School, so as to fit him for Business, suitable to their Station, and got him instructed in religious Principles.</p>
            <p>When of Age, his Father educated him to his own Business, which was that of a <rs id="OA17310514-occupation-13" type="occupation">Gardiner</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17310514n66-1 OA17310514-occupation-13"/>; this Trade he followed for some Time, but being soon weary of constant Employment, he betook himself to an idle Life, going about the Country, and keeping wicked Company, which in the End prov'd his Ruin.</p>
            <p>But all this, (as he said) happen'd after his Father's Death, who by his paternal Authority, kept him in some Order; but when his Parents were once dead, being left without any Restraint, he gave himself up to all</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA173105140015"/>
            <p>Manner of Wickedness, and could not be holden in, by any of his Relations or Acquaintances. His Brother's Admonitions, (who often told him, that he would certainly be hang'd,) were of no Manner of Effect, but he still continu'd an abandon'd Wretch, forsaking every Thing that's Good or Virtuous.</p>
            <p>He continu'd in this Course of Life, and refuss'd the Advice of all those who endeavour'd to Reclaim him.</p>
            <p>About Michaelmas last, he met with a Company of common Thieves, House-breakers, Highway-men, and Horse-stealers, who did his Business at once, and brought him to his fatal End.</p>
            <p>They advised him to engage in their Gang, and all gave him fair Promises, that he should never Want, while he had Success in their laudable Enterprizes. He being of a perverse Disposition, too readily concurr'd with them, and succeeded in the stealing of five or six Horses, till at length the unlucky Mare, for which he died, was his final Overthrow.</p>
            <p>He confess'd that he Stole the Mare, which he sold at <placeName id="OA17310514-geo-26">
                  <interp inst="OA17310514-geo-26" type="type" value="parish"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17310514n66-1 OA17310514-geo-26"/>Brentford</placeName>; and that his Sentence was just, according to Law, that he had Stollen several other Horses, and had been guilty of many other Crimes, such as Housebreaking, Highway, Robbing, Picking, Stealing, Whoring, Drinking to Excess, Swearing and Blaspheming, and that he knew no Kind of Sin he had not committed, excepting Murder, or some such atrocious Sins.</p>
            <p>He acknowledg'd that he suffer'd most justly, for his Contempt of God and Transgression of his Laws, and for his neglecting the good Admonitions of his Instructors and Well-wishers.</p>
            <p>He always behav'd very well, both in Publick and Private, and made regular Responses to the Prayers. He declar'd that he believ'd in Jesus Christ, repented of all his Sins, and died in Peace with all Mankind.</p>
            <p>
               <persName id="OA17310514n76-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n76-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n76-1" type="surname" value="TRAP"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n76-1" type="given" value="RICHARD"/>Richard Trap</persName>, alias Blue Dick, of <placeName id="OA17310514-geo-27">
                  <interp inst="OA17310514-geo-27" type="type" value="parish"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17310514n76-1 OA17310514-geo-27"/>Paddington</placeName>, was Indicted for assaulting <persName id="OA17310514n76-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n76-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n76-2" type="surname" value="MONK"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n76-2" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Monk</persName>, on the Highway, putting him in Fear, and taking from him two Cloth Coats, Value thirty Shillings, a Wastcoat, a Pair of Boots and Spurs, a Guinea, a half Guinea, and twelve Shillings in Money, the 19th of March last.</p>
            <p>5. <persName id="OA17310514n77-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n77-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n77-1" type="surname" value="TRAP"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n77-1" type="given" value="RICHARD"/>Richard Trap</persName>, about 26 Years of Age, of mean Parents in <placeName id="OA17310514-geo-28">
                  <interp inst="OA17310514-geo-28" type="type" value="county"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17310514n76-1 OA17310514-geo-28"/>Dorsetshire</placeName>, who gave him no Education at School, having a numerous Family of Children, for whom they could not provide.</p>
            <p>When of Age, he learn'd to be a <rs id="OA17310514-occupation-14" type="occupation">Bricklayer</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17310514n76-1 OA17310514-occupation-14"/>, and a <rs id="OA17310514-occupation-15" type="occupation">Pavier</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17310514n76-1 OA17310514-occupation-15"/>; and by following those Employments, he gain'd his Bread. Business not being very brisk in the Country at some Times, he us'd to came up to <placeName id="OA17310514-geo-29">
                  <interp inst="OA17310514-geo-29" type="type" value="urban_centre"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17310514n76-1 OA17310514-geo-29"/>London</placeName> about Harvest Time for some Years</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA173105140016"/>
            <p>past, and Wrought at Country Work, Brick-laying, or Paving of the Streets as he could be Employed.</p>
            <p>He fell in Love with, and lately Married a young Woman at <placeName id="OA17310514-geo-30">
                  <interp inst="OA17310514-geo-30" type="type" value="parish"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17310514n76-1 OA17310514-geo-30"/>Harrow on the Hill</placeName>, which occasion'd his coming oftner to, and staying longer in or about London than he intended.</p>
            <p>As for the Highway-Robbery Sworn against him, he said he knew nothing of it, and that Humphreys who swore himself an Accomplice, knew as little of it as he; but that he was induc'd to do it upon some other Motive. After all the Arguments could be us'd for an ingenious Confession; he still said, he did not do the Robbery, but that he was at Home all the Night it was committed, in Company with his Wife at Harrow on the Hill; and that Humphreys the Evidence was all that Night in the same House with them.</p>
            <p>He own'd, he had been a great Sinner in several Respects, but that he was never Guilty of Thieving or Robbery in his Life. Under his Misfortunes he behav'd very Decently and Christianly; and though he was no Scholar yet he was very attentive to Prayers and Exhortations, and appear'd to have some Sense of Religion upon his Spirits. He hop'd for Salvation through the Merits of Jesus Christ our Lord, Repented of all his Sins, and died in perfect Peace with all Mankind.</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA173105140017"/>
            <p>At the Place of EXECUTION.</p>
            <p>
               <persName id="OA17310514n84-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n84-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n84-1" type="surname" value="WOODMARSH"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n84-1" type="given" value="FRANCIS"/>FRancis Woodmarsh</persName> and <persName id="OA17310514n84-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n84-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n84-2" type="surname" value="COOPER"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n84-2" type="given" value="RICHARD"/>Richard Cooper</persName>, had another Divine, who came that Morning they died, and gave them the Sacrament privately in the Cells.</p>
            <p>Cooper came up to Prayers, but Woodmarsh staid below with some of his Friends. Under the Tree, he was in great Confusion and Disorder and a mighty Terrour of Death: He seem'd to be a little Stupid, and call'd aloud two or three Times in Time of Prayer, wanting to speak with Some-body. Some of his fellow Sufferers bid him be quiet. He was impatient to know when they would be turn'd off. He had no further Confessions, but insisted too much upon his Innocence, saying, he had no ill Intention, and knew nothing of any Body being Kill'd, that he only defended himself, &amp;c. When he had hung a little, he was stript naked to the Skin, (by the Executioner) a very undecent Spectacle; and likewise Berry was strip'd naked at the same Time by the Executioner, only leaving his Breeches on.</p>
            <p>Cooper had no more to say.</p>
            <p>
               <persName id="OA17310514n87-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n87-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n87-1" type="surname" value="TRAP"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n87-1" type="given" value="RICHARD"/>Richard Trap</persName> adher'd to his former Confessions, going to Death with a positive Denial of the Fact he died for, or that he was ever guilty either of Theft or Robbery in his Life.</p>
            <p>Newport said he was griev'd for his most sinful and wicked Life, but that he hop'd God out of his infinite Mercy would Pardon him.</p>
            <p>
               <persName id="OA17310514n89-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n89-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n89-1" type="surname" value="BERRY"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n89-1" type="given" value="JAMES"/>James Berry</persName> earnestly desir'd hearty Prayers to be offer'd up to God for them. They were all serious at Prayers and Singing of Psalms, and ment off the Stage, crying to God, to have Mercy upon them, and the Lord Jesus would receive their Spirits. &amp;c.</p>
            <p>This is all the Account given by me,</p>
            <p>
               <persName id="OA17310514n91-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n91-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n91-1" type="surname" value="GUTHRIE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n91-1" type="given" value="JAMES"/>JAMES GUTHRIE</persName>,</p>
            <p>Ordinary of Newgate.</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA173105140018"/>
            <p>ADVERTISEMENTS.</p>
            <p>Just publish'd,</p>
            <p>A Rational and Useful ACCOUNT of the VENERAL DISEASE: with Observations on the Nature, Symptoms, and Cure, and the bad Consequences that attend by ill Management; with proper Admonitions; recommended as a Friendly Instruction to all Persons who do, or may, labour under this Misfortune.</p>
            <p>ALSO</p>
            <p>A short Enquiry into Old GLEETS, and other Weaknesses; whether from Veneral Embraces, Self Pollution, or Natural Imbecillity, and the Reason why they are so seldom cur'd: With the Author's Method of Cure.</p>
            <p>To which is added,</p>
            <p>Some Hints of the Practical Scheme, the Methods and and Medicines therein expos'd, and the gross Impositions justly detected. With an Account of Specificks, the Use and Abuse of the Name, and how it covers Ignorance and a Cheat.</p>
            <p>The Eighth Edition, corrected, with Additons.</p>
            <p>
               <persName id="OA17310514n101-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n101-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n101-1" type="surname" value="CAM"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17310514n101-1" type="given" value="JOSEPH"/>By JOSEPH CAM</persName>, M. D.</p>
            <p>Evasti? credo metues, doctusque cavebis.</p>
            <p>Quares quando it erum paveas, iterumque perire</p>
            <p>Possis  toties servus! Horat.</p>
            <p>Principiis obsta. Ovid.</p>
            <p>LONDON: Printed for the Author, and Sold at his House in Bow Church Yard in Cheapside; and by E. Midwinter, in St. Paul's-Church-Yard, Price stitch'd, one Shilling.</p>
            <p>Soap sold by Retale.</p>
            <p>THE best Cuttings at Four-Pence</p>
            <p>Half Penny a Pound; and very good Green Soap, at Four Pence a Pound; which is very sweet, will wash as well, and go as far as the best Crown Soap, and is a Penny a Pound cheaper, by William Cowpland, Soap Maker at the 3 Pidgeons and Crown in the Old Bailey, near Ludgate Hill. He also Makes and Sells, fine hard Soap, white Barrel Soap, and all his other sorts of Soap Wholesale as well as Retale, for Ready Money, at the very lowest Prices, even tho' a Child be sent for them.</p>
            <p>He likewise makes and sells, his admirable new invented Liquid Soap, at one shilling a Pint, which is as clear as Canary, and smells more pleasant than any Perfume, it being the only Soap yet known for washing the finest Laces, Muslins, Cambricks, Silks, Callicoes, &amp;c. even in cold Water as well as hot, and is highly esteemed by most of the best Quality in England, for washing and beautifying the Hands and Face, as also by Gentlemen for shaving. Only to be had as above directed of William Cowpland, who having petitioned his Majesty to grant him his Royal Letters Patents for the sole making thereof, hath obtained the Honourable Attorney General's Report in his Favour.</p>
            <p>THE ROYAL COSMETICK;</p>
            <p>To beautify and cleanse the Face, Neck, and Hands, and to preserve the Complection of Ladies and Others: Devised by several learned Physicians, and used by Queens; Princesses, and other Ladies of Quality, in Italy, Germany, France, and England.</p>
            <p>WHich, for its excellent Virtues, exceeds all others, and beautifies the Face, Neck, and Hands, to the utmost Perfection, giving a charming Lustre and fine Air to the Features, rendering the Face delicately fair, plump, and smooth, though before ever so ordinary; instantly causing a youthful Fairnes, to Admiration, making a Person look young though old; it makes rough and red Hands exceeding white and smooth, infallibly taking away Redness, Wrinkles, Pimples, Spots, Worms, Morphews, Sun-Burns, Heats, or any other Discolourings of the Skin. It nourishes, plumps, smooths, clears and softens the Skin to the last Degree. It likewise heals Chops of the Lips, Hands, and Arms to Admiration.</p>
            <p>The Use of it is so clean, and it hath so pleasant a Flavour, that nothing can exceed it; and is therefore a most excellent Thing to preserve or regain a fine Skin and Complection.</p>
            <p>Prepared and Sold by the Author, a Chymist, at his House, the second Door on the Right Hand in Bride-lane, near Fleetstreet; 'tis also Sold at Robotham's Toy-shop without Whitechappel Bars; at Mr. Neal's Toy-shop opposite the Whiteheart Inn in the Borough of South- ark; and at Mr. Greg's, Bookseller, next Northumber-land-house, Charing cross.</p>
            <p>Price 3 s. 6 d. a Bottle.</p>
            <p>Where is also Sold,</p>
            <p>FOR a certain CURE of the SCURVEY, and all SCORBUTICK HUMOURS, is recommended the Tincture Magnum, Anti-Scorbuticum: Or, The Grand Anti-Scorbutick Purging-Tincture of Scurvy Grass; prepared after a new compendious Method, whereby is, made much more beneficial in purging the Blood of all salt brinish, and watery Humours, thn any Preparation heretofore prepared of that Sovereign Herb; to be taken any Time of the Year, but more especially Spring and Fall.</p>
            <p>At One Shilling a Battle.</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA173105140019"/>
            <p>An ADDRESS to the GENTLEMEN, By Dr. GREGORIUS, (Noted for his Skill in Surgery and Anatomy, as well as Physick and Chymistry.)</p>
            <p>Who having observ'd the frequent Advertisements in the News Papers, of one and another Single Medicine, said to cure all Sorts of Gleets, and Seminal Weaknesses, which their Authors confound together, as if there were no Difference between them, has been prevail'd upon, by his Friends, in this Publick Manner, to inform, and undeceive those who have unwarily been brought into either, (or both together, as it sometimes happens) of these perplexing, draining Imbecilities.</p>
            <p>That where the Gleeting is only from a Laxity of the Glands in the Urethra, what leaks and drills away insensibly from them, through the Urinary Passage, and spots or smears the Linnen, though it be yellowish, yet being without Pain, or any ill-condition'd Disorder, is no more than Mucus, and must be cured one Way.</p>
            <p>And where it is a Seminal Weakness, that which slips away involuntarily, though it be thin, watery, and unelaborate, either by itself, in the Day-time, or a Nights too frequently, or profusely in the Sleep, or with the Upine, or upon Stool, whether from an Acrimony, or Deravity of the Juices, or by over straining the Spermatick Vessels, or both, is Seed, and is to be remedied another, inasmuch, as that Medicine which will cure the one, will not cure the other, and (vice versa) as every Practitioner that knows the Nature, Make, and different Situation of the Parts ministring to Generation, will allow; and that for want of this due Distinction, and right Application, it is, that so many People are disappointed of Cure; and by Continuance of the Gleetings are drain'd, as they are, into Impotencies, or Infertili, ties, which as it hinders their Marrying, gives them great Anxiety, and the more, when attended, as in some, with Pain and Weakness in the Back and Reins; or as, in others, with Difficulty, or Dribblings of the Urine in, or after making it, which at Length comes away either foul, sharp, slimy, or of an ill Smell.</p>
            <p>As this is so in Fact, and the Doctor well known to have experienc'd, in numberless Instances, the noble and neverfailing Effects of Two particular Balsamick Electuaries, which he spared no Pains or Expence to find out, the one to restrain the Mucus, and the other, the involuntary shedding of the Seed, by their respectively bracing up the Fibres, and restoring the Tone and Springiness of the relaxed Glands and Seminals, invigorating the Genitals, and fertilizing the Seed, was also perswaded to recommend their Use, that those, who, for a long while together, had tried other Medicines for the same Weaknesses, and by their not succeeding, concluded themselves incurable, might be convinc'd by their speedy Amendment and Recovery by these, that it was not the Incurability of their Malady, but the wrong Method they had been in for Cure,</p>
            <p>But yet, in either of the said Two Weaknesss, or where it happens that they are complicated, and have proceeded, either from Self-Abuses, excessive, or over straining Coitions, or from over Purgations in Venereal Cures, or any other Cause, as a Flux of Humours generally falls down and settles upon all weakened Parts, rendering them still the weaker, and these tender nervous Parts more especially: The first Step to be taken in order to make way for a regular and substantial Cure, (and without which it is not to be accomplished) must, in a pecular Manner, be to correct, and gently divert those Humours; and the only Medicine he could ever rely upon to do this effectually, that is to overcome the Cause, and introduce the Cure of the most difficult of these Weakness, (even where the Vessels had been obstructed, Manhood greatly enfeebl'd, and in some, well nigh extinct, or at least not able to touch a Woman, but ad primum labiorum contactum, semen emittunt;) has been his Preparing Pills, of which when the Patient has taken only three Doses, at due Distances he is to begin (and not before) with one or t'other (or both together, as the Case may chance to be) of the said Two Electuaries, which how to distinguish in, and how to proceed with, the printed Directions, wrap'd up with the Pills, do so plainly shew, that no Persons, even of the meanest Capacities, can be any Loss to understand them; but will, by their observing the easy Rules therein laid down, have their Blood and whole Body, well cleans'd and purified, the debilated Parts strengthened, and by Degrees, compleatly, and lastingly invigorated and restored, so as to be enabled quickly, and safely to Marry, without the least Need of any further, or other Advice or Medicine.</p>
            <p>They are to be had, Price 7 s. 6 d. the Box, sealed up-ready to be deliver'd to any Messenger, upon only asking for, A Box of Pills, at Mr. Payne's, a Bookseller, at the Crown, facing the Chapter Coffee-house, in PaternosterRow.</p>
            <p>Note, The said Two Electuaries, viz, Numb, 1, for Gleets, and Numb. 2, for Seminal and Genital Weaknesses, are to be had there also, Price 7 s. 6 d. each Pot, and are likewise sealed up, and to be asked for by Electuary Number 1, or Electuary Number 2.</p>
         </div0>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>