<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<TEI.2>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div0 type="ordinarysAccount" id="OA17200815">
            <interp inst="OA17200815" type="uri" value="ordinarysAccounts/OA17200815"/>
            <interp inst="OA17200815" type="date" value="17200815"/>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA172008150001"/>
            <p>THE Ordinary of NEWGATE HIS ACCOUNT OF The Behaviours, Confessions, and Last Dying Words of the Malefactors that were Executed at Tyburn on Monday the 15th of August, 1720.</p>
            <p>THE Sunday preceeding the Execution of the Prisoners, I preached to them from the following Words.</p>
            <p>Bloody and Deceitful Men shall not live out half their Days. (Psalm 55th, part of the 23d Verse.)</p>
            <p>We first observed that the Psalmist every where speaks of Murder with conscious Sense of Shame; The Prophet Nathan's Parable had pierced his Bosom, and cut deep into his Heart. Well knew he, that Uriah was the poor Man with an only Lamb, that was tender to him, and lay every Night in his Bosom: His Conscience started at his Guilt; and the prospect of Love that was pleasing late, is shocking now: The Beautiful Bathsheba, and the Blood-stain'd Uriah rise up at once to his View; and in the bitterness of Soul he cries out, Deliver Me from Bloodguiltiness O God, Thou God of my Salvation! (ver. 14.)</p>
            <p>But deep and hearty was David's Repentance; and for every Pleasure he paid a thousand Tears. Therefore, notwithstanding his Guilt, he hopes God will save him from his Enemies. That Confidence as he often expresses, so particularly in my Text, Thou, O God, shalt bring them down into the Pit of Destruction; Bloody and Deceitful Men shall not live out half their Days.</p>
            <p>From the Words we observed the following Things.</p>
            <p>First, We consider'd the Nature of Bloodguiltiness: According to, 1st, the Natural; 2d, the Jewish; 3d, the Christian Law.</p>
            <p>Secondly, We consider'd Who were meant by Deceitful Men.</p>
            <p>Thirdly, Very briefly advis'd all to a serious Reflection on the Doctrine; because, Bloody and Deceitful Men do not live out half their Days.</p>
            <p>First, We consider'd Bloodguiltiness according to the Law of Nature.</p>
            <p>This is a tacit Law, engraven on the Heart, that plainly exclaims against Murder. For 'tis not agreeable to Natural Reason to suppose that I and another Rational Creature, being both of Us the Right and</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA172008150002"/>
            <p>Property of some Superiour Being that caused us to be, can have a Right to rob that superior Being of that his other Creature by Murder. That other Creature also has a Natural Right lodg'd in him, by the Creator, to enjoy the Light of the Sun; to sleep, and feed, and whatever else the Creator has thought fit to make him capable of enjoying. As therefore, I did not give him this Capacity of Enjoyment, 'tis plain, I can have no Right to take it from him; Unless indeed where I have a particular Commission from God to do it; which is the Case of the Brutes we devour.</p>
            <p>This is according to the Light of Nature: And even the Heathens of Popayan and Paraguay, Tho' they used to fat up their Captive Foes, to feast upon their Flesh, yet had so much Glimmering of the Dictates of Reason, as to detest, and severely Punish the Murder of their own People; Looking upon no Crimes as Capital but Incest and Murder; But to show their Abhorrence of Them, The Prince with a Dart pursued the Offender and with his own Hands destroyed him.</p>
            <p>2d, We consider'd Bloodguiltiness according to the Mosaic Law.</p>
            <p>This Law, agreeable to that of Nature, is very express against Murder. Whosoe sheddeth Man's Blood, by Man shall his Blood be shed.</p>
            <p>UNDER this Head, I took Notice of what I have sometimes thought remarkable, viz. That the very Giver of this Law, Moses, should slay a Man, without any Accusation laid against him. This a Hebrew, who had heard of it, thought a Crime; and accusingly said, Intendest thou to kill Me as thou didst the Egyptian Yesterday? It also made a great Noise in the Land, so that Pharoah was acquainted with it: But Moses fled from the Face of Pharoah, and dwelt in the Land of Midian. (Exod. 2. 15.) The Manner of his Slaying Him, was thus; And he spy'd an Egyptian smiting an Hebrew, one of his Brethren. And he looked this way and that way, and when he saw that there was no Man, he slew the Egyptian, and hid him in the Sand. (Exod. 2. 11, 12.)</p>
            <p>The usual way of Answering this Difficulty, is, either by supposing it a wicked Action, tho' not noted as such in Scripture; Or else, by saying, that Moses had a particular Commission from God to perform this Murder. But certainly that would be an Omission in the Sacred Writ (which far be it from any one to conceive) to leave out such a material Information; because the Murder is committed by a Person who is represented to Us as the Reverse of such a Doer. All Evil-Actions mention'd in Scripture, are mention'd for a Good End; and serve either to deter Us from the same Sins, by the Punishment annex'd to them; Or, to prevent our Despair, by the Sight of God's Forgiveness: But it can serve to neither, of these Ends, to show Us a Virtuous Man Sinning, without noting him as disagreeing from himself.</p>
            <p>THIS Answer therefore, seems to Me not to come up to the Difficulty. I would rather, with Submission, answer it thus. We must suppose it to be a Lawful Action; and who can assert the Con</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA172008150003"/>
            <p>trary; unless he knew the Nature of the Skirmish between the Egyptian and the Hebrew? For it might be a justifiable Murder, if we suppose the Egyptian to be so beating the Hebrew, as resolving to have his Life; and to be so violent and furious therein, as that the Interposer Moses could not save the Life of the Servant of God, but by taking away That of the Barbarian; I think, with Submission, in that Case, it might be lawful for Moses to do it. The Egyptian was in the nature of an Assaulter, or Robber; and Grotius with the other Ethick Writers, determine, that I and my Friend may defend my own Life at the Expence of a Robber's Blood. And this especially before the Christian Dispensation.</p>
            <p>To this it may be objected, that Moses need not have looked this Way and that Way, to see if any was near, had he had this Cause for slaying the Egyptian. To this I answer, that tho' this justified the Action in the sight of God, yet Moses knew it would not in the Eyes of Pharoah; who, we may suppose, had rather ten Hebrews should dye, than one Egyptian; As appears from his ordering all the Male Hebrew Children to be slain, only lest the Hebrews should grow too strong.</p>
            <p>To confirm this Explication, we may observe, that the rescued Hebrew would not, in all probability, have discover'd his Brother and Deliverer, unless he had conceiv'd an Opinion (without thinking so far as Pharoah's Partiality towards the Hebrews) that it was not a Criminal Action, on Account of the Murderous Intent of the Egyptian: And He must be the Discoverer, because we read, There was no one present. (ver. 12.)</p>
            <p>2dly, The Christian-Law is much more express against Bloodguiltiness, than either the Natural or the Jewish; insomuch, that, Whosoe hateth his Brother is a Murderer. And agen, Whosoe sayeth to his Brother, Thou Fool, is in Danger of Hell-Fire. So far must Christians be from Murder, that Christ says, Resist not Evil; but whosoever smiteth thee on one Cheek, turn to him the Other also. (Mat. 5. 39.) Contrary to the Jewish Law, which said, An Eye for an Eye, and a Tooth for a Tooth.</p>
            <p>Secondly, Under the Second general Head we consider'd, who are meant by Deceitful Men, - Bloody, and Deceitful Men.</p>
            <p>1st.) By Deceitful Men, may be meant False-Friends. This certainly is very sinful. 'Tis also imprudent, We should well consider before we take a Friend to our Bosom; and better consider before we throw him thence agen.</p>
            <p>2dly.) By Deceitful Men, may be meant Thieves. As the Psalmist says, He sitteth lurking in the thievish Corners of the Streets. Psal. 10. 8.</p>
            <p>It is become usual for Us to see Robbings in the publick Streets; How different are you from the Example of our Saviour; He went about Doing Good, But you Doing Ill: He preach'd Peace thro' the Streets, But you denounce Slaughter and Rapine. Little then would one think, ye had renounced the World at your Baptism, and profest your selves Followers, Pupils, Imitators of Christ.</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA172008150004"/>
            <p>Some in your Conditions have seem'd to value themselves upon their bearing their Misfortunes as becomes Men: But can ye take a sort of Pride in dying Couragiously like a Man, and not be ashamed of having liv'd like Brutes? Was their not something Mean and Base (for that ye will most regard) in inhabiting the Night, and flying the Face of Day, which Man was form'd with an Aspect erect to gaze at? The Apostle says, We are not of the Night, but of the Day; and let us who are of the Day be Sober; putting on the Breast-plate of Faith and Love, and for an Helmet, the Hope of Salvation. 1 Thess. 5. 8.</p>
            <p>3dly.) By Deceitful Men may be meant Defamers and Backbiters. This is a Deceit, perhaps as pernicious as the Thief's, tho' not equally liable to Punishment: The Robber despoils Us of our Goods, the Defamer, of our Reputations; One injures Us Clandestinely, The other to our Face. But Christ said, Let him who is without Sin among you, first throw a Stone at Her.</p>
            <p>Thirdly. The Third General Head was, to perswade All to the Consideration of the Doctrine, for the Reason in the Text, Bloody and Deceitful Men shall not live out half their Days.</p>
            <p>Under this Head we consider'd the Misery of being cut off in the Pride and Prime of Youth, while the Face of Nature was delightful, and joyous the Light of the Sun: And that this Misery was but the Natural Consequence of Sin, especially of Bloodguiltiness, agreeable to the Text.</p>
            <p>I lastly conjured them, to compensate for their former evil Lives, by the uncommon Earnestness of their Repentance; Never to leave Assaulting the Throne of Grace, till they had some dawning Assurances of Salvation; But so to expend their few remaining Hours, that they might launch forth from Sorrow to Joy; from Pain to Satisfaction; and from a World of Care into Realms of never fading Pleasures.</p>
            <p>1. <persName id="OA17200815n33-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17200815n33-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17200815n33-1" type="surname" value="COMKINS"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17200815n33-1" type="given" value="MATTHEW"/>Matthew Comkins</persName>, was Convicted of robbing <persName id="OA17200815n33-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17200815n33-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17200815n33-2" type="surname" value="WICKERS"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17200815n33-2" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Wickers</persName>, on the High-way, of 4 Guineas and 16 s. 6 d.</p>
            <p>The Account he gave me of himself was as follows.</p>
            <p>He said he was 22 Years of Age; a single Man; born at <placeName id="OA17200815-geo-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17200815-geo-1" type="type" value="urban_centre"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA17200815n33-1 OA17200815-geo-1"/>Tunbridge</placeName>, where he has now a Father and Mother residing in good Credit and Reputation. He said, they brought him up with the utmost Tenderness, and gave him a considerable share of Learning. He never was Apprentice to any Trade; but was in <rs id="OA17200815-occupation-1" type="occupation">Quality of a Book-keeper for some time, at a great China Shop</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17200815n33-1 OA17200815-occupation-1"/> in <placeName id="OA17200815-geo-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17200815-geo-2" type="type" value="urban_centre"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA17200815n33-1 OA17200815-geo-2"/>London</placeName>, where nothing was objected against his Behaviour.</p>
            <p>He said, he was lately Master of about 400 l. That he then gave himself up too much to Pleasure: He was often advis'd by his Friends to purchase a Place for Life, but never was so happy as to follow their good Counsel; He added, that he liv'd in a very jovial Manner, upon the principal Money, pursuing his Pleasures, and denying himself nothing that might tend to the Gratifying his Inclinations.</p>
            <p>Upon a Day (as he told me) he took a Ride to <placeName id="OA17200815-geo-3">
                  <interp inst="OA17200815-geo-3" type="type" value="county"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA17200815n33-1 OA17200815-geo-3"/>
                  <placeName id="OA17200815-geo-4">
                     <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA17200815n33-1 OA17200815-geo-4"/>Ware</placeName> in Hartfordshire</placeName>, alone by himself; but he there got into some Company,</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA172008150005"/>
            <p>they proposed a Game at Cards, which they said they did not well Understand, 'twas a new Game, but they were told 'twas very Diverting. Mr. Tompkins soon undertook to play with them. When he had lost all his Money, he call'd for his Horse, in order to return to London.</p>
            <p>Upon the Road, he said, he met a Man, of a sober Aspect; whose Occupation he should little have suspected from his Appearance. With this Person he fell into Discourse, and was complaining of the Tricks and Deceits of Cards, and related how he had been served at <placeName id="OA17200815-geo-5">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA17200815n33-1 OA17200815-geo-5"/>Ware</placeName>, where he had been bubbled out of all his Money. The Stranger told him, he need not be necessitated for Money, so long as he was upon an open Road; and in short, gave him a Pistol. The next Gentleman they met, they rob'd of four Guineas and some Silver, half of which he had; and parting with his Instructor at <placeName id="OA17200815-geo-6">
                  <interp inst="OA17200815-geo-6" type="type" value="urban_centre"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA17200815n33-1 OA17200815-geo-6"/>London</placeName>, never saw him after.</p>
            <p>This is the Account he gave me of his committing this wicked Action. He also told me, That he had let his Parents know his Misfortunes he was under, but had, at the same time requested of them, not to come to London on that Account, for it was not in their Power to be any way Serviceable to him in that Condition; but that the Sight of them, who had always used him with so great Tenderness and Affection, would greatly aggravate and encrease his Sorrow.</p>
            <p>He shou'd me a Book, which a Clergyman sent him, which he said had been the occasion of his passing the sad and Melancholly Hours of Confinement, not only with Patience but with some Satisfaction and Delight.</p>
            <p>The Saturday before his Execution, He told me he had then entirely laid aside all Thoughts of the World, and that the Sight of his Acquaintance was become Painful to him; for he had in some measure habituated Himself to think of Heaven, till it was become Grateful to him in the Consideration.</p>
            <p>2. <persName id="OA17200815n43-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17200815n43-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17200815n43-1" type="surname" value="LAZENBY"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17200815n43-1" type="given" value="DAVID"/>David Lazenby</persName>, was Convicted of breaking open the Chambers of <persName id="OA17200815n43-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17200815n43-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17200815n43-2" type="surname" value="WOOD"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17200815n43-2" type="given" value="CHARLES"/>Charles Wood</persName>, <rs id="OA17200815-occupation-2" type="occupation">Esq</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17200815n43-2 OA17200815-occupation-2"/>; in the Night-time, and stealing thence, some Holland Shirts, Cravats, a Beaver Hat, Sheets, a Cloath Coat and Wast-coat, Worsted Stockings, &amp;c. The Account he gave me of himself was as follows.</p>
            <p>He said, He was 26 Years of Age; Born at <placeName id="OA17200815-geo-7">
                  <interp inst="OA17200815-geo-7" type="type" value="county"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA17200815n43-1 OA17200815-geo-7"/>
                  <placeName id="OA17200815-geo-8">
                     <interp inst="OA17200815-geo-8" type="type" value="parish"/>
                     <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA17200815n43-1 OA17200815-geo-8"/>Market-Weston</placeName> in Suffolk</placeName>, of honest and reputable Parents. He was put <rs id="OA17200815-occupation-3" type="occupation">Prentice to a Weaver</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17200815n43-1 OA17200815-occupation-3"/>; to which Trade he served his 7 Years out. But this Employment not being sufficient to maintain him, he said, he went into the Country; Being there at a loss how to employ his time, and procure a comfortable Subsistance, he at last determin'd to <rs id="OA17200815-occupation-4" type="occupation">set up a Publick House</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17200815n43-1 OA17200815-occupation-4"/>, which he accordingly did; but soon growing weary of that noisy and quarrelsome Life, he returned again to <placeName id="OA17200815-geo-9">
                  <interp inst="OA17200815-geo-9" type="type" value="urban_centre"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA17200815n43-1 OA17200815-geo-9"/>London</placeName>, where he met with tolerable Encouragement in his own Trade.</p>
            <p>He said, that at the Time he was Apprehended on Suspicion, he liv'd at <placeName id="OA17200815-geo-10">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17200815n43-1 OA17200815-geo-10"/>Hoxton</placeName>, where he Employ'd 5 Journeymen under him at the <rs id="OA17200815-occupation-5" type="occupation">Weaving Business</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17200815n43-1 OA17200815-occupation-5"/>.</p>
            <p>He told me, that during my Sickness, a Great Distiller in Fore-street had desired to speak with me concerning him; that I would put the Question to him, whether he was not concern'd in robbing his Dining-Room, of several peices of Plate, some marked with his Coat of Arms, and some Plain. When the Prisoner had told me this, I accordingly taxed him, as he was a Dying Man, and had I hoped a value for his Soul, whether he knew any thing of the aforesaid Robbery? But he solemnly protested that he was entirely ignorant of it.</p>
            <p>Another Gentleman also in Hoxton-Square, apply'd to me, to desire I would put the Question to him, whither he was not concern'd in the Breaking open his House; he having suspected him on Account of some Tickets for an Entertainment, dropt near his House, with <persName id="OA17200815n47-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17200815n47-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17200815n47-1" type="surname" value="Lazenby"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17200815n47-1" type="given" value="David"/>David Lazenby</persName>'s Name</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA172008150006"/>
            <p>thereto. But the Prisoner said, the Tickets were accidentally dropt by that House, and were for him and some Friends to make merry innocently together. I hope he was sincere in his Declarations.</p>
            <p>3. <persName id="OA17200815n49-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17200815n49-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17200815n49-1" type="surname" value="FITZGERALD"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17200815n49-1" type="given" value="MAURICE"/>Maurice Fitzgerald</persName>, was condemned for the Murder of a Watchman in the <placeName id="OA17200815-geo-11">
                  <interp inst="OA17200815-geo-11" type="type" value="street"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17200815n49-1 OA17200815-geo-11"/>Strand</placeName>.</p>
            <p>He was about 20 Years of Age; born in <placeName id="OA17200815-geo-12">
                  <interp inst="OA17200815-geo-12" type="type" value="region"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17200815n49-1 OA17200815-geo-12"/>Ireland</placeName>; his Education was Liberal and Genteel. As to his Behaviour during his Confinement, after the Sentence pass'd upon him, it was Sober and Grave; he constantly frequented the publick Service in the Chappel, where he appear'd not without Devotion and a sense of Religion, making the Responces very duely, and reading the Psalms alternately after me. Notwithstanding this, It has been thought that he did not dye in the Communion of the Church of England; But this I think he would not have dissembled, had it been so; for I put the Question to him, and he told me that he dyed a Member of the English Church. I frequently talk'd with him about the Nature of his former Course of Life, and his Stabbing a Man sometime ago with a Penknife; he seem'd to acknowledge that among all Courses of Life, the Sober and Serene Man bids the fairest for Happiness even here; and that no Satisfaction really consists in having the Spirits always in a Hurry and a Flutter, and in flying about from one House of Obscenity to another.</p>
            <p>The Account of them at the Place of Execution.</p>
            <p>
               <persName id="OA17200815n52-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17200815n52-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17200815n52-1" type="surname" value="FITZGERALD"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17200815n52-1" type="given" value="MAURICE"/>Maurice Fitzgerald</persName>. At the Tree he spoke to the People present; signifying that he had reason to accuse some Persons as to his being Executed, whom he Named. He then declared, that he dyed in Charity towards all Men; and desired the Spectators Prayers for his departing Soul; adding, that he was pleas'd and easy at his leaving Care and Anxiety. He then gave me a Letter for his Brother; and ask'd me if I had retain'd the Paper he gave me at the Sacrament. He had been Scandaliz'd for Living with a Lady in a vicious Manner, to wit, Mrs. Witworth; That Paper relates to this, and is as follows.</p>
            <p>SIR,</p>
            <p>I Beg you will satisfy the World, that I was lawfully Married to Mrs. Witfield, according to the Rights and Ceremonies of the Church of England, as I shall answer before the Great and Good God one Day, and to her. Witness my Hand, this 14th of August, 1720. M. Fitzgerald.</p>
            <p>
               <persName id="OA17200815n55-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17200815n55-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17200815n55-1" type="surname" value="LAZENBY"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17200815n55-1" type="given" value="DAVID"/>David Lazenby</persName>. At the Tree, he deliver'd me a Paper, which he desired I would by all means Publish; and was as follows.</p>
            <p>WHEN under Sentence of Death, one Mrs. Flowers came to me, concerning a Robbery, which one <persName id="OA17200815n56-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17200815n56-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17200815n56-1" type="surname" value="YOUNG"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17200815n56-1" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Young</persName> swore her into: Now, I <persName id="OA17200815n56-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17200815n56-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17200815n56-2" type="surname" value="LAZENBY"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17200815n56-2" type="given" value="DAVID"/>David Lazenby</persName> do solemnly declare upon the Holy Sacrament, which I take this 15th day of August, that the said Robbery (at the <placeName id="OA17200815-geo-13">
                  <interp inst="OA17200815-geo-13" type="type" value="parish"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17200815n56-3 n56-4 OA17200815-geo-13"/>
                  <placeName id="OA17200815-geo-14">
                     <interp inst="OA17200815-geo-14" type="type" value="site"/>
                     <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                           targets="OA17200815n56-3 n56-4 OA17200815-geo-14"/>Quaker's next Door to the Nagg's Head</placeName> in Islington</placeName>) was committed by two other Persons, whose Names are <persName id="OA17200815n56-3">
                  <interp inst="OA17200815n56-3" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17200815n56-3" type="surname" value="BRUSH"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17200815n56-3" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Brush</persName>, and <persName id="OA17200815n56-4">
                  <interp inst="OA17200815n56-4" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17200815n56-4" type="surname" value="SMITH"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17200815n56-4" type="given" value="JOSEPH"/>Joseph Smith</persName>. Neither was Mrs. Flowers any way concern'd in purchasing the Goods.</p>
            <p>
               <persName id="OA17200815n57-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17200815n57-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17200815n57-1" type="surname" value="PURNEY"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17200815n57-1" type="given" value="THO"/>THO. PURNEY</persName>, <rs id="OA17200815-occupation-6" type="occupation">Ordinary</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17200815n57-1 OA17200815-occupation-6"/> and <rs id="OA17200815-occupation-7" type="occupation">Chaplain</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17200815n57-1 OA17200815-occupation-7"/>.</p>
            <p>
               <placeName id="OA17200815-geo-15">
                  <interp inst="OA17200815-geo-15" type="type" value="urban_centre"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17200815n58-1 OA17200815-geo-15"/>LONDON</placeName>: Printed and Sold by <persName id="OA17200815n58-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17200815n58-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17200815n58-1" type="surname" value="APPLEBEE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17200815n58-1" type="given" value="JOHN"/>JOHN APPLEBEE</persName>, a little below <placeName id="OA17200815-geo-16">
                  <interp inst="OA17200815-geo-16" type="type" value="parish"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17200815n58-1 OA17200815-geo-16"/>
                  <placeName id="OA17200815-geo-17">
                     <interp inst="OA17200815-geo-17" type="type" value="site"/>
                     <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                           targets="OA17200815n58-1 OA17200815-geo-17"/>Bridewel-Bridge</placeName>, Black-Fryers</placeName>.</p>
         </div0>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>