<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<TEI.2>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div0 type="ordinarysAccount" id="OA17160919">
            <interp inst="OA17160919" type="uri" value="ordinarysAccounts/OA17160919"/>
            <interp inst="OA17160919" type="date" value="17160919"/>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA171609190001"/>
            <p>THE Ordinary of NEWGATE HIS ACCOUNT OF The Behaviour, Confessions, and Last Speeches of the Malefactors that were Executed at TYBURN, on Wednesday the 19th of September, 1716.</p>
            <p>AT the General Sessions held at Justice-Hall in the Old-Baily, on Thursday the 6th, Friday the 7th, Saturday the 8th, and Monday the 10th of September, 1716, Thirty-two Persons, viz. 20 Men, and 12 Women, who were Try'd for several Capital Crimes, being found guilty, did accordingly receive Sentence of Death together with another Person brought down to his former Judgment. But 17 of them (viz. 10 Women pregnant, and 7 Men) having obtain'd a Reprieve, (which I pray GOD give them Grace to improve to his Glory) Eleven of these Malefactors are now order'd, and the Five Rioters defer'd to another time, for their Execution.</p>
            <p>On the Lord's Day the 9th instant, I preaeh'd to them and others then present in the Chapel of Newgate, both in the Forenoon and Afternoon, upon Matt. 10. 7. being part of the Second Lesson for that Morning Service, and the Words these: And as ye go, Preach, saying, The Kingdom of Heaven is at hand.</p>
            <p>Which Words, together with their Context, I explain'd and illustrated by several parallel Places; shewing, that by this Text, The Kingdom of Heaven is at hand, (which Christ gave his Disciples to preach upon) is meant,</p>
            <p>I. That the Time was come when GOD had fulfill'd his Promise of the Messiah, the Laws of whose Kingdom, then going to be set up in the World, all Men were to submit to.</p>
            <p>II. That the whole Substance and Summary of those Laws was (as the Apostle declares, Acts 20. 21.) Repentance toward God, and Faith in our Lord Jesus Christ. And,</p>
            <p>III. ult. That this comprehended all that which they were to teach, for as much as on these Two, viz.</p>
            <p>1. Faith; and,</p>
            <p>2. Repentance,</p>
            <p>depended the whole Gospel, and our Salvation by it.</p>
            <p>Price 3 Halfpence.</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA171609190002"/>
            <p>Of these I treated largely, and concluded with proper Exhortations to the Persons that were then for Judgment.</p>
            <p>On the last Lord's Day, the 16th instant, I preach'd to them again, both in the Morning and Afternoon, and my Text then was, Exod. 20. 13. Thou shalt not kill.</p>
            <p>Which having first explain'd in general, and illustrated by several parallel Places in Scripture, I then proceeded to shew in particular,</p>
            <p>I. What is Murder in strictness of Speech, and what may more largely be comprehended under it.</p>
            <p>II. The Punishment to be inflicted upon the Murderer, (which is Death) and the Reason for it.</p>
            <p>III. ult. What he ought to do, who is guilty of this, or any other Crime, that he may avoid the Eternal Condemnation due to it.</p>
            <p>On these I enlarg'd, and concluded all with particular Admonitions to the Persons under Sentence of Death, whom I exhorted to Faith and Repentance; teaching them what those Graces were, and how to be obtain'd. These were the two great Points I chiefly discoursed them upon, as being most proper for me to instruct them in, and them to learn and practise.</p>
            <p>In my private Discourses with them, they gave me the following respective Accounts of themselves.</p>
            <p>1. <persName id="OA17160919n21-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n21-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n21-1" type="surname" value="GRIFFITH"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n21-1" type="given" value="RICHARD"/>Richard Griffith</persName>, condemn'd for the Murther by him committed on the Person of <persName id="OA17160919n21-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n21-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n21-2" type="surname" value="DAVIS"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n21-2" type="given" value="RICHARD"/>Richard Davis</persName>, his Fellow-<rs id="OA17160919-occupation-1" type="occupation">Servant</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17160919n21-1 n21-2 OA17160919-occupation-1"/>, on the 1st of February last. He said, he was 24 years of age, born at <placeName id="OA17160919-geo-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17160919-geo-1" type="type" value="county"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA17160919n21-1 OA17160919-geo-1"/>
                  <placeName id="OA17160919-geo-2">
                     <interp inst="OA17160919-geo-2" type="type" value="parish"/>
                     <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA17160919n21-1 OA17160919-geo-2"/>Hadley</placeName> in Middlesex</placeName>: That he was brought up to no Trade, but from his Youth a <rs id="OA17160919-occupation-2" type="occupation">Servant-man</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17160919n21-1 OA17160919-occupation-2"/>, and as such had liv'd with some Gentlemen, whom he serv'd very faithfully: That he had never indulg'd himself in any Vice, nor committed any Crime before this he now stood condemn'd for, which he own'd deserv'd Death, tho' he did it in a Passion, being (as he said) highly provok'd by the Deceased. He much lamented his woful Condition, which indeed was so much the more dismal, by how much he was unable to receive good Instruction, and joyn with me in Prayer, as being, all the time he lay under this Condemnation, extreamly ill of a malignant Fever, and under great Weakness of Body. I did what I could to raise in him a Sense of his enormous Crime, and to bring him into a State of Repentance, and I hope (by the Grace of God intervening) some Good was wrought upon him.</p>
            <p>2. <persName id="OA17160919n22-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n22-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n22-1" type="surname" value="EVANS"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n22-1" type="given" value="ROBERT"/>Robert Evans</persName>, indicted for several Burglaries and Robberies by him committed within these two months past, to all which he pleaded Guilty. He said, he was 25 years of age, born in the <placeName id="OA17160919-geo-3">
                  <interp inst="OA17160919-geo-3" type="type" value="urban_centre"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA17160919n22-1 OA17160919-geo-3"/>
                  <placeName id="OA17160919-geo-4">
                     <interp inst="OA17160919-geo-4" type="type" value="parish"/>
                     <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA17160919n22-1 OA17160919-geo-4"/>Parish of St. Margaret</placeName>, Westminster</placeName>: That he <rs id="OA17160919-occupation-3" type="occupation">serv'd two Years with a Perriwig-maker</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17160919n22-1 OA17160919-occupation-3"/>, and then went into the <rs id="OA17160919-occupation-4" type="occupation">Service</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17160919n22-1 OA17160919-occupation-4"/> of several Gentlemen: That about a</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA171609190003"/>
            <p>Twelvemonth since, he became acquainted with one <persName id="OA17160919n23-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n23-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n23-1" type="surname" value="MILLS"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n23-1" type="given" value="THOMAS"/>Thomas Mills</persName>, (the Evidence against him) who enticed him into wicked Practices: That those Facts for which he now stood condemn'd were committed by him in company with the said Mills and Leatherton. Upon my admonishing him to do Right (so far as he could) to the Persons he had wrong'd, by restoring to them their stolen Goods, or letting them know how they were dispos'd of, he said, That Mills sold 'em, and gave him what he thought fit for his Share, which was little enough; but now he found he had his full Reward, as he justly deserv'd.</p>
            <p>3. <persName id="OA17160919n24-3">
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n24-3" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n24-3" type="surname" value="Leatherton"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n24-3" type="given" value="James"/>James</persName> (falsly call'd <persName id="OA17160919n24-4">
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n24-4" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n24-4" type="surname" value="Leatherton"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n24-4" type="given" value="Jacob"/>Jacob) Leatherton</persName>, alias <persName id="OA17160919n24-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n24-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n24-1" type="surname" value="SMITH"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n24-1" type="given" value="THOMAS"/>Thomas Smith</persName>, condemn'd for the same Facts with <persName id="OA17160919n24-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n24-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n24-2" type="surname" value="EVANS"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n24-2" type="given" value="ROBERT"/>Robert Evans</persName>, to which he also pleaded Guilty. He said, he was 21 years of age, born in the <placeName id="OA17160919-geo-5">
                  <interp inst="OA17160919-geo-5" type="type" value="parish"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17160919n24-1 n24-3 n24-4 OA17160919-geo-5"/>Parish of St. Giles in the Fields</placeName>: That his Father, a <rs id="OA17160919-occupation-5" type="occupation">Distiller</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17160919n24-1 n24-3 n24-4 OA17160919-occupation-5"/>, (when alive, and since his Death his Mother) imploy'd him in that Business, which he carefully attended, till of late years happening to be acquainted with <persName id="OA17160919n24-5">
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n24-5" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n24-5" type="surname" value="Mills"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n24-5" type="given" value="Tho"/>Tho. Mills</persName>, (the Evidence against him) he was enticed by him to the commission of those Facts he now stood condemn'd for. Upon my putting him in mind that he had, before now, been under Sentence of Death, and obtain'd the Mercy of a Pardon, which I was sorry to see he had so ill improv'd, he own'd it, and said he heartily repented, and earnestly pray'd God, for Christ's sake, to forgive him both these, and all other his Sins; for he could make no Satisfaction for them.</p>
            <p>4. <persName id="OA17160919n25-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n25-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n25-2" type="surname" value="Devaral"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n25-2" type="given" value="William"/>William Devaral</persName>, condemn'd for breaking the House of Mrs. <persName id="OA17160919n25-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n25-1" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n25-1" type="surname" value="DAVIS"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n25-1" type="given" value="ELIZABETH"/>Elizabeth Davis</persName>, on the 24th of August last, between the Hours of 3 and 5 in the Morning, and taking thence a Porridge-pot, value 30 s. and several other things. He said, he was 33 years of age, born in the <placeName id="OA17160919-geo-6">
                  <interp inst="OA17160919-geo-6" type="type" value="parish"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA17160919n25-2 OA17160919-geo-6"/>Parish of St. Giles in the Fields</placeName>: That his Friends bound him to, and he serv'd an <rs id="OA17160919-occupation-6" type="occupation">Apprentiship of 7 Years with, a Glover</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17160919n25-2 OA17160919-occupation-6"/> in <placeName id="OA17160919-geo-7">
                  <interp inst="OA17160919-geo-7" type="type" value="parish"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA17160919n25-2 OA17160919-geo-7"/>St. Giles's Cripplegate</placeName>; and, That when his Time was out, he set up for himself in the Parish last mention'd, where he hired a House, and <rs id="OA17160919-occupation-7" type="occupation">wrought for the Shops</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17160919n25-2 OA17160919-occupation-7"/>, himself keeping none. He would not at first own his Guilt of the Fact he stood condemn'd for, but afterwards did, and said, He had long deserv'd the Death he was now to suffer, for he had been a great Offender, and GOD was just, in bringing him to this shameful End, who had (of late especially) liv'd a shameful Life, in abandoning himself to all manner of Leudness and Vice; and, unless God were merciful to him, he was lost for ever.</p>
            <p>5. <persName id="OA17160919n26-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n26-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n26-1" type="surname" value="JACKSON"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n26-1" type="given" value="THOMAS"/>Thomas Jackson</persName>, <persName id="OA17160919n26-4">
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n26-4" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n26-4" type="surname" value="Purchase"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n26-4" type="given" value="Thomas"/>alias Purchase</persName>, (which latter, he said, was his right Name) found guilty of two Indictments, viz. 1st, for breaking the House of Mr. <persName id="OA17160919n26-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n26-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n26-2" type="surname" value="BARREL"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n26-2" type="given" value="EDWARD"/>Edward Barrel</persName>, and stealing thence a Silver-Watch, 4 Gold Rings, and other things of a considerable value, on the 10th of March last: And, 2dly, for assaulting upon the King's Highway Mr. <persName id="OA17160919n26-3">
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n26-3" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n26-3" type="surname" value="JEFFERIES"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n26-3" type="given" value="ALEXANDER"/>Alexander Jefferies</persName>, and taking from him a Perriwig, on the 15th of August last. He said, he was 25 years of age, born in <placeName id="OA17160919-geo-8">
                  <interp inst="OA17160919-geo-8" type="type" value="urban_centre"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17160919n26-1 n26-4 OA17160919-geo-8"/>London</placeName>, a <rs id="OA17160919-occupation-8" type="occupation">Carpenter</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17160919n26-1 n26-4 OA17160919-occupation-8"/> by Trade, but had been of late Years <rs id="OA17160919-occupation-9" type="occupation">in the Sea-service</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17160919n26-1 n26-4 OA17160919-occupation-9"/>, on board several Men of War. I found him a very stubborn and obstinate Sinner, who pretended his Condition not to be altogether so bad as theirs whom</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA171609190004"/>
            <p>he look'd upon to be greater Offenders than himself; but at last own'd he was guilty of the Facts he stood condemn'd for, and also of many other wicked Actions, which he was unwilling to give any particular Account of.</p>
            <p>6. <persName id="OA17160919n28-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n28-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n28-1" type="surname" value="ALLEN"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n28-1" type="given" value="THOMAS"/>Thomas Allen</persName>, condemn'd for breaking the House of <persName id="OA17160919n28-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n28-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n28-2" type="surname" value="HALES"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n28-2" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Hales</persName>, <rs id="OA17160919-occupation-10" type="occupation">Esq</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17160919n28-2 OA17160919-occupation-10"/>; and taking thence 12 Silver hafted Knives, a dozen of Table-cloths, and other Goods, in all amounting to the value of 30 l. He said, he was 24 years of age, born at <placeName id="OA17160919-geo-9">
                  <interp inst="OA17160919-geo-9" type="type" value="county"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA17160919n28-1 OA17160919-geo-9"/>
                  <placeName id="OA17160919-geo-10">
                     <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                           targets="OA17160919n28-1 OA17160919-geo-10"/>Wiggesley</placeName> in Nottinghamshire</placeName>: That he was a <rs id="OA17160919-occupation-11" type="occupation">Ship Carpenter</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17160919n28-1 OA17160919-occupation-11"/> by Trade, and had wrought sometimes in <placeName id="OA17160919-geo-11">
                  <interp inst="OA17160919-geo-11" type="type" value="site"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17160919n28-1 OA17160919-geo-11"/>Deptford Yard</placeName>, at other times on board several Men of War, for these 12 years past. He confest, that about a Year ago he was burnt in the Hand for stealing a Boat upon the Thames: That he was guilty of the Fact he now stood condemn'd for, and of some others he had committed before, adding, That Sheppard (the Evidence against him) was the Person who enticed him into this wicked Course of Life; and, That within these 8 weeks past he had been concern'd with him in 7 or 8 Burglaries, of which an Account was given to the Persons injur'd, whose Pardon he begg'd, praying God to bless them, and have Mercy upon his Soul.</p>
            <p>7. <persName id="OA17160919n29-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n29-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n29-1" type="surname" value="SCOTT"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n29-1" type="given" value="RICHARD"/>Richard Scott</persName>, condemn'd for privately stealing 20 l. weight of Worsted out of the Shop of Mr. <persName id="OA17160919n29-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n29-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n29-2" type="surname" value="LOWEN"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n29-2" type="given" value="WILLIAM"/>William Lowen</persName>, on the 7th of July last. He said, he was 20 years of age, born in <placeName id="OA17160919-geo-12">
                  <interp inst="OA17160919-geo-12" type="type" value="urban_centre"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17160919n29-1 OA17160919-geo-12"/>
                  <placeName id="OA17160919-geo-13">
                     <interp inst="OA17160919-geo-13" type="type" value="street"/>
                     <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                           targets="OA17160919n29-1 OA17160919-geo-13"/>Thames-street</placeName>, London</placeName>: That he serv'd his <rs id="OA17160919-occupation-12" type="occupation">Apprentiship with his Father, a Narrow Ribbon-weaver</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17160919n29-1 OA17160919-occupation-12"/>, and when out of his Time, work'd with him as a <rs id="OA17160919-occupation-13" type="occupation">Journey-man</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17160919n29-1 OA17160919-occupation-13"/>. He wou'd fain have perswaded me that this was his first Fact, but he was forced to own, that he had been an old Offender before, and that he committed it even upon the Day he was discharg'd from New-Prison; which to palliate (as he thought) he said he was then in Drink. He acknowledg'd himself to have greatly offended GOD, in breaking the Sabbath, and keeping lewd and vicious Company, that brought him to his Ruin; for which, and all other Sins, he said, he was now heartily sorry, and repented.</p>
            <p>8. <persName id="OA17160919n30-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n30-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n30-1" type="surname" value="LLOYD"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n30-1" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Lloyd</persName> 
               <persName id="OA17160919n30-3">
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n30-3" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n30-3" type="surname" value="Bray"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n30-3" type="given" value="alias"/>alias Bray</persName>, (the former he said was his right Name) condemn'd for breaking open the House of Mr. <persName id="OA17160919n30-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n30-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n30-2" type="surname" value="ARMSTRONG"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n30-2" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Armstrong</persName>, and stealing thence 5 Perriwigs, and other Goods. He said, he was 17 years of age, born in the <placeName id="OA17160919-geo-14">
                  <interp inst="OA17160919-geo-14" type="type" value="parish"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17160919n30-1 n30-3 OA17160919-geo-14"/>Parish of St. Giles in the Fields</placeName>: That he was brought up to no other Business than that of helping his Mother, who <rs id="OA17160919-occupation-14" type="occupation">keeps the Market</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17160919n30-1 n30-3 OA17160919-occupation-14"/> in <placeName id="OA17160919-geo-15">
                  <interp inst="OA17160919-geo-15" type="type" value="site"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17160919n30-1 n30-3 OA17160919-geo-15"/>Covent-garden</placeName>. He confess'd the Fact he was condemn'd for; and, That he had also committed some others of the like nature, and was whipt but the last Sessions, for having pickt out of One's Pocket a Handkerchief of small value. He laid the Cause of his ill Facts (in a great measure) upon Mills, the Evidence against him: But, that himself was much inclin'd to Thieving, Stealing, &amp;c is what he readily own'd; yet seem'd at first very little sensible of the miserable Condition he was in by reason of his Sins, and gave no great marks of Repentance, but at last he express'd his Grief and Sorrow for having so much offended GOD, and thereby brought this Evil upon himself.</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA171609190005"/>
            <p>9. <persName id="OA17160919n31-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n31-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n31-1" type="surname" value="GREEN"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n31-1" type="given" value="THOMAS"/>Thomas Green</persName> alias <persName id="OA17160919n31-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n31-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n31-2" type="surname" value="WORRELL"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n31-2" type="given" value="RICHARD"/>Richard Worrell</persName>, which latter he said was his right Name. This Person was to have been Try'd this Sessions (as being arraign'd) for robbing Mr. <persName id="OA17160919n31-3">
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n31-3" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n31-3" type="surname" value="MILLINGTON"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n31-3" type="given" value="ISAAC"/>Isaac Millington</persName> on the King's Highway, in taking 5 Shirts from him, on the 3d of Aug. last; and for another Fact he had committed; but having receiv'd Sentence of Death before, Execution was now awarded against him for his former Crimes. He said, he was 16 years of age, born at <placeName id="OA17160919-geo-16">
                  <interp inst="OA17160919-geo-16" type="type" value="urban_centre"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17160919n31-1 n31-2 OA17160919-geo-16"/>Bedford</placeName>, and there brought up to School: That about 3 years ago (his Eather being dead) he came upto <placeName id="OA17160919-geo-17">
                  <interp inst="OA17160919-geo-17" type="type" value="urban_centre"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17160919n31-1 n31-2 OA17160919-geo-17"/>London</placeName> with his Mother, who took care of him while she was alive; but she dying a Twelvemonth after, a Relation of his (a <rs id="OA17160919-occupation-15" type="occupation">Brasier</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17160919n31-1 n31-2 OA17160919-occupation-15"/>) took him, and imploy'd him in his Business: That not liking that Trade, nor his said Relation, he would not be bound Apprentice to him, but went from him within less than two years, and got into ill Company, by whose means he improv'd in Idleness, and became very loose and wicked. He did not appear much concern'd at, nor in the least asham'd of, or sorry for, the Abuse he had made of former Mercy; neither did he seem to be at all sensible of his present Misery, or apprehensive of a future Judgment; he being so very ignorant, so foolish, and so stupified, as not to be affected or mov'd in the least with any thing that was offer'd to him, in order to bring him to Repentance, that he might be sav'd.</p>
            <p>10. <persName id="OA17160919n32-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n32-1" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n32-1" type="surname" value="WILLIAMS"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n32-1" type="given" value="MARY"/>Mary Williams</persName> 
               <persName id="OA17160919n32-3">
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n32-3" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n32-3" type="surname" value="Spencer"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n32-3" type="given" value="Mary"/>alias Spencer</persName>, condemn'd for privately stealing 70 yards of Stuffs out of the Shop of Mr. <persName id="OA17160919n32-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n32-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n32-2" type="surname" value="WOOD"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n32-2" type="given" value="THOMAS"/>Thomas Wood</persName>, on the 4th of June last. She said, she was above 50 years of age, born at <placeName id="OA17160919-geo-18">
                  <interp inst="OA17160919-geo-18" type="type" value="county"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17160919n32-1 n32-3 OA17160919-geo-18"/>
                  <placeName id="OA17160919-geo-19">
                     <interp inst="OA17160919-geo-19" type="type" value="urban_centre"/>
                     <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                           targets="OA17160919n32-1 n32-3 OA17160919-geo-19"/>Ludlow</placeName> in Shropshire</placeName>, and had liv'd these many years in <placeName id="OA17160919-geo-20">
                  <interp inst="OA17160919-geo-20" type="type" value="urban_centre"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17160919n32-1 n32-3 OA17160919-geo-20"/>London</placeName>, and <rs id="OA17160919-occupation-16" type="occupation">kept a Boiling-Cook-Shop</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17160919n32-1 n32-3 OA17160919-occupation-16"/> in <placeName id="OA17160919-geo-21">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17160919n32-1 n32-3 OA17160919-geo-21"/>Cow cross</placeName>. She would not own that she was guilty of the Fact she stood condemn'd for, nor that she had committed any other of the same nature of late years; but confess'd, That about nine years ago she receiv'd Sentence of Death at the Old-Baily, where she afterwards pleaded the late Queen's Pardon, and was sent to the Workhouse for two Years. She appear'd to be very ignorant, and could not so much as read, nor understand the very first Principles of the Christian Religion. When I told her, she had done a very ill thing in endeavouring with Money to corrupt the Women sworn to examin and make a true Report concerning her being or not being with Quick Child, whom she would have had give in their Verdict, that she was, tho' she knew her self not to be pregnant; she then answer'd me, That a certain Person perswaded her to it; and besides, she could not think it was any Sin to save her Life that way, if possible. She all-along behav'd her self as one that had no apprehension at all of a Future State, was very clamorous, stubborn, and unwilling to receive any Instruction for the Good of her Soul, till she was almost within the very Sight of Death.</p>
            <p>11. <persName id="OA17160919n33-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n33-1" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n33-1" type="surname" value="SLATE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n33-1" type="given" value="ELIZABETH"/>Elizabeth Slate</persName>, condemn'd for being concern'd with several other naughty Women, in assaulting and robbing Mr. <persName id="OA17160919n33-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n33-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n33-2" type="surname" value="Major"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n33-2" type="given" value="Abraham"/>Abraham Major</persName>, and taking from him 2 Gold-Rings, a pair of Silver-Buckles, and a Silver Tobacco-box, and 18 s. in Money, on the 13th of June last, and 26 Guinea's, a Broad-piece, and a Moydore on the next Day after. She said, she was 18 Years of age, born at <placeName id="OA17160919-geo-22">
                  <interp inst="OA17160919-geo-22" type="type" value="parish"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17160919n33-1 OA17160919-geo-22"/>Wapping</placeName>, and liv'd in the <placeName id="OA17160919-geo-23">
                  <interp inst="OA17160919-geo-23" type="type" value="parish"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17160919n33-1 OA17160919-geo-23"/>Parish of St. Dunstan Stepney</placeName>: That she first began to be imploy'd in <rs id="OA17160919-occupation-17" type="occupation">throwing Silk for the Weavers</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17160919n33-1 OA17160919-occupation-17"/>, and afterwards learnt to <rs id="OA17160919-occupation-18" type="occupation">make Buttons</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17160919n33-1 OA17160919-occupation-18"/>; but for these</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA171609190006"/>
            <p>3 Years past had been an idle Body, who falling into company with lewd Women and other wicked and vicious People, was deluded by them, and enticed into their evil Practices, chiefly that of picking up Men in the Streets (especially when in Drink) and carrying them into Bawdy-houses, and stripping and robbing them there of their Cloaths, Money, and other Goods about them. All this she plainly and fully confess'd, and in particular own'd she was guilty of the Facts she stood Condemn'd for; of which, and of all other her Deeds of Wickedness, which were many and great, she pray'd GOD would give her Grace heartily to repent.</p>
            <p>At the Place of Execution, to which they were this Day carry'd from <placeName id="OA17160919-geo-24">
                  <interp inst="OA17160919-geo-24" type="type" value="site"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17160919n21-1 n22-1 n24-1 n24-3 n24-4 n25-2 n26-1 n26-4 n28-1 n29-1 n30-1 n30-3 n31-1 n31-2 n32-1 n32-3 n33-1 OA17160919-geo-24"/>Newgate</placeName> in 4 Carts, I attended them for the last time, and according to my usual manner, exhorted them, pray'd for them, sung some Penitential Psalms with them, made them rehearse the Apostles Creed; and after I had wish'd them that Forgiveness of Sins, that Resurrection of the Body, and that Everlasting Life which they had thus made Profession of, and finally recommended their Souls to GOD, I left them to their private Devotions, for which they had some Time allotted them; then the Cart drew away, and they were turn'd off; all of them calling upon GOD to have Mercy on them, and receive their Souls.</p>
            <p>NB. <persName id="OA17160919n36-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n36-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n36-1" type="surname" value="LEATHERTON"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n36-1" type="given" value="JAMES"/>James Leatherton</persName> (which he said was his right Name) confess'd, That <persName id="OA17160919n36-3">
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n36-3" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n36-3" type="surname" value="Richardson"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n36-3" type="given" value="William"/>William Richardson</persName> was the Name he went by, when formerly condemn'd. And <persName id="OA17160919n36-4">
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n36-4" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n36-4" type="surname" value="Worrell"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n36-4" type="given" value="Tho"/>Tho. Worrell</persName> said, He took that of <persName id="OA17160919n36-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n36-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n36-2" type="surname" value="WHITE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n36-2" type="given" value="THOMAS"/>Thomas White</persName> when Try'd for the Fact on which he was before Condemn'd and Pardon'd.</p>
            <p>
               <persName id="OA17160919n37-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n37-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n37-1" type="surname" value="EVANS"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n37-1" type="given" value="ROBERT"/>Robert Evans</persName> and <persName id="OA17160919n37-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n37-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n37-2" type="surname" value="Purchase"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n37-2" type="given" value="Tho"/>Tho. Purchase</persName> desir'd, that none would (on account of this their shameful Death) reflect upon their Friends; for they were honest Persons, had given them good Education, and were not at all the Cause of their taking to evil Courses. And the said Purchase declar'd further, That he was one of the Men concern'd in the late Riot in <placeName id="OA17160919-geo-25">
                  <interp inst="OA17160919-geo-25" type="type" value="site"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17160919n37-2 OA17160919-geo-25"/>Salisbury-Court</placeName>; and, That he went into the Mugg-house there, and took off from the Bar a Bottle of Brandy, and another of Cinamon-water, and ran away with them. He said, it was the Fact <persName id="OA17160919n37-3">
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n37-3" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n37-3" type="surname" value="Price"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n37-3" type="given" value="Richard"/>Richard Price</persName> was charg'd with. But when I observ'd to him, that the said Price might have done the like also, either before or after he was gone, he could say Nothing to that.</p>
            <p>This is all the Account here to be given of these Dying Malefactors, by me,</p>
            <p>
               <persName id="OA17160919n39-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n39-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n39-1" type="surname" value="LORRAIN"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n39-1" type="given" value="PAUL"/>PAUL LORRAIN</persName>, <rs id="OA17160919-occupation-19" type="occupation">Ordinary</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17160919n39-1 OA17160919-occupation-19"/>.</p>
            <p>Wednesday, Sept. 19. 1716.</p>
            <p>ADVERTISEMENTS.</p>
            <p>THis is to give Notice to all Gentlemen, Booksellers, and others, That there is lately publish'd a new Sett of Cuts, adapted to several sizes of Common prayers, all new Designs by Mr. Gocree of Amsterdam, engrav'd by P. Vandergucht. Likewise Mr. Sturt's Cuts Sold by <persName id="OA17160919n42-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n42-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n42-1" type="surname" value="WHITLEDGE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n42-1" type="given" value="ROBERT"/>ROBERT WHITLEDGE</persName>, at <placeName id="OA17160919-geo-26">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17160919n42-1 OA17160919-geo-26"/>
                  <placeName id="OA17160919-geo-27">
                     <interp inst="OA17160919-geo-27" type="type" value="street"/>
                     <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                           targets="OA17160919n42-1 OA17160919-geo-27"/>
                     <placeName id="OA17160919-geo-28">
                        <interp inst="OA17160919-geo-28" type="type" value="site"/>
                        <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                              targets="OA17160919n42-1 OA17160919-geo-28"/>the Bible and Ball</placeName> in Ave-Maria-Lane</placeName>, near Ludgate</placeName>, where may be had all sorts of Bibles, either in Folio, Quarto, Octavo, Twelves, or other sizes; Common-prayers in Folio, for the Use of Churches; Commonprayers in Octavo and Twelves. A New Edition of the Book of Homilies in Folio; all neatly bound The Duty of Man's Works of all sizes. Duty of Man in Latin. Latin and Welsh Commonprayers, Tat and Brady's new Version of Psalms, with the new Supplement. Dr. Gibson on the Sacrament. Mr. Clutterbuck on the Liturgy. The Statutes at large in 3 Volumes. Bp Beveridge's Sermons and private Thoughts.</p>
            <p>In a few Days will be publish'd,</p>
            <p>THe Third and Last Volume of Posthumous Works written by Mr. <persName id="OA17160919n44-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n44-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n44-2" type="surname" value="Butler"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n44-2" type="given" value="Samuel"/>Samuel Butler</persName>, Author of Hudibras; part written in the time of the Usurpation, and the rest in the Reign of K. Charles II. To which is added, The Coffin for the Good Old Cause; publish'd just before the Restoration. By <rs id="OA17160919-occupation-20" type="occupation">Sir</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17160919n44-1 OA17160919-occupation-20"/> 
               <persName id="OA17160919n44-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n44-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n44-1" type="surname" value="LAKE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17160919n44-1" type="given" value="SAMUEL"/>Samuel Lake</persName>. Printed for S. Briscoe.</p>
            <p>London Printed, and Sold by J. Morphew, near Stationers-hall.</p>
         </div0>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>