<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<TEI.2>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div0 type="ordinarysAccount" id="OA17050504">
            <interp inst="OA17050504" type="uri" value="ordinarysAccounts/OA17050504"/>
            <interp inst="OA17050504" type="date" value="17050504"/>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA170505040001"/>
            <p>The ORDINARY of NEW GATE his Account of the Behaviour, Confessions, and Last Speeches of the Malefactors that were Executed at Tyburn on Friday the 4th of May, 1705.</p>
            <p>AT the Sessions held at Justice-Hall in the Old Baily, on the 18, 19 and 20th Days of April last, Sentence of Death was pass'd upon Six Malefactors; whereof Three were Repriev'd, and the other Three order'd for Execution. One of the last Three, viz. <persName id="OA17050504n3-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17050504n3-1" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17050504n3-1" type="surname" value="LABREE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17050504n3-1" type="given" value="CECILIA"/>Cecilia Labree</persName> having receiv'd it on Wednesday last, and an Account of it been already given to the Publick, those that will see her Confession, are referr'd to that Account.</p>
            <p>On the Lord's Day the 22d of April last I Preach'd both to them and others then in the Chappel of Newgate, viz.</p>
            <p>In the Morning upon part of the Second Lesson appointed then to be read, viz. Acts 19. 4. Then said Paul, John verily baptiz'd with the Baptism of Repentance, saying unto the People, that they should Believe on Him which should come after him, that is, on Christ Jesus.</p>
            <p>Which Words having first illustrated and explain'd, I then proceeded to shew from them;</p>
            <p>That as the Baptism of John was, so the Christian Baptism is, a Baptism of Repentance and Faith; and that no one is the better for being by Baptism outwardly admitted into Christ's Religion, who (when come to Years of Understanding) does not in his Heart Believe on Jesus Christ, and Repent of his Sins.</p>
            <p>Here I treated at large of the Doctrine of Faith and Repentance; shewing from the Scripture;</p>
            <p>1. That without Faith it is impossible to please God, and be Saved, Heb. 11. 6. and Mark 16. 16.</p>
            <p>2. That unless we Repent we shall perish. Luke 13. 3.</p>
            <p>3. That if we Believe on the Lord Jesus, and Repent; our Sins shall be blotted out, and we shall be sav'd, Acts 3. 19. 16. 30.</p>
            <p>4. That to obtain this saving Faith and Repentance, which is the gracious Gift of God, [Eph. 2. 8, and 2 Tim. 2. 25.] we must beg it of him by fervent Prayer, &amp;c.</p>
            <p>In the Afternoon I Preach'd upon the 2d of St. Peter 1. 10. Being part of the Second Lesson for that Evening-Prayer, and the Words these; Wherefore the rather Brethren, give diligence to make your Calling and Election sure; for if ye do these things, ye shall never fall.</p>
            <p>Which Words and their Context, after I had open'd, I shew'd the Necessity of our exerting those Virtues and Graces of Faith, Knowledge, Temperance, Patience, Godliness, Brotherly Love, and Charity, which are mention'd in the 5. 6, and 7th Verses; in order to our obtaining a comfortable Assurance of our Election and Vocation: Which tho' they cannot be made surer, than they are in themselves, and with respect to God, with whom there is no Variableness, nor shadow of turning, and whose Gifts and Calling are without Repentance, because the Lord Knows them that are his: [Jam. 1. 17. Rom. 11. 29. 2 Tim. 2. 19.] Yet this our Election and Calling may be made surer to our selves and to others, by our living a truly Christian Life, in departing from all iniquity, and doing Works meet for Repentance: And this we are so much the more concern'd in, by how much we have neglected Religions Duties before, and done so many Evils, to the dishonour of God, and the Doctrine of Christ; and to the hurt of our Neighbour, and of our own Souls.</p>
            <p>In Prosecution of this Subject, and to bring those poor miserable Sinners to Repentance, I laid before them the following Considerations, on which I inlarg'd.</p>
            <p>1. That Repentance is a sure way for Sinners to regain the Favour of God, which they have lost, and to obtain that Happiness, which they have forfeited, by their Sins.</p>
            <p>2. That it is in vain, and most dangerous, for Sinners to flatter themselves with the hopes of being made happy any other way, than by a sincere Repentance, which is the inseparable Companion of Faith; and both of them, the great Work of the Spirit of God upon the Hearts and Souls of Men.</p>
            <p>3. That if Sinners neglect their Repentance while God is graciously pleased to call them to it, and allow them Time and Grace for it, they shall at last be shut out of all Mercy, and doomed to a State of Misery for ever.</p>
            <p>On the last Lord's Day the 29th of April, I Preach'd again to them, both in the Forenoon and Afternoon, upon Deut. 32. 29. O that they were Wise, that they understood this, that they would consider their latter end.</p>
            <p>From which Words,</p>
            <p>1. I shewed, the shortness of this Life.</p>
            <p>2. The Necessity of our making a good use of it.</p>
            <p>3. I gave Directions for it; from the Consideration.</p>
            <p>1. Of Death, to which all Men are Subject, and from which none may justly suppose to be at a great distance.</p>
            <p>2. Of the Judgment which is to follow after Death, and will place and  Men in a State of Bliss or Woe, that is to have no end.</p>
            <p>3. Of the ns, as Meditations and Prayers, &amp;c. which we may use here in this World, to avoid the Misery, and obtain the Happiness of the next.</p>
            <p>In the Close of all these Sermons, I made a particular Application to the Condemned Persons, whom I constantly Visited and Taught every Day while under this Condemnation: And in my private Discourses with them, I received from them the respective Account following.</p>
            <p>I. <persName id="OA17050504n28-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17050504n28-1" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17050504n28-1" type="surname" value="GREEN"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17050504n28-1" type="given" value="MARGARET"/>MARGARET GREEN</persName>, alias <persName id="OA17050504n28-3">
                  <interp inst="OA17050504n28-3" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17050504n28-3" type="surname" value="WOTHY"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17050504n28-3" type="given" value="MARGARET"/>Wothy</persName>, Condemn'd for Felony and Burglary, for Breaking the House of Mr. <persName id="OA17050504n28-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17050504n28-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17050504n28-2" type="surname" value="MAY"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17050504n28-2" type="given" value="MATTHEW"/>Matthew May</persName>, and taking from thence 7 pair of Sheets and other Goods, on the 24th of March last. She said, she was about 29 Years of Age, born in the <placeName id="OA17050504-geo-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17050504-geo-1" type="type" value="region"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17050504n28-1 n28-3 OA17050504-geo-1"/>North of Ireland</placeName>; but had liv'd a considerable time at <placeName id="OA17050504-geo-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17050504-geo-2" type="type" value="urban_centre"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17050504n28-1 n28-3 OA17050504-geo-2"/>Dublin</placeName>, where she was marry'd to One that ruin'd her, and left her about a Twelve-month after they were marry'd; and then marry'd another Woman, with whom he lives now in Adultery: Of which she pray'd to God he might repent. She further said, That that Husband of hers was the first Cause of her ensuing Sins and Misfortunes; for she being thus left by him, came up to <placeName id="OA17050504-geo-3">
                  <interp inst="OA17050504-geo-3" type="type" value="urban_centre"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17050504n28-1 n28-3 OA17050504-geo-3"/>London</placeName>, and there got acquainted with another Ma who kept her Company, and they lived together as Man and Wife for these 7 Years last past; within which time he had (together with a certain Woman, a Receiver of Stol'n Goods) prompted her to the Commission of several Robberies, which she said, she did always by her self; as she did, (that is, she was alone) when she attempted to rob Mr. May: Which Fact she confess'd; and acknowledged the Justice of God and Man in her Punishment for it. Only this stuck mightily at her Heart, and she could hardly overcome it. 'That the perfidiousness 'of her Husband, and the Solicitations of that wicked Man who 'kept her Company, and of that Receiver of Stol'n Goods before 'mention'd, had brought her to this her untimely End; which she 'once little thoug she should ever come to; as having, before 'she knew them, been very careful to live honestly and serve God. She mightily complain'd of the hardness of her Heart, and was for a while in great despair of her Salvation; desiring my Prayers for her, who could not well pray for her self. Afterwards she seem'd to be more melted, and earnestly implored God's Mercy and Pardon for all her Sins both great and small, both known and unknown; and she declared, that she dy'd in Charity with all Men, and desired that her Death might be a Warning to others. To which she added, that the Robberies she had ever committed were inconsiderable: Yet she could not make any other amends for them, than by her Death, which she freely took as the one Reward of her Sins.</p>
            <p>II. <persName id="OA17050504n29-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17050504n29-1" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17050504n29-1" type="surname" value="DYER"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17050504n29-1" type="given" value="JANE"/>Jane Dyer</persName>, alias <persName id="OA17050504n29-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17050504n29-2" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17050504n29-2" type="surname" value="BROWN"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17050504n29-2" type="given" value="JANE"/>Brown</persName>, Condemn'd for stealing Divers Goods of Mrs. Tinnel. She said, she was about 24 Years of Age, born at <placeName id="OA17050504-geo-4">
                  <interp inst="OA17050504-geo-4" type="type" value="region"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17050504n29-1 n29-2 OA17050504-geo-4"/>
                  <placeName id="OA17050504-geo-5">
                     <interp inst="OA17050504-geo-5" type="type" value="urban_centre"/>
                     <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                           targets="OA17050504n29-1 n29-2 OA17050504-geo-5"/>Burnt helling</placeName>, a Sea-port-Town, within 18 Miles of <placeName id="OA17050504-geo-6">
                     <interp inst="OA17050504-geo-6" type="type" value="urban_centre"/>
                     <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                           targets="OA17050504n29-1 n29-2 OA17050504-geo-6"/>Edinburg</placeName> in Scotland</placeName>: That she left her Countrey about 9 Years ago, and went to <placeName id="OA17050504-geo-7">
                  <interp inst="OA17050504-geo-7" type="type" value="urban_centre"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17050504n29-1 n29-2 OA17050504-geo-7"/>Dublin</placeName>, where she liv'd 7 Years; and then came to <placeName id="OA17050504-geo-8">
                  <interp inst="OA17050504-geo-8" type="type" value="urban_centre"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17050504n29-1 n29-2 OA17050504-geo-8"/>London</placeName>: That she was virtuously and religiously brought up by her Parents; to whom she had been very undutiful and disobedient; and that she had broke their Hearts by her Wickedness; which was now a great grief to her. She confess'd the Fact for which she was Condemn'd to die, and own'd she had deserv'd Death before now; and she much lamented her Folly in not taking Warning and amending her Life, by the former Punishment she had justly receiv'd, as having been burnt, not long since, for a Felony. She said, she had been desparately Wicked, and was Guilty (to the highest degree) of Lewdness and Debauchery, of Swearing, Lying, Cursing, Sabbath-breaking, and of the total Neglect of God's Service, and of all Sins, Murther excepted. She laid very heavy Loads upon her self, and she was mightily troubled in her Spirit, and desired me to pray more heartily for her than for the rest, because (said She) I am a much greater Sinner than others. Being admonish'd to search out her own Heart, she said, she durst not look back upon her sinful Life past, it was so odious a Sight to her, which fill'd her with horror. Oh that she had liv'd otherwise, and not abus'd her precious Soul as she had done! Oh that she had time to live longer here! Oh that she could live her Life over again, that she might amend it! Oh that God would for Christ's sake, forgive her Sins, which were many, and grievous, and great. These were some of her sorrowful Expressions, as being now sensible (and desirous that others might be sensible also) of the Grief</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA170505040002"/>
            <p>and Misery which Sin is always attended with. She declar'd, that she dy'd in Charity with all the World; and wish'd she were able to make Satisfaction and Reparation to the Persons she had wrong'd; whose Pardon she begg'd: Which, she said, was the only thing she could now do; desiring God to bless them, and to forgive her.</p>
            <p>This Day <persName id="OA17050504n31-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17050504n31-1" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17050504n31-1" type="surname" value="GREEN"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17050504n31-1" type="given" value="MARGARET"/>Margaret Green</persName> and <persName id="OA17050504n31-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17050504n31-2" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17050504n31-2" type="surname" value="DYER"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17050504n31-2" type="given" value="JANE"/>Jane Dyer</persName> being carry'd (in a Cart) to <placeName id="OA17050504-geo-9">
                  <interp inst="OA17050504-geo-9" type="type" value="site"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17050504n31-1 n31-2 n31-3 n31-4 n31-5 OA17050504-geo-9"/>Tyburn</placeName>, I met them there: And having asked them, whether they had any thing more to say, in order to the clearing of their Consciences, and disposing themselves for an easie and happy Departure out of this miserable World, in which God did not think fit they should continue any longer: They told me, They had nothing more to say, but desir'd my Prayers for them, and the Prayers of all good People, while there was Breath in them; This they both of them did desire, but particularly <persName id="OA17050504n31-3">
                  <interp inst="OA17050504n31-3" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17050504n31-3" type="surname" value="DYER"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17050504n31-3" type="given" value="JANE"/>Jane Dyer</persName>, who was very earnest with me, That I should do (as she phrased it) my Duty to God for her Soul, till she was quite dead. I exhorted them to lift up their Affections to God more and more, and to pray earnestly to the t, for the Assistance of his Divine Spirit, and the free Pardon of all their Sins: For which I also made Prayers, and in their behalves desired the Standers by to join therein. Then we sung a Penitential Psalm, and rehearsed the Articles of our Christian Faith. Which being done, and some further Admonitions made to them, they spoke to the People to this Effect, That they would take Warning by them; and not to Swear, Lie, Curse, and Blaspheme, nor break the Sabbath day, and neglect God's Service, and do ill things as they had done: For which they were now justly punished in this World, and without God's infinite Mercy, should be much more severely punish'd in the next. <persName id="OA17050504n31-4">
                  <interp inst="OA17050504n31-4" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17050504n31-4" type="surname" value="GREEN"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17050504n31-4" type="given" value="MARGARET"/>Margaret Green</persName> warned all Young Women and Old, not to keep Company with idle and wicked Fellows, and maintain them by Thieving, which was the thing that had brought her to this her sad shameful, and untimely End. After this, I pray'd again, and sung another Psalm; and then committing them to God, and the Power of his Grace, I withdrew from them: Who having some time allow'd for their private Devotions, cry'd to God for Mercy in these and the like Ejaculations, Lord have Mercy upon me, (said each of them) Lord Jesu one Drop of thy precious Blood to my polluted sinful Soul! Lord save me! And <persName id="OA17050504n31-5">
                  <interp inst="OA17050504n31-5" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17050504n31-5" type="surname" value="DYER"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17050504n31-5" type="given" value="JANE"/>Jane Dyer</persName> in particular had these Expressions, Lord Jesu, Thou diedst for me: O let me patiently suffer, according to thy Will! O receive me to thy self! Lord, I come, I come. And both of them. O Sweet Jesu, Dear Jesu, have Mercy upon us! O Father of Mercies have Mercy upon us! O Holy, Blessed, and Glorious Trinity have Mercy upon us; The speaking again to the Standers by, said, Good People pray for us, pray to God for our precious Souls. To all which they sometimes, each one by her self, and sometimes joyntly, added many other fervent Ejaculations and Liftings up of their Souls to God. While they were thus praying, the Cart drew away, and they were turn'd off, and their Souls launched into their Eternal State.</p>
            <p>Whereas it lately happen'd in a publick Place, that some Words were spoken in undue Reflection upon the Ordinary of Newgate, as if he us'd to administer the Lord's Supper to Condemn'd Persons for Temporal Ends: The said Ordinary, in just Vindication of his Ministry, which he has ever discharg'd Conscientiously both towards God and those poor Souls under his Care, finds himself oblig'd to give this publick notice; That he never administred that Holy Sacrament to any Prisoners with other intent or regard, than for their Spiritual and Eternal Good; and that he is so far from having fought any Temporal Advantage that way, that ever since his being Ordinary of Newgate, he has provided Bread and Wine for that Sacred Use there, at his own Charge: Neither has he ever received any Promise, or Gratuity, for his representing the Case of Malefactors, better or worse, than it really appear'd to his Judgment; nor was he ever Brib'd for obtaining, or endeavouring to obtain Reprieves for any. Of the Truth of all which he is ready to make Oath.</p>
            <p>This is all the Account here to be given of this Session by</p>
            <p>
               <persName id="OA17050504n34-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17050504n34-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17050504n34-1" type="surname" value="LORRAIN"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17050504n34-1" type="given" value="PAUL"/>PAUL LORRAIN</persName>, <rs id="OA17050504-occupation-1" type="occupation">Ordinary</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17050504n34-1 OA17050504-occupation-1"/> of <placeName id="OA17050504-geo-10">
                  <interp inst="OA17050504-geo-10" type="type" value="site"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17050504n34-1 OA17050504-geo-10"/>Newgate</placeName>.</p>
            <p>Friday May 4. 1705.</p>
            <p>Advertisements.</p>
            <p>THE History of Infant-Baptism in two Parts. The First being am impartial Collection of all such Passages in the Writers of the four first Centuries as do make for, or against it. The Second containing several things that do help to illustrate the said History. By W. WALL, Vicar of Shoreham in Kent.</p>
            <p>THE Exemplary Life and Character of <persName id="OA17050504n38-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17050504n38-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17050504n38-1" type="surname" value="BONNELL"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17050504n38-1" type="given" value="JAMES"/>James Bonnell</persName>, <rs id="OA17050504-occupation-2" type="occupation">Esq</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17050504n38-1 OA17050504-occupation-2"/>; late <rs id="OA17050504-occupation-3" type="occupation">Accomptant General</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17050504n38-1 OA17050504-occupation-3"/> of <placeName id="OA17050504-geo-11">
                  <interp inst="OA17050504-geo-11" type="type" value="region"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17050504n38-1 OA17050504-geo-11"/>Ireland</placeName>. To which is added the Sermon preach'd at his Funeral by Edward Lord Bishop of Killmore and Ardagh The Life by <persName id="OA17050504n38-3">
                  <interp inst="OA17050504n38-3" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17050504n38-3" type="surname" value="HAMILTON"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17050504n38-3" type="given" value="WILLIAM"/>William Hamilton</persName>, A. M. <rs id="OA17050504-occupation-4" type="occupation">Archdeacon</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17050504n38-3 OA17050504-occupation-4"/> of <placeName id="OA17050504-geo-12">
                  <interp inst="OA17050504-geo-12" type="type" value="county"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17050504n38-3 OA17050504-geo-12"/>Armagh</placeName>. Attested by Six of the most eminent Bishops in the Kingdom of Ireland.</p>
            <p>J. Downing in Bartholomew-Close near West-Smithfield. 1705.</p>
            <p>AN Account of the Progress of the Reformation of Manners in England, Scotland and Ireland, and other Parts of Europe and America, &amp;c. The Twelfth Edition Enlarg'd.</p>
            <p>THE Necessary Duty of Family Prayer, and the deplorable Condition of Prayerless Families consider'd. In a Letter from a Minister to his Parishioners. With Prayers for their Use.</p>
            <p>A Discourse concerning Sins of Infirmity and wilful Sins, with another of Restitution. By the Right Reverend Richard, late Lord Bishop of Bath and Wells. Price 3 d.</p>
            <p>Sold by <persName id="OA17050504n43-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17050504n43-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17050504n43-1" type="surname" value="Downing"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17050504n43-1" type="given" value="Joseph"/>Joseph Downing</persName> in <placeName id="OA17050504-geo-13">
                  <interp inst="OA17050504-geo-13" type="type" value="street"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17050504n43-1 OA17050504-geo-13"/>Bartholomew Close</placeName>.</p>
            <p>BOOKS set forth by <persName id="OA17050504n44-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17050504n44-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17050504n44-1" type="surname" value="LORRAIN"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17050504n44-1" type="given" value="PAUL"/>Paul Lorrain</persName>. <rs id="OA17050504-occupation-5" type="occupation">Ordinary</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17050504n44-1 OA17050504-occupation-5"/> of <placeName id="OA17050504-geo-14">
                  <interp inst="OA17050504-geo-14" type="type" value="site"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17050504n44-1 OA17050504-geo-14"/>Newgase</placeName>, viz.</p>
            <p>THE last Words of the <rs id="OA17050504-occupation-6" type="occupation">Lady</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17050504n45-1 OA17050504-occupation-6"/> 
               <persName id="OA17050504n45-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17050504n45-1" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17050504n45-1" type="surname" value="DE LA MUSSE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17050504n45-1" type="given" value="MARGARET"/>Margaret De la Musse</persName>: And The Dying-Man's Assistant, both printed for J. Lawrence at the Angel in the Poultry. And A Guide to Salvation, Sold at the Star in St. Paul's Church-Yard.</p>
            <p>THE Christian Education of Children. In a Letter to a Friend. In which are contain'd the Fundamental Truths of Religion, and the Duties of a Christian Life. Profitable for all sorts of Persons; but especially recommended to Schools of Charity. Printed for R. Sympson at the Harp in St. Paul's Church-Yard, 1704.</p>
            <p>THE Ingenious Youth's Companion, furnished with Variety of Copies of the Hand in Fashion, adorned with Curious Figures and Flourishes. Invented and Performed à la Volee by <persName id="OA17050504n47-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17050504n47-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17050504n47-1" type="surname" value="SEDDON"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17050504n47-1" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Seddon</persName>. Sold by <persName id="OA17050504n47-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17050504n47-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17050504n47-2" type="surname" value="STUART"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17050504n47-2" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Stuart</persName> at the <placeName id="OA17050504-geo-15">
                  <interp inst="OA17050504-geo-15" type="type" value="site"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17050504n47-2 OA17050504-geo-15"/>
                  <placeName id="OA17050504-geo-16">
                     <interp inst="OA17050504-geo-16" type="type" value="site"/>
                     <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                           targets="OA17050504n47-2 OA17050504-geo-16"/>Three Bibles and Ink Bottles</placeName> at the Corner of the Square on London-Bridge</placeName>, 1705.</p>
            <p>
               <persName id="OA17050504n48-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17050504n48-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17050504n48-1" type="surname" value="WHITLEDGE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17050504n48-1" type="given" value="ROBERT"/>RObert Whitledge</persName>, <rs id="OA17050504-occupation-7" type="occupation">Bookbinder</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17050504n48-1 OA17050504-occupation-7"/>, now living at the Bible in <placeName id="OA17050504-geo-17">
                  <interp inst="OA17050504-geo-17" type="type" value="parish"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17050504n48-1 OA17050504-geo-17"/>
                  <placeName id="OA17050504-geo-18">
                     <interp inst="OA17050504-geo-18" type="type" value="street"/>
                     <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                           targets="OA17050504n48-1 OA17050504-geo-18"/>Creed Lane</placeName>, within Ludgate</placeName>, where all Booksellers, and others, may be furnished with the WELSH Bible, WELSH Common Prayer and WELSH Almanack, and with all sorts of other Bibles and Common-Prayers, large and small, with Cuts or without, Rul'd or Unrul'd, Bound in Turkey Leather, extraordnary or plain, or unbound. Also the Statutes at large, and Articles and Canons of the Church of England; Tate and Brady's new Version of the Singing Psalms, the Common-Prayer in French, the new Book of Rates compleat; and also all Books neatly Bound.</p>
            <p>A Specifick Powder for the Cure of the King's-Evil.</p>
            <p>THIS Powder by a long Experience, has been found to be extraordinarily successful and specifick against the King's-Evil: It helps Digestion, takes off the Crudity of the Chyle, revives the Spirits, purifies the Blood, and gives Strength and a Tonus to the several parts of the Body; so that by it, Sores and Ulcers are easily dried up, Swellings discuss'd, the Humours diverted, and their Malignity corrected: It hath a pleasant Taste, and makes no sensible Evacuation, and so may be taken without any Trouble or Disturbance from Business 'Tis a gentle and safe Remedy, which doth agree with the Constitutions of all People. It is to be had at Mr. Rogers's a Bookseller at the Sun against St. Dunstan's Church in Fleet-street, at Mr. Round's a Bookseller in Exchange-Alley in Cornhill, at Mr. Baker's Bookseller at Mercers-Chappel in Cheap-side, at Mr. Fleetwood's at the Parliament-Stairs Westminster-Hall, at Mr. Rowe's-Coffee-House at the Bridge-Foot in Southwark, and at Mr. Watson's Coffee-house the Corner of Denmark-street in Ratcliff High-Way. Price 5 s. the Box, containing seven Doses. Allowance will be made to those who take any Quantity.</p>
            <p>A Medicine for the Cure of the Stone and Gravel, of much greater Certainty than any yet offer'd in Publick; having been experienced in divers Bodies, effectually to Dissolve and Redue the STONE into Slime in 20 or 30 days time, clearing the Kidneys of Gravel; and in any Fit of the Stone or Gravel to give Ease in the most Raging Pains, and procures Freedom of Urine in a few hours time. To be had of a Chymist at the Golden-Ball and Crown in New-Street without Bishops-Gate, London.</p>
            <p>DIrections for Communicants how to Celebrate the blessed Sacrament of the Lord's-Supper, according to the Prescription of the Church of England, laid down in a plain and familiar way, for the Use of all, but designed especially for the meanest Capacities. With Considerations and Exhortations to encourage our frequent Coming to that Table, &amp;c. Sold by R. Sympson at the Harp in St. Paul's Church-yard.</p>
            <p>WHEREAS some Persons take the Liberty of putting out Sham-Papers, pretending to give an Account of the Malefactors that are Executed; in which Papers they are so defective, and unjust, as sometimes to mistake even their Names and Crimes, and often quite misrepresent the State they plainly appear to be in under their Condemnation, and at the time of their Death: To prevent which great Abuses, These are to give Notice, That the only true Account of the Dying Criminals, is that which comes out the next Day afte their Execution, about 8 in the Morning, the Title whereof constantly begins with these Words, The ORDINARY of NEWGATE his Account of the Behaviour, &amp;c. In which Paper (the better to distinguish it from Counterfeits) are set down the Heads of the several Sermons Preach'd before the Condemned; and after their Confessions and Prayers, an Attestation thereto under the Ordinary's Hand, that is, his Name at length: and at the bottom the Printer's Name,</p>
            <p>J. Downing in Bartholomew-Close near West-Smithfield. 1705.</p>
         </div0>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>