<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<TEI.2>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div0 type="ordinarysAccount" id="OA17320809">
            <interp inst="OA17320809" type="uri" value="ordinarysAccounts/OA17320809"/>
            <interp inst="OA17320809" type="date" value="17320809"/>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA173208090001"/>
            <p>THE ORDINARY of NEWGATE, His ACCOUNT of the Behaviour, Confession, and Dying Words, OF THE MALEFACTOR, Who was EXECUTED at TYBURN, On WEDNESDAY the 9th of this Inst. AUGUST, 1732.</p>
            <p>BEING THE SEVENTH EXECUTION in the MAYORALTY OF THE <rs id="OA17320809-occupation-1" type="occupation">Rt. Hon</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17320809n3-1 OA17320809-occupation-1"/>. <persName id="OA17320809n3-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n3-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n3-1" type="surname" value="CHILD"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n3-1" type="given" value="FRANCIS"/>FRANCIS CHILD</persName>, <rs id="OA17320809-occupation-2" type="occupation">Esq</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17320809n3-1 OA17320809-occupation-2"/>;</p>
            <p>Number VII. For the said YEAR.</p>
            <p>LONDON:</p>
            <p>Printed and Sold by <persName id="OA17320809n6-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n6-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n6-1" type="surname" value="APPLEBEE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n6-1" type="given" value="JOHN"/>JOHN APPLEBEE</persName>, in <placeName id="OA17320809-geo-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17320809-geo-1" type="type" value="street"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA17320809n6-1 OA17320809-geo-1"/>Bolt-Court</placeName>, near the <placeName id="OA17320809-geo-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17320809-geo-2" type="type" value="street"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA17320809n6-1 OA17320809-geo-2"/>
                  <placeName id="OA17320809-geo-3">
                     <interp inst="OA17320809-geo-3" type="type" value="site"/>
                     <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA17320809n6-1 OA17320809-geo-3"/>Leg-Tavern</placeName>, Fleet-street</placeName>. M.DCC.XXXII.</p>
            <p>[Price Three-Pence.]</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA173208090002"/>
            <p>THE ORDINARY of NEWGATE, His ACCOUNT of the Behaviour, Confession, &amp;c.</p>
            <p>AT the King's Commission of Oyer and Terminer, and Gaol-Delivery of Newgate, held (before the <rs id="OA17320809-occupation-3" type="occupation">Right Hon</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17320809n9-1 OA17320809-occupation-3"/>. <persName id="OA17320809n9-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n9-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n9-1" type="surname" value="CHILD"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n9-1" type="given" value="FRANCIS"/>FRANCIS CHILD</persName>, <rs id="OA17320809-occupation-4" type="occupation">Esq</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17320809n9-1 OA17320809-occupation-4"/>; <rs id="OA17320809-occupation-5" type="occupation">Lord Mayor</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17320809n3-1 n9-1 OA17320809-occupation-5"/> of the <placeName id="OA17320809-geo-4">
                  <interp inst="OA17320809-geo-4" type="type" value="urban_centre"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA17320809n9-1 OA17320809-geo-4"/>City of London</placeName>; the Right Hon. my Lord Chief Baron Reynolds, the Hon. Mr. Justice Probyn; the Hon. Mr. Justice Fortescue; the Worshipful Mr. Serjeant Urlin, Deputy-Recorder of the City of London, and others his Majesty's Justices of Oyer and Terminer, for the City of London, and Justices of the Gaol-Delivery of Newgate, holden for the said City and County of Middlesex) at Justice-Hall in the <placeName id="OA17320809-geo-5">
                  <interp inst="OA17320809-geo-5" type="type" value="site"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17320809n9-1 n10-1 n10-2 n10-3 n10-4 n10-5 n10-6 n10-7 n10-8 n10-9 OA17320809-geo-5"/>Old-Bailey</placeName>, on Wednesday, Thursday, Friday and Saturday, being the 5th, 6th, 7th and 8th of July, 1732; in the Sixth Year of his Majesty's Reign.</p>
            <p>Nine Men, viz. <persName id="OA17320809n10-8">
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n10-8" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n10-8" type="surname" value="Gillets"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n10-8" type="given" value="John"/>John Gillets</persName>, <persName id="OA17320809n10-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n10-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n10-1" type="surname" value="GLADMAN"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n10-1" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Gladman</persName>, <persName id="OA17320809n10-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n10-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n10-2" type="surname" value="TIPPING"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n10-2" type="given" value="DANIEL"/>Daniel Tipping</persName>, <persName id="OA17320809n10-9">
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n10-9" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n10-9" type="surname" value="Ellement"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n10-9" type="given" value="Robert"/>Robert Ellement</persName>, <persName id="OA17320809n10-3">
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n10-3" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n10-3" type="surname" value="ROBINS"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n10-3" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Robins</persName>, <persName id="OA17320809n10-4">
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n10-4" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n10-4" type="surname" value="ROBINS"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n10-4" type="given" value="VALENTINE"/>Valentine Robins</persName>, <persName id="OA17320809n10-5">
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n10-5" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n10-5" type="surname" value="BARRET"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n10-5" type="given" value="HENRY"/>Henry Barret</persName>, <persName id="OA17320809n10-6">
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n10-6" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n10-6" type="surname" value="CHARLEY"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n10-6" type="given" value="JOSEPH"/>Joseph Charley</persName>, and <persName id="OA17320809n10-7">
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n10-7" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n10-7" type="surname" value="DANGERFIELD"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n10-7" type="given" value="RICHARD"/>Richard Dangerfield</persName>, were by the Jury found Guilty of capital Crimes, and receiv'd Sentence of Death accordingly.</p>
            <p>Upon Friday, the 21st of July last, Report was made to her Majesty in Council, of these nine Malefactors in the Cells of Newgate, under Sentence of Death: When <persName id="OA17320809n11-7">
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n11-7" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n11-7" type="surname" value="Gladman"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n11-7" type="given" value="John"/>John Gladman</persName> of <placeName id="OA17320809-geo-6">
                  <interp inst="OA17320809-geo-6" type="type" value="parish"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA17320809n11-7 OA17320809-geo-6"/>Ickenham</placeName>, for stealing a Horse; <persName id="OA17320809n11-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n11-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n11-1" type="surname" value="GILLET"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n11-1" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Gillet</persName>, alias <persName id="OA17320809n11-8">
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n11-8" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n11-8" type="surname" value="MOUTH"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n11-8" type="given" value="JOHN"/>Mouth</persName>, for a Street-Robbery; <persName id="OA17320809n11-9">
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n11-9" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n11-9" type="surname" value="ROBINS"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n11-9" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John</persName> and <persName id="OA17320809n11-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n11-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n11-2" type="surname" value="ROBINS"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n11-2" type="given" value="VALENTINE"/>Valentine Robins</persName>, Brothers, <persName id="OA17320809n11-3">
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n11-3" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n11-3" type="surname" value="BARRET"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n11-3" type="given" value="HENRY"/>Henry Barret</persName>, <persName id="OA17320809n11-4">
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n11-4" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n11-4" type="surname" value="CHARLEY"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n11-4" type="given" value="JOSEPH"/>Joseph Charley</persName> and <persName id="OA17320809n11-5">
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n11-5" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n11-5" type="surname" value="DANGERFIELD"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n11-5" type="given" value="RICHARD"/>Richard Dangerfield</persName>, of <placeName id="OA17320809-geo-7">
                  <interp inst="OA17320809-geo-7" type="type" value="parish"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17320809n11-5 n11-4 OA17320809-geo-7"/>Pancras</placeName>, for robbing <persName id="OA17320809n11-6">
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n11-6" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n11-6" type="surname" value="ATKINS"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n11-6" type="given" value="SAMUEL"/>Samuel Atkins</persName>, in a Field, nigh the Highway, not far</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA173208090003"/>
            <p>
               <placeName id="OA17320809-geo-8">
                  <interp inst="OA17320809-geo-8" type="type" value="parish"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17320809n11-4 n11-5 n11-6 OA17320809-geo-8"/>Pancras</placeName>, of his Hat, and 3 s. in Money, receiv'd her Majesty's most gracious Reprieve: <persName id="OA17320809n12-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n12-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n12-1" type="surname" value="TIPPING"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n12-1" type="given" value="DANIEL"/>Daniel Tipping</persName>, and <persName id="OA17320809n12-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n12-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n12-2" type="surname" value="ELEMENT"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n12-2" type="given" value="ROBERT"/>Robert Element</persName> were order'd for Execution.</p>
            <p>N. B. <persName id="OA17320809n13-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n13-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n13-2" type="surname" value="Ellement"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n13-2" type="given" value="Robert"/>Robert Ellement</persName> had the Sentence Executed upon him, on Wednesday, the 26th of July last, and a genuine Account of his Life and Character was given, in the last Dying Speech of the said Date, and of his Behaviour and of the rest, while they were under Sentence; to which we refer the Reader. The Evening being the Execution of <persName id="OA17320809n13-3">
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n13-3" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n13-3" type="surname" value="Ellement"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n13-3" type="given" value="Robert"/>Robert Ellement</persName>, <persName id="OA17320809n13-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n13-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n13-1" type="surname" value="TIPPING"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n13-1" type="given" value="DANIEL"/>Daniel Tipping</persName> was graciously Repriev'd for a Fortnight, but the Crime for which he was convicted, having been represented henious and grievous, it was not thought expedient to enlarge his Reprieve any farther, but to let Justice take Place against him, according to his Sentence.</p>
            <p>
               <persName id="OA17320809n14-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n14-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n14-1" type="surname" value="TIPPING"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n14-1" type="given" value="DANIEL"/>Daniel Tipping</persName> had the same Exhortations and godly Advices with all the rest, when they were under Sentence, which we shall not repeat here. I attended him in Chappel, and exhorted him to a serious Preparation for Death, from these Words, Mark the perfect Man, and behold the upright: for the End of that Man is Peace. Psalms, xxxvii. 37. From which Words I show'd him, that after all the vain Pursuits Men may pretend to have in enquiring after happiness; the only solid Ground and Foundation of attaining Felicity, is holiness in all manner of Life and Conversation, for without holiness no Man can see the Lord: The Reflection upon a Life well Spent, is the only Angel can give us comfort in a dying Hour; it is not the great Estates we have conquer'd, nor the numerous Honours and Employments we have gone through which can then afford us any Content or Satisfaction; but the only Thing which then can give us any Pleasure or Delight, is the Reflection upon the Innocency of our Life past, and the good Works we have done. I represented to him how terrible a Thing it is for a wicked Man to think, when Death approaches and his Fate is inevitable, how idlely and unprofitably, how viciously and profligately he hath spent his Time, in doing Mischief to his fellow Creatures, and in ruining and demolishing the common Interest of Mankind; but more especially, in offending and displeasing the great God, in breaking his Laws and contemning his Ordinances; how could he then ex</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA173208090004"/>
            <p>expect to meet with any Comfort, with any thing which could afford him the least ground of Contentment, when all the Riches, all the Pleasures, all the Satisfactions, all the conveniencies of this Life are insipid and unsatisfactory; when all the Supports, all the Friends and these upon whom we rely'd, have deserted and are no ways profitable unto us? And then nothing presents itself to our view, but a Death's-Head, and Beltechazzar's writing upon the Wall, Summoning us to appear before God this Night, yea this very Moment, and before him to render an Account of all the Actions done in the Body, whether good or bad; and what a terrible thing is it, when the wicked Man hath not made his Peace with God, to fall into the Hands of the Almighty, and to be expos'd to that fiery Wrath and Indignation, which shall devour the Adversary, when one is no ways thinking upon, or expecting such a terrible Judgment? From that Text, Rev. xiv. xiii. And I heard a Voice from Heaven, saying unto me, write, blessed are the dead which die in the Lord, from henceforth: Yea, saith the Spirit, that they may rest from their Labours, and their works do follow them. From this I say, I show'd them what it is to die, and that in the Lord, which is to die in conformity unto Christ Jesus, who (while he was in this World) went about doing good, Acts x. xxxviii. As a good Life gives us Peace at our last Hour; so it will give us some assurance of our everlasting Peace and Happiness; with what strange delight and satisfaction, does a good Man at the approach of Death, reflect upon the good he had done in his Life! those joys and consolations, which before maintain'd a gentle course within their own Channels, now begin to swell above the Banks and overflow the Man. But then I represented to him, on the other Hand, what a dismal thing it is for a wicked Man to reflect upon a Life ill spent. Behind him he sees nothing but Murders, Adulteries, Whoredoms, Uncleanness, Robberies, Thefts, Drunkenness, Blasphemous Oaths, Perjuries, Lies, Profligate, and the worst of Company, enticing and advising him, to commit these and many such like abominations. When the wicked Man looks before him, he sees nothing but a Prospect of certain Wrath and Judgment, which shall devour the Adversary; the Devils is his Tormentors, wicked and damned Men and Women for his Companions, and lakes of Fire and</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA173208090005"/>
            <p>Brimstone for his Portion, and that for ever and ever; and O what a dreadful thing is it to fall into the Hands of the living God! yet notwithstanding of all this I exhorted him, for his encouragement, not to despair of the Mercy of God; but to hear what is the Answer of God, by his Servant the Prophet, to the wicked Jews saying, If our transgressions and our Sins be upon us, and we pine away in them, how shall we then Live! Say unto them, as I live, saith the Lord God, I have no pleasure in the Death of the Wicked, but that the Wicked turn from his way and Live: Turn ye, turn ye from your evil ways; for why will ye die, O House of Israel? Ezek. xxxiii. x, xi. I show'd him, that here the Lord engag'd himself by a solemn Oath, to protect and pardon all true Penitents: He Swears, or Promises, or Protests, by his Life, i. e. by himself, that he hath no pleasure in the Death of Sinners; as I live, saith the Lord God, I have no pleasure in the Death of the Wicked, &amp;c. As if God had said, I have no delight in the Destruction of the Miserable, in the Ruin of those who have undone themselves; but my great design is, to save those who have destroy'd themselves, to rescue them from the Jaws of Hell, and eternal destruction.</p>
            <p>I desir'd him to consider how often, how seriously Christ is inviting Sinners to come, i. e. to believe in him; O! every one that thirsteth, come ye to the Waters, &amp;c. Isaiah, lv. i. And whosoever will, let him take the water of Life freely. Rev. xxii. xvii. In the last Day, Jesus stood, and cryed, saying, if any Man thirst, let him come unto me and Drink. He that believeth on me, as the Scripture hath said, out of his Belly shall flow Rivers of living Water. St. John, 7. 37, 38. What more pressing motives; what more earnest invitations than these, can we possibly have from Jesus Christ; to forsake our Sins and come to him, that we may become partakers of everlasting Life? From those considerations I exhorted him to believe in Christ; that he underwent a laborious, troublesome, despicable Life, having been reproached, harrassed and persecuted by his inveterate Enemies, on all Hands, environing and oppressing him; that he suffered a cursed, shameful and ignominious Death, upon the Cross for his Sins: That he rose again from the Dead, upon the third Day, for our Justification,</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA173208090006"/>
            <p>i. e. that our Justification or the work of our Salvation might be compleated: By his resurrection, Christ declar'd himself to be the Son of God with Power, that he was the Sovereign Lord of Life and Death; that by his Death and Resurrection, he triumphed over him that had the power of Death, i. e. the Devil; that he had obtain'd a compleat Victory over the Kingdom, and Power of Satan, and purchased a right unto eternal Life for all them who believe him.</p>
            <p>I instructed him also that we must believe, that Christ ascended into Heaven, where he is now sitting at the right hand of God the Father, pleading and interceeding for the Pardon of our Sins; for as the Apostle saith, if we have Sinned, we have an advocate with the Father, Jesus Christ the righteous, &amp;c. 1. John. 2. 1. And this Faith in Christ must be attended with good Works, for Faith without Works is Dead, being alone St. James, 2. 16.</p>
            <p>I also instructed him, how that his committing Theft and Robbery made him an avow'd Enemy to God and Man, and such a course of Life was detrimental to, and destructive of all Human Society. The Fact for which he died, having been in a manner Murther joined to Robbery, I expos'd to him the great Evil of that horrid Sin of Murder, how unnatural, how pernicious, how barbarous it was to destroy the living Image of the living God; and what Confidence could any Man guilty of such barbarity, expect Mercy from God, who had shown no Commiseration upon his fellow Creatures.</p>
            <p>I also took special Care to instruct him in the Christian Sacrament, how necessary it was to renew himself by Repentance, and to dedicate himself a new to God, in the Sacrament of the Lord's Supper; since, in the preceeding part of his Life, he had so far forsaken God, and gone astray from the Obedience of his Laws.</p>
            <p>While these and many like Instructions were advanced, he behaved decently, and was attentive to Prayers and Exhortations, and failed not to make regular responses, yet he did not appear to be so tender and broken hearted, as became one in his most deplorable Circumstances. When the dead Warrant first came down against him, he wept and shed abundance of Tears, but afterwards knowing of a Re</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA173208090007"/>
            <p>prieve, when he thought upon nothing but Death, next Morning he turn'd a little more indifferent; although he was never outragious in his Carriage, as that set of Men are too ready to be: After some Days loosing all hopes of any further Reprieve; he turn'd very penitent to Appearance, and as he declar'd, tho' he seemed a little too daring and hard-hearted.</p>
            <p>
               <persName id="OA17320809n24-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n24-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n24-1" type="surname" value="TIPPING"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n24-1" type="given" value="DANIEL"/>Daniel Tipping</persName>, was indicted for assaulting (with <persName id="OA17320809n24-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n24-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n24-2" type="surname" value="PLUMRIDGE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n24-2" type="given" value="JAMES"/>James Plumridge</persName> not yet taken) <persName id="OA17320809n24-3">
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n24-3" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n24-3" type="surname" value="LUMM"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n24-3" type="given" value="JOSHUA"/>Joshua Lumm</persName> in a a Field, near the Highway, in the Parish of <placeName id="OA17320809-geo-9">
                  <interp inst="OA17320809-geo-9" type="type" value="parish"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17320809n24-1 n24-2 n24-3 OA17320809-geo-9"/>Stepney</placeName>, putting, him in Fear, and taking from him a Cloth Coat, value 3 l. a Hat, value 10 s. a Wig, value 40 s. a Silk Handkerchief, and 19 s. in Money, on Sunday the 18th of June last, near 11 o'Clock at Night.</p>
            <p>
               <persName id="OA17320809n25-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n25-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n25-1" type="surname" value="TIPPING"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n25-1" type="given" value="DANIEL"/>Daniel Tipping</persName> 22 Years of Age, of honest creditable Parents in Town, had Education at School, in reading, writing, and Accompts, to fit him for Business; and was instructed in the Principles of our Holy Faith. When of Age, he was put out <rs id="OA17320809-occupation-6" type="occupation">Apprentice to a Poulterer</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17320809n25-1 OA17320809-occupation-6"/> in <placeName id="OA17320809-geo-10">
                  <interp inst="OA17320809-geo-10" type="type" value="site"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17320809n25-1 OA17320809-geo-10"/>Newgate Market</placeName>, and serv'd good part of his Time to the liking of his Master, as at his Trial, he gave in Evidence in favour of him. He turn'd unruly and obstreperous, and his Master not liking to make himself uneasy, was willing to part with him, and suffer'd him to go <rs id="OA17320809-occupation-7" type="occupation">to Sea</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17320809n25-1 OA17320809-occupation-7"/>. Accordingly he went a Voyage to <placeName id="OA17320809-geo-11">
                  <interp inst="OA17320809-geo-11" type="type" value="region"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17320809n25-1 OA17320809-geo-11"/>China</placeName>, and returned last Year, having been recommended to the Captain's Care, who was a good Man, and kept him right while he was at Sea. But it seems he had contracted Acquaintance with black guards, thieves and pick-pockets, before he went abroad, and that kind of Company he loved best, preferring them to any settled Business or Imployment, by which he might have liv'd in a virtuous and industrious Way.</p>
            <p>He liv'd for some Time by keeping and killing Fowls, and carrying them about the Streets, and selling them to Master Poulterers.</p>
            <p>He needed not have wanted for any Thing, having had his Mothers House to go to, who was concern'd for and took a special Care of him; but his following after bad Company, of the worst Set of Men and Women about the Town, prov'd his Ruin.</p>
            <p>His Father-in-law, his Master to whom he was Apprentice, and another Master whom he had serv'd</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA173208090008"/>
            <p>for a considerable Time, in overseeing his Business of a Poulterer, gave him a very good Character of his honesty, and said, that they had intrusted him in their Houses at all Times, and particularly with large Sums of Money, sometimes to the Value of a hundred Pounds, which he had pay'd for them, without embezelling one Farthin: They added farther, that was he set at Liberty, they would trust him with all their Affairs, and any Sum of Money, as soon as any other Man whatsoever.</p>
            <p>Beside them a great Number of other Men, who appear'd to be People of respect, gave him an excellent Character, and declar'd they knew no ill of him; and many more were ready to make the same Declaration in his Favour, if it had been thought needful; but such Evidence could not do much Service, against a clear Proof of a notorious Fact and most barbarous Crime, of which he was convicted.</p>
            <p>As to the particular Fact of which he was convicted, he continued to deny the same, till such Time as the dead Warrant came out against him, and then he confessed his Crime with Tears in his Eyes, and own'd himself guilty, and that he suffer'd deservedly for such a vile and cruel Action.</p>
            <p>The Account he gave was, that he accidentally met with Buck in the Street, who persuaded him to go along with him to <placeName id="OA17320809-geo-12">
                  <interp inst="OA17320809-geo-12" type="type" value="street"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17320809n25-1 OA17320809-geo-12"/>Drury-Lane</placeName>, where Buck's Sister would entertain them, though they wanted Money. Accordingly they went and were treated by her, and they stay'd so late in Company, that Tipping was content to lie that Night with Buck, who in the Morning went out upon Pretence of getting his Wig powder'd: This gave some uneasiness to Daniel, but the Sister persuaded him to stay till her Brother's Return, who in the mean Time had gone before a Justice, and sworn the Robbery against Tipping, for which he died.</p>
            <p>After this they haunted and kept by Tipping, upon one Pretence or another, till such Time as they found proper Persons to apprehend him, and carry him before a Justice, who committed him to <placeName id="OA17320809-geo-13">
                  <interp inst="OA17320809-geo-13" type="type" value="site"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17320809n25-1 OA17320809-geo-13"/>Newgate</placeName>, where he was kept till he was brought to condign Punishment.</p>
            <p>All this, and a much larger Account he gave, was nothing but Fiction; it was true thus far, that</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA173208090009"/>
            <p>he was in Company with Buck and his Sister, a little before he was taken up, and that they laid the design of bringing Tipping to justice, and by that means to save Buck, but his telling the Story, as if Buck and his Sister had contrived the whole Affair against him, only to save himself, in whose Power it was to Swear Tipping's Life away, because of their intimate familiarity, this (I say) was utterly false, for Tipping was present and assisted in the Robbery of <persName id="OA17320809n35-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n35-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n35-1" type="surname" value="LUMM"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n35-1" type="given" value="JOSHUA"/>Joshua Lumm</persName>, as will appear in his after-confession.</p>
            <p>I exhorted and endeavoured by many Arguments and Reasons to persuade him to a full Cofession of his Sins; but after all could be said, he continued obstinate and inflexible in denying the Fact, till all hope of Safety was past.</p>
            <p>Two or three Days before he died, he own'd to me that he was equally guilty with the other two, viz. Buck and Plumridge, who is gone out of the way, in commiting the Robbery upon, and abusing of Mr. Lumm. This Account was to this purpose.</p>
            <p>That on Sunday the 18th of June last, Buck, Plumridge, and he meeting together, they went to a Brandy Shop, where they stay'd and din'd with the Landlord, and after Dinner they drank liberally at the Punch, till they were pretty well elevated, then towards Night, finding their Pockets light, and that the Money was gone, taking a large Dram, like so many unchain'd Dogs, they went out towards <placeName id="OA17320809-geo-14">
                  <interp inst="OA17320809-geo-14" type="type" value="parish"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17320809n25-1 n24-2 OA17320809-geo-14"/>White-Chapel</placeName> and <placeName id="OA17320809-geo-15">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17320809n25-1 n24-2 OA17320809-geo-15"/>Stepney-fields</placeName>, being fully resolved to Attack the first Person they met, of whom they had any hopes of getting any plunder.</p>
            <p>The first Man they saw, of whom they thought it probable any good could be had, was <persName id="OA17320809n39-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n39-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n39-1" type="surname" value="LUMM"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n39-1" type="given" value="JOSHUA"/>Joshua Lumm</persName>, who had been in the City visitting some of his Friends, one of them laid hand upon him, and desired him to deliver his Money, he was not very willing to comply with their Demands; then Plumridge took a Knife, which he had taken out of the House where they had been drinking immediately before, and with it cut him desperately across the Throat, next he cut his Nose, and then he gave him a great Wound upon the Face; they design'd next to draw him over the Bank, and Plumridge and Tipping dragg'd him violently to the Bank, but finding themselves unable to throw him over, or him not willing or capable to pass over, Buck came</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA173208090010"/>
            <p>behind and struck him most furiously upon the Head several times, with a Stick which he had in his Hand, till at last he being wounded in several places of the Head, having lost great quantities of Blood, in several Parts of the Body, he knock'd him down to the Ground, and he lost his Senses, being almost wholly dead; and to aggravate the Villany more and more; Plumridge with a Knife, wounded him in the middle of the back, cut through his Coat and all his Cloaths, and made the Blood gush out; I ask'd him, if he did any Acts of Violence, or if he had a Stick? he said, he had a Stick, which he threw away, that he had no offensive Weapons about him, neither Pistols, Swords nor Knives; and that he did no acts of Violence to the Prosecutor, saving that he and Plumridge drag'd him to the Bank, where he was knock'd down, and otherwise barbarously treated by the other two, as is above related.</p>
            <p>He said also, that had it not been for him, he believ'd they had actually Murther'd the Prosecutor, and left him dead upon the Spot, and that he endeavour'd, what he could, to dissuade them from beating and slashing him unmercifully, for which they were like to fall out, and to take Vengeance upon him, for speaking any Way in Favour of the distress'd wounded Man.</p>
            <p>I told him, that he was equally guilty with the rest, by being engag'd in combination with them, and going out upon such unlawful and wicked Enterprizes in their Company; and that he ought to repent of Murther, as well as Theft and Robbery, since it was nothing but an indulgent Providence, which kept the Prosecutor from being kill'd, or murder'd, or from dying of his Wounds.</p>
            <p>The Truth of all this he own'd, and that his Sentence was most just, since he was present at, assisted in, and upon the Main approv'd of their villainous and cruel Deed, only in extenuation of his Guilt; he alledg'd that the Evidence swore against him, those Acts of Violence which he himself did; otherwise he acknowledg'd that he was guilty of the Indictment, and suffer'd most justly for being concern'd in such villainous Attempts.</p>
            <p>He denied that at any other Time he had robbed or thiev'd, except</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA173208090011"/>
            <p>ing this Instance, but what Credit can be given very often to the Confessions of such People, we leave it to every Man to judge upon, as he thinks fit.</p>
            <p>I told him, that what he said now, was in the Presence of God, before whom in a few Minutes he must appear, and that lying was an adding of Sin to Sin, and iniquity unto transgression, which would certainly aggravate his Condemnation, if he did not Repent. He said, that all he alledg'd, was spoken as before God, and that it might be depended upon for a Truth.</p>
            <p>He had certainly been a very wicked, profligate, young Man, and his ruin was owing to the Company of bad Women, and the worst Set of young Men.</p>
            <p>While under Sentence, in the Company of his Companions, he told that once he lay all Night with a Woman, and rising early in the Morning, he bid her lie still and sleep a little, till he came in again; but he thought fit to take Madam's Stays, and to truss them and her Cloaths all together, and then to carry them off, and sell them for Money, to provide himself in Punch and other Liquors; but he never saw the Way back again to Madam, but left her to provide Cloathing the best Way she could.</p>
            <p>On Sunday the 23d of July last, as he went from Chapel to the Cells, beholding some People looking through the Grate, he ran furiously, and snatched a Pail of Water which he threw upon them; this did not seem to be a very proper Diversion for one in his pitiful Circumstances,</p>
            <p>On Sunday, the 6th of this Instant August, his Mother came to take her leave of him; they embraced each other, and cry'd in a most lamentable Manner, so that it was hard to get them parted, and all the Spectators were mov'd with the highest Sympathie, at the beholding of such a doleful Sight.</p>
            <p>N. B. It is expected, that in christian Charity, no Body will reflect upon the Parents or Relations of this unfortunate young Man, who are People of an excellent Character and unblemish'd Reputation.</p>
            <p>
               <persName id="OA17320809n52-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n52-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n52-1" type="surname" value="Ellement"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n52-1" type="given" value="Robert"/>Robert Ellement</persName> who was executed the 26th of July last, Tip</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA173208090012"/>
            <p>ping and several others of those wicked Gangs, desir'd to take Notice, that there is a House in the Parish of St. Giles's in the Fields, not far from the Church, which is a common Receptacle for all the Robbers, Thieves and Whores, in and about the Town, and that the Parish-Officers would do well to take Notice of it, and endeavour to get it supprest.</p>
            <p>
               <persName id="OA17320809n54-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n54-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n54-1" type="surname" value="TIPPING"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n54-1" type="given" value="DANIEL"/>Daniel Tipping</persName>, always behav'd well in Chapel, but not with so much Seriousness, as might be desir'd: Some Days before he died, he exprest much more Penitence than he had formerly done, but this was, when all hopes of any further Reprieve were quite over.</p>
            <p>Upon Sunday the 23d of July last, when Chapel was over in the Afternoon, some of his Friends having come to visit him, he was allow'd to wait upon them a little in an empty Room, in the Pressyard Side: Among others, a Butcher took him by the Hand, and spoke to him with a deal of Sympathy, pray'd for his Soul, and gave him godly Advices, to double his Diligence, in his Preparations for Eternity; for although afterwards he was repriev'd for a Fortnight, yet then the Day of his Execution was appointed on Wednesday following: While the poor Man was thus addressing himself to him, Tipping quickly snatch'd the Butcher's Knife by his Side, and pointed it backwards towards his Belly: The Man was mightily surpriz'd and affrighted, and taking hold of Tipping's Hand, he oblig'd him to drop the Knife, which the Butcher broke in several Pieces, and then threw it away, and thanked God for his Deliverance.</p>
            <p>I ask'd him, what mov'd him to do so? He said, he only did it out of a Joke, which was common among the Butchers, and that he had no ill Design. This appear'd a very unseasonable Jest, for one in his miserable Circumstances, having immediately before pretended to resign and give up himself wholly to God. But we leave every Man to judge upon this, as his charitable Sentiments shall direct him. He declar'd, that he hop'd for Salvation through Christ, sincerely repented of all his Sins, particularly the henious Sins of his Life, and that for which he died; and that he was in perfect Peace with all Men.</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA173208090013"/>
            <p>At the Place of EXECUTION.</p>
            <p>' HE was serious in his ' Devotions, and singing of Psalms. He had no ' more to add to his former ' Confessions; only he said, ' he hop'd God would have ' Mercy upon him for Christ's ' Sake, and that he had ' us'd his utmost endeavours ' to make his peace with ' God. He desir'd young ' People to take example ' from his fall, to keep the ' Lord's Day, to shun evil ' Company, and to keep ' God's Laws. After Prayers were ended, he desir'd ' the Spectators to take notice, that he freely forgave ' Buck and his Sister, for ' causing him to be taken up, ' and commencing Evidence ' against him. Then he said ' he hop'd God would receive him to his Eternal rest. ' He went off the Stage, ' crying out, God have Mercy upon me, a miserable ' Sinner, and Lord Jesus receive my Spirit.</p>
            <p>This is all the Account given by me <persName id="OA17320809n59-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n59-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n59-1" type="surname" value="Gutherie"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n59-1" type="given" value="James"/>James Gutherie</persName>, <rs id="OA17320809-occupation-8" type="occupation">Ordinary</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17320809n59-1 OA17320809-occupation-8"/> of <placeName id="OA17320809-geo-16">
                  <interp inst="OA17320809-geo-16" type="type" value="site"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17320809n59-1 OA17320809-geo-16"/>Newgate</placeName>.</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA173208090014"/>
            <p>A Paper left by <persName id="OA17320809n60-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n60-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n60-1" type="surname" value="TIPPING"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320809n60-1" type="given" value="DANIEL"/>Daniel Tipping</persName>.</p>
            <p>' Custom has made it necessary for Persons in ' my unhappy Condition, ' to say something at the Place ' of Death, or to leave somewhat behind them in writing, in order to satisfy the ' Curiosity of those who are ' either Spectators of their ' melancholly End, or desire to be acquainted from ' the Criminal himself of his ' Fate.</p>
            <p>' That no fictitious Account therefore may at once ' impose upon the Publick ' and add to the number of ' those real Offences I have ' committed; a Catalogue of ' imaginary Crimes; I declare ' that with the utmost sincerity, I have confess'd them ' to the proper Person, who ' I suppose will Publish what ' is alone concerning me.</p>
            <p>' Yet as my miserable and ' ignominious Death will reflect Shame on all who have ' any relation to me, so I ' conceive it my Duty; the ' last Duty indeed that I am ' capable of expressing to my ' Parents, to declare in the ' most solemn Manner, that ' not thro' their Faults or Omissions, but thro' my own ' corrupt inclinations and ' headstrong Passions; I have ' provoked the heavy Vengeance of God, manifested in ' the just Judgment of the ' Law. Had I had Grace to ' improved the care taken in ' my Education, and to have ' preserved those early principles of Piety, with which</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA173208090015"/>
            <p>' my tender Youth was season'd. I had escaped the ' bitterness of this unnatural ' Death, and what is still ' more bitter the stings of a ' tormented Conscience. But ' since I have given my self ' over to work Wickedness, ' and by quitting the Path of ' Virtue and Honesty, have ' drawn such a Weight of ' Shame and Misery on my ' self, let it not be thrown ' back on my unhappy Parents, (especially my poor ' Mother) but as my Death ' will satisfy the Law; let it ' also satisfy the Tongues of ' Mankind and prevent their ' adding to that load of Sorrow which without deserving, it those from whom I ' desire my Birth already bear.</p>
            <p>' How little soever it is in ' my Power to benefit the ' Publick; yet with the last ' moments of my Breath, I ' will endeavour it, by earnestly exciting all young ' Persons who as yet have ' indulged themselves in unlawful Pleasures to set my ' Example before them and ' from the terror of my Death ' amend their Lives.</p>
            <p>' Almighty God to whom ' I owe my being, have Mercy on thy Creature, who ' is coming into thy Presence, ' without Hope, without ' Comfort, and without Expectation of forgiveness; but ' from the infinite goodness ' of thy Son, my Saviour, ' who died for Sinners, and ' shed his Blood for their Redemption; Lord Jesus intercede for Me at the ' Throne of Grace; Lord ' Pitty thy dying Servant; ' O God receive my Soul! ' Christ Jesus accept my Spirit.</p>
         </div0>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>