<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<TEI.2>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div0 type="ordinarysAccount" id="OA17001106">
            <interp inst="OA17001106" type="uri" value="ordinarysAccounts/OA17001106"/>
            <interp inst="OA17001106" type="date" value="17001106"/>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA170011060001"/>
            <p>An Account of the Behaviour and Confessions of the Condemn'd Criminals that were Executed at Tyburn on Wednesday November the Sixth, 1700.</p>
            <p>MR Wykes, the late Ordinary of Newgate Prison, being deceased, I was appointed (during the Vacancy) to attend the Prisoners there, and accordingly on Saturday last, being the second instant, I began to visit them. I then pray'd with them, and exhorted them to Repentance; using to that purpose all the Arguments I could think proper to work them into a just sense of their miserable Estate, &amp;c.</p>
            <p>On the Lord's Day I Preach'd to them both in the Fore and Afternoon, and took my Text out of 1 Cor. 15. 24. which was in these Words; Awake to Righteousness, and Sin not. From which I shew'd them, 1st the mischievous Consequences of Sin, 2. The necessity of Repentance, 3. The means of effecting it, and obtaining Pardon of God.</p>
            <p>On Monday I attended them again, and continued Exhorting, and Instructing, and Praying with them. And then proceeded to an Exhortation of each of them in particular; adapting at the same time, Admonitions suitable to their respective Cases. Now I thought them to be Penitent, and willing to endeavour after the obtaining that state of Grace, which I had shewed them they must be in, before they were fit to enter into that of everlasting Happiness and Glory. They sighed mightily, and grown'd and shed Tears: But would not confess, but obstinately deny'd their Crimes. They had told me the Day before, namely the last Lord's Day, that <persName id="OA17001106n5-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17001106n5-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17001106n5-1" type="surname" value="PAYNE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17001106n5-1" type="given" value="THOMAS"/>Thomas Payne</persName> (one of the Condemned Prisoners, and a <rs id="OA17001106-occupation-1" type="occupation">Papist</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17001106n5-1 OA17001106-occupation-1"/>) desired to receive some Instructions from me, that very Afternoon, in the Lodge, and now they repeated that Request again to me, who told them that I was very willing to give him the satisfaction and Instruction he desired; and therefore intended immediately to follow them to the Lodge. But by the good Providence of God, which I humbly acknowledge, and am thankful for, staying behind a little longer than I purposedly design'd, and they expected; when I came down, I found they were all in an uproar in the Lodge, where they offer'd violence to the Officers about them, and took some Persons into the Hold, where they kept them all Night. To repress this Mutiny, and make these Prisoners governable, the Officers were forc'd to fire several times upon them. And then it was that one of the Criminals, <persName id="OA17001106n5-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17001106n5-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17001106n5-2" type="surname" value="BROWN"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17001106n5-2" type="given" value="MICHAEL"/>Michael Brown</persName> by Name, was killed with a Bullet.</p>
            <p>On the Tuesday I went to speak to them in the Morning, but could not perswade them into a sober sense. In the Afternoon they were now willing to come and meet me in the Chappel; but it was not thought safe they should then be remov'd out of the Hold, least they should again grow Rebellous and troublesom.</p>
            <p>On this Day I went to them betimes in the Morning, and had them in the Chappel, I made a short Exhortation to them, and then prayed for them suitably to their Conditions. I was forc'd to be very succint for fear of fresh Disturbance. They were carried down again, and being a little while after put into several Carts, and conducted to <placeName id="OA17001106-geo-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17001106-geo-1" type="type" value="site"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17001106n8-1 n9-1 n10-1 n11-1 n12-1 n14-1 n15-1 n16-1 OA17001106-geo-1"/>Tyburn</placeName>, I met them at that place of Execution to assist them with my last Admonitions and Prayers: when they were seeing themselves upon the brink of Death, they made more open Confessions than before; which are as followeth,</p>
            <p>I. <persName id="OA17001106n8-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17001106n8-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17001106n8-1" type="surname" value="SLAUGHTER"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17001106n8-1" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Slaughter</persName>, Condemn'd for Robbing on the High-way. He was Born in <placeName id="OA17001106-geo-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17001106-geo-2" type="type" value="region"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA17001106n8-1 OA17001106-geo-2"/>Ireland</placeName>, and <rs id="OA17001106-occupation-2" type="occupation">Apprentice to a Smith</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17001106n8-1 OA17001106-occupation-2"/> there. He went from his Master, and listed himself a <rs id="OA17001106-occupation-3" type="occupation">Soldier</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17001106n8-1 OA17001106-occupation-3"/>. He confest he had been a most notorious Offender; That he was much given to Wine and Women; That about a Twelve-month since he killed a Serjeant of the King's Guard on <placeName id="OA17001106-geo-3">
                  <interp inst="OA17001106-geo-3" type="type" value="site"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA17001106n8-1 OA17001106-geo-3"/>Tower-hill</placeName>; That he had committed many and grievous Crimes; and now was heartily sorry for them, and particularly for that he stood condemn'd for; begging God's Pardon from his Heart, and desiring the Pardon of all he had injur'd. Now he seem'd to struggle mightily against his corrupt Nature, and to be truly Penitent. He earnestly cry'd to God for Mercy in Jesus Christ.</p>
            <p>II. <persName id="OA17001106n9-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17001106n9-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17001106n9-1" type="surname" value="SPELL"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17001106n9-1" type="given" value="WILLIAM"/>William Spell</persName>, A <rs id="OA17001106-occupation-4" type="occupation">Waterman</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17001106n9-1 OA17001106-occupation-4"/>, Condemn'd for Felony and Burglary, own'd his having been a great Sinner, and justly brought to this condign Punishment. He at last particularly confess'd himself guilty of the Fact for which he was Condemn'd; and prayed that God for Christ's sake would forgive him all his Sins.</p>
            <p>III. <persName id="OA17001106n10-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17001106n10-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17001106n10-1" type="surname" value="PATRICKSON"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17001106n10-1" type="given" value="ROBERT"/>Robert Patrickson</persName>, Condemn'd for Felony and Burglary. He confest he was guilty of this and several other Crimes; for which he earnestly askt Pardon of God, and those Persons he had wrong'd.</p>
            <p>IV. <persName id="OA17001106n11-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17001106n11-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17001106n11-1" type="surname" value="TURNER"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17001106n11-1" type="given" value="THOMAS"/>Thomas Turner</persName>, Condemn'd for Robbing on the High-ways, acknowledged that he had committed many sins, of which he heartily repented, and particularly of that he was to die for. He implored God's boundless Mercy thro' the infinite Merits of Christ.</p>
            <p>V. <persName id="OA17001106n12-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17001106n12-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17001106n12-1" type="surname" value="FIELD"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17001106n12-1" type="given" value="THOMAS"/>Thomas Field</persName>, being also Condemn'd for Robbing on the High ways, bewail'd his lamentable Condition. He confest he was guilty of many Miscarriages, and acknowledged the Ju</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA170011060002"/>
            <p>stice of God towards him. And at last owned in particular, his having committed the Fact that had brought him to this sad and untimely Death.</p>
            <p>VI. <persName id="OA17001106n14-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17001106n14-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17001106n14-1" type="surname" value="HUGGINS"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17001106n14-1" type="given" value="THOMAS"/>Thomas Huggins</persName>, Condemned for Felony and Robbery. I found this Person to have been well brought up, and to know better things than he practised. He was but a young Man, but had been a great Offender, and much hardned in sin. At last he was (I hope) melted into true Repentance, and confessed he was justly Condemned and Punished.</p>
            <p>VII. <persName id="OA17001106n15-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17001106n15-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17001106n15-1" type="surname" value="ARTHUR"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17001106n15-1" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Arthur</persName>, Condemned for Felony and Burglary. He acknowledged his Sins to have been many and great, and most grievous; and in particular. owned himself guilty of the Robbery for which he was now justly to suffer. He prayed God would Pardon him for Christs sake, and desired also their Pardon whom he had done wrong to.</p>
            <p>VIII. <persName id="OA17001106n16-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17001106n16-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17001106n16-1" type="surname" value="PAYNE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17001106n16-1" type="given" value="THOMAS"/>Thomas Payne</persName>, Condemned for Robbing on the High-ways. He was an Irish-man, and of the <rs id="OA17001106-occupation-5" type="occupation">Romish Religion</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17001106n16-1 OA17001106-occupation-5"/>. He declared he had Lived, and now Died in that Communion. He seemed however to take my Admonitions in good part, and to be satisfied in a Point that then fell in my way to take notice of to him. As soon as he was come to the Gallows, one brought some certain Garments for him to put on. But it being found improper that he should strip himself, and shift his Cloaths, in that Place: He bemoaned himself mightily that he was not at liberty to put on Holy Garments before he died. Then I took occasion to tell him, That it mattered not what the Garments were his Body was covered with, provided he had his Soul cloathed with the Righteousness of Christ, and obtained his Grace and Pardon here, in order to future Joy and Glory hereafter. He seemed to be Penitent, and owned he was justly Condemned. He prayed God, and all the World to forgive him, and declared that he died in Charity with all Men.</p>
            <p>There was another Condemnrd Prisoner, namely, <persName id="OA17001106n17-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17001106n17-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17001106n17-1" type="surname" value="BROWN"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17001106n17-1" type="given" value="MICHAEL"/>Michael Brown</persName>, that should have been Executed with these 8 Persons, but he received his Death before, being (as I have said killed in the Fray that hapned in the <placeName id="OA17001106-geo-4">
                  <interp inst="OA17001106-geo-4" type="type" value="site"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17001106n17-1 n5-2 OA17001106-geo-4"/>Lodge at Newgate</placeName>, on Munday last. He was then but just gone from me, and I had wrought more on him than on any of the rest at that time; for he not only confest with Tears, that he was a gret Sinner, and undone for ever, unless God was pleased to shew Mercy to him, which he earnestly implored: But he also ingenuously acknowledged that he was justly Condemned. He had first declared to me, That he was born of Protestant Parents, but in his Travels had changed his Religion, and turned <rs id="OA17001106-occupation-6" type="occupation">Papist</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17001106n17-1 n5-2 OA17001106-occupation-6"/>, and now owned that he was in a great measure convinced of his Error, and would desire some farther Discourse with me about it before he Died. Thus far he was brought towards a Reformation, both in his Principles and Manners, when Death met him before he was aware of it.</p>
            <p>This is the Account, which the short time I had to be with the Criminals above-named has enabled me to give of them. They all confest the respective Crimes for which they now suffered, and seemed to to be all of them very Penitent. I hope their Repentance (though late) was Sincere, and that our Good and Gracious God had Mercy on their Souls.</p>
            <p>Dated, Nov. 6. 1700.</p>
            <p>
               <persName id="OA17001106n20-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17001106n20-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17001106n20-1" type="surname" value="LORRAIN"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17001106n20-1" type="given" value="PAUL"/>Paul Lorrain</persName>.</p>
            <p>ADVERTISEMENTS.</p>
            <p>Francklin, who Cup't at the Hummums in Covent-garden for many Years, without the use of Fire; any Persons having occasion for him, he is ready to attend them at their Chambers, and is to be heard of at the Crown in Charles-street Covent-garden, not at the Hummums, by reason they have Prejudice against me.</p>
            <p>AT the farthest House on the Left-hand, in Blew-ball Court, in Salisbuy-Court, Feet-street, (being the first Court on the Left-hand over against Salisbury-Square) Gentlemen, &amp;c. may heaven Interest made to Invest them in Places suitable to their Capacities. We have several good Places now to dispose of in Town and Country, some for Life, from 300 l. to 50 l. a Year; for those who are good Clerks and Accomptants. We speedily and faithfully Sollicite all sorts of Business, in the Courts of Law and Equity, Treasury, Navy-Offices, &amp;c. Persons may have what Sums they please on good Mortgages. We Buy and Sell Estates, Houses, Ground-Rents, &amp;c. For farther particulars, we refer to our larger Bills. To prevent the Publicks being impos'd on, we think fit to add; That this Office is composed of a Society of Gentlemen of Quality, &amp;c. established by a Deed of Settlement, who are pleas'd to employ some near Relations of Mr. C - Deceased, who was the original Undertaker of this Business upwards of 30 Years ago, who have carried it on ever since his Decease, all other Pretenders to our Business being Upstarts, not of a Years standing. Attendance is given at the place aforesaid, by the Sub-Agents of this Office, by whom Persons may be conducted to the chief Manager's principal Office.</p>
            <p>B. Lilburn, that lately Lived on Ludgate-hill, next to the Kings Arms Tavern near Fleet-Bridge, now Lives at the Golden-Board, and Ball, near the Globe-Tavern, in little Moor-fields, near great Moor-gate, up one Pair of Stairs. Who maketh and selleth, (and has done above 16 Years) the Water for taking away the Freckels Pimple, Worms, and Morphew in the Face: With Elixir Salutis, Balsamum Vitae, Tinctura Vitae. Waters and Ointments for the Eyes, and Ointments for sore Nipples; Ointments for the Rickets, Burns, Scalds, Wounds, Aches, Strains, &amp;c. Powders, Dentrifices, Elixirs, Essences, Oils, Spirits, &amp;c. both for Ornament, and Curing most Distempers incident to Humane Bodies; where you may have Advice as well as Medicines, likewise Judgment upon Urine.</p>
            <p>The Water for the Freckles, Pimples, &amp;c. The Author has for some Years past, left with several for Sale; and now doth understand, they have been abused by Counterfeits; which to prevent for the future, doth desire those who have bought from them - and not found the Effects answer the Ends for which it is proposed, to acquaint her with it, and where they bought it and likewise to take notice of the Seal, viz. The 3 Water-budgets, and B. L. on the top of the Seal. The Price of the half Pint-bottle 3s.</p>
            <p>London. Printed for E. Mallet, at the Hat and Hawk in Bride-Lane. 1700.</p>
         </div0>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>