<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<TEI.2>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div0 type="ordinarysAccount" id="OA17121223">
            <interp inst="OA17121223" type="uri" value="ordinarysAccounts/OA17121223"/>
            <interp inst="OA17121223" type="date" value="17121223"/>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA171212230001"/>
            <p>THE Ordinary of NEWGATE HIS ACCOUNT OF The Behaviour, Confessions, and Last Speeches of the Malefactors that were Executed at Tyburn, on Tuesday the 23d Day of December, 1712.</p>
            <p>AT the Sessions held at Justice-Hall in the Old-Baily, on Wednesday, Thursday, Friday, and Saturday, the 10th, 11th, 12th, and 13th Days of this instant December, Nine Persons (viz. Seven Men and Two Women) that were then Try'd for, and Convicted of Capital Crimes, receiv'd Sentence of Death. The two Women being found Pregnant, were of course Respited from Execution; and Five of the Men having obtain'd HER MAJESTY's gracious Reprieve, (which I wish they may have Grace to improve to the Glory of GOD and the Good of Mankind) Two of them only are now appointed to die.</p>
            <p>While they lay under this Condemnation, I constantly attended them, sometimes in the Condemn'd Hold, most times in <placeName id="OA17121223-geo-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17121223-geo-1" type="type" value="site"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17121223n47-1 n49-1 OA17121223-geo-1"/>the Chapel of Newgate</placeName>, where being brought up to me twice every Day, I pray'd with them, and read and expounded the Word of GOD to them; shewing them how they ought to apply themselves to GOD for his Grace and Mercy; that truly repenting not only of the respective Crimes by which they had brought themselves to this sad Condition, but of all other the Sins of their past Lives (which I fear'd were great and many) they might (thro' Faith in CHRIST JESUS) receive Absolution, Pardon, and Salvation.</p>
            <p>On the Lord's Day the 14th instant, I preach'd to them, viz. in the Morning upon Luke 21. 27. And then shall they see the Son of Man coming in a Cloud with Power and great Glory.</p>
            <p>Upon this Text I had begun to discourse on the Lord's Day before this, when (in the Forenoon) I open'd it, and shew'd the Import of it in general, and then laid down these two principal Points to be enlarg'd upon, viz.</p>
            <p>I. The Certainty of Christ's coming to judge the World: And,</p>
            <p>II. The Uncertainty of the Time when He shall come.</p>
            <p>Upon the first of these Two Points I shew'd, That Christ's coming to Judgment is declar'd by Words, and will be confirm'd by Wonders.</p>
            <p>1st, It is declar'd by Words, spoken by Him who cannot lie, as being the God of Truth: and those Words, not only affirm'd barely, as in the Text, Then shall they see the Son of Man coming in a Cloud; nor only enforc'd by an Oath, or strong Asseveration, as at the 32d Verse: Verily I say unto you, this Generation shall not pass away till all be ful</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA171212230002"/>
            <p>filled: But they are further ascertain'd by this peremptory Conclusion at the 33d Verse; Heaven and Earth shall pass away, but my Words shall not pass away.</p>
            <p>2dly, This Coming of Christ, which is thus evidently declar'd and asserted by Words, will be confirm'd also by Wonders; and those Wonders shall be universal, in Heaven, in Earth, and in the Sea, as Harbingers of the great and terrible Day of the Lord: Of which the Holy Evangelists (St. Matthew, ch. 24. St. Mark, ch. 13. and St. Luke in the Ch. of the Text) give us a large and lively Description: And the like we find in 1 Thess. 4. 16, and in other Places of Scripture. It is also a main Article of our Christian Faith, That Christ shall come at the last Day to judge the World, both the Quick and the Dead.</p>
            <p>Which affords abundant</p>
            <p>Matter of {Comfort to the Godly, Terror to the Wicked, Instruction to all: As I shew'd at large, when I discours'd that Morning upon this First General Point; which having then fully demonstrated from the Holy Scripture, I proceeded (in the Afternoon of that Day) to prove from the same Scripture,</p>
            <p>II. The Uncertainty of the Time when Christ shall come to Judgment.</p>
            <p>And from this Doctrine exemplify'd I drew some Practical Inferences, shewing the importance of our being at all times ready for that Day and Hour, keeping our selves free from Sins, and having always a good Conscience, void of Offence towards God and towards Men, Acts 24. 16.</p>
            <p>Thus far I proceeded on my Text that Lord's Day: But forasmuch as the Time would not then permit me to make an end of what I was further to say upon this Subject, I now resumed it again; and to the two General Points before mention'd (and then treated of) I did (this Morning) add,</p>
            <p>III. and lastly, The weighty Consideration of the nearer, or (at least) more visibly approaching Judgment, which is passed upon the Soul of every Man at his Death, and will be publickly confirm'd, and extended to his Body also, at his Resurrection on the last Day.</p>
            <p>After I had fully explain'd this Doctrine, and shew'd, That the Use of it consisted chiefly in making due Preparation for that great Change, which all Men in general ought to look upon as not far off, because Human Life (at the longest period) is but short; and those in particular who (by their enormous Crimes) have made it still shorter, ought to be most of all concern'd herein; I then concluded with some proper Exhortations to the Condemn'd Persons, whom I endeavour'd to perswade to a Life of Faith, and Acts of Repentance, and to that end implore the Assistance of the Divine Spirit.</p>
            <p>This Afternoon I preach'd again to them, and took my Text out of the Epistle for the Day, viz. 1 Cor. 4. 5. Therefore judge nothing before the time until the Lord come, who will bring to light the hidden things of Darkness, and will manifest the Counsels of the Hearts. From which Words, first paraphrastically explain'd, I shew'd,</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA171212230003"/>
            <p>I. That it does not belong to Man, but to GOD alone, to judge of secret things, of the Intentions and Imaginations of the Heart; but,</p>
            <p>II. They may judge of those things which outwardly appear; the Ministers of GOD, and the Civil Magistrate, having Power to take Cognisance of, and to rebuke and punish such Persons as offend either in Words or Deeds: So that whenever any Sin comes to publick Knowledg, He or She that has committed it must receive the Reproof and Punishment it deserves; as in the Case of those Persons who are guilty of Adultery, Fornication, Uncleanness, Lasciviousness, Envyings, Murders, Thefts, and the like, which St. Paul tells us (Gal. Ch.5. and other places) are manifest; Men indeed (in Authority) are not only allow'd, but commanded to judge of them.</p>
            <p>Having enlarg'd upon, and from Scripture illustrated, these Propositions, I undertook to speak to these two things chiefly, viz.</p>
            <p>1st, The Works of the Flesh, i. e. Adultery, Fornication, &amp;c. which I have (now) mention'd from the Apostle, and consider'd (then) under these three Particulars;</p>
            <p>1. Their Kinds, which I singly examin'd.</p>
            <p>2. Their Effects, which tend to Destruction.</p>
            <p>3. Their Punishment, which is very severe, in that the commission of those Sins shut Men out of Heaven, unless they do truly, and in due time repent. And against those Works of the Flesh I did set,</p>
            <p>2dly, These Virtues, which are diametrically opposite to those Vices, and the Apostle, in that 5th Chap. of his Epistle to the Galatians, calls, The Fruit of the Spirit, being (as he there says) Joy, Peace, Long-suffering, Gentleness, Goodness, Faith, Meekness, Temperance, &amp;c.</p>
            <p>In my Explanation of which Christian Virtues, I distinctly treated of,</p>
            <p>1. Their Property.</p>
            <p>2. Their Kinds.</p>
            <p>3. Their Benefits.</p>
            <p>Shewing from the same Apostle, that against such as practise them, there is no Law; i. e. the Law cannot take hold on such Persons as are endow'd with such Virtues: There is no Law to condemn them; No Law to compel them; for as they are led by the Spirit, so are they free, serving the Lord without Compulsion or Constraint. If there were no Punishment in this Life, nor Hell in the next for Adultery, Fornication, Uncleanness, Drunkenness, Murder, Theft, and other Sins and Works of the Flesh, yet they would abstain from them out of meer Love to GOD and Goodness: For they that are Christ's have crucified the Flesh, with the Affections and Lusts thereof, Gal. 5. 24.</p>
            <p>On these Heads and Particulars I then largely discours'd: And on the last Lord's Day, the 21st instant, I again preach'd to them, both in the Morning and Afternoon, upon this Text, Mat. 11. 28, 29, 30. Come unto me all ye that labour and are heavy laden, and I will give you Rest. Take my Yoke upon you, and learn of me, for I am meek and lowly in Heart, and ye shall find Rest unto your Souls. For my Yoke is easie, and my Burthen is light.</p>
            <p>These Words I first explain'd in general, and then did distinctly and particularly discourse from them upon these four principal Heads, shewing,</p>
            <p>I. Who is the Inviter here, and that is CHRIST JESUS, saying, Come unto me.</p>
            <p>II. Who are the Invited, viz. All that labour and are heavy laden; i. e. All that lie opprest under the weighty Load of their Sins.</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA171212230004"/>
            <p>III. What is this Invitation, and what are the Motions and Means by which we may effectually come to CHRIST; and these are Faith, Love, Repentance, Humility, and Meekness; which He would have us to follow in imitation of Him: Learn of me, (says he in the Text) for I am meek and lowly in Heart.</p>
            <p>IV. and lastly, The great Motives and strong Arguments here used by CHRIST, for our Perswasion to receive this his most gracious Invitation, To come unto Him, and take his Yoke upon us. Which Arguments are thse:</p>
            <p>1st, Because He will give us Rest.</p>
            <p>2dly, Because we shall find this Rest unto (and in) our Souls.</p>
            <p>3dly, Because his Yoke is easie, and his Burthen is light: intimating thereby That tho' the Precepts of his Gospel be a Yoke and a Burthen, in that they are contrary to our corrupt Nature, and too hard and too heavy for our Strength to bear, yet they will become not only easie and light, but pleasant and comfortable to us, by His Divine Spirit powerfully assisting us in the hearing thereof.</p>
            <p>After I had gone through, and inlarged upon these several Heads and Particulars. I then exhorted my Auditory to Repent of their Sins; and come unto CHRIST (who inviteth them to receive Help, Rest, and Salvation;) and so bear his Cross here on Earth, that they might wear his Crown in Heaven.</p>
            <p>Which having done, I summ'd up all with suitable Admonitions, and a close Application to the Condemn'd; who (to me) appeared very attentive to what was said to them both in Publick and Private.</p>
            <p>I have here dwelt the longer upon these respective Heads or chief Points of my Sermons to the Condemn'd Persons, because I may have but little else to fill this Paper with; which (as I take it) should be excus'd from the Tax, being a Paper that (for the most part) contains Matter of Divinity and Devotion, and is chiefly intended for the Instruction and Reformation of Sinners.</p>
            <p>These who are the Subject of it, and are now order'd for Execution, gave me the respective Accounts of their past Lives, and present Dispositions, as follows.</p>
            <p>1. <persName id="OA17121223n47-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17121223n47-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17121223n47-1" type="surname" value="CRABB"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17121223n47-1" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Crabb</persName>, condemn'd for a Burglary and Robbery, by him committed with R. B. in the House of <persName id="OA17121223n47-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17121223n47-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17121223n47-2" type="surname" value="ANNESLEY"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17121223n47-2" type="given" value="FRANCIS"/>Francis Annesley</persName>, <rs id="OA17121223-occupation-1" type="occupation">Esq</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17121223n47-2 OA17121223-occupation-1"/>; on the 12th of August last. He said, he was about 22 Years of age, (but appear'd to be more) and was born at <placeName id="OA17121223-geo-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17121223-geo-2" type="type" value="county"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA17121223n47-1 OA17121223-geo-2"/>
                  <placeName id="OA17121223-geo-3">
                     <interp inst="OA17121223-geo-3" type="type" value="urban_centre"/>
                     <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA17121223n47-1 OA17121223-geo-3"/>Bishops-Stortford</placeName> in Hartfordshire</placeName>; and, That this Fact which he is now to die for, and which he own'd, was the first he ever committed, saving that a little before, he had in the absence of his Master, a <rs id="OA17121223-occupation-2" type="occupation">Cabinet-maker, (to whom he was Apprentice)</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17121223n47-1 OA17121223-occupation-2"/> receiv'd the Sum of 24 s. for him, and never gave him any account of it, but carried it away after he had assisted in this Robbery R. B. the Person condemn'd with him for it, and now repriev'd. How far this Crabb was concern'd in the said Robbery, may (in some measure) be gather'd from his following Confession, tho' in something it differs from that which R. B. made to me. And this Crabb's Confession is this: That R. B. (who then was a Domestick Servant of Mr. Annesley) having one Day (as it seem'd) lost the Key of a Desk or Press, wherein he us'd to put Table-Linnen, ask'd him, Whether he could help him to a Key that could open it. To which he answer'd, He could; and so he did. Some time after this, the said R. B. (who knew he lov'd Snuff) told him, That his Master had rare Snuff in one of his Scrutores, and if he could help him to a Key that would open it, he would be sure to let him have some. Upon that he gave the said R. B. several Keys, to try whether of 'em would serve turn, but none did, till he the said Crabb came to the House that Night they committed the Robbery, and unscrew'd and took off the Lock, and by bearing down some of the Wards, fitted a Key to it, and so put on the Lock again; and after they had taken out of the Scrutore some Pieces of Gold, a Diamond-Ring, and two or three Money-Bills that were in a Pocket-book, which they left behind 'em, they went off, and would fain have made a Bargain with two Watermen, to procure them a Vessel to carry them to Holland, offering to give them 200 l. for their Passage; but they not being able to effect this their Design, went into <placeName id="OA17121223-geo-4">
                  <interp inst="OA17121223-geo-4" type="type" value="region"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA17121223n47-1 OA17121223-geo-4"/>Wales</placeName>, and there (some time after) were taken, and brought to Justice; as 'tis set forth in their printed Tryal, to which I refer my Reader. And now, upon my asking this Crabb which of the two (R. B. or Himself) made first the Proposition of Robbing Mr. Annesley, he said, That R. B. propos'd</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA171212230005"/>
            <p>the Thing to him first; telling him plainly, that he could get a great Booty, if he could open his Master's Scrutore, in which there was a great quantity of Gold and other valuable Things; and, that if he would assist him therein, and be true to him, he should partake of what they should find there: Upon which he the said Crabb promis'd him his Assistance and Secrecy; telling him withal, that they might then go over into Holland, and there live like Gentlemen; And (said he) let the worse come to the worse, I have a good Trade, which I will teach you, and you shall never want any thing so long as I have it. Thus far you have Crabb's Tale, which whether true or false, I shall not here determin; but certain it is, that Mr. Annesley's Servant told me otherwise: For he said all-along, that when he had not the least Thought of wronging his Master, who ever was a most kind Master to him, and whose Service he lov'd, Crabb put him upon this piece of Villany, who had induced him before to steal several Bottles of Wine out of his Master's Cellar, thereby preparing him to commit a greater Theft. This latter part was acknowledg'd by Crabb himself; who confess'd also, that he had been a wicked Liver, and had committed Fornication and (for ought he knew) Adultery too, and had thro' the Course of his sinful Life (several ways) greatly offended GOD; which he was now heartily sorry, and begg'd Pardon for.</p>
            <p>2. <persName id="OA17121223n49-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17121223n49-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17121223n49-1" type="surname" value="TOWN"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17121223n49-1" type="given" value="RICHARD"/>Richard Town</persName>, of <placeName id="OA17121223-geo-5">
                  <interp inst="OA17121223-geo-5" type="type" value="urban_centre"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA17121223n49-1 OA17121223-geo-5"/>London</placeName>, <rs id="OA17121223-occupation-3" type="occupation">Tallow-chandler</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17121223n49-1 OA17121223-occupation-3"/>, condemn'd for Cheating and Defrauding his Creditors by Concealment of his Goods, &amp;c. He said, he was an <placeName id="OA17121223-geo-6">
                  <interp inst="OA17121223-geo-6" type="type" value="county"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA17121223n49-1 OA17121223-geo-6"/>Oxford-shire</placeName>-Man, and now just 41 Years of age. When I had him under Examination, he at first said but little for himself, save that he did not intend to be Unjust to any Man, but his Adversaries were bitter against him, and took what Opportunity they could to ruine him, &amp;c. Upon this I told him, that such frivolous Excuses would not now serve his turn: He was fairly try'd, and justly condemn'd, and so must die; and therefore what concern'd him to do under the sad Condition he was in, was to make his Peace with GOD and Man, clearing his Conscience of all Sins, known and unknown, by Repentance towards GOD, and Satisfaction to all Men he had wrong'd, so far as he was able to discharge this great and indispensable Duty. For his Help towards which, I advis'd him seriously to consider these three Things chiefly, viz.</p>
            <p>1. What he had done through the whole Course of his past Life: How he had offended a good and gracious GOD, and injur'd his honest Neighbour.</p>
            <p>2. What it behov'd him to do at this time, viz. To repent with all his Heart of all his Misdeeds; give Glory to GOD now, whom he had heretofore so much dishonour'd; make the best Amends he could to his wrong'd Neighbour, and as far as possible remove the great Scandal he had given to the best Religion in the World, by professing it, and living contrary to the Divine Rules of it: For, upon my asking him before what Religion he was of, whether an Anabaptist, (as it was reported) or what else? He had told me, That he ever was of the Church of England, and never went to any Meeting in his Life.</p>
            <p>3. The third Thing I pray'd him seriously to consider was, What should become of him hereafter: What strict Account he must give to the great Judge of all the World, not only of his Words and Actions, but of the very Intentions and Imaginations of his wicked Heart: What severe Sentence should be pass'd on him at the great Tribunal; How he should be excluded the Joys and Happiness of of Heaven, and be doom'd to the Pains and Torments of Hell, to all Eternity, if he did not truly repent, without any the least delay; And what a Curse he should entail upon his Family, if he should leave them any thing he had no Right to dispose of: Things which he ought now duly to weigh, &amp; ponder on, and take into his serious Consideration; praying to GOD, that he might have Grace rightly to understand and savingly practise what might further his Everlasting Peace, before it was too late, and he be finally shut out of all Mercy, and consign'd over to endless Woes.</p>
            <p>This was the Substance of my Admonitions to him, which whether he heard or no, I cannot well tell; for he seem'd to be so very deaf, that tho' I spoke as loud as ever I could to him, yet he gave me no Answer to the purpose; but taking a small Book in his Hand that lay by, concerning Death and Judgment, he said to me, This is a very good Book. Upon which I told him, It was so; and wish'd him to make a good use of it, and prepare for his approaching Death and the unavoidable Judgment that should immediately follow it.</p>
            <p>Before his Condemnation he had a Chamber by himself in the Press-yard; but when he had had Sentence pass'd upon him he was with his Fellow-Condemned put into the Hold; where (as he told me) he contracted such a Cold, as that his former Thickness of Hearing (for I find he had been ever afflicted with it since his Confinement) was now even turned to a perfect Deafness. And as he much</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA171212230006"/>
            <p>complain'd of the Uneasiness of the Place he was in, and the little Conveniency he could find there among so many other Prisoners, to recollect himself and prepare for another Life; so he was soon after remov'd to his former Room in the Press-yard. But instead of mending there, he seem'd to grow worse and worse, his Weakness and Deafness encreasing to that degree, that I could hardly understand what he said; neither he what I said to him: And he remaining in that Room (and for the most part too in his Bed) till this Day of his Execution; There it was chiefly that I pray'd by him, and gave him the Exhortations which I have mention'd above. Some Time before he was so very Weak and Deaf, he told me, he would write his Case, and leave it to the World; but whether he has done it, or no, I know not certainly; for perhaps his Illness may have prevented his doing it. Which Illness of his gave me a great deal of Trouble, and I am afraid with little Success. However, I shall not answer for it, if he was not brought to a better frame before he dy'd. I did conscientiously discharge my Duty to his Soul, and likewise to the others; who by reason of the Illness of some of them, that could not therefore be always brought to the Chapel, I often went to the Condemned Hold to pray with them.</p>
            <p>Some Time before his Death, Mr. Town having partly recover'd his Hearing, he came this Morning to the Chapel, and attended at Prayer, and at my Exhortations towards the making a due Preparation for Death and a happy Eternity. I had also some private Discourse with him; but he would not confess himself Guilty; and said, the World should hereafter better know what he has been, than they now do: And, That one certain Person, whom he had charitably reliev'd, and saved from Ruin, had prov'd the chief Cause of his. Adding, That indeed those he was most kind to, had been his greatest Enemies; but he dy'd in Charity with them, praying GOD to forgive them, and him also, who (he acknowledg'd) had been too eager to make himself rich in this World, and too too remiss in the Service of GOD.</p>
            <p>As he was rididg in the Coach with me to the Place of his Execution, he told me, That this was a Remarkable Day to him; for on this very Day he was born. Upon which I took occasion to mention this of Solomon to him, viz. That the Day of Death is better than the Day of one's Birth; shewing him, That by our Birth we enter into a World of Sin and Misery, but by our Death are deliver'd out of it, and admitted (if well prepar'd) into a State of Bliss and Glory, that never shall end.</p>
            <p>At the Place of Execution, whither they were this Day carry'd, Mr. Town in a Coach, (as said before) and Crabb in a Cart, I attended them for the last time, and (as usually) exhorted them to clear their Consciences, and to leave nothing undiscover'd that they knew the World might be benefitted by the knowledge of; Upon which they told me, They had nothing more to say.</p>
            <p>After this I pray'd with them, made them rehearse the Apostles Creed, and sing some Penitential Psalms. Which done, I finally recommended them to GOD's Mercy, and before I withdrew, I advis'd them to speak to the Spectators that they might follow better Courses than themselves had done. Mr. Town spoke to this Effect, That He dy'd with a clear Conscience; That he had been very much abus'd by some he had shew'd great kindness to, and he would let the World know it, by a Paper he had left behind him, &amp;c.</p>
            <p>Then they apply'd themselves in their private Devotions to GOD, for which they had some time allow'd them; and while they were crying to Him for the Pardon of their Sins, and the Salvation of their Souls, the Cart drew away, and they were turn'd off.</p>
            <p>This is all the Account here to be given of these dying Malefactors, by me,</p>
            <p>
               <persName id="OA17121223n62-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17121223n62-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17121223n62-1" type="surname" value="LORRAIN"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17121223n62-1" type="given" value="PAUL"/>PAUL LORRAIN</persName>, <rs id="OA17121223-occupation-4" type="occupation">Ordinary</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17121223n62-1 OA17121223-occupation-4"/>.</p>
            <p>Tuesday, Decemb. 23. 1712.</p>
            <p>NB. In a few Days will be Publish'd, A true Copy of the abovesaid Paper left by Mr. Town the Tallow-chandler, which he desir'd might not be expos'd till after his Execution. Sold by J. Morphew near Stationers-hall.</p>
            <p>ADVERTISEMENTS.</p>
            <p>THis is to give Notice to all Gentlemen, Booksellers, and others, That there is lately publish'd a new sett of Cuts, adapted to several sizes of Common prayers, all new Designs, by Mr. Gocree of Amsterdam; engrav'd by P. Vandergucht. Likewise Mr. Sturt's Cuts. Sold by <persName id="OA17121223n66-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17121223n66-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17121223n66-1" type="surname" value="WHITLEDGE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17121223n66-1" type="given" value="ROBERT"/>Robert Whitledge</persName>, at <placeName id="OA17121223-geo-7">
                  <interp inst="OA17121223-geo-7" type="type" value="street"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA17121223n66-1 OA17121223-geo-7"/>
                  <placeName id="OA17121223-geo-8">
                     <interp inst="OA17121223-geo-8" type="type" value="site"/>
                     <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA17121223n66-1 OA17121223-geo-8"/>
                     <placeName id="OA17121223-geo-9">
                        <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA17121223n66-1 OA17121223-geo-9"/>the Bible and Ball</placeName> in Ave-Maria-Lane</placeName>, near Ludgate</placeName>; where may be had all sorts of Bibles, either in Folio, Quarto, Octavo, Twelves, or other sizes; Common-prayers in Folio, for the use of Churches; Common-prayers in 8° &amp; 12°. All neatly bound. Duty of Man's Works of all sizes; Duty of Man in Latin; Latin and Welsh Common-prayers; Tate and Brady's new Version of Psalms, with the new Supplement: Dr. Gibson on the Sacrament, Mr. Clutterbuck on the Liturgy; The Statutes at large, in 3 vol. Bp. Beveridge's Sermons and private Thoughts, &amp;c.</p>
            <p>In few Days will be Publish'd,</p>
            <p>THE Whiggs Unmask'd; or, The Secret History of the Calves-head-Club, shewing the rise and progress of that infamous Society since the Grand Rebellion, containing all the Treasonable Songs and Ballads, sung as Anthems by those Saints at their King-killing Anniversaries, with Reflections thereupon. Much enlarg'd and improv'd by a genuine Account of all the Plots and Conspiracies of the Whiggish Party against the Queen and Government, since the Persecution of the Church, under the disguise of Moderation, in their violent Proceedings against Dr. Sacheverel, with proper Animadversions, in Prose and Verse, upon their wicked Machinations. Adorn'd with Cuts applicable to every particular Design. To which are added, several suitable Characters, pen'd by <rs id="OA17121223-occupation-5" type="occupation">Sir</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17121223n68-1 OA17121223-occupation-5"/> 
               <persName id="OA17121223n68-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17121223n68-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17121223n68-1" type="surname" value="DENHAM"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17121223n68-1" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Denham</persName>, and other valuable Authors. Also a Vindication of the Royal Martyr K. Charles the First; wherein are laid open, the Hellish Mysteries of the old Republican Rebellion. The 8th Edition, with large Additions. Sold by J. Morphew, near Stationers-hall.</p>
            <p>London printed, and sold by J. Morphew near Stationers-hall.</p>
         </div0>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>