<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<TEI.2>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div0 type="ordinarysAccount" id="OA17080924">
            <interp inst="OA17080924" type="uri" value="ordinarysAccounts/OA17080924"/>
            <interp inst="OA17080924" type="date" value="17080924"/>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA170809240001"/>
            <p>The ORDINARY of NEWGATE his Account of the Malefactor that was Executed at Tyburn on Friday the 24 of September, 1708.</p>
            <p>AFter the happy Discontinuation of this Paper for two Sessions last past, in which there was none executed; it now appears abroad again upon the melancholy Account of the Persons hereafter mention'd.</p>
            <p>At the Sessions held at Justice-Hall in the Old-Baily, on Wednesday the 8th, Thursday the 9th, and Friday the 10th of this instant September, there were three Persons, who upon their Trials being found Guilty of Death, received Sentence accordingly. Of these Three, One is order'd for Execution, and the other Two are Reprieved.</p>
            <p>On the Lord's Day the 12th instant I preach'd to them and several Strangers, who were there in great (and indeed too great) Numbers, both in the Morning and Afternoon; and my Text at both times was Acts 17. 31. Because He hath appointed a Day, in the which He will judge the World.</p>
            <p>From which Words, first explain'd with their Context, I shew'd;</p>
            <p>I. The Certainty and Infallibility, as well as Necessity of a future Judgment after this Life: Which is declar'd to us by a threefold Voice; viz.</p>
            <p>The Voice of{Scripture,</p>
            <p>Conscience,</p>
            <p>God's Justice.</p>
            <p>II. The Severity and Dreadfulness of that Judgment: which to impenitent Sinners will be terrible indeed, and most intolerable upon many accounts; but chiefly these, viz.</p>
            <p>1. The Sight of their Judge.</p>
            <p>2. The Manner of his coming to Judgment.</p>
            <p>3. The Accusations of their own Consciences.</p>
            <p>4. The Nature and Characters of that Judgment, which will be Universal, Exact, Just, and Irreversible.</p>
            <p>III. and lastly, The Use we ought to make of this Doctrine of a future Judgment, so as to avoid the Severity of it, and be advanced to endless Happiness by it: Considering it to be,</p>
            <p>1. A powerful Disswasive from Vice; because it will then most certainly and severely be punish'd. And,</p>
            <p>2. A Strong Perswasive to Virtue; because then it will be most certainly and fully rewarded.</p>
            <p>On the last Lord's Day the 19th instant, I preach'd again to them both in the Forenoon and Afternoon, and enlarged upon the same Subject of a Future Judgment, as being of great use and import to them to understand it well, and prepare themselves for it accordingly: And to that purpose I then took for my Text these Words of our Saviour, Mat. 25. 46. And these shall go away into Everlasting Punishment; but the Righteous into Life Eternal.</p>
            <p>From which Words I took occasion to shew what the Design of Christ is in the Chapter of the Text, from the 31st Verse to the end of that Chapter; which is to give us a plain Description of the last Judgment; and to inform us of the Nature of it; viz. That it shall be twofold, as the Persons to be judged shall be of two sorts.</p>
            <p>I. There shall be a Judgment unto Eternal Death, which shall seize upon wicked and impenitent Sinners, who shall be punish'd both with the Loss of God and all that is good; and with intolerable Pains, that shall have neither relaxation nor end. All which is imply'd in this former Clause of the Text, And these shall go away (cursed as they are) into Everlasting Punishment.</p>
            <p>II. There shall be a Judgment unto immortal Life and Happiness for the Godly and Penitent; for those who shall be found to have truly served God, by departing from Sin and practising Religion and Virtue. Such Persons shall be accounted Righteous; And (saith our Saviour in the later Clause of the Text) The Righteous shall go (Blessed as they are) into Life Eternal.</p>
            <p>Having inlarg'd upon these Heads, I drew such Inferences as naturally arise from the Doctrine of a future Judgment; and concluded all my Discourses with particular Exhortations and Applications to the Condemned, whom (while under this Condemnation) I visited twice every Day, sometimes in the Condemned Hold, and oftener in the Chapel, where I pray'd with them, and shew'd them from the Word of God how they ought and might repent. They seem'd to be very attentive to my publick and private Admonitions.</p>
            <p>
               <persName id="OA17080924n24-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17080924n24-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17080924n24-1" type="surname" value="CRAFTS"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17080924n24-1" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Crafts</persName>, <persName id="OA17080924n24-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17080924n24-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17080924n24-2" type="surname" value="Rutt"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17080924n24-2" type="given" value="John"/>alias Rutt</persName>, the only Person that is now to suffer, and therefore the only Subject of the remaining part of this Paper.</p>
            <p>He was condemned for breaking open the House of Mr. Harling, and taking from thence 20 Doz. of Stockings, on the 17th day of August last; and also for privately stealing 40 yards of Camlet out of Mr. Hall's Shop, a few days before. He owned he was guilty of both these Facts; and likewise of the other which at the same time he was try'd for, viz. the breaking open Mr. Physick's House, and taking from thence a Peruke and other Goods; of which, for want of full proof, he was acquitted. He also confess'd some other Facts of the like nature, which he had committed these two or three Years last past, in which he had follow'd a vicious Course of Life; being at first brought into it by <persName id="OA17080924n25-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17080924n25-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17080924n25-1" type="surname" value="MONTISANO"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17080924n25-1" type="given" value="JOSEPH"/>Joseph Montisano</persName>, who was executed in December 1707, and confirmed in it by some others he became afterwards acquainted and concerned with, who very much contributed to bring this Judgment upon him. Yet at the same time he acknowledg'd that all this Evil was come to him by his own Folly and Wickedness; That he had had great Warnings, and receiv'd great Mercies, and improv'd neither as he should have done: That when very lately he had deserved Death, and obtain'd his Pardon by becoming an Evidence against one that was in the Fact with him, and bringing him to Judgment; he yet was so dishonest and unwise as not to keep himself afterwards from the like Judgment; but soon ran into it, by returning to his old ways of Robbing and Thieving. Now he felt the guilt of all this Folly and Wickedness to be very heavy upon his Soul, when he seriously reflected on his past sinful life, and Abuse of former Mercies, and consider'd both his present Misery, and what more (and more terrible) he might feel hereafter, if God dealt severely with him, as he had justly deserved; who had been a Lewd Liver, an Adulterer, a Swearer, a Profaner of the Lord's Name and Day, and one that had put no restraint at all upon himself from any Vice that he had any opportunity to commit, Murther excepted, which he profess'd he never was guilty of, but always most averse to; therefore never carry'd any Pistol, or other Instruments wherewith he might do michief to any Body, when he went to rob Houses, &amp;c. He said, he thanked God that he had not that heinous Sin to answer for; and he express'd a great deal of sorrow for all other the Sins he had so much given way to and indulg'd himself in so long. The Consideration of all this, and the Account he must give to God of his mispent and wicked Life, made him very much afraid of the Judgment to come; wishing he had never done an ill thing before, or that it were now in his power to undo all that he had done amiss, and make due Reparation for it. This seem'd to be at first the Disposition of his mind; and accordingly he did (as he said) whatever he could to help them again to their Goods, whom he had robb'd.</p>
            <p>He begg'd Pardon both of God and of all Persons he had wrong'd in any wise, and promis'd he would give the best Advice he was able to give to Sinners, that they might take timely Warning by him, and repent, and serve God, and depart from Evil, and shun the company of all wicked People; for he had learn'd by his own woful Experience, that such company was most pernicious (particularly) to Young Men, and that it was the thing that had corrupted him, and taken him off from</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA170809240002"/>
            <p>the way of Religion, in which he was train'd up by his good Mother, now dead; adding, that (to his great grief) his Vicious Life had broke her Heart; and therefore he now justly suffer'd for it. He told me, he was about Twenty Years of age, born in the <placeName id="OA17080924-geo-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17080924-geo-1" type="type" value="parish"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17080924n24-1 n24-2 OA17080924-geo-1"/>Parish of St. Andrews Holborn</placeName>, and a <rs id="OA17080924-occupation-1" type="occupation">Butcher</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17080924n24-1 n24-2 OA17080924-occupation-1"/> by his Trade, who might have lived very well, if he had follow'd an honest Course. To all which he added, That last Sunday were 3 Weeks, he (with some others) robb'd a Hackney-Coach which was going to the <placeName id="OA17080924-geo-2">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17080924n24-1 n24-2 OA17080924-geo-2"/>
                  <placeName id="OA17080924-geo-3">
                     <interp inst="OA17080924-geo-3" type="type" value="site"/>
                     <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                           targets="OA17080924n24-1 n24-2 OA17080924-geo-3"/>Rose-Inn</placeName> in West-Smithfield</placeName>, taking out of it a Portmantle with a Gown and Wearing Linnen and Apparel for Men; but he knew not the Persons to whom those Goods belong'd, nor could hear of them, though he had (since his condemnation) sent to enquire after them, in order to do them justice: For he was often told and seemed sometimes to be perswaded, that he must make all the Restitution he was able, to the Parties he had wrong'd, if ever he desired to obtain Mercy from God.</p>
            <p>Now, what I am further to inform the World of, concerning this matter, is, That he has (unless he did prevaricate) left a Direction with me where to find those Goods again. Therefore if the Persons who lost them desire to have that Direction, I will be ready to give it them at any time they may please to call for it at my Habitation in the East-Walk of the Cloisters of Christ's Hospital, London.</p>
            <p>But now to make an end with this Malefactor, I found that after he had made some Discoveries, he seem'd at last to be very much reserv'd in other Particulars, wherein his desir'd Confession might have been of great use to some honest People, whose Goods he had stoln, and of no less use to himself for the clearing of his Conscience, and making his peace with God and Man before he dy'd. But whether the long time granted him since his Condemnation had made him wish and hope for more, as too often it does, or whether any Body had been tampering with him, so as to put it in his Head, that he should purchase a Reprieve by his Discoveries, is what I cannot well determine: But this I must say, that both my self and others that saw him and discoursed him about the matter, did then find him unwilling to speak freely to any thing more, unless he were sure to be reprieved. And so he persisted in this his Obstinacy for a great while; by which I perceiv'd (and he gave hints enough of it) that there were some Persons concern'd therein, whom he was desirous to spare.</p>
            <p>At the Place of Execution (to which he was this Day carry'd in a Cart) I attended him for the last time, and according to my usual Method, exhorted him to clear his Conscience, and freely and unreservedly declare what he might further discover for the use of the World, or any particular Person. To which he answer'd, That he had clear'd his Conscience in every thing that he remembred, and That he had done all the Justice he could to the Persons by him injur'd, whose Pardon he begg'd; declaring also, That he dy'd in Charity with all the World, and hop'd the World was in charity with him.</p>
            <p>Which having said, I further exhorted him to excite and stir up his Heart to God, with humble Acknowledgment of his Sins, and earnest Suit to Him for Mercy, that his Pardon might be seal'd in Heaven before he went out of this miserable World, where he should be seen no more. Then I pray'd with him and for him to that purpose; and after the Singing of two Penitential Psalms, the Rehearsing of the Apostle's Creed, and some further Prayers made for him, That God would please to assist him with his Grace, and have Mercy upon his Soul, I advis'd him to warn the People by his sad Example: And so he spake to them to this effect.</p>
            <p>Gentlemen, and all about this place, I am a Young Man, come here to suffer for my Sins; consider my Condition, and take Warning by me. Serve God, and keep the Sabbath-day, and resolve now, from your going away from this place, to ead a good Life, that you may never come to such an End.</p>
            <p>When he had done speaking, I return'd to Prayer again, and having recommended him to the boundless Mercy of Almighty God, I left him to his private Devotions, for which he had some time allow'd him. Then the Cart drew a way, and he was turn'd off while he pray'd, That God would (for Christ's sake) grant him forgiveness of all his Sins, and receive his Soul.</p>
            <p>This is all the Account here to be given of this Dying Person, by</p>
            <p>
               <persName id="OA17080924n35-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17080924n35-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17080924n35-1" type="surname" value="LORRAIN"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17080924n35-1" type="given" value="PAUL"/>PAUL LORRAIN</persName>, <rs id="OA17080924-occupation-2" type="occupation">Ordinary of Newgate</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17080924n35-1 OA17080924-occupation-2"/>.</p>
            <p>Sept. 24. 1708.</p>
            <p>ADVERTISEMENTS.</p>
            <p>
               <persName id="OA17080924n38-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17080924n38-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17080924n38-1" type="surname" value="WHITLEDGE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17080924n38-1" type="given" value="ROBERT"/>ROBERT WHITLEDGE</persName>, who formerly lived at the <placeName id="OA17080924-geo-4">
                  <interp inst="OA17080924-geo-4" type="type" value="street"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA17080924n38-1 OA17080924-geo-4"/>
                  <placeName id="OA17080924-geo-5">
                     <interp inst="OA17080924-geo-5" type="type" value="site"/>
                     <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA17080924n38-1 OA17080924-geo-5"/>Bible</placeName> in Creed-Lane</placeName>, is removed to the <placeName id="OA17080924-geo-6">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA17080924n38-1 OA17080924-geo-6"/>
                  <placeName id="OA17080924-geo-7">
                     <interp inst="OA17080924-geo-7" type="type" value="street"/>
                     <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA17080924n38-1 OA17080924-geo-7"/>
                     <placeName id="OA17080924-geo-8">
                        <interp inst="OA17080924-geo-8" type="type" value="site"/>
                        <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA17080924n38-1 OA17080924-geo-8"/>Bible and Ball</placeName> in Ave-Mary-Lane</placeName>, near Ludgate</placeName>, where all Booksellers and others may be furnisht with Bibles and Common-Prayers of all Sorts, with Cuts or without, Ruled or Unruled, Bound in Turkey Leather or Plain. Mr. Sturt's Cuts Curiously Engrav'd; also other fine Cuts fitted for all Sizes and Common-Prayers. The Welsh Bible, Welsh Common Prayer, and Welsh Almanack. The Duty of Man's Works of all Sizes. The Duty of Man in Latin. Latin and French Common-Prayers. Tate and Brady's New Version of Psalms, with the New Supplement. Dr. Gibson on the Sacrament. The Statutes at large, in Three Volumes. Washington and Wingate's Abridgment of them. The Lord Clarendon's History of the Rebellion, in Folio and Octavo. All which Books and Cuts are likewise Sold by J. Baker, in Mercer's Chapel in Cheapside.</p>
            <p>Lately Publisht (Printed on Fine Paper, with a large Letter, and Approved of by above 30 School-Masters as the best Spelling-book extant) useful also for Foreigners.</p>
            <p>A Guide to the English Tongue, in Two Parts; the First shewing a natural and easie Method to Pronounce and Express both Common Words and proper Names: In which particular Care is had to shew the Accent for preventing vicious Pronunciation. The Second, containing Observations on the Sound of Letters and Diphthongs, Rules for the true division of Syllables, and the Use of Capitals, Stops and Marks, with large Tables of Abbreviations and distinctions of Words, and several Alphabets of Instructions for Young-Writers. By <persName id="OA17080924n40-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17080924n40-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17080924n40-1" type="surname" value="Dyche"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17080924n40-1" type="given" value="Tho"/>Tho. Dyche</persName>, <rs id="OA17080924-occupation-3" type="occupation">School-Master</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17080924n40-1 OA17080924-occupation-3"/> in <placeName id="OA17080924-geo-9">
                  <interp inst="OA17080924-geo-9" type="type" value="urban_centre"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA17080924n40-1 OA17080924-geo-9"/>London</placeName>. Printed for <persName id="OA17080924n40-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17080924n40-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17080924n40-2" type="surname" value="Butler"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17080924n40-2" type="given" value="Sam"/>Sam. Butler</persName>, at <placeName id="OA17080924-geo-10">
                  <interp inst="OA17080924-geo-10" type="type" value="parish"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17080924n40-2 OA17080924-geo-10"/>
                  <placeName id="OA17080924-geo-11">
                     <interp inst="OA17080924-geo-11" type="type" value="site"/>
                     <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                           targets="OA17080924n40-2 OA17080924-geo-11"/>Bernard's-Inn-Gate</placeName>, in Holbourn</placeName>. Price Bound, 1 s.</p>
            <p>Memoirs of the right Villianous <persName id="OA17080924n41-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17080924n41-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17080924n41-1" type="surname" value="Hall"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17080924n41-1" type="given" value="John"/>John Hall</persName>, the late famous and Notorious Robber. Pen'd from his Mouth some time before his Death. Containing the exact Life and Character of a Thief in General. As also a lively Representation of <placeName id="OA17080924-geo-12">
                  <interp inst="OA17080924-geo-12" type="type" value="site"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17080924n41-1 OA17080924-geo-12"/>Newgate</placeName>, and its Inhabitants, with the Manners and Customs observed there. The Nature and Means by which they commit their several Thefts and Robberies, and the Distinctions observed in their respective Functions. To which is added, the Cant generally us'd by those Sort of People to conceal their Villanies; and Rules to avoid being Robb'd or Cheated by them. Usefully set forth for the Good of the Publick, at the Instance of many honest People. The third Edition, with large Additions, and a Description of Ludgate, the two Compters, and other Prisons for Debt.</p>
            <p>The wooden World dissected in the Character, of, 1. a Ship of War; 2. a Sea-Captain; 3. a Sea-Lieutenant; 4. a Sea Chaplain; 5. The Master of a Ship of War; 6. The Purser; 7. The Surgeon; 8. The Gunner; 9. The Carpenter; 10. The Boatswain; 11. a Sea-Cook; 12. a Midship-man; 13. The Captain's Steward; 14 a Sailor. By a lover of the Mathematicks. The Second Edition, corrected and amended by the Author. Price bound, 1s.</p>
            <p>Secret Memoirs of the Life of the Honourable Sir <persName id="OA17080924n43-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17080924n43-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17080924n43-1" type="surname" value="Shovel"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17080924n43-1" type="given" value="Cloudesly"/>Cloudesly Shovel</persName>, <rs id="OA17080924-occupation-4" type="occupation">Kt</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17080924n43-1 OA17080924-occupation-4"/>. <rs id="OA17080924-occupation-5" type="occupation">Admiral of Great Britain</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17080924n43-1 OA17080924-occupation-5"/>, containing his Birth, Education and Rise, with a full account of all the Naval Battles since the Revolution, and other Honourable Exploits perform'd for the Service of his Country; and a more exact Relation of the Enterprize upon <placeName id="OA17080924-geo-13">
                  <interp inst="OA17080924-geo-13" type="type" value="urban_centre"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17080924n43-1 OA17080924-geo-13"/>Thoulon</placeName> than any yet extant: By a Gentleman who serv'd in that Expedition, and was several Years under Command of that Admiral; with his Effigies curiously Engraven on a Copper Plate. Price Bound, 1 s.</p>
            <p>Murder within Doors: or, a War among our selves proving there are more kill'd by the Vintners, &amp;c. than are sav'd by the Physicians, in a Bacchanalian Dialogue, representing the Danger and Abuse of our most modern celebrated Liquors: Which will never be prevented while the Vintners deal with the Syder-Men, our Punch-Makers with the Apothecaries, and our Derby and Nottingham-Ale-Brewers with the Lime-Kilns, to the great Dishonour of the Grape, and the irreparable Disgrace of Immortal Barly. Written by a Club of - - *** The Power and Prerogative of Humour and Faction, Exemplify'd in Variety of modern Instances, is private Transactions, and publick Affairs.</p>
            <p>All Sold by B. Bragg, at the Raven in Pater-Noster-Row.</p>
            <p>
               <placeName id="OA17080924-geo-14">
                  <interp inst="OA17080924-geo-14" type="type" value="urban_centre"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17080924n46-1 OA17080924-geo-14"/>London</placeName> Printed, and are to be Sold by <persName id="OA17080924n46-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17080924n46-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17080924n46-1" type="surname" value="Bragg"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17080924n46-1" type="given" value="Benj"/>Benj. Bragg</persName>, at <placeName id="OA17080924-geo-15">
                  <interp inst="OA17080924-geo-15" type="type" value="street"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17080924n46-1 OA17080924-geo-15"/>
                  <placeName id="OA17080924-geo-16">
                     <interp inst="OA17080924-geo-16" type="type" value="site"/>
                     <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                           targets="OA17080924n46-1 OA17080924-geo-16"/>the Raven</placeName> in Pater-noster-Row</placeName>.</p>
         </div0>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>