<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<TEI.2>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div0 type="ordinarysAccount" id="OA17150622">
            <interp inst="OA17150622" type="uri" value="ordinarysAccounts/OA17150622"/>
            <interp inst="OA17150622" type="date" value="17150622"/>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA171506220001"/>
            <p>THE Ordinary of NEWGATE HIS ACCOUNT OF The Behaviour, Confessions, and Last Speeches of the Malefactors that were Executed at TYBURN on Wednesday the 22d of June, 1715.</p>
            <p>AT the general Sessions held at <placeName id="OA17150622-geo-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17150622-geo-1" type="type" value="site"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17150622n51-1 n52-1 n53-1 n53-99 n55-2 n55-1 n54-1 n56-1 n56-99 n56-88 OA17150622-geo-1"/>Justice-Hall in the Old-Baily</placeName>, on Thursday, Friday, and Saturday, the 2d, 3d, and 4th Days of this instant June, Twelve Persons, viz. Eleven Men and One Woman, that were Try'd for, and Convicted of diverse Capital Crimes, and by their Jury brought in Guilty, receiv'd Sentence of Death accordingly. Of these the Woman (who was found to be pregnant) and Six of the Men, having obtain'd a gracious Reprieve (which I wish they may rightly improve) the other ive, together with <persName id="OA17150622n3-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17150622n3-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17150622n3-1" type="surname" value="GUY"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17150622n3-1" type="given" value="SHADRACH"/>Shadrach Guy</persName> formerly condemn'd, are now order'd for Execution.</p>
            <p>While they lay under this Condemnation, I constantly visited them; and having them brought up to the <placeName id="OA17150622-geo-2">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17150622n3-1 n57-1 n51-1 n52-1 n53-1 n53-99 n55-2 n55-1 n54-1 n56-1 n56-99 n56-88 OA17150622-geo-2"/>Chapel of Newgate</placeName> twice every Day, I there pray'd with them, and read and open'd the Scripture to them, in order to the informing their dull Understandings, awakening their drouzy Consciences, enlightening their dark Minds, changing the Affections of their wicked Hearts, and turning them unto the Lord, whose Sacred Word, which (being ingrafted by the Holy Spirit, is able to save Men's Souls, as the Apostle expresses it, Jam. 1. 21.) I endeavour'd to apply to, and fix on them.</p>
            <p>On Whitsunday, the 5th instant, I preach'd to the Condemn'd Persons and others there present, both in the Morning and Afternoon, upon part of the Scripture appointed to be read for the Epistle for that Day, viz. Acts Ch. 2. the 1st, 2d, 3d, and 4th Verses, the Words being these: And when the Day of Pentecost was fully come, they were all with one accord in one place. And suddenly there came a Sound from Heaven as of a rushing mighty Wind, and it filled all the House where they were sitting. And there appear'd unto them Cloven Tongues, like as of Fire, and it sate upon each of them. And they were all filled with the Holy Ghost, and began to speak with other Tongues, as the Spirit gave them utterance.</p>
            <p>In my Explication of which Words I observ'd this following Method.</p>
            <p>First, I shew'd, that by the Figure of Cloven Tongues that sate upon each of the Apostles, is signified,</p>
            <p>1st, The Light, which they then receiv'd, and were to impart both to the Jews and Gentiles, i.e. to all the People and Nations of the World.</p>
            <p>2dly, The fervent Heat and Zeal, the supernatural Strength and Courage wherewith the Apostles were endu'd by the Holy Ghost, so as to be enabled (in a moment) effectually, and with wonderful Success, to Preach CHRIST and the Power of his Resurrection.</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA171506220002"/>
            <p>3dly, The speedy Spreading of the Gospel through the whole World, carrying all before it, and prevailing over all Prejudice, Ignorance, Error, Malice, and Wickedness.</p>
            <p>4thly, The Purity and Holiness both of Life and Doctrine, which the Apostles then did, and all true Ministers of CHRIST do appear with in the World.</p>
            <p>These Particulars I illustrated, by shewing,</p>
            <p>That as the Properties of Fire are,</p>
            <p>1st, To Melt that which is Hard:</p>
            <p>2dly, To Heat that which is Cold:</p>
            <p>3dly, To Enlighten that which is Dark:</p>
            <p>4thly, To Harden that which is Soft:</p>
            <p>5thly, To Cleanse that which is Impure:</p>
            <p>6thly, To Ascend upwards:</p>
            <p>And</p>
            <p>7thly, To Encrease and Multiply, when dispers'd:</p>
            <p>So the Properties of the Spirit are,</p>
            <p>1st, To Soften our Hard Hearts.</p>
            <p>2dly, To Heat our Cold Devotions.</p>
            <p>3dly, To Enlighten our Dark Understandings.</p>
            <p>4thly, To Strengthen our Weaknesses and Infirmities.</p>
            <p>5thly, To Try and Cleanse the Impurities of our Souls.</p>
            <p>6thly, To make our Thoughts and Desires to Ascend upwards, and fix on those things which are above.</p>
            <p>And lastly, To Encrease and Multiply the Gifts of Grace in us.</p>
            <p>Secondly, I proceeded to, and enlarg'd upon, this Argument (arising from the Premises) viz. That seeing the Christian Religion was Establish'd and Confirm'd by such stupendious Miracles as were wrought by Christ Himself, and His Apostles, Men are inexcusable who will not demonstrate their Belief by a strict Obedience to the Divine Precepts of it.</p>
            <p>Lastly, I concluded all (for the present) with this Admonition to my Auditory, and particularly to the Condemn'd Prisoners, viz. That they would seriously examin themselves in this Matter, duly considering, Whether their Lives had been conformable to those Precepts; and it not take effectual care speedily to amend whatever they should find they had done amis that they might die in a better state than that which they had liv'd in, and by exerting such Acts of Faith and Repentance as might restore them to GOD's Image and Favour, prevent their Eternal Damnation, and obtain the Salvation of GOD, through the alone Merits of JESUS CHRIST our Lord.</p>
            <p>Again, on Trinity-Sunday, the 12th instant, I likewise preach'd to them both in the Morning and Afternoon, and took my Text out of the Gospel appointed for that Day, viz. St. Joh iii. 3. JESUS answer'd and said unto him. Verily, verily I say unto thee, Except a Man be born again, he cannot see the Kingdom of God.</p>
            <p>From these Words, first explain'd in general with their Context, I then endeavour'd to shew in particular,</p>
            <p>I. What it is to be born again,</p>
            <p>II. What is here meant by the Kingdom of God, and the Seeing of it.</p>
            <p>III. How much it concerns every one earnestly to labour after Regeneration, or the New Birth, mention'd in the Text, because without it, it is impossible for Men to see the Kingdom of God; i. e. to be admitted either into his Kingdom of Grace in this World, or to the blessed Enjoyment of his Kingdom of Glory in the next.</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA171506220003"/>
            <p>IV. How an old Habit of Sin, to which unthinking Carnal Men Insensibly arrive by degrees, is directly opposite to this New Birth, and consequently a perfect Hindrance to the Attainment both of the Kingdom of Grace here, and the Kingdom of Glory hereafter.</p>
            <p>V. ult. What effectual Means Men may and ought to use for their being Renew'd and Born again, so as to be enabled to recover themselves out of those Sins into which they have unhappily fall'n, and by such a Recovery escape the dreadful Punishment they had deserv'd, and regain both the Favour of God they had forfeited, and his Kingdom of Grace and Glory, which they had lost.</p>
            <p>And on the last Lord's Day, the 19th instant, I likewise preach'd to them gain on part of the Gospel appointed for that Day, viz. Luk 16. 23, 24. And in Hell he lift up his Eyes being in Torments, and sees Abraham afar off, and Lazarus in his Bosom. And he cry'd and said, Father Abraham, have Mercy on me, and send Lazarus, that he may dip the tip of his Finger in Water, and cool my Tongue, for I am tormented in this Flame.</p>
            <p>From which Words, first explain'd (with their Context) in general, I shew'd in particular,</p>
            <p>I. That the Soul is capable of an Existence separate from the Body.</p>
            <p>II. That when the Souls of good Men, and true Penitents, depart from their Bodies, they immediately pass into a State of Blessedness.</p>
            <p>III. and lastly, That the Souls of wicked Men and impenitent Sinners, do at the Departure out of their Bodies, presently fall into a State of Misery.</p>
            <p>On these Points I discours'd, and for a further Illustration of them, enlarg'd upon these Particulars.</p>
            <p>1st, The dreadful Torments of the Damned in Hell, who (like the Rich-man in the Parable, of which the Text is a part) cannot obtain so much as a Drop of Water to ease and cool their burning Thirst.</p>
            <p>2dly, The Happiness of the Blessed in Heaven, who (after the Miseries of this present Life are over) enjoy perpetual Rest and Felicity in the Bosom of God their Heavenly Father.</p>
            <p>3dly, The Certainty and Eternity of both thse, viz. the Punishment of the Wicked, and the Reward of the Righteous, i. e. the true Penitents</p>
            <p>Having enlarg'd upon these Heads and Particulars, I concluded at this, as at other times before, with such pathetick and pressing Exhortations to the Condemn'd Persons as I thought most proper and conducive to the begetting in them a true Sense and sincere Repentance of their Sins, together with a Spirit of Love both to GOD and their Neighbour, and a due Concern for their own Souls. And here, that I might (if possible) be the happy Instrument of rescuing them out of their Spiritual Slavery, even from under the Dominion of Sin and Satan, I shew'd them the necessity of using their utmost Endeavours to redeem the Time they had mispent, to grieve for their Sins, to humble themselves before God, to cry unto Him for Pardon, and to implore his Grace, that by the Power of it they might recover themselves, and be brought out of the great Danger they were in of dying in their Sins, into the happy state of being made alive unto GOD, who alone was able and willing to make such a blessed Change in them, as to turn their Temporal Shameful Death (which was approaching and terrible) in this World, into an Eternal Life of Immortal Glory and all Blissful Enjoyment in the next</p>
            <p>When I had them under Examination in private, I severally admonish'd them, and apply'd my self with plain Instructions and earnest Exhorta</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA171506220004"/>
            <p>tions to them, according to their respective Capacities and Circumstances (discover'd by themselves to me, and by me in them) then such of them as were appointed for Death gave me the following Accounts both of their past Lives and present Dispositions.</p>
            <p>1. <persName id="OA17150622n51-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17150622n51-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17150622n51-1" type="surname" value="IRISH"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17150622n51-1" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Irish</persName>, condemn'd for breaking the House of <persName id="OA17150622n51-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17150622n51-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17150622n51-2" type="surname" value="BATEMAN"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17150622n51-2" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Bateman</persName>, <rs id="OA17150622-occupation-1" type="occupation">Esq</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17150622n51-2 OA17150622-occupation-1"/>; and taking thence 18 Pewter Dishes, 4 Plates, and other Goods, on the 27th of April last. He said, he was above 70 Years of Age, born at <placeName id="OA17150622-geo-3">
                  <interp inst="OA17150622-geo-3" type="type" value="county"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA17150622n51-1 OA17150622-geo-3"/>
                  <placeName id="OA17150622-geo-4">
                     <interp inst="OA17150622-geo-4" type="type" value="urban_centre"/>
                     <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA17150622n51-1 OA17150622-geo-4"/>Havant</placeName> in Hampshire</placeName>; That he formerly <rs id="OA17150622-occupation-2" type="occupation">follow'd Husbandry</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17150622n51-1 OA17150622-occupation-2"/>, and rented a Farm of 200 a Year, at <placeName id="OA17150622-geo-5">
                  <interp inst="OA17150622-geo-5" type="type" value="county"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA17150622n51-1 OA17150622-geo-5"/>
                  <placeName id="OA17150622-geo-6">
                     <interp inst="OA17150622-geo-6" type="type" value="urban_centre"/>
                     <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA17150622n51-1 OA17150622-geo-6"/>
                     <placeName id="OA17150622-geo-7">
                        <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA17150622n51-1 OA17150622-geo-7"/>Apoledrum</placeName>, near Chichester</placeName> in Sussex</placeName>; That he liv'd very well by it for 7 Years together; but then being too busy in the Rebellion in the West, Anno 1685, he was turn'd out of it by his Landlord. After this, he employ'd himself in going about to <rs id="OA17150622-occupation-3" type="occupation">sell Fish and Fowl</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17150622n51-1 OA17150622-occupation-3"/>, both in <placeName id="OA17150622-geo-8">
                  <interp inst="OA17150622-geo-8" type="type" value="urban_centre"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA17150622n51-1 OA17150622-geo-8"/>London</placeName> and in the Country; and by that got his Livelihood for these 20 Years past. As to the Fact that brought him under this Condemnation, he said, he did not commit it himself, but own'd, that he bought the Pewter of the Thief. He would fain have pretended that he never was guilty of any other Thing illegal; but when I put him in mind, that he had been in <placeName id="OA17150622-geo-9">
                  <interp inst="OA17150622-geo-9" type="type" value="site"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA17150622n51-1 OA17150622-geo-9"/>Newgate</placeName> before, and (to the best of my Remembrance) burnt in the Hand, he could not deny it, but confess'd he had been a great Sinner, and pray'd GOD, and the Persons he had wrong'd to forgive him.</p>
            <p>2. <persName id="OA17150622n52-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17150622n52-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17150622n52-1" type="surname" value="COCKALE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17150622n52-1" type="given" value="HENRY"/>Henry Cockale</persName>, condemn'd for 2 Burglaries, viz. 1st, for breaking the House of Mr. <persName id="OA17150622n52-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17150622n52-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17150622n52-2" type="surname" value="MAN"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17150622n52-2" type="given" value="THOMAS"/>Thomas Man</persName>, and stealing thence 8 Stone of Beef, on the 19 of May last. And 2dly, for breaking the House of Mr. <persName id="OA17150622n52-3">
                  <interp inst="OA17150622n52-3" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17150622n52-3" type="surname" value="ROBERTS"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17150622n52-3" type="given" value="FRANCIS"/>Francis Roberts</persName>, and stealing thence 17 Cheeses, on the 31st of the same Month. He said, he was 24 Years of Age, born in <placeName id="OA17150622-geo-10">
                  <interp inst="OA17150622-geo-10" type="type" value="parish"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17150622n52-1 OA17150622-geo-10"/>
                  <placeName id="OA17150622-geo-11">
                     <interp inst="OA17150622-geo-11" type="type" value="street"/>
                     <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                           targets="OA17150622n52-1 OA17150622-geo-11"/>Wheeler's-street</placeName> in Spittlefields</placeName>; That for a time he follow'd the <rs id="OA17150622-occupation-4" type="occupation">Silk-weaver's Trade</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17150622n52-1 OA17150622-occupation-4"/>, which he had learnt; but wanting Work, <rs id="OA17150622-occupation-5" type="occupation">went to Sea</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17150622n52-1 OA17150622-occupation-5"/>, and serv'd 3 Years in the Newport, a 6th Rate, commanded by Capt. Poole, and afterwards 7 Weeks in the Monmouth: That being come from Sea, and much in Debt, he was arrested, and put into the <placeName id="OA17150622-geo-12">
                  <interp inst="OA17150622-geo-12" type="type" value="site"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17150622n52-1 n52-4 OA17150622-geo-12"/>Marshalsea</placeName>, where he became acquainted with <persName id="OA17150622n52-4">
                  <interp inst="OA17150622n52-4" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17150622n52-4" type="surname" value="SCALE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17150622n52-4" type="given" value="EDWARD"/>Edward Scale</persName>, who brought him into those 2 Robberies, and then turn'd Evidence against him. At first he would make me believe that these were his first Facts; but afterwards he own'd he had been guilty of some others, tho' not many, nor great. He further confess'd, he had liv'd a loose Life, breaking the Sabbath day, Swearing, Drinking, Gaming, &amp;c. tho' by the good Education he had receiv'd from his Parents, he well understood the heinousness of those Sins; the Remembrance of which was a great Trouble to his Mind, especially when he consider'd he must now account to GOD for them. He earnestly pray'd for Mercy and Forgiveness.</p>
            <p>3. <persName id="OA17150622n53-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17150622n53-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17150622n53-1" type="surname" value="DURHAM"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17150622n53-1" type="given" value="RICHARD"/>Richard Durham</persName>, alias <persName id="OA17150622n53-99">
                  <interp inst="OA17150622n53-99" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17150622n53-99" type="surname" value="BARROW"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17150622n53-99" type="given" value="RICHARD"/>Barrow</persName>, (this latter being his right Name) condemn'd for breaking the House of <persName id="OA17150622n53-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17150622n53-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17150622n53-2" type="surname" value="PUGH"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17150622n53-2" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Pugh</persName>,<rs id="OA17150622-occupation-6" type="occupation"> Esq</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17150622n53-2 OA17150622-occupation-6"/>; and stealing thence 3 Callicoe Curtains, a Quilt, 6 Napkins, a Silk Petticoat, a Gawze Scarf, 3 Blankets, and other Goods, on the 16th of May last. He said, he was about 24 Years of Age, born in the Parish of <placeName id="OA17150622-geo-13">
                  <interp inst="OA17150622-geo-13" type="type" value="parish"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17150622n53-1 n53-99 n55-2 OA17150622-geo-13"/>St. James Westminster</placeName>; That he had been in Mr. Pugh's House (wherein there was then no Inhabitant) thrice before he was taken there, and own'd also that he had committed some other Thefts, particularly that for which he was try'd at the <placeName id="OA17150622-geo-14">
                  <interp inst="OA17150622-geo-14" type="type" value="site"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17150622n53-1 n53-99 n55-2 OA17150622-geo-14"/>Old-baily</placeName>, in December last, viz. the breaking open the House of <persName id="OA17150622n53-4">
                  <interp inst="OA17150622n53-4" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17150622n53-4" type="surname" value="HERBERT"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17150622n53-4" type="given" value="PHILIP"/>Philip Herbert</persName>, <rs id="OA17150622-occupation-7" type="occupation">Esq</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17150622n53-4 OA17150622-occupation-7"/>; on the 8th of October, 1714; of which Fact (not for his Innocency, but for want of sufficient Evidence) he was acquitted. But taking no Warning, nor Care to prevent his final Ruin, he went on in his wicked Ways, and so brought himself at last to this shameful untimely End. He further said, That he <rs id="OA17150622-occupation-8" type="occupation">went to Sea</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17150622n53-1 n53-99 n55-2 OA17150622-occupation-8"/> very Young; had serv'd on board several Men of War, and led a vicious Life, the dismal Consequences of which he was now sensible of; and therefore earnestly pray'd GOD to be merciful to him, and forgive him all his Sins. He desir'd that the World might be told, That <persName id="OA17150622n53-88">
                  <interp inst="OA17150622n53-88" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17150622n53-88" type="surname" value="Barrow"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17150622n53-88" type="given" value="Elizabeth"/>Elizabeth Barrow</persName> (his lawful <rs id="OA17150622-occupation-9" type="occupation">Wife</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17150622n53-88 OA17150622-occupation-9"/>) was a very honest Woman, not in the least concern'd with him in any of his wicked Doings: That he had not liv'd with her for above these 5 Years past; and, That for the three last of them he had kept Company with another Woman, whose Husband had left her: Of which double Adultery he heartily repented, and wish'd that this lewd Woman</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA171506220005"/>
            <p>would do so too; considering the innumerable Miseries such lascivious and dishonest Practices always involve Men and Women in. Upon my asking him, in what manner he robb'd Esq; Pugh's House, and what Goods he took thence, he gave me this particular Account, viz. That on the Friday Night before he was taken, he got over the Pales, forc'd a Shutter open, enter'd the House, (being then alone) and took a pair of Tongs, a Frying-pan, a Stue-pan, a Shovel, and a Poker, all which he carry'd away; and presently return'd with a lighted Candle (for before he was in the Dark) and took the Bed-Curtains, one pair of Sheets, 2 Table cloths, a Furbelo'd Scarf, and a Silk Petticoat: All this he did the first Night. On the next, which was the Saturday Night, he went in again alone, and took a Quilt and another Bed-Curtain, with 3 Blankets; which was all he took that Night. On the Monday following he entic'd <persName id="OA17150622n54-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17150622n54-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17150622n54-1" type="surname" value="EDWARDS"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17150622n54-1" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Edwards</persName> to go along with him, and so they went together to the same House at Night, and took one Indian Silk-Gown and Petticoat, one Indian Callicoe Gown and Petticoat, a Morning-Gown, 2 Sarsenet Hoods, a black Hood, a Suit of Lac'd Head-dresses, a Pair of Stays trimm'd with Silver, and another plain, a Parcel of Ribbons, 2 Lac'd Shifts, a Silver Inkhorn, and a little Trunk that was done with Silver, in which there was 3 Locks of Hair, a pair of Bracelets, a Snuff-box, and 2 small Scent-bottles: All which they then carry'd away, leaving behind 'em a great quantity of Linnen and other Goods, which they had bundl'd up in the Ticking of a Bed, after they had taken the Feathers out, with a design to fetch it away the next Night; so indeed they came accordingly, but there being then some Men in the House ready to receive them, they were apprehended and brought to Justice.</p>
            <p>4. <persName id="OA17150622n55-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17150622n55-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17150622n55-1" type="surname" value="EDWARDS"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17150622n55-1" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Edwards</persName>, condemn'd for being concern'd in the Fact with the abovenamed <persName id="OA17150622n55-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17150622n55-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17150622n55-2" type="surname" value="DURHAM"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17150622n55-2" type="given" value="RICHARD"/>Richard Durham</persName>. He said he was about 19 years of Age, born in the Parish of <placeName id="OA17150622-geo-15">
                  <interp inst="OA17150622-geo-15" type="type" value="parish"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17150622n55-1 n54-1 OA17150622-geo-15"/>St. Giles in the Fields</placeName>; That he was bound <rs id="OA17150622-occupation-10" type="occupation">Apprentice to a Brickmaker</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17150622n55-1 n54-1 OA17150622-occupation-10"/>, and never committed any Robbery before; but being a little loose, he was easily brought into the Commission of this, by the said Durham, to whom he was something related.</p>
            <p>5. <persName id="OA17150622n56-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17150622n56-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17150622n56-1" type="surname" value="JOHNSON"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17150622n56-1" type="given" value="JAMES"/>James Johnson</persName>, alias <persName id="OA17150622n56-99">
                  <interp inst="OA17150622n56-99" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17150622n56-99" type="surname" value="FISHPOND"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17150622n56-99" type="given" value="JAMES"/>Fishpond</persName>, alias <persName id="OA17150622n56-88">
                  <interp inst="OA17150622n56-88" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17150622n56-88" type="surname" value="VIVIER"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17150622n56-88" type="given" value="JAMES"/>Vivier</persName>, condemn'd for breaking the House of Mr. <persName id="OA17150622n56-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17150622n56-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17150622n56-2" type="surname" value="BAKER"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17150622n56-2" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Baker</persName>, and stealing thence 7 dozen of Hatts, on the 28th of May last. He said, he was 16 years of Age, born of honest Parents in <placeName id="OA17150622-geo-16">
                  <interp inst="OA17150622-geo-16" type="type" value="parish"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17150622n56-1 n56-99 n56-88 OA17150622-geo-16"/>Spittlefields</placeName>; That he <rs id="OA17150622-occupation-11" type="occupation">went to Sea</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17150622n56-1 n56-99 n56-88 OA17150622-occupation-11"/> (when but 10 years old) and serv'd on board the Russel, and a Prize-ship, call'd in French, Le Jeu d'Enfant; in English, The Child's Play, with other Men of War. He acknowledg'd he had not liv'd that virtuous Life to which he was brought up; and, That GOD was just in bringing this Calamity upon him; praying, That all his Sins (of which he heartily repented) might be forgiven.</p>
            <p>6. <persName id="OA17150622n57-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17150622n57-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17150622n57-1" type="surname" value="GUY"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17150622n57-1" type="given" value="SHADRACH"/>Shadrach Guy</persName>, who receiv'd Sentence of Death at the <placeName id="OA17150622-geo-17">
                  <interp inst="OA17150622-geo-17" type="type" value="site"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17150622n3-1 n57-1 OA17150622-geo-17"/>Old-baily</placeName>, on the 25th day of February, 1714/1715, for breaking open the Chambers of <persName id="OA17150622n57-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17150622n57-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17150622n57-2" type="surname" value="MUSGRAVE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17150622n57-2" type="given" value="RALPH"/>Ralph Musgrave</persName>, <rs id="OA17150622-occupation-12" type="occupation">Esq</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17150622n57-2 OA17150622-occupation-12"/>; in <placeName id="OA17150622-geo-18">
                  <interp inst="OA17150622-geo-18" type="type" value="site"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17150622n3-1 n57-1 n57-2 OA17150622-geo-18"/>Staple's Inn</placeName>, and stealing thence a Gold Watch and Chain, of the Value of 35 l. together with a Pocket-book, two pair of Pistols, and other Things, on the 15th of January last; having all this while lain in <placeName id="OA17150622-geo-19">
                  <interp inst="OA17150622-geo-19" type="type" value="site"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17150622n3-1 n57-1 OA17150622-geo-19"/>Newgate</placeName> under a Reprieve during Pleasure, was now referr'd to his former Judgment, and order'd for Execution, which it seem'd he did little expect, till he was told of it on last Wednesday the 15th instant, when as he then thought he should die on Friday the 17th, so he became very serious, and was very earnest in making Preparation for Death against that Day; but when afterwards he came to understand that the Day of his Execution was put off to this Wednesday, he grew somewhat remiss; for he employ'd too much of his time in contriving how to make an Interest to obtain a further Reprieve, if not a Pardon. He said, he was about 22 years of age, born in the Parish of <placeName id="OA17150622-geo-20">
                  <interp inst="OA17150622-geo-20" type="type" value="urban_centre"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17150622n3-1 n57-1 OA17150622-geo-20"/>
                  <placeName id="OA17150622-geo-21">
                     <interp inst="OA17150622-geo-21" type="type" value="parish"/>
                     <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                           targets="OA17150622n3-1 n57-1 OA17150622-geo-21"/>St. Thomas the Apostle</placeName>, London</placeName>, of Good and Reputable Parents: That his Father being a Captain in General Talmash's Regiment, went to that Expedition against France, in which this great General was kill'd: That when he was but young, and had learnt to Read and Write well, his Friends sent him to a Latin School; and then he was taught to cast Accompts, and to speak French: That being thus furnish'd with School-Learning, and understanding (likewise) something of Dancing, so as to carry himself handsomly in any Company, he was</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA171506220006"/>
            <p>entertain'd in his Grace the Duke of Roxbury's Service, in the Capacity of a <rs id="OA17150622-occupation-13" type="occupation">Page</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17150622n3-1 n57-1 OA17150622-occupation-13"/>, wherein he continu'd above 2 Years, and then left it, and went to serve in the same Capacity the Morocco Embassador, then in England: That after he had been in this last Service about 3 Years, his Friends perswaded him to leave it; which he accordingly did, and went to Travel: That he was in his Travels about 4 Years, which he chiefly spent in <placeName id="OA17150622-geo-22">
                  <interp inst="OA17150622-geo-22" type="type" value="region"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17150622n3-1 n57-1 OA17150622-geo-22"/>France</placeName> and <placeName id="OA17150622-geo-23">
                  <interp inst="OA17150622-geo-23" type="type" value="region"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17150622n3-1 n57-1 OA17150622-geo-23"/>Holland</placeName>; and there having improv'd himself in the French Tongue, (which he had been taught before) and learnt to speak Dutch, he return'd into England about 16 Months ago. I asking him, What Estate he had, and how he supported himself all the while; He answer'd, 1st, That having a Pass, he could Travel at little or no Charge; 2dly, That he had an <rs id="OA17150622-occupation-14" type="occupation">Ensign's Pay</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17150622n3-1 n57-1 OA17150622-occupation-14"/>, which (upon his Father's Account) was procur'd him by Major Rhine, an Irish Officer. I further asking him, How it came to pass that he left the Service of a Christian, to go to that of a Mahumetan, by which he put himself in danger of being forc'd to embrace that Religion, if the said Embassador had carry'd him home with him: He reply'd, That his Design was to leave him in <placeName id="OA17150622-geo-24">
                  <interp inst="OA17150622-geo-24" type="type" value="region"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17150622n3-1 n57-1 OA17150622-geo-24"/>Spain</placeName>, where he had an Uncle, whom he was desirous to see, and (if he could) to live with; for he understood that Embassador was (in his Return) to pass thro' that part of <placeName id="OA17150622-geo-25">
                  <interp inst="OA17150622-geo-25" type="type" value="region"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17150622n3-1 n57-1 OA17150622-geo-25"/>Spain</placeName> where his Uncle liv'd. This is what he said as to the Passages of his former Life; but as to the Fact which he was condemn'd for, he would not at first confess himself guilty of it; tho' at last he did. He acknowledg'd he had committed many Faults thro' the whole Course of his Life; as, neglecting the Service of GOD, profaning the Lord's Day, and being otherwise very loose; but had never committed any Theft or Robbery before this. Upon which I told him, That if he would take the pains to recollect himself, he should find (as I did) that he had been a Prisoner in Newgate before now. To which he answer'd, That it was so; and that about 6 Years ago (a little before he went to Travel) he was committed to this Goal, upon Suspicion of having stoln a pair of Sheets from his Landlord; but as his said Landlord did afterwards believe he was not guilty of that Fact, (of which himself also told me he was very innocent) he never was prosecuted for it. He seem'd in his outward Carriage to be serious and sensible, and behav'd himself as became a Person under his sad Circumstances so far as I could discern. Sometimes indeed he would reflect upon his Adversary, as if he had dealt too severely with him; but he soon return'd to a Christian Temper, and brought home all his Reflections upon himself, acknowledging that he had justly deserv'd this Punishment, and therefore freely submitted to it, and said, That if any had offended him, he heartily forgave them, as he desir'd to be forgiven. I being inform'd, that he had been an extravagant Youth, very undutiful to his Mother, and had broke her Heart, I put the Question to him: To which he answer'd, That it was too true; and, That he look'd upon this his shameful End as a due Punishment to him for his Undutifulness and Cruelty to his Mother, and wish'd it might be a Warning to others.</p>
            <p>At the Place of Execution (whither they were carry'd from <placeName id="OA17150622-geo-26">
                  <interp inst="OA17150622-geo-26" type="type" value="site"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17150622n3-1 n57-1 n51-1 n52-1 n53-1 n53-99 n55-2 n55-1 n54-1 n56-1 n56-99 n56-88 OA17150622-geo-26"/>Newgate</placeName> in 2 Carts this Day) I attended them for the last time; and after proper Exhortations to them, Prayers, and singing of Penitent Psalms, and rehearsing the Apostles Creed, I recommended them to GOD's gracious Mercy, which they all did earnestly pray for. They also desir'd the Prayers of the Spectators, and wish'd, That all (both Young and Old) would take Warning by them, avoid their Sins, and prevent their coming to the like shameful End. After this, I withdrew, praying GOD to give them a blessed Admittance into his Everlasting Kingdom. Then the Cart drew away, and they were turn'd off, calling upon GOD to have Mercy on them, and receive their Souls.</p>
            <p>This is all the Account here to be given of these Dying Persons, by me,</p>
            <p>
               <persName id="OA17150622n61-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17150622n61-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17150622n61-1" type="surname" value="LORRAIN"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17150622n61-1" type="given" value="PAUL"/>PAUL LORRAIN</persName>, <rs id="OA17150622-occupation-15" type="occupation">Ordinary</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17150622n61-1 OA17150622-occupation-15"/>.</p>
            <p>Wednesd. June 22d. 1715.</p>
            <p>London Printed, and are Sold by J. Morphew, near Stationers-hall.</p>
            <p>Where may be had the 2d Edition of the Tale of the Raven and Blackbird; the 2d Edit, of the State of the Church of England; two Poems, by the Author of the Blackbird's-Song. Pr. 4d. each.</p>
         </div0>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>