<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<TEI.2>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div0 type="ordinarysAccount" id="OA17320605">
            <interp inst="OA17320605" type="uri" value="ordinarysAccounts/OA17320605"/>
            <interp inst="OA17320605" type="date" value="17320605"/>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA173206050001"/>
            <p>THE ORDINARY of NEWGATE, His ACCOUNT of the Behaviour, Confessions, and Dying Words, OF THE MALEFACTORS, Who were EXECUTED at TYBURN, On MONDAY the 5th of this Instant JUNE, 1732.</p>
            <p>BEING THE FIFTH EXECUTION in the MAYORALTY OF THE Rt. Hon. <persName id="OA17320605n3-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n3-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n3-1" type="surname" value="CHILD"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n3-1" type="given" value="FRANCIS"/>FRANCIS CHILD</persName>, <rs id="OA17320605-occupation-1" type="occupation">Esq</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17320605n3-1 OA17320605-occupation-1"/>;</p>
            <p>Number V. For the said YEAR.</p>
            <p>LONDON:</p>
            <p>Printed and Sold by <persName id="OA17320605n6-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n6-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n6-1" type="surname" value="APPLEBEE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n6-1" type="given" value="JOHN"/>JOHN APPLEBEE</persName>, in <placeName id="OA17320605-geo-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605-geo-1" type="type" value="street"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA17320605n6-1 OA17320605-geo-1"/>Bolt-Court</placeName>, near the <placeName id="OA17320605-geo-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605-geo-2" type="type" value="site"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA17320605n6-1 OA17320605-geo-2"/>Leg-Tavern</placeName>, <placeName id="OA17320605-geo-3">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605-geo-3" type="type" value="street"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA17320605n6-1 OA17320605-geo-3"/>Fleet-street</placeName>. M.DCC.XXXII.</p>
            <p>[Price Three-Pence.]</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA173206050003"/>
            <p>THE ORDINARY of NEWGATE, His ACCOUNT of the Behaviour, Confession, &amp;c.</p>
            <p>AT the King's Commission of Oyer and Terminer, and Gaol-Delivery of Newgate, held (before the Right Hon. <persName id="OA17320605n9-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n9-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n9-1" type="surname" value="CHILD"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n9-1" type="given" value="FRANCIS"/>FRANCIS CHILD</persName>, <rs id="OA17320605-occupation-2" type="occupation">Esq</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17320605n9-1 OA17320605-occupation-2"/>; <rs id="OA17320605-occupation-3" type="occupation">Lord Mayor</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17320605n9-1 OA17320605-occupation-3"/> of the City of <placeName id="OA17320605-geo-4">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605-geo-4" type="type" value="urban_centre"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA17320605n9-1 OA17320605-geo-4"/>London</placeName>; the Hon. Mr. Justice Page; the Hon. Mr. Baron Cummins; the Worshipful Mr. Serjeant Urlin, Deputy-Recorder of the City of London, and others his Majesty's Justices of Oyer and Terminer, for the City of London, and Justices of the Gaol-Delivery of Newgate, holden for the said City and County of Middlesex) at <placeName id="OA17320605-geo-5">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605-geo-5" type="type" value="site"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA17320605n9-1 OA17320605-geo-5"/>Justice-Hall in the Old Bailey</placeName>, on Thursday, Friday, Saturday and Monday, being the 25th, 26th, 27th and 29th of May, 1732; in the Fifth Year of his Majesty's Reign.</p>
            <p>Nine Men, viz. <persName id="OA17320605n10-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n10-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n10-1" type="surname" value="DUNSTON"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n10-1" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Dunston</persName>, <persName id="OA17320605n10-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n10-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n10-2" type="surname" value="OSBURN"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n10-2" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Osburn</persName>, <persName id="OA17320605n10-3">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n10-3" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n10-3" type="surname" value="ROBERTS"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n10-3" type="given" value="ROBERT"/>Robert Roberts</persName>, alia <persName id="OA17320605n10-10">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n10-10" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n10-10" type="surname" value="ROBINSON"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n10-10" type="given" value="ROBERT"/>Robinson</persName>, <persName id="OA17320605n10-4">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n10-4" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n10-4" type="surname" value="WAKELING"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n10-4" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Wakeling</persName>, <persName id="OA17320605n10-5">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n10-5" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n10-5" type="surname" value="WOOLCOTT"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n10-5" type="given" value="WILLIAM"/>William Woolcott</persName>, <persName id="OA17320605n10-6">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n10-6" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n10-6" type="surname" value="BARNS"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n10-6" type="given" value="HENRY"/>Henry Barns</persName>, <persName id="OA17320605n10-7">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n10-7" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n10-7" type="surname" value="LONGMORE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n10-7" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Longmore</persName>, <persName id="OA17320605n10-8">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n10-8" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n10-8" type="surname" value="SPAUL"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n10-8" type="given" value="EDWARD"/>Edward Spaul</persName>, alias <persName id="OA17320605n10-11">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n10-11" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n10-11" type="surname" value="SPAW"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n10-11" type="given" value="EDWARD"/>Spaw</persName>, and <persName id="OA17320605n10-9">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n10-9" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n10-9" type="surname" value="SHAW"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n10-9" type="given" value="MICHAEL"/>Michael Shaw</persName>, were by the Jury found guilty of capital Offences, and sentenc'd to die.</p>
            <p>While under Sentence, they were instructed from these Words, Then said Jesus unto his Disciples, if any Man will come after me, let him deny himself, and take up his Cross, and follow me. St. Math. xvi. 24. This Jesus said unto his Disciples, unto these who are willing to be taught and instructed by him, in the Way which leadeth unto Life everlasting. All they who are come unto him. By a new and living Way which he hath consecrated for</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA173206050004"/>
            <p>us through the Vail, that is to say his Flesh. Heb. x. 20. All who come to Christ, our compassionate high Priest, touched with the feeling of our Infirmities, by the new Way, the only perpetual, effectual Means of Salvation, in opposition to the Jewish Sacrifices and Ceremonies, which, by the coming of the Massias, are now abrogated, by the way consecrated, or solemnly appointed and by him used in his Ascention unto Heaven; all who come to him through the Vail, not the great Vail or Curtain of the Sanctuary, by which the Jews entered into it, but all true believers, who come to God in Heaven, who look up unto him, from whom cometh their Salvation, and who, by a lively Faith, represent unto themselves Christ's Flesh, that is to say, his human Nature; with all that he hath done in it for them, that so they may come to the Enjoyment of God's Grace and Glory: All who approve and make their free Choice, of this only certain, new, infallible Method of Salvation, propos'd and offer'd to us by our Lord Jesus Christ in his everlasting Gospel, all such are here invited to come unto him, and to be made partakers of eternal Life, in and through him. I likewise observ'd to them the Freedom and Universality of God's Grace, as it is here signify'd to us, if any Man will come after me, any Man be what he will, Jew or Gentile, Bond, or Free of whatever Station, high or low, Rich or Poor, &amp;c. they are all without Distinction, or making any Difference, invited to come unto Jesus Christ, and become partakers of his Holiness, in order to attain that Happiness and Glory, which is prepared for the Saints in Light. Then I insisted upon the Terms, on which we are thus invited to come unto our blessed Saviour, if any Man will come after me, let him deny himself; this is the Condition of the Gospel, to deny ourselves to all ungodliness and wordly Lusts, and to live Soberly, Righteously and Godly, in a present evil World; to renounce that ease and softness, those Pleasures and Delights, with which the Flesh is gratified and pamper'd; we must renounce our own understandings, and give ourselves wholly up to God, to be led and conducted in all our ways by his holy Spirit; since it is God that worketh in us, both to will and to do of his good Pleasure; finally we must deny ourselves to all the Pleasures, Pomps, Vanities, Riches and Grandieur of a present evil World, wherein there is nothing</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA173206050005"/>
            <p>but the Lusts of the Flesh, the Lust of the Eye, and Pride of Life.</p>
            <p>I show'd them also, how unreasonable it was, to be addicted to such vile and abominable Courses, as Thieving and Robbery; which Method of Life brought them into a State of Enmity with all Mankind, set them in opposition to all Religion and Virtue, and reduced them to the Nature of Savage Brutes and Animals, which live upon devouring the Intectines of each other</p>
            <p>I instructed them also concerning the christian Sacraments, how they were early dedicated to God in Baptism, and since they had in such a scandalous Manner broken their baptismal Vows, I advised them to renew their Vows and Obligations to Almighty God, by partaking in the Sacrament of the Lord's Supper, the Nature of which I explain'd to them from these Words. The Cup of Blessing which we bless, is it not the Communion of the Blood of Christ. The Bread which we break, is it not the Communion of the Body of Christ, 1. Cor. x. 16. When these and many like Exhortations were given, all of them attended in Chapel, and made regular Responses saving <persName id="OA17320605n15-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n15-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n15-1" type="surname" value="Spawl"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n15-1" type="given" value="Edw"/>Edw. Spawl</persName>, who could not read; and they were apparently devout and serious, and behav'd gravely, being attentive, both to Prayers and Exhortations; only Roberts, after the dead Warrant came out, he us'd some indecent Imprecations, at which some of them smil'd, for this I reprov'd him, and he promis'd not to do so again; And on Friday the second Instant, Woolcott laughed to his Neighbours in Time of the Exhortations, for which I commanded Silence, and a decent Carriage, and then all of them were very quiet, and behav'd as became them.</p>
            <p>Upon Wednesday the 21st of May last, the Report was made to his Majesty in Council, of these nine Malefactors under Sentence of Death in <placeName id="OA17320605-geo-6">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605-geo-6" type="type" value="site"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17320605n10-1 n10-2 n10-3 n10-4 n10-5 n10-6 n10-7 n10-8 n10-9 n10-10 n10-11 OA17320605-geo-6"/>Newgate</placeName>, when all of them were order'd for Execution.</p>
            <p>
               <persName id="OA17320605n17-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n17-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n17-1" type="surname" value="WAKELING"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n17-1" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Wakeling</persName>, was indicted for breaking and entring the House of <persName id="OA17320605n17-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n17-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n17-2" type="surname" value="RICHARDS"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n17-2" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Richards</persName>, in the Parish of <placeName id="OA17320605-geo-7">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605-geo-7" type="type" value="parish"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17320605n17-1 n17-2 OA17320605-geo-7"/>St. Margarets Westminster</placeName>, and stealing 64 Guineas, a half Broad-piece, val. 11 s. 6 d. a Leather Pocket, value one Half penny, and two Mole-Skins of no value, the 23d of February last, about 9 in the Morning, no Person then being in the House.</p>
            <p>1. <persName id="OA17320605n18-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n18-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n18-1" type="surname" value="WAKELING"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n18-1" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Wakeling</persName>, near 20 Years of Age, of honest Parents, in <placeName id="OA17320605-geo-8">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605-geo-8" type="type" value="county"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA17320605n18-1 OA17320605-geo-8"/>Bedfordshire</placeName>. His Father came to Town, when he was Young, and serv'd a Brewer, and did not neglect his Son John's education, but put him to School, taught him to Read, Write, and Accompts, to fit him for Business, and had him instructed in the necessary Principles of Religion; and when of Age, he put him <rs id="OA17320605-occupation-4" type="occupation">Apprentice to a Tire-Smith</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17320605n18-1 OA17320605-occupation-4"/> in the Borough, with whom he serv'd till August last, as he said, honestly and carefully; when his Master allow'd him to go out upon a Sunday to visit his Father's Family, or other Relations, but he staying out, as his Master thought, too late, and</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA173206050006"/>
            <p>as Wakeling imagin'd, there being nothing to do, yet at that time, to his fatal misfortune, as he said, they wanted him to look after or order something about a Coach. Upon his coming home, the Master was very severe upon him for neglecting his Business, and beat him; he told him, he would not suffer such treatment, and went off, and stay'd away from his Service for some time; till at last upon his Father's intercession, his Master took him home again, but never forgot the old quarrel, so beat and abus'd him; upon which he ran away and liv'd with his Father, who fail'd not to give him good advices, but he being of a pervese and wicked inclinations, took up with the worst of Company, as lew'd Women, who advis'd him to his ruin, and to follow those pernicious courses, which speedily brought him to an ignominious End. He deny'd that he ever was a common Thief or Robber, but own'd the breaking open Mr. Richards's House, and Stealing thence 64 Guineas, and some more Gold, to the value of 70 l. having got such a considerable Sum of Money, he knew not what to do with it, but went streight to the place of his Nativity in <placeName id="OA17320605-geo-9">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605-geo-9" type="type" value="county"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA17320605n18-1 OA17320605-geo-9"/>Bedfordshire</placeName>, where he was well known, and whether they went immediately in pursuit of him, and upon the third Day after he had done the Robbery, he was taken and brought to Town; that he might meet with the deserved punishment of his Villanies: As this was a considerable Robbery or Burglary, so he was no less lavish in throwing away the Money, for in three Days, at the end of which he was taken up; he spent above twenty Guineas, one of which, he gave to a Coachman, for carrying him to <placeName id="OA17320605-geo-10">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605-geo-10" type="type" value="parish"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17320605n18-1 OA17320605-geo-10"/>High-gate</placeName>. I ask'd him whether he intended to go, or what he was to do with his Money? He said, he intended to go into <placeName id="OA17320605-geo-11">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605-geo-11" type="type" value="county"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17320605n18-1 OA17320605-geo-11"/>Lincolnshire</placeName>, where his Mother's Friends were, and to pass some time there. Being urg'd, that both the places he went to, or intended for, in them he was best known: He own'd that he was infatuated, and had no distinct notions how to dispose upon himself, or his effects; but that by evil Spirits, or his own distracted Thoughts and wicked Dispositions; he was driven head-long towards Destruction. He behav'd civilly and gravely, and own'd that he had been a perverse, wicked and disobedient Youth, both to God and Man, particularly to his Parents; that he had been a notorious Sabbath breaker, Drunkard, Gamester, and haunter of evil Company, particularly vile Women. He hoped for Salvation by the Mercy of God in Christ, declar'd himself Penitent for the Offence of his Life, and died in peace with all Mankind.</p>
            <p>
               <persName id="OA17320605n20-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n20-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n20-1" type="surname" value="OSBORN"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n20-1" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Osborn</persName> and <persName id="OA17320605n20-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n20-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n20-2" type="surname" value="LONGMORE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n20-2" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Longmore</persName>, were indicted for assaulting <persName id="OA17320605n20-3">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n20-3" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n20-3" type="surname" value="ELLIOT"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n20-3" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Elliot</persName> in an open Field, near the Highway, in the Parish of <placeName id="OA17320605-geo-12">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605-geo-12" type="type" value="parish"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17320605n20-1 n20-2 n20-3 OA17320605-geo-12"/>Stepney</placeName>, putting him in Fear, and taking from him a Hatt, a Wigg, a Coat, a Waistcoat, a pair of Shoes and a pair of Buckles, and 5d. in Money, the 10th of April last.</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA173206050007"/>
            <p>They were a second time indicted for assaulting <persName id="OA17320605n21-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n21-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n21-1" type="surname" value="ALLAM"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n21-1" type="given" value="JOSEPH"/>Joseph Allam</persName> in an open Field, near the High-way, in the Parish of <placeName id="OA17320605-geo-13">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605-geo-13" type="type" value="parish"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17320605n20-1 n20-2 n21-1 OA17320605-geo-13"/>Stepney</placeName>, putting him in fear, and taking from him a Wigg, a Cloath Coat and Waistcoat, a woolen Waistcoat, a Shirt, a pair of Holland Sleeves with Cambrick Ruffles, a pair of Shoes, a pair of Buckles, and a pair of Gloves, and 15 d. in Money, April the 12th. Of the first of these Indictments, Longmore was acquitted, but as to the second, he was found Guilty of single Felony. Osborn was cappitally convicted for both. Death.</p>
            <p>
               <persName id="OA17320605n22-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n22-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n22-1" type="surname" value="LONGMORE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n22-1" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Longmore</persName>, who was a third time indicted for assaulting <persName id="OA17320605n22-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n22-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n22-2" type="surname" value="PANTON"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n22-2" type="given" value="JOSHUA"/>Joshua Panton</persName>, in an open place near the High-way, in <placeName id="OA17320605-geo-14">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605-geo-14" type="type" value="parish"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17320605n22-1 n22-2 OA17320605-geo-14"/>White-Chappel</placeName> Parish, putting him in fear, and taking from a Silver Watch, value 3 l. and 4 s. 6d. in Money, April the 20th.</p>
            <p>2. <persName id="OA17320605n23-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n23-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n23-1" type="surname" value="LONGMORE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n23-1" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Longmore</persName>, about 20 Years of Age, was born in <placeName id="OA17320605-geo-15">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605-geo-15" type="type" value="parish"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17320605n23-1 OA17320605-geo-15"/>St. Giles's Parish in the Fields</placeName>, his Father dying left him young, and his Mother setled in Rag-fair, <placeName id="OA17320605-geo-16">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605-geo-16" type="type" value="street"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17320605n23-1 OA17320605-geo-16"/>Rosemary lane</placeName>, educated him at School in reading, writing and casting Accounts for Business, and had him instructed in Religious Principles, so far as he was willing to receive them; when of Age, he <rs id="OA17320605-occupation-5" type="occupation">went to Sea</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17320605n23-1 OA17320605-occupation-5"/>, and served sometimes in Ships of War, at other times in Merchant men, and has been in the <placeName id="OA17320605-geo-17">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605-geo-17" type="type" value="region"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17320605n23-1 OA17320605-geo-17"/>West-Indies</placeName>, up the Streights, upon the <placeName id="OA17320605-geo-18">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605-geo-18" type="type" value="region"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17320605n23-1 OA17320605-geo-18"/>Coast of Guinea</placeName>, and in other places of the World; and as he said, in all his Travels he behav'd himself honestly, and to the liking of his Superiors. When out of Business at Home, he <rs id="OA17320605-occupation-6" type="occupation">wrought upon Ships in the River</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17320605n23-1 OA17320605-occupation-6"/>, and got abundance of Money to maintain himself; but being naturally of a wicked Inclination, he lov'd idleness, best, and applied himself to whoring, gaming, drinking, swearing, and all other kind of Vices, and got into Acquaintance of the most notorious gang of Thieves about the Town; and of these he particular delighted in the Company of Tripland and Fleming, who readily led him into all manner of outragious Villanies. He at First, denied that he had been guilty of any capital Crimes, but that by keeping bad Company, he had put it into the power of wicked Miscreants, to inform of swear against him, whether Guilty or not; but when the dead Warrant came down and all hopes of safety was past, he acknowledged that he had committed a vast many Robberies in partnership with Tripland Fleming and others, and that he was plunged in a most abominable wickednesses and notorious Crimes. As to the three Indictments against him he said that he was innocent of the First, guilty of the Second, for which he was order'd for Transportation, and that he did not commit the third, of which he was capitally convicted, and for which he died, as the same was sworn against him. I represented to him the danger of going to Eternity with a Lye in his right Hand, and show'd him the necessity of Glorifying God, by a plain Confession; but he would not alter in his Acknow</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA173206050008"/>
            <p>ledgments. He was solicited by one to die in another Communion, but would not turn from the Profession he was educated in, as thinking it to be the best. He behav'd himself always soberly, decently, and devoutly in Chapel, declared himself penitent for all, especially the heinous Sins of his Life; that he believed in Christ his only Saviour, and forgave all Men, as he expected forgiveness from God.</p>
            <p>3. <persName id="OA17320605n25-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n25-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n25-1" type="surname" value="OSBORN"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n25-1" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Osborn</persName>, 18 years of Age, of honest Parents about <placeName id="OA17320605-geo-19">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605-geo-19" type="type" value="parish"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17320605n25-1 OA17320605-geo-19"/>Wapping</placeName>, his Father dying and leaving him young, the Mother took care of his Education at School, in reading, writing, and casting Accounts, as became one of his Birth: When of Age, about 12 or 13, he was put our <rs id="OA17320605-occupation-7" type="occupation">Apprentice to a Waterman</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17320605n25-1 OA17320605-occupation-7"/>, whom he served a little more than a Year, but his Master and he not agreeing well together, the cause of which he imputed to his Masters severity and hardships he had put upon him, but 'tis to be fear'd, the true Cause was his own wicked and pervers'd Disposition; he having been naturally an ingrain'd villanous young Rogue, not willing to apply himself to no constant Business, but associating with the vilest of Company, Whores, Thieves, Robbers, Pickpockets, and other refuse of Mankind, who brought him quickly to a fatal and unfortunate End. After he broke his Apprenticeship, he would plie to no more business but drinking in Shops with a set of vile Miscreants and when he wanted Money went out upon the Sneak, stealing what he could lay his Hands upon, picking of Pockets, and at last he had the Impudence, tho' both of a small Stature and young to attack People on the Streets and High-ways; and amongst his other Crimes, he kept Company with base Women, one of whom, tho' he affirm'd to me, that he was never Married, pass'd for his Wife, with whom he liv'd, who had no good advice to give, but was ready to receive what purchase he brought in upon Thieft and Rapine.</p>
            <p>As to the Robbery he was convicted of, he own'd himself equally guilty with the rest; only he said, that the Evidence was in a mistake as to his stabbing of him with a knife, either in the Hand or Breast; for when the Man was Robb'd, he stood at a distance and did nothing of that kind, being upon Guard, while the others committed the Fact. He was an impudent, obdur'd Boy; but after the dead Warrant came out, he often wept and shed Tears, which may be feard was rather the effect of terrour and consternation, upon the apprehensions of a violent Death, than of a sincere Repentance for his Sins. He own'd that he had been a most notorious Rogue and Villain; that he had been a Sabbath breaker, and although his Mother gave him good advices, and endeavour'd to have him instructed in principles of Christianity, yet he minded none of these thins; but gave himself wholly up to a most licentious, disorderly, irregular course</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA173206050009"/>
            <p>of Life; and that therefore God had in Justice afflicted him, and he suffer'd most deservedly for his Crimes. He said, that he believ'd in Christ, repented of his Sins, and forgave all Men.</p>
            <p>
               <persName id="OA17320605n28-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n28-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n28-1" type="surname" value="WOOLCOTT"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n28-1" type="given" value="WILLIAM"/>William Woolcott</persName>, alias <persName id="OA17320605n28-4">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n28-4" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n28-4" type="surname" value="WILLIWICK"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n28-4" type="given" value="WILLIAM"/>Williwick</persName>, and <persName id="OA17320605n28-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n28-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n28-2" type="surname" value="BARNS"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n28-2" type="given" value="HENRY"/>Henry Barns</persName>, were indicted for assaulting <persName id="OA17320605n28-3">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n28-3" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n28-3" type="surname" value="PARDON"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n28-3" type="given" value="WILLIAM"/>William Pardon</persName>, upon the Highway, in <placeName id="OA17320605-geo-20">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605-geo-20" type="type" value="parish"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17320605n28-1 n28-2 n28-3 n28-4 OA17320605-geo-20"/>White-chappel</placeName> Parish, putting him in fear, and taking from him two Keys, a Hat, a Wigg, and 5 s. 10 d. in Money, April the 5th.</p>
            <p>4. <persName id="OA17320605n29-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n29-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n29-1" type="surname" value="BARNS"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n29-1" type="given" value="HENRY"/>Henry Barns</persName>, 17 Years and 5 Months old, born in <placeName id="OA17320605-geo-21">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605-geo-21" type="type" value="parish"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17320605n29-1 OA17320605-geo-21"/>St. Sepulchres</placeName> Parish, of mean Parents, who go about the Streets with Wheel-barrows selling Fruit; was educated at a Free-School there, to read, write and cast Accompts, fit for Business, and instructed in the necessary Articles of Religion; but when he should have gone to School, he mostly stay'd away, and told notorious Lies to his Father and Mother, who when they found him out in his faults, neglected not to give him the best of Advice, and to correct him sharply for the same; but that he soon forgot, because of the pleasure he took in the Company and Society of the vilest Black-guards, who learn'd him to Drink, Pick and Thieve from his Childhood; at the Age of 13, he was bound <rs id="OA17320605-occupation-8" type="occupation">Apprentice to a Waterman</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17320605n29-1 OA17320605-occupation-8"/>, who ply'd at the <placeName id="OA17320605-geo-22">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17320605n29-1 OA17320605-geo-22"/>Tower-wharf</placeName>, whom he serv'd two Years, but neither with that Care or Honesty which became him; for although he was a kind Master, and greatly encourag'd him, letting him want for nothing needful, yet he had contracted such a base habit of idleness and other vices, that he could not keep to any constant employment, but neglecting his Master's business, and cheating him as much as he could, he still sought after idle and wicked Companions, with whom he drank to excess, and committed other Vices, whenever opportunity offer'd; and at two Years end, he ran away from his Master, and join'd himself to those gangs of Whores and Thieves, who hurried him a pace to his Ruin. He liv'd with a Woman unmarried, who is now taken up upon a Warrant for quarrelling, and is in New-Prison. He blam'd nobody for his misfortunes, but his own vicious inclinations. He pretended that he left his Master, because he made him draw Drink in an Ale-house which he kept; but that was only an excuse. He own'd himself to have been a most naughty, perverse, disobedient Boy; that he was acquainted with all kind of Thieving, and all manner of Vice; that he was a most notorious Sabbath-breaker, for some Years past having never gone to Church, but in the time of Divine Service; having employ'd himself in Drinking, and keeping Company with lew'd Women, &amp;c. He own'd the Fact he was convicted of, and that he had committed a vast number of other Thefts and Robberies, in company with Tripland, Fleming and others; having had no other way to subsist, or at least to be provided with Money, for some considerable time past, but</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA173206050010"/>
            <p>by such hellish, devilish, unaccountable Practices. He own'd the Justice of his Sentence, and that he was a Villainous, naughty Boy, good for nothing. He said that he was a great drinker of Drams in Ginneva-Shops, where was the common rendezvous of such vile, wicked People, with whom having contracted acquaintance; he willingly went to all manner of excess of Riot. He declar'd his Faith in Christ, that he was Penitent for his Sins, and died in peace with all the World.</p>
            <p>5. <persName id="OA17320605n31-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n31-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n31-1" type="surname" value="WOOLCOT"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n31-1" type="given" value="WILLIAM"/>William Woolcot</persName>, alias <persName id="OA17320605n31-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n31-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n31-2" type="surname" value="WILLIWICK"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n31-2" type="given" value="WILLIAM"/>Williwick</persName>, 20 Years of Age, Born at <placeName id="OA17320605-geo-23">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605-geo-23" type="type" value="county"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17320605n31-1 n31-2 OA17320605-geo-23"/>
                  <placeName id="OA17320605-geo-24">
                     <interp inst="OA17320605-geo-24" type="type" value="urban_centre"/>
                     <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                           targets="OA17320605n31-1 n31-2 OA17320605-geo-24"/>Tauton</placeName> in Somersetshire</placeName>, of mean Parents, his Father dy'd and left him Young, upon the Care of the Mother, who took care of his Education at School, in reading, writing and accompts, to fit him for Business, and instructed him in christian Principles. When of Age he was put to a <rs id="OA17320605-occupation-9" type="occupation">Tanner</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17320605n31-1 n31-2 OA17320605-occupation-9"/> in <placeName id="OA17320605-geo-25">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605-geo-25" type="type" value="urban_centre"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17320605n31-1 n31-2 OA17320605-geo-25"/>Bristol</placeName>, not loving the Trade, nor agreeing with his Master, at the End of two Years he left him, and came to Town, without visiting his Mother or any of his Relations, where being a Stranger he knew not what to do, so he plied at Stocks Market as a <rs id="OA17320605-occupation-10" type="occupation">Porter</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17320605n31-1 n31-2 OA17320605-occupation-10"/>, and sometimes he had Business and at other times he had none: Then seeing that Affairs did not answer to his Mind, he drew to the Acquaintance of Gangs of Thieves and Robbers, and in Company of his Evidences Tripland, Fleming and others. He committed a great Number of Street and Highway Robberies, and at other Times he was employ'd in picking of Pockets, Shoplifting and other kinds of Thefts. He was a meer, naked Black-guard, void of all Grace and good Manners, and the main of his Business was, to rob, thieve and steal; so that it is to be suspected, although he denied it, that he was addicted to the same Manner of Life at <placeName id="OA17320605-geo-26">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605-geo-26" type="type" value="urban_centre"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17320605n31-1 n31-2 OA17320605-geo-26"/>Bristol</placeName>, before he came up. He own'd, that he was guilty of all those Vices to which those vile People are inclin'd, and that he suffered most justly for his contempt of God and neglecting of his Ordinances. In Chapel he made regular Responses, and outwardly complied with the Worship, and was attentive to Exhortations, but sometimes he smil'd to his Companions, which was a most undecent Carriage for one in his deplorable Circumstances. He was a sottish, senseless, unthinking, impudent young Fellow. He acknowledg'd that he had been always inclin'd to all manner of Vice, and void of all Virtue. He hoped for God's Mercy through Christ; said that he repented of his Sins, and died in Peace with all Mankind.</p>
            <p>
               <persName id="OA17320605n32-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n32-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n32-1" type="surname" value="DUNSTAN"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n32-1" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Dunstan</persName>, was indicted for breaking and entering the House of <persName id="OA17320605n32-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n32-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n32-2" type="surname" value="SIMMONS"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n32-2" type="given" value="WILLIAM"/>William Simmons</persName>, in <placeName id="OA17320605-geo-27">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605-geo-27" type="type" value="parish"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17320605n32-1 n32-2 OA17320605-geo-27"/>St. Sepulchres</placeName> Parish, and stealing a Saw, a pair of Nippers, a pair of Plyers, a pair of Compasses, a pair of Scissars, a Brush, a black-lead Pencil, a piece of Mother of Pearl, a small wooden Pully, 12 sets of inside ivory Fan-sticks, 12 sets of outside ivory Fan-sticks, 3 engraved copper Plates, and two pair of Shoes, the</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA173206050011"/>
            <p>Goods of several Persons, the 19th of this Instant May, in the Night.</p>
            <p>6. <persName id="OA17320605n34-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n34-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n34-1" type="surname" value="DUNSTAN"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n34-1" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Dunstan</persName>, 32 Years of Age, of honest Parents who educated him at School to fit him for Business, and taught him christian Principles. When of Age he did not incline to a particular Trade, but lov'd best to <rs id="OA17320605-occupation-11" type="occupation">drive Hackney Coaches</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17320605n34-1 OA17320605-occupation-11"/>, and follow'd that employment for a great many Years, and as he said with Honesty and Reputation. He married a Wife who had some Children by him, one of which is still living, but dissention arising between him and his Wife, as may reasonably be suppos'd, because of his ill Behaviour, he had no Pleasure in living a sociable Life, but went out upon all kind of Extravagances, and would take no Advice either of his own or his Wife's Friends. He got acquainted with thievish and wicked dispos'd People, and took up with strange Women; and that ruin'd him at once Having no more Credit in his ordinary Way of Business, he went to Sea, and serv'd in some Ships of War for 2 or 3 Years past. But when at Home, he plied to his old Way of thieving, picking and stealing, as he had been accustom'd. As to the Burglary he was convicted of, he own'd the same as sworn against him, only with some variation, of Circumstances not material. He acknowledg'd himself to have been a vile, notorious Thief, and a base, whoring, drinking, good for nothing Fellow. He behav'd very well, and apparently with christian Devotion, and a true Sense of his Sins. He declar'd his Faith in Christ; a true Repentance for all, but especially his notorious Sins, and in token of his Penitence he wept often, when all hopes of safety was past; and he heartily forgave all injuries done him, in expectation of forgiveness from God.</p>
            <p>
               <persName id="OA17320605n35-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n35-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n35-1" type="surname" value="ROBERTS"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n35-1" type="given" value="ROBERT"/>Robert Roberts</persName>, alias <persName id="OA17320605n35-3">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n35-3" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n35-3" type="surname" value="ROBERTSON"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n35-3" type="given" value="ROBERT"/>Robertson</persName>, was indicted for breaking and entering the House of <persName id="OA17320605n35-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n35-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n35-2" type="surname" value="WATKINS"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n35-2" type="given" value="HENRY"/>Henry Watkins</persName>, in <placeName id="OA17320605-geo-28">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605-geo-28" type="type" value="parish"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17320605n35-1 n35-2 n35-3 OA17320605-geo-28"/>Shoreditch</placeName> Parish, and stealing a feather Bed, a Bolster, a pair of Sheets, a Pottage Pot, a Pewter Dish, a Plate, 2 Sauce pans, 3 Candlesticks, a Chasfingdish, a Pepper-box, a Drudging-box, a Bottle, and 2 Handkerchiefs, April the 26th about the Hour of 2 in the Morning.</p>
            <p>7. <persName id="OA17320605n36-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n36-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n36-1" type="surname" value="ROBERTS"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n36-1" type="given" value="ROBERT"/>Robert Roberts</persName>, alias <persName id="OA17320605n36-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n36-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n36-2" type="surname" value="ROBERTSON"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n36-2" type="given" value="ROBERT"/>Robertson</persName>, 35 or 36 Years of Age, of honest Parents, who gave him the best of Education they could, and his Father being concerned in a Man of War, got him further instructed in reading, writing and arithmetick, on board the Ship, and he was also instructed in the necessary Principles of Religion; but his evil Inclinations render'd all these Endeavours of none Effect. He always serv'd on board of Ships of War, and came to be <rs id="OA17320605-occupation-12" type="occupation">Boatswain's Mate</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17320605n36-1 n36-2 OA17320605-occupation-12"/>, in which Station, as one who was in his Company told, he was very severe and rigid to the Sailors. He married a Wife about 13 Years ago, of whom he spoke very indifferent off. He was an expert good <rs id="OA17320605-occupation-13" type="occupation">Sailor</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17320605n36-1 n36-2 OA17320605-occupation-13"/>, and, as he said, was respected by his equals, and had the Approbation of his su</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA173206050012"/>
            <p>perior Officers. But being a silly foolish Fellow, what Money he got with much Labour and Industry, the same he spent no less profusely and prodigally, when at home. The Account he gave of the Fact for which he was convicted was to this Purpose. That a Man and his Wife coming into his Room, desir'd Lodging, not knowing were to go: Roberts allow'd them the Use of his Bed, but withal offer'd undecent Carriage to the Woman; upon which as they went off, the Husband promis'd revenge, and that he should land him at Tyburn next Day. When he came into his Room, he found the Goods mention'd in the Indictment, and calling up to his Neighbour above, he said, we want Money, will you pawn these Things? He answer'd, I'll have nothing to do in such Matters. Roberts pawn'd part of the Goods, and the rest of them were found in his Custody; this, his Neighbour aforesaid inform'd and witnessed against him. He own'd, that he was a most debauch'd, wicked Fellow, and that for along time he had been accustom'd to Thieving, and such other Vices as are Incident to those of his Profession. He behav'd always very decently, professed a deep Penitence, that he believ'd in Jesus Christ as his only Saviour, and that he died in Peace with all Men.</p>
            <p>
               <persName id="OA17320605n38-4">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n38-4" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n38-4" type="surname" value="Spawle"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n38-4" type="given" value="Edward"/>Edward Spawle</persName>, alias <persName id="OA17320605n38-5">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n38-5" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n38-5" type="surname" value="Spaw"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n38-5" type="given" value="Edward"/>Spaw</persName>, and <persName id="OA17320605n38-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n38-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n38-1" type="surname" value="LIGHTFOOT"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n38-1" type="given" value="DANIEL"/>Daniel Lightfoot</persName>, were indicted for stealing in the Parish of <placeName id="OA17320605-geo-29">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605-geo-29" type="type" value="parish"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17320605n38-1 n38-4 n38-5 n38-6 n38-2 n38-3 OA17320605-geo-29"/>St. George's in the East</placeName>, Fourteen Chissels, an Ax, A Gouge, two Gimblets, two Hammers, and two Stones; the Goods of <persName id="OA17320605n38-6">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n38-6" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n38-6" type="surname" value="Slack"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n38-6" type="given" value="John"/>John Slack</persName> An Ax, an Iron Square, a pair of Pincers; Chissels, and other things; The Goods of <persName id="OA17320605n38-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n38-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n38-2" type="surname" value="LINDSEY"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n38-2" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Lindsey</persName>, a Lock, two pound of Nails, and other things, the Goods of <persName id="OA17320605n38-3">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n38-3" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n38-3" type="surname" value="SPARKS"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n38-3" type="given" value="RICHARD"/>Richard Sparks</persName>, the 24th of April last; the Jury found them Guilty to the value of 10 d. each.</p>
            <p>
               <persName id="OA17320605n39-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n39-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n39-1" type="surname" value="SPAUL"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n39-1" type="given" value="EDWARD"/>Edward Spaul</persName>, alias <persName id="OA17320605n39-4">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n39-4" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n39-4" type="surname" value="SPAW"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n39-4" type="given" value="EDWARD"/>Spaw</persName> (was a second time) and <persName id="OA17320605n39-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n39-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n39-2" type="surname" value="SHAW"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n39-2" type="given" value="MICHAEL"/>Michael Shaw</persName>, were indicted for breaking and entering the House of <persName id="OA17320605n39-3">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n39-3" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n39-3" type="surname" value="WEBB"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n39-3" type="given" value="ELIZABETH"/>Elizabeth Webb</persName>, in <placeName id="OA17320605-geo-30">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605-geo-30" type="type" value="parish"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17320605n39-1 n39-2 n39-3 n39-4 OA17320605-geo-30"/>White-Chapel</placeName> Parish, and stealing two Porridge Pots, two Saucepans, one Stewpan, a Waistcoat, and some old Rags, April the 21st. between Eleven and Twelve at Night.</p>
            <p>8. <persName id="OA17320605n40-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n40-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n40-1" type="surname" value="SHAW"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n40-1" type="given" value="MICHAEL"/>Michael Shaw</persName>, about 22 or 23 years of Age, what Parents he was descended is not known, but he was educated at School, in, and by the Parish of <placeName id="OA17320605-geo-31">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605-geo-31" type="type" value="parish"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17320605n40-1 OA17320605-geo-31"/>Cripple-Gate</placeName>. When of Age, he was put to a <rs id="OA17320605-occupation-14" type="occupation">Stocking Weaver</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17320605n40-1 OA17320605-occupation-14"/>, and learnt his Trade to a pretty good perfection, so that few such young Men excel'd him: But he was of such a pervers'd Disposition, that it was impossible to keep him at his Business, for he was so addicted to Gaming and Company-keeping, that he prefer'd these Occupations to every thing else. He associated himself to the greatest Robbers and Thieves about the Town, and had infamous Women also to his Companions; and this Method of Life soon brought him to an ignominious End. There was a Gentleman of the Parish, a sober, good Man, who us'd all means imaginable, out of Christian compassion, to reclaim him</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA173206050013"/>
            <p>from this hellish Life, but all in vain. For after he had taken him out of almost all the Prisons in and about <placeName id="OA17320605-geo-32">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605-geo-32" type="type" value="urban_centre"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17320605n40-1 OA17320605-geo-32"/>London</placeName>, for small Crimes and foolish Enterprizes, he still continued in his obstinate and wicked Courses. Once after he came out of <placeName id="OA17320605-geo-33">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605-geo-33" type="type" value="site"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17320605n40-1 OA17320605-geo-33"/>Newgate</placeName>, he recommended him to a Master, and plainly told him his weakside and Faults. The Master took him upon the Gentleman's Account, though he was informed of his preceeding villanous course of Life. He could not settle himself into this good Service, although his Friend had furnish'd him with all manner of Cloaths, which he wanted; he had not been above 8 or ten Days, but went to his old Companions, such as Tripland and Fleming, the most noteable Rogues in the World, and with them Prosecuted his former wicked ways.</p>
            <p>The Gentleman who was his Friend and well wisher, never saw him again but once in <placeName id="OA17320605-geo-34">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605-geo-34" type="type" value="street"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17320605n40-1 OA17320605-geo-34"/>Hounds-ditch</placeName>, when he desir'd another Man who was with him, to cross the Street and pursue him, and another Fellow like himself in his Company: He and the other Man observing his well-wisher, and another Person following close after them, and run away; so his Friend heard no more about him, till he writ to him to come and give him some assistance in <placeName id="OA17320605-geo-35">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605-geo-35" type="type" value="site"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17320605n40-1 OA17320605-geo-35"/>Newgate</placeName>, which the Gentleman was ready to do, as opportunity offered; but then it was out of his Power to serve him any more, with respect to the saving of his Life. He acknowledg'd that he had been a most abominable worthless Person, a Sabbath-breaker, a companion of lew'd Women, a vile Drunkard, and that he had been guilty of a great number of Street or Highway Robberies, and otherwise that he was scarce free of any Sin, except actual Murder. After the Dead Warrant came out, he Cry'd much and lamented his pitiful Case. He declar'd his hope of being sav'd through the merits of Jesus Christ; that he sincerely Repented of all his Sins, and forgave all injurier, as he expected forgiveness from God.</p>
            <p>9. <persName id="OA17320605n43-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n43-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n43-1" type="surname" value="SPAWL"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n43-1" type="given" value="EDWARD"/>Edward Spawl</persName>, alias <persName id="OA17320605n43-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n43-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n43-2" type="surname" value="SPAW"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n43-2" type="given" value="EDWARD"/>Spaw</persName>, about 22 years of Age, of mean Parents, who gave him no education at School, and was very ignorant of Religion. He was put to a <rs id="OA17320605-occupation-15" type="occupation">Weaver</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17320605n43-1 n43-2 OA17320605-occupation-15"/>, and as he said, serv'd his Time carefully and honestly; yet he own'd that he had been a naughty, vitious, and most profligate young Fellow; in joining himself to the worst of Company, both Men and Women, as the rest had done. He own'd the Fact for which he was convicted, though at first he deny'd it, and that he had committed many more Robberies, and had been an habitual Thief for a considerable Time, and that Drinking and Whoring had in a great Measure ruin'd him. He was very ignorant, as all the rest were little better, so that time being but short, it could not be expected that they could profit or advance much in knowledge. They were a set of most Ignominious, Ignorant, Villainous, Disgraceful, Obstinate, Obdur'd young Rogues, as have any</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA173206050014"/>
            <p>time been seen; and doubtless they met with a fate answerable to their just deserts.</p>
            <p>N. B. <persName id="OA17320605n45-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n45-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n45-1" type="surname" value="CHEESBOROUGH"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n45-1" type="given" value="EDMUND"/>Edmund Cheesborough</persName>, was indicted for forging a promissary Note, for 50 l. Dated July the 2d, 1731, and Payable 6 Months after Date, to <persName id="OA17320605n45-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n45-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n45-2" type="surname" value="OLIPHANT"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n45-2" type="given" value="THOMAS"/>Thomas Oliphant</persName>, or Order, by <persName id="OA17320605n45-8">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n45-8" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n45-8" type="surname" value="Brumton"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n45-8" type="given" value="Rich"/>Rich. Brumton</persName>, and an Indorsment upon the said Note, in the Name of <persName id="OA17320605n45-3">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n45-3" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n45-3" type="surname" value="OLIPHANT"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n45-3" type="given" value="THOMAS"/>Thomas Oliphant</persName>, and afterwards Indorsing his own Name thereon, and Publishing the said Note so Indorsed, knowing the same to be false and Counterfeit, with an intent to deceive and defraud <persName id="OA17320605n45-4">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n45-4" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n45-4" type="surname" value="PRUE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n45-4" type="given" value="STEPHEN"/>Stephen Prue</persName>, and unjustly to charge <persName id="OA17320605n45-5">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n45-5" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n45-5" type="surname" value="OLIPHANT"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n45-5" type="given" value="THOMAS"/>Thomas Oliphant</persName>, with the Payment of 50 l. to the great Damage of the said <persName id="OA17320605n45-6">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n45-6" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n45-6" type="surname" value="OLIPHANT"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n45-6" type="given" value="THOMAS"/>Thomas Oliphant</persName> and <persName id="OA17320605n45-7">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n45-7" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n45-7" type="surname" value="PRUE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n45-7" type="given" value="STEPHEN"/>Stephen Prue</persName>. Of this Indictment he was guilty by the Jury, and capitally Convicted on Friday the 26th of May last; but when he was put up into the Cell that Evening, he said to the Keeper who lock'd him in, Good Night to you, for I shall be well to Morrow Morning. He took a piece of Pack-thread and Platted it four fold, with which his Irons were held up; he tied the Pack thread to the Iron grate of the Cell Window, and therewith Strangl'd himself; so that the next Morning when they open'd the Cell, he was found Cold-dead. The Grand-Jury brought him in felo de-se, and he was buried in the <placeName id="OA17320605-geo-36">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605-geo-36" type="type" value="parish"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17320605n45-1 OA17320605-geo-36"/>
                  <placeName id="OA17320605-geo-37">
                     <interp inst="OA17320605-geo-37" type="type" value="street"/>
                     <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                           targets="OA17320605n45-1 OA17320605-geo-37"/>Cross-Road</placeName> at Islington</placeName>. This Cheesborough, broke out of <placeName id="OA17320605-geo-38">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605-geo-38" type="type" value="site"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17320605n45-1 OA17320605-geo-38"/>Newgate</placeName> some Months ago, and was re-taken at <placeName id="OA17320605-geo-39">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605-geo-39" type="type" value="urban_centre"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17320605n45-1 OA17320605-geo-39"/>Carlisle</placeName>, and from thence, by a Habeas Corpus, he was brought to Town by some of the Keepers of Newgate, a Day or two before the Sessions begun.</p>
            <p>The Place of EXECUTION.</p>
            <p>BEfore they went out, Roberts desir'd a Word of me in Secret, and own'd that he had been a very wicked Man, and committed the Burglary, for which he Died, and which he denyed before; and Dunston desir'd it should be made Publick to the World, that, one Night, he stole another Man's Cloaths, who was a Cousin of his own, and not having time to put them on, went out Naked, and broke into a Coachmaker's Shade in <placeName id="OA17320605-geo-40">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605-geo-40" type="type" value="street"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17320605n34-1 OA17320605-geo-40"/>Aldersgate-street</placeName>, with an intt to Rob the same, but being frighten'd by some Noise, he went off Naked as he was, and left his Friend's Cloaths; who for that, was like to be brought into trouble; so this is to acquaint that Coachmaker, that Dunston mas the only Man who design'd to Rob him, (as he said) and that no other Body ever knew of any such thing. They had no more to add to their former Confessions, only that they died in Peace with all Mankind, and being great Sinners, that they hop'd God would have Mercy on them for Christ's Sake.</p>
            <p>
               <persName id="OA17320605n48-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n48-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n48-1" type="surname" value="BARNES"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n48-1" type="given" value="HENRY"/>Henry Barnes</persName>, gave me a short Paper which is as follows, viz. " I desire none " would blame my Parents, for it was " not them that brought me to it, for if " I had been rul'd by them, I might " liv'd a sober and honest Life, work'd " for my Livelyhood; so I beg of all " People that knows them, not to hit</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA173206050015"/>
            <p>" then in the Teeth of my Misfortune. " Written and Sign'd by himself, <persName id="OA17320605n49-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n49-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n49-1" type="surname" value="Barns"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n49-1" type="given" value="Hen"/>Hen. " Barns</persName>, Aged between 16 and 17.</p>
            <p>Having Sung a Psalm, after all the Prayers were concluded, Dunston desir'd me to sing a second Time, which I did, being the 6th last Verses of the 73d Psal. None but Roberts and Dunston were willing to receive the Sacrament that Morning; but after I had spoken a short, serious Exhortation to them extempore, Shaw, and Osborn, exprest a vehement desire, and were partakers with them and some others. They went off the Stage, crying out, God have Mercy upon us, Lord Jesus receive our Spirits.</p>
            <p>This is all the Account given by me <persName id="OA17320605n51-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n51-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n51-1" type="surname" value="Gutherie"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n51-1" type="given" value="James"/>James Gutherie</persName>,</p>
            <p>
               <rs id="OA17320605-occupation-16" type="occupation">ORDINARY</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17320605n51-1 OA17320605-occupation-16"/> of <placeName id="OA17320605-geo-41">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605-geo-41" type="type" value="site"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17320605n51-1 OA17320605-geo-41"/>Newgate</placeName>.</p>
            <p>The following, is an Account of the Robberies which was committed by <persName id="OA17320605n53-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n53-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n53-1" type="surname" value="WOOLCOTT"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n53-1" type="given" value="WILLIAM"/>William Woolcott</persName>, <persName id="OA17320605n53-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n53-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n53-2" type="surname" value="OSBORN"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n53-2" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Osborn</persName> and other: which they gave two Days before their Execution to the Printer; which is as follows, viz.</p>
            <p>
               <persName id="OA17320605n54-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n54-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n54-1" type="surname" value="WOOLCOTT"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n54-1" type="given" value="WILLIAM"/>WILLIAM WOOLCOTT</persName> said, he had been <rs id="OA17320605-occupation-17" type="occupation">at Sea</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17320605n54-1 OA17320605-occupation-17"/> three or four Years, with one Captain Hooke, on Board the Bedford Man of War; when I came Home, I took up my Pay, and spent it very soon, I was put to my Shifts how to get more. Being at a Brandy shop I came acquainted with one Williams; (who is since Executed) he and I soon came to a right understanding, and agreed to go on the Sneak, that is a Shoplifting; sometimes stopping People in the Street, and taking from them every thing we could lay our Hands on. We follow'd this Course of Life for sometime, till at last I was apprehended for taking two Gowns upon the Sneak. While I was confin'd in the <placeName id="OA17320605-geo-42">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605-geo-42" type="type" value="site"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17320605n54-1 OA17320605-geo-42"/>Foultry Compter</placeName>, one that went by the Name of Tom the Cooper, did his endeavour to make himself an Evidence against me for a Robbery which he and I committed in <placeName id="OA17320605-geo-43">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605-geo-43" type="type" value="street"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17320605n54-1 OA17320605-geo-43"/>Wellclose Square</placeName>; but I turn'd the Tables upon him, for being allow'd an Evidence against him he was try'd and Executed for it upon my Evidence.</p>
            <p>After this I was remanded back to the <placeName id="OA17320605-geo-44">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605-geo-44" type="type" value="site"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17320605n54-1 OA17320605-geo-44"/>Poultry Compter</placeName>, where <persName id="OA17320605n55-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n55-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n55-1" type="surname" value="BECK"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n55-1" type="given" value="THOMAS"/>Thomas Beck</persName>, (who was Executed last Sessions) Edwards and <persName id="OA17320605n55-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n55-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n55-2" type="surname" value="TRIPLAND"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n55-2" type="given" value="JAMES"/>James Tripland</persName> came to see their Wives, that is their Doxies; they being confin'd in the said Gaol; by that Means I came acquainted with this Tripland. A little Time after this I was discharg'd from my Confinement. I went immediately to a Brandy-shop, where we all generally use, and had not been there long, but in comes <persName id="OA17320605n55-3">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n55-3" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n55-3" type="surname" value="TRIPLAND"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n55-3" type="given" value="JAMES"/>James Tripland</persName>, and ask'd me if we would go upon the Outdacious; that is Knocking People down; and he would furnish me, with Pistols, Cutlasses, and things proper for our use. But before we went upon Business News was brought us, that <persName id="OA17320605n55-4">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n55-4" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n55-4" type="surname" value="Osbourn"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n55-4" type="given" value="John"/>John Osbourn</persName>
            </p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA173206050016"/>
            <p> was to be discharg'd out of <placeName id="OA17320605-geo-45">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605-geo-45" type="type" value="site"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17320605n55-4 OA17320605-geo-45"/>Newgate</placeName>, where he had lain for sometime, upon which Tripland and I made it our Business to go and see if it was true; and just as we got into <placeName id="OA17320605-geo-46">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605-geo-46" type="type" value="street"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17320605n54-1 n55-2 n55-4 OA17320605-geo-46"/>Newgate-Street</placeName> we met him, and wish'd him Joy upon his Enlargement, and said, shan't we Drink together; so according we went to our old House, and there we ask'd <persName id="OA17320605n56-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n56-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n56-1" type="surname" value="OSBORN"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n56-1" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Osborn</persName> to go along with us, upon which he reply'd Ay, with all my Heart. And the first Robbery we committed was on a Captain of a Ship, from whom we took 3 s. 6 d. a Hat, Wigg, the Shoes from his Feet, with a Pair of Silver Buckles, which we sold to one Mrs. Wasson a Fence in the <placeName id="OA17320605-geo-47">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605-geo-47" type="type" value="street"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17320605n54-1 n55-2 n55-4 n56-1 OA17320605-geo-47"/>Back-Lane</placeName>, near <placeName id="OA17320605-geo-48">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17320605n54-1 n55-2 n55-4 n56-1 OA17320605-geo-48"/>Rag-Fair</placeName>, for 5s. 6d.</p>
            <p>The same Night we committed a Robbery in <placeName id="OA17320605-geo-49">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17320605n54-1 n55-2 n55-4 n56-1 n57-1 OA17320605-geo-49"/>Goodman's Fields</placeName> on a School-Master; (upon which Robbery I die for, as likewise does <persName id="OA17320605n57-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n57-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n57-1" type="surname" value="BARNES"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n57-1" type="given" value="HENRY"/>Henry Barnes</persName> upon the Evidence of <persName id="OA17320605n57-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n57-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n57-2" type="surname" value="TRIPLAND"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n57-2" type="given" value="JAMES"/>James Tripland</persName>) we took from him five Shillings and Six-pence in Silver, and three-pennyworth of Half-pence, and his Hat and Wigg; the Gentleman begg'd for God's Sake not to Misuse him; we took no Notice of his Praying, he might as well Pray to a Horse, as to Pray to us; our Design was to strip him stark Naked, being all very bare of Money, by Reason some of us was but just Discharg'd from Confinement; but People hearing a Noise, came out, so that we did not dare venture to strip him; Tripland was so Barbarous as to cut the Gentleman across the Head, and gave him a very great Wound; upon which <persName id="OA17320605n57-3">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n57-3" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n57-3" type="surname" value="OSBORN"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n57-3" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Osborn</persName> immediately got up from searching the Gentleman's Fob for his Watch, and swore he would stick Tripland for using the Gentleman so Barbarous; we got him upon his Legs, and bid him go about his Business, which he did. After we had robb'd him, we went to our Fence, and left our Things that we took from the Gentleman, for her to Pawn, she said she had not Money enough; accordingly she Pawn'd them, and we divided every Man his Share.</p>
            <p>The next Night about 8 o'Clock, we met by the <placeName id="OA17320605-geo-50">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605-geo-50" type="type" value="street"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17320605n54-1 n55-2 n55-4 n56-1 n57-1 OA17320605-geo-50"/>
                  <placeName id="OA17320605-geo-51">
                     <interp inst="OA17320605-geo-51" type="type" value="site"/>
                     <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                           targets="OA17320605n54-1 n55-2 n55-4 n56-1 n57-1 OA17320605-geo-51"/>Maypole</placeName> in Tooley-street</placeName>, a Master Taylor, whom we Robb'd of his Hat, Wigg, a Traveller, that is a Shilling, and his Thimble, which prov'd to be Silver; People coming along, we was oblig'd to leave him, for fear of being taken.</p>
            <p>After that we went upon the Sneak, I and <persName id="OA17320605n59-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n59-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n59-1" type="surname" value="OSBORN"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n59-1" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Osborn</persName> went together, we jump'd a Glaze, that is lifting up a Sash of a Window, where we took out a bundle of Yarn Stockings of Mens, and likewise a bundle of Womens; after this Robbery we thought we had done enough for that Night, we all agreed to go Home.</p>
            <p>The next Night, Tripland and Barns went down one side of the Street, I and <persName id="OA17320605n60-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n60-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n60-1" type="surname" value="OSBORN"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n60-1" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Osborn</persName>, went down the other side; <persName id="OA17320605n60-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n60-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n60-2" type="surname" value="OSBORN"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n60-2" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Osborn</persName> spy'd a Gentleman going along, upon which he follow'd him and Pick'd his Pocket of a Clout, that is a Handkerchief; after this we made towards <placeName id="OA17320605-geo-52">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605-geo-52" type="type" value="street"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17320605n57-1 n55-2 n56-1 n54-1 OA17320605-geo-52"/>Ratcliff Highway</placeName>, where we took a Bermudas Hat upon the Sneak. Then we went to a Brandy-shop to Drink, and who should be</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA173206050017"/>
            <p>there a Drinking but Fleming, which was the first time that we ever saw him. There was a Man a Drinking in the same Shop, and the Woman of the Shop gave us Notice, that, that Man had just receiv'd his Weeks Wages; upon which <persName id="OA17320605n61-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n61-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n61-1" type="surname" value="OSBORN"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n61-1" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Osborn</persName> said to him, Honest Friend I want to speak with you; upon which the poor Man (not mistrusting any thing) immediately went to him, and Osborn took him to <placeName id="OA17320605-geo-53">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17320605n61-1 OA17320605-geo-53"/>Salt-Peter-Bank</placeName>, and then told him his Business, which was, to Deliver his Money, or else he was a Dead Man; the poor Man being very much Surpriz'd, and did not know what the Consequence might be if he did not, he gave him what he had, which was 10 s. 6d, and Osborn swore, if he follow'd him, he wou'd shoot him thro' the Head; Osborn return'd again to the Brandy-shop, and Fleming said to him, if you don't give me some of the Clie, I'll Squeek; upon which, I took him to the <placeName id="OA17320605-geo-54">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605-geo-54" type="type" value="street"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17320605n54-1 OA17320605-geo-54"/>
                  <placeName id="OA17320605-geo-55">
                     <interp inst="OA17320605-geo-55" type="type" value="site"/>
                     <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                           targets="OA17320605n54-1 OA17320605-geo-55"/>Black-Horse</placeName> in Well street near Rag-Fair</placeName>, where I gave him a Pot of Beer, and told him, I had taken but two Shillings from him; after that I wou'd have taken him over the Water, but he wou'd not go, but before we parted he promis'd me he wou'd bring one of his Wives the next Day to Dine with me, but he was not as good has his Word.</p>
            <p>After this Woolcot was committed to Bridewell in attempting to Pick a Gentleman's Pocket. Then I, Tripland and Fleming, met together on Easter Monday last, at a Brandy-shop in <placeName id="OA17320605-geo-56">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605-geo-56" type="type" value="street"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17320605n63-1 n63-2 n54-1 OA17320605-geo-56"/>Well street</placeName>; I having a small matter of Money about me at that time. I lent Fleming a Traveller, that is a Shilling; then we went to the Musick House at <placeName id="OA17320605-geo-57">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605-geo-57" type="type" value="parish"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17320605n63-1 n63-2 n54-1 OA17320605-geo-57"/>Stepney</placeName> with our Wives; where we staid till we thought it proper to turn out upon Business; we took our leaves of our Doxes, and wish'd them good Night; and they reply'd, We wish you good Luck. And as we was going along, Fleming said, let us go two and two; we pass'd some Gentlemen, but we did not approve of their Looks, by Reason we knew some of them. So Fleming step'd up to me, and said Jack, there is a Watch in that Gentleman's Pocket, let us take him from the rest; but we thought it not proper to come into his Proposal, till we saw him take his leave of his Friends, and turn'd down another way; then went up to him, and bid him Stand and Deliver, he obey'd the Word of Command, and begg'd of us not to use him Ill, for he was a going to see his Brothers Wife, which was his Sister, and had just lain Inn, and if he was any ways hurt, she wou'd be so surpriz'd that it might cost her her Life. We told him we only wanted his Money and Watch, he said he should have what he had, withal his Heart; for he said he had but 5d. in his Pocket, and for a Watch he never had one; he said he work'd very hard for his Bread; we took his Word, and gave him his 5d. again, and wish'd him a good Night.</p>
            <p>After this <persName id="OA17320605n63-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n63-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n63-1" type="surname" value="TRIPLAND"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n63-1" type="given" value="JAMES"/>James Tripland</persName>, <persName id="OA17320605n63-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n63-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n63-2" type="surname" value="FLEMING"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n63-2" type="given" value="WILLIAM"/>William Fleming</persName>, <persName id="OA17320605n63-3">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n63-3" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n63-3" type="surname" value="LONGMORE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n63-3" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Longmore</persName> and I, stop'd a Barber, and Robb'd him of his Hat, and Wig, his Coat and Waistcoat, his Shoes from his Feet, Buckles, and five-penny</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA173206050018"/>
            <p>worth of Half-pence. I cannot deny but we us'd him very inhuman, which was by cutting him across the Hands with the Knives we carry about us; <persName id="OA17320605n64-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n64-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n64-1" type="surname" value="FLEMING"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n64-1" type="given" value="WILLIAM"/>William Fleming</persName> knock'd him down with a little Truncheon which at the end has lead, and would have Murder'd him if we had not more Mercy than he; we should not us'd him so, but that he Resisted very much.</p>
            <p>The next Night <persName id="OA17320605n65-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n65-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n65-1" type="surname" value="TRIPLAND"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n65-1" type="given" value="JAMES"/>James Tripland</persName>, Fleming Longmore and I, was going over the Water to our Lodgings, but going a long we met a Man in <placeName id="OA17320605-geo-58">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605-geo-58" type="type" value="street"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17320605n65-1 n64-1 n63-3 n54-1 OA17320605-geo-58"/>Tooley-Street</placeName>, and stop'd him, we bid him Deliver, if not, he was a dead Man; he not immediately obey'd, upon which, they snatch'd his Hat off, he cry'd out, and they all ran away and left me: I had presence of Mind, and putting a Knife to the Gentleman, and said, if he offer'd to stir or speak, I wou'd out his Throat; I robb'd him of 10 s. and a Ring, but the Ring prov'd to be a Brass one. The Watchmen going the Rounds I was oblig'd to take to my Heels, and so got clear off; I gave <persName id="OA17320605n65-3">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n65-3" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n65-3" type="surname" value="TRIPLAND"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n65-3" type="given" value="JAMES"/>James Tripland</persName>, 2 s. 6 d. and the rest I Sunk, because they left me; then we all went Home to Bed.</p>
            <p>The next Night, Tripland, Fleming and I, went out upon the Sneak, and we jump'd a Grate, in order to get into a Shoemakers Shop in <placeName id="OA17320605-geo-59">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605-geo-59" type="type" value="street"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17320605n65-1 n64-1 n54-1 OA17320605-geo-59"/>Ratcliff Highway</placeName>, and took from thence six pair of new Shoes, and so made off. Going along the same Night, I met a Gentleman in <placeName id="OA17320605-geo-60">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605-geo-60" type="type" value="street"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17320605n54-1 OA17320605-geo-60"/>Ratcliff-Highway</placeName>, and snatch'd his Hat off, and ran away with it. Fleming made after me and over took me; and said to me, as a Gentleman came along, this is he, that we may make our Mouth up; that is, we may get a great deal of Money; (this is the Robbery which I am to Die for) we robbed the Gentleman of his Wig, Coat and Waistcoat, Six-pence in Silver, his Shoes and Buckles, and so made off.</p>
            <p>After this Robbery, we had a Mind to try our Fortune upon the <placeName id="OA17320605-geo-61">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17320605n54-1 n67-1 OA17320605-geo-61"/>River of Thames</placeName>; accordingly, <persName id="OA17320605n67-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n67-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n67-1" type="surname" value="BARNES"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n67-1" type="given" value="HENRY"/>Henry Barnes</persName>, I, and another, (which I hope will take warning by my untimely End) went and got a Boat after this manner; we took a Broomstick, and Swarm off to the Roads, and broke the Locks which Lock'd the Sculls and Boat; when we got into her, we rowed to a Ship call'd an Irish Brigg, when we came to the Stern of her, I got on Barn's Shoulders being Naked, and listened for sometime if I could hear any Body in the Captains Cabbin, which I did not, so I lifted up the Glaze, that is the Window, and so got in, while they rest staid in the Boat to Receive what Goods I Stole, which was a Bagg of Linnen, a great parcel of Cloaths, a Box of Ruebard, a small Box of Cambrick, a Watch, a pair of silver Buckles, two pair of black Silk Stockings, a Hat and Wigg, the Captains Coat and Waistcoat, Shoes, a Snow ball, that is, a Sugar Loaf. I saw some Bottles upon the Table, upon which I handed one to my Fellowmen, and bid them, Drink the Captain's Health, and a Prosperous Voyage; looking about the Cabbin, I spyed four or five Boxes, upon which I asked them, if I should cut the Cords to see what was in them, their Answer was, They had enough, they being in the Boat at the Stern of the Ship, in order to Receive the Goods which I got out of the said Ship. The same Night we went on Board a Hoye, and went down the Forecastle, where we found the Men a Sleep, and there I took a Bagg with a Suit of Cloaths, a Holland Shirt, an India Handkerchief, a pair of Shoes and Buckles; after this Robbery we concluded to go Home; and going to <placeName id="OA17320605-geo-62">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17320605n54-1 n67-1 OA17320605-geo-62"/>Pepper-Alley-Stairs</placeName>, with an intent to Land our Goods, but upon second Thoughts we thought it not safe, so we Landed at the <placeName id="OA17320605-geo-63">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17320605n54-1 n67-1 OA17320605-geo-63"/>Bankside</placeName>; but coming on Shore, one Mr. Rice, or otherwise Mantrump, seeing us, and he knowing us to be Persons of different Characters, he came down and asked me for a Sculler, and said Osborn, you are better than a Sculler, so seiz'd me; upon which</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA173206050019"/>
            <p>one of my Companions jump'd over board and got to Shore, and the other ran for it; but Mantrump in his Surprize let me go, in order to run after him; as soon as he was gone, I pushed the Boat off, and immediately got into her, and toss'd every Thing that was in the Boat into the River, (which was to the value of above a 100 l.) my Reason for so doing was, if I had been Persued, they should find nothing in the Boat. My Fellowman being taken by Mr. Rice, he was committed to the New Goal for the County of Surrey, and was carried down to Guilford the last Assizes, no Person appearing against him, he was Discharg'd.</p>
            <p>After this Robbery, we was soon apprehended, and justly brought to our condign Punishment; altho' I had received Mercy several times, I could not take warning, for about two Months agoe I was discharg'd from <placeName id="OA17320605-geo-64">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605-geo-64" type="type" value="site"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17320605n54-1 OA17320605-geo-64"/>Newgate</placeName>, and the same Day I was discharged, I committed a Robbery with <persName id="OA17320605n69-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n69-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n69-1" type="surname" value="TRIPLAND"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n69-1" type="given" value="JAMES"/>James Tripland</persName>, the Evidence and my fellow sufferer Woolcot.</p>
            <p>N. B. This Osborn two or three Days before his Execution, employ'd his Time in his Cell, in writing such things which we thought proper not to mention, and likewise in drawing of several Things on a Paper, and in particular his own Effigie hanging on <placeName id="OA17320605-geo-65">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605-geo-65" type="type" value="site"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17320605n56-1 OA17320605-geo-65"/>Tyburn</placeName>, which he wrote it Gib, which shows the Stupidity of these poor wicked Wretches, that they have no Notion of a future State.</p>
            <p>At the Time the above Account was taken from their own Mouths, which was but two Days before their Execution, they laugh'd all the Time at each other, while the Person was writing what they said, altho desired several Times to be serious, and consider how short their Time was.</p>
            <p>FINIS.</p>
            <p>ADVERTISEMENT.</p>
            <p>Newly published,</p>
            <p>The FIFTEENTH EDITION of</p>
            <p>ONANIA, Or, The Heinous Sin of Self Pollution, and all its frightful Consequences (in both Sexes) considered, with Spiritual and Physical Advice to those who have already injured themselves by this abominable Practice.</p>
            <p>As also the SIXTH EDITION of the SUPPLEMENT to it, both of them Revised, and Enlarged, and now Printed together in One Volume.</p>
            <p>And as the several Passages in the former Impression  that have been charged with being obscure, and ambiguous are in these cleared up, and explained, there will be no more Alterations, or Additions made to them.</p>
            <p>These Editions contain some further and surprizing Instances of the Mischiefs by that filthy, sinful Commerce with ones self, which is so notoriously practised, as well by the Adult as Youth, Women as Men, Married as Single, to the weakening their Generative Faculties, and hindering Procreation, as their Letters of Complaints to the Author, herein inserted, shew.</p>
            <p>And, amongst others, a curious Letter from a Lady, with his Answer to it, concerning the Use, and Abuse of the Marriage-Bed; together with divers Casuistical and other Letters from both Sexes, of some secret unnatural Effeminancies, necessary to be known both by the married and single of eac Sex.</p>
            <p>To which is added,</p>
            <p>A Curious PIECE, translated out of the Latin, from L. S. SCKMEIDER, as it is inserted in the Acta Lipsiesia, concerning the Return of the Seed into the Mass of Blood; well worth the Perusal of Physicians. Surgeons, Anatomists, and all others of Art and Curiosity.</p>
            <p>As also Dr. QUINCY's Translation of Dr. CARR's remarkable Answer to a Letter sent by a Divine, concerning two Nuns of Rome, reported to have changed their Sex.</p>
            <p>Likewise Dr. DRAKE's and several other Physicians Opinions of Hermaphrodites, and Women brought to a Resemblance of them, by the Practice of Self-Pollution, as was the Case of a young Lady of 18, whose wellwrote Letter to the Author, describing and lamenting her Condition, is (in order to deter others) inserted.</p>
            <p>A very grave and learned Divine and Physician having perused this Discourse, before it went to Press, returned it with his Opinion of it in these Words.</p>
            <p>'This little Book ought to be read by all Sorts of 'People, of both Sexes, of what Age, Degree, Profession, or Condition soever, guilty, or not guilty of the 'Sin declaimed against in it.</p>
            <p>Is now Sold only by J. ISTED, Bookseller, (Mr. CROUCH, Bookseller in Pater noster-Row being dead.) at the Golden Ball between St. Dunstan's Church, and Chancery Lane. in Fleet-street. Price Stitch'd 3 s. Bound 3 s. 6 d,</p>
            <p>Where may be had,</p>
            <p>The SUPPLEMENT, by itself, Price stitch'd, 1 s. 6 d.</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA173206050020"/>
            <p>The Best WATER in the World,</p>
            <p>Judg'd to deserve that Name by all who have experienc'd it in the following Distempers, VIZ.</p>
            <p>IT Cures the most inveterate ITCH, tho' of never so long a standing, as also all Scorbutick Humours, and breakings out in Blotches on the Skin, in which Distemper, its Efficacy is so wonderful, that in a few Days it rectifies and cleanses the Blood, and strikes at the very Root of those acid Humours which are the Cause of it, and accomplishes the Cure with all the Ease and Safety imaginable.</p>
            <p>And as the Water is so great a Purifier of the Blood, and so admirable a Rectifier of the Juices, it has been found of a long Experience to be very efficacious in all Sores, Ulcers and Fistula's, and when apply'd in the case of sore Eyes, it has work'd so great an Effect, that it has given intire Satisfaction when all other Remedies have failed.</p>
            <p>This WATER is sold only at Mr. Radford's Toy-Shop, at the Rose and Crown, over against St. Clement's Church in the Strand, at One Shilling and Six Pence per Bottle, with Directions for the Use of it in the different Distempers.</p>
            <p>ELectuarium Mirable; or the Admirable Electuary, which infallibly cures all Degrees and Symptoms of the Secret Disease, with more Ease, Speed, and Safety, than any Medicine yet published. Any old Running, &amp;c. tho' of several Years standing, whether occasion'd by an Overstrain, Weakness of the Seminals or the Relicts of a former Infection, is certainly cured in a short Time, without a Minutes Confinement, Suspicion, or the Use of Astringents; being a Medicine so wonderfully pleasant and easie in its Operation, that the nicest Palate, or weakest Constitution may take it with Delight. Two Pots are generally sufficient to compleat a Cure in most Cases, To be had (with Directions at large) only of the Author, Dr. C A M, a graduate Physician, who has published it Thirty Years, and is constantly to be advised with at his House, at the Golden-Ball in Bow-Church-yard, Cheap side, at Half a Guinea the Pot.</p>
            <p>N. B. Since nothing is more requisite, in the Cure  Distemper, than for a Patient to have free access to cian; therefore beware of buying Medicines from  Book-sellers-shops, &amp;c. the Authors of which are always conceal'd, and not to be Spoke with, on any Occasion: And tho' by their specious Pretences) you are promised a cheap Cure, you'll certainly find it very Dear in the End.</p>
            <p>Verbum sat sapienti.</p>
            <p>See his Books lately publish'd, viz. His Rational and Useful Account of the Secret Disease. Price 1 s. His Practical Treatise; or Second Thoughts on the Consequences of the Venereal Disease. In Three Parts. viz. I. On the Simple Gonorrhaea Gleets and other Weaknesses, whether from Venereal Embraces Self-pollution, improperly call'd Onanism, or Natural Imbecility. II. On the Virulent Gonorrhaea, or Clap. III. On the Venereal Lues, or Grand Pox, &amp;c. Price 2 s. His Essay on the Rheumatism and Gout. Price 6 d. His Discourse on Convulsions. Price 6 d. And his Dissertation on the Pox, Dedicated to <persName id="OA17320605n98-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n98-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n98-1" type="surname" value="SLOANE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17320605n98-1" type="given" value="HANS"/>Sir Hans Sloane</persName>. Price 1 s. 6 d. All sold by G. Strathan in Cornhil, E. Midwinter in St. Paul's Church-yard, and at the Author's House ebfore-mentioned.</p>
         </div0>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>