<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<TEI.2>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div0 type="ordinarysAccount" id="OA17640307">
            <interp inst="OA17640307" type="uri" value="ordinarysAccounts/OA17640307"/>
            <interp inst="OA17640307" type="date" value="17640307"/>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA176403070001"/>
            <p>THE ORDINARY of NEWGATE'S ACCOUNT of the Behaviour, Confession, and Dying Words, OF FIVE MALEFACTORS, VIZ.</p>
            <p>
               <persName id="OA17640307n3-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n3-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n3-1" type="surname" value="PRINCE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n3-1" type="given" value="JOHN"/>JOHN PRINCE</persName> for Forgery, Who was executed at <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307-geo-1" type="type" value="site"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA17640307n3-1 OA17640307-geo-1"/>Tyburn</placeName>, on Wednesday, March 7; <persName id="OA17640307n3-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n3-2" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n3-2" type="surname" value="BAKER"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n3-2" type="given" value="ANNE"/>ANNE BAKER</persName> for a Street Robbery, <persName id="OA17640307n3-3">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n3-3" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n3-3" type="surname" value="ROBINS"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n3-3" type="given" value="PETER"/>PETER ROBINS</persName> for a Burglary, AND <persName id="OA17640307n3-5">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n3-5" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n3-5" type="surname" value="ROCKET"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n3-5" type="given" value="JAMES"/>JAMES ROCKET</persName> and <persName id="OA17640307n3-4">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n3-4" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n3-4" type="surname" value="STEWARD"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n3-4" type="given" value="TIMOTHY"/>TIMOTHY STEWARD</persName> for a Robbery, near the Highway, Who were executed at <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307-geo-2" type="type" value="site"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17640307n3-5 n3-2 n3-3 n3-4 OA17640307-geo-2"/>Tyburn</placeName> on Wednesday, March 28, 1764.</p>
            <p>BEING THE FOURTH and FIFTH Executions in the MAYORALTY OF THE Rt. Hon. <persName id="OA17640307n4-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n4-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n4-1" type="surname" value="BRIDGEN"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n4-1" type="given" value="WILLIAM"/>WILLIAM BRIDGEN</persName>, Esq.</p>
            <p>
               <rs id="OA17640307-occupation-1" type="occupation">LORD MAYOR of the CITY of LONDON</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17640307n4-1 OA17640307-occupation-1"/>.</p>
            <p>NUMBER III. for the said Year.</p>
            <p>LONDON, Printed for J. COOKE, at Shakespear's Head, in Pater-noster Row, and Sold by all Booksellers and News Carriers. Price 8d.]</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA176403070002"/>
            <p>THE ORDINARY of NEWGATE'S ACCOUNT of the Behaviour, Confession, and Dying Words, &amp;c.</p>
            <p>THE Introduction to the tryal and conviction of <persName id="OA17640307n9-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n9-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n9-1" type="surname" value="PRINCE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n9-1" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Prince</persName> having been published in the foregoing account of six malefactors, Numb. II. need not be recited here.</p>
            <p>1. <persName id="OA17640307n10-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n10-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n10-1" type="surname" value="PRINCE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n10-1" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Prince</persName> was indicted, for feloniously forging and counterfeiting a certain bill of exchange, for the payment of 125l. and publishing the same, wellknowing it to have been forged, with intent to defraud <persName id="OA17640307n10-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n10-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n10-2" type="surname" value="MACKOUN"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n10-2" type="given" value="ROBERT"/>Robert Mackoun</persName>, July 8.</p>
            <p>The steps, by which this well-known offender was brought to justice, are remarkable: He was apprehended, about the 12th or 13th of September, on account of a fraud only, at the suit of Mr. <persName id="OA17640307n11-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n11-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n11-2" type="surname" value="MARSHE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n11-2" type="given" value="RICHARD"/>Richard Marshe</persName>, <rs id="OA17640307-occupation-2" type="occupation">Hosier</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17640307n11-2 OA17640307-occupation-2"/>, near <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-3">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA17640307n11-2 OA17640307-geo-3"/>Temple Bar</placeName>, for obtaining from him a parcel of silk hose, by false pretences. It was no easy task to lay hold of a man long practised in much greater frauds, and yet evading the hand of justice. Prince (who always flattered himself, and looked on his own actions in the most favourable light,) told me, he had not fair play on that occasion. At least he was inclined to think so, because the consequence of his being taken up for this fraud, brought to light a worse crime, which proved fatal to him. He said Mr. Marshe had taken out warrants against him, and way-laid him in three or four counties, as well as the city of <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-4">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307-geo-4" type="type" value="urban_centre"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA17640307n10-1 OA17640307-geo-4"/>London</placeName>; that about this time he was seen casually passing through <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-5">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307-geo-5" type="type" value="street"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA17640307n10-1 OA17640307-geo-5"/>Fleet Street</placeName>, by Mr. Marshe, who pursued him, with an hue and cry of stop thief, and was taken in a publick house under that character, where he stepped in for shelter; whereas, said Prince, he had no right to consider me as a thief, but only his debtor. However, he was taken before <persName id="OA17640307n11-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n11-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n11-1" type="surname" value="FIELDING"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n11-1" type="given" value="JOHN"/>Sir John Fielding</persName>, and being examined, was committed to the <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-6">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307-geo-6" type="type" value="urban_centre"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA17640307n10-1 OA17640307-geo-6"/>
                  <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-7">
                     <interp inst="OA17640307-geo-7" type="type" value="site"/>
                     <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA17640307n10-1 OA17640307-geo-7"/>Gatehouse</placeName>, Westminster</placeName>, September the 13th last, for obtaining from <persName id="OA17640307n11-3">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n11-3" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n11-3" type="surname" value="MARSHE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n11-3" type="given" value="RICHARD"/>Richard Marshe</persName>, by false pretences, silk hose to the value of 13l. and upwards. By this time the transaction of the forgery began to be looked after by the injured party, and, like a mine, was ready to be sprung, and involve the miner in its ruin. Prince was now advertised to be re-examined the 15th, at the very time Mr. Mackoun was meditating how to prosecute this forgery; who seeing the advertisement in a news paper, which he took up in a coffee-house, attended at Sir John's, and produced this bill. Prince being examined on it, said, Bricklen (the supposed drawer of the bill,) was gone into Yorkshire. It now probably appeared before the Magistrate, by the same evidence, afterwards given on tryal, that Prince had told the prosecutor two different stories about the drawer of this bill;</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA176403070003"/>
            <p>the first was, that Bricklen and Co. were great Distillers and Brandy-merchants, living near the watch-house, in Moorfields; that they served Orcherton, the accepter of the bill, who then kept the Rose Tavern, in Cursitor Street, with rum and brandy. This being proved false, on enquiry, no such persons as Bricklen and Co. to be found, and Orcherton gone aside; the second story was, that Bricklen in truth was an outlawed smuggler, but was worth three or four thousand pounds, and the bill would be paid when due, and that he lodged in some lane or alley near Moorfields. This was equally true with the former; and now, being urged by the necessity of the case, to produce this drawer of the bill, he said he lived in the country, and was gone into Yorkshire. The bill was to this purport:</p>
            <p>" London June 3, 1763.</p>
            <p>" Three months after date pay to Mr. " <persName id="OA17640307n14-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n14-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n14-1" type="surname" value="PRINCE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n14-1" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Prince</persName>, or his order, the sum of " one hundred twenty five pounds sterl. " and place the same to account of, Sir, " your most humble servant,"</p>
            <p>" G. Bricklen and Co.</p>
            <p>" To <persName id="OA17640307n16-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n16-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n16-1" type="surname" value="OCHERTON"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n16-1" type="given" value="WM"/>Wm. Orcherton</persName>, at the </p>
            <p>
               <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-8">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307-geo-8" type="type" value="street"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA17640307n16-1 OA17640307-geo-8"/>
                  <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-9">
                     <interp inst="OA17640307-geo-9" type="type" value="site"/>
                     <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="OA17640307n16-1 OA17640307-geo-9"/>Rose" Tavern</placeName>, Cursitor Street</placeName>.</p>
            <p>" Accepted, <persName id="OA17640307n18-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n18-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n18-1" type="surname" value="ORCHERTON"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n18-1" type="given" value="WILLIAM"/>William Orcherton</persName>."</p>
            <p>This bill had been passed by the prisoner to the prosecutor, instead of 100l. cash, payable by way of deposit to bind a bargain and sale of an estate, near <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-10">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307-geo-10" type="type" value="street"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17640307n10-1 OA17640307-geo-10"/>
                  <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-11">
                     <interp inst="OA17640307-geo-11" type="type" value="county"/>
                     <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                           targets="OA17640307n10-1 OA17640307-geo-11"/>
                     <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-12">
                        <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                              targets="OA17640307n10-1 OA17640307-geo-12"/>Long Ford</placeName>, Middlesex</placeName>, in the Windsor Road</placeName>, about 15 miles from London. The terms of this sale had been agreed upon in a memorandum, of which the seller had given the buyer a copy, signed by him. On discovery that the bill was bad, the former would have returned it to the latter, on condition of recovering his memorandum again; but this was wilfully and obstinately refused by Prince, who insisted on his bargain; for that he had friends who would raise him the money when the bill became due. The bill was now due nine days before this examination, as appears by the date in the face of it; and yet neither he nor his friends had paid it, otherwise we should probably have heard nothing of this prosecution. This is here mentioned to demonstrate the audacious temper and effrontery of this prisoner, who persisted, after his conviction, to assert, "that it was no forgery, but a good bill, and would have been paid had it been demanded when due; and that it never was demanded;" which is contrary to the whole tenor of the evidence on trial. But if this assertion had any appearance of truth, it was a mere fallacious evasion; if it was not demanded, it was because none of the parties, by whom it was payable, could be found. On this issue the prisoner himself put the affair at the time of this examination, when he pretended that Bricklen was gone into Yorkshire, and desired five or six days might be allowed him till he should return, or be found. Sir John granted him eight or nine days, and also proposed, if the prisoner would give him an account what part of Yorkshire he was in, he would send an express for him, at his own expence; for, as he told the prisoner, it was a matter that nearly concerned him; this kind offer was not accepted, because it could not be complied with. At this examination Orcherton, the keeper of the Rose Tavern, in Cursitor Street, was produced. Some words dropt from him, which caused him to be secured as an evidence at least, if not an accomplice in the forgery; he set forth, that he had known the</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA176403070004"/>
            <p>prisoner only since May last, that he wrote the body of that bill of exchange, and accepted it with his own name; but G. Bricklen and Co. was not on it at that time, nor did he ever remember to hear of that name, till he saw it on the draught with Mr. Mackoun's Attorney; consequently, that he had never dealt with Bricklen and Co. for brandy and rum, as the prisoner had pretended. Orcherton also now opened the pretences, by which he was drawn in by Prince and his associates, to write this, and some other bills of the same nature, to the amount of 500l. which was, to raise money for Prince to purchase the house Orcherton then lived in, being advertised for sale, and, when purchased, it was to be mortgaged for money to pay off those bills. This was to be for the use and benefit of Orcherton, to prevent his being turned out of the house. Prince was remanded back to the Gatehouse for further examination; but would not yet be persuaded to think, or seem to believe, that his case was any way dangerous. In conversation between Prince and Orcherton, as they were carried in a coach together, a kind of dispute or quarrel arose; Prince charging Orcherton with giving evidence too severely against him, and the other insisted it was the truth: And charged him with having been the occasion of great losses to him, by which he became a bankrupt; adding, " that he " would not think much to be banished, " for the satisfaction to see him hanged." Prince, forward to catch at any thing that might break the force of so pointed an evidence, considered this hasty and vindictive expression, as sufficient to invalidate his testimony; and therefore had subpoena'd witness to prove it on his trial. But Orcherton having, of his own accord, acknowledged it in his cross examination, and accounted for it by a sudden passion he was put in, for being sent to prison on account of these notes, which Prince induced him to write, and also explained himself, that he did not mean to have him hanged unless he deserved it, the objection seemed to lose its weight.</p>
            <p>Prince being searched when charged with the forgery, a paper, teeming with secret practices and dark deeds, was found upon him, which, as it tended to confirm Orcherton's evidence, in relation to the company that used to frequent his house with Prince, and their practices, was also read at the close of his evidence on the trial, to the purport following: " An agreement between <persName id="OA17640307n21-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n21-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n21-1" type="surname" value="FISHER"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n21-1" type="given" value="SAMUEL"/>Samuel Fisher</persName>, <persName id="OA17640307n21-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n21-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n21-2" type="surname" value="HART"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n21-2" type="given" value="EDWARD"/>Edward Hart</persName>, <persName id="OA17640307n21-3">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n21-3" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n21-3" type="surname" value="WHITE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n21-3" type="given" value="GEORGE"/>George White</persName>, and <persName id="OA17640307n21-4">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n21-4" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n21-4" type="surname" value="PRINCE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n21-4" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John " Prince</persName>, concerning dividing the money " that should be raised by a bill, or bills, " drawn by the prisoner, and the expences " how to be paid." An occasion will offer itself, in the course of this account, to compare some names in the aforesaid paper with another curious piece dictated by Prince, and by means of which his respite of three weeks was obtained.</p>
            <p>On his next examination before the Justice, no Bricklen, no drawer of the bill being found or traced out, and the presumption of a forgery rising proportionably higher, he was committed to <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-13">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307-geo-13" type="type" value="site"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17640307n10-1 OA17640307-geo-13"/>Newgate</placeName> toward the latter end of September; when the gaol being sickly, he caught the distemper, which occasioned his trial to be put off, he being reduced so low in health that it was believed he could not live to be tried. During this interval, there was no opportunity for me to know or converse with him, he being either disabled by sickness, or (like the bulk of the other prisoners) disinclined to think of his duty in the chapel, till after trial and conviction. His trial at length came on in January</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA176403070005"/>
            <p>sessions. Beside what has been said, it was proved, that all possible enquiry was made for Bricklen and Co. but they were not to be found by the prosecutor, or his clerk; and it was proved positively, by an old inhabitant, of twenty years, near the watch-house, Moorfields, that no such person was in that time known to live there. The prisoner only said in his defence, that he lived in an alley beyond the watch-house, and produced two witnesses, to prove they had seen the prisoner in company with a person of that name, above a year since, and that he was a dealer in horses; and one of them believed the signing of the bill to be like his hand. But this did not come up to the point, nor prove such persons as Bricklen and Co. to exist under the description and character given by the prisoner, of the drawers of the bill, and therefore it was determined he had forged the person; and no such person appearing, he was found guilty.</p>
            <p>Thus the charge against this prisoner, with its proof and issue, has been briefly collected and laid before the reader. His behaviour after conviction, together with the means used to bring him to a repentance proportioned to his crimes and course of life, have been also in part represented to the publick, with that of his other eight fellow-convicts; two of which, <persName id="OA17640307n24-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n24-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n24-1" type="surname" value="ANDERSON"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n24-1" type="given" value="JAMES"/>James Anderson</persName> and <persName id="OA17640307n24-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n24-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n24-2" type="surname" value="THOMPSON"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n24-2" type="given" value="THOMAS"/>Thomas Thompson</persName>, have been executed Feb. 15, and six respited.</p>
            <p>So long as there is any hope of the reformation of criminals in the character of penitents, and while there is life there is hope, all possible patience, and forbearance, and tenderness should be exercised towards them: But when their lives are forfeited, and the forfeit paid for the warning of other hardened and presumptuous offenders, and the safeguard and protection of the honest and industrious; the best use should be made of their subtile schemes and evil conduct, to answer those purposes for which criminals are punished.</p>
            <p>And first, it is a desperate and most provoking degree of hardness in guilt, for any surviving criminal to encourage himself in his wickedness, and persist in his evil courses, because he sees or hears of a dying criminal making a decent exit at the place of execution. This is a most fallacious sign, on which there is no dependence. We are, indeed, in general obliged to perform the best offices of piety and charity we can, and they are capable of, for the worst of dying sinners and criminals; but the success is wholly unknown and uncertain to us; it is deep involved in futurity, and the divine counsels. There is no judging, by present superficial outward appearances, of their true spiritual state at present, nor of the judgment that will pass upon them for their eternal lot hereafter. 'Tis impossible for us, for any but the Searcher of Hearts, to know how far these seeming penitents have complied with the terms of salvation. Whether they have outsinned their day of Grace and Salvation, or are still objects of it? Whether they strive earnestly in prayer, that a true repentance, a lively faith, and all the graces requisite for their condition may be granted to them? or whether it is too late to sue for them? For however presumptuous and ignorant men may flatter themselves, and each other, that it is never too late to repent (and tho' perhaps this may be true of a sincere repentance) yet we are assured, by the highest authority, that the hope of the hypocrite shall perish; that there is a time when these good things are hid from mens eyes, and the door of mercy is shut. And the reasons and causes are assigned, which bring things to this</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA176403070006"/>
            <p>desperate pass. When men hate knowledge and do not chuse the fear of the Lord; when they refuse his calls and disregard the stretching out of his hand; when they set at naught his counsel and will hear none of his reproof; then will he also laugh at their calamity, and mock when their fear cometh; - when their fear cometh as desolation, and their destruction cometh as a whirlwind; when distress and anguish cometh upon them. Then shall they call upon me, but I will not answer; they shall seek me early, but they shall not find me, saith the supreme Judge. We know, and are witnesses, that these causes and symptoms too generally prevail among obdurate sinners, within and without our prison-doors, whether at large or in chains. How then can they escape the inevitably connected consequences? Have we not invincible arguments, to make us expect and dread them all in the worst sense? It appears to me the best good office which humanity and good-will can do such men, to set these things strongly before their eyes, ere it be yet too late, for ever.</p>
            <p>We know, and are witnesses, that in general the apparent repentance of convicts in chains seems to be merely forced upon them by their present fears and miseries; for they too frequently prove this, by putting it off as long as they can, and relapsing as soon as they can, i. e. on the first opportunity.</p>
            <p>These reflexions naturally rise from the long course of frauds and misconduct which the convict now in view had run thro', and the little sense he seemed to feel of his real case and danger. For tho' he attended the chapel almost daily after conviction, yet he acknowledged he had never been there above three or four times in so many months that he was a prisoner before it: And now that he came, the point he seemed to have most at heart was to deny his guilt, plead innocence, and consult with me how to escape this death? rather than ask and learn how he should obtain eternal life; for this was the convict hinted at in the former Account, (No. II. p. 9.) who desired a private conversation on this subject; but being then respited, was not named. This is the convict, there also unnamed, who mistook the Commination for the Communion Office, after some weeks instruction and preparation. For it appeared from his conversation, from his incapacity to read common English with propriety, or write a plain hand, that he was of a more ignorant and low-bred class than he found it his interest to assume in the several scenes he had gone thro'. From his being known to have been a <rs id="OA17640307-occupation-3" type="occupation">Draper</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17640307n10-1 OA17640307-occupation-3"/> on <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-14">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17640307n10-1 OA17640307-geo-14"/>Ludgatehill</placeName>, or a <rs id="OA17640307-occupation-4" type="occupation">Warehouseman</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17640307n10-1 OA17640307-occupation-4"/> in <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-15">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307-geo-15" type="type" value="street"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17640307n10-1 OA17640307-geo-15"/>Bread-street</placeName>, one would form an idea of a man of suitable birth and education. And this pretence he still endeavoured to support; for being asked one day, whether he had served his time to a Draper? he answered no, he had learned it by being bred up and travelling among the woollen manufacturers; that he was born in <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-16">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307-geo-16" type="type" value="county"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17640307n10-1 OA17640307-geo-16"/>Wiltshire</placeName>, and there educated with his father, came to <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-17">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307-geo-17" type="type" value="urban_centre"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17640307n10-1 OA17640307-geo-17"/>London</placeName> at the age of eighteen or twenty years, and having lived sometime among the principal Drapers, to whom he was sometime a <rs id="OA17640307-occupation-5" type="occupation">rider</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17640307n10-1 OA17640307-occupation-5"/>, he then set up the business on his own account. The truth is, he came to town a raw country young fellow, about twelve years ago, and was first employed in a considerable Print-shop kept by Mr. O - v - n, facing <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-18">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307-geo-18" type="type" value="site"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17640307n10-1 OA17640307-geo-18"/>St. Sepulchre's church</placeName>, as a <rs id="OA17640307-occupation-6" type="occupation">menial servant</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17640307n10-1 OA17640307-occupation-6"/>, and acted as <rs id="OA17640307-occupation-7" type="occupation">footman and porter</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17640307n10-1 OA17640307-occupation-7"/> to carry out parcels, and used to ride journeys with his master, to carry his portmanteau. In this service he was thought to be rather</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA176403070007"/>
            <p>heavy and stupid, than capable of those pranks, which he has since had a part in playing off. When he had lived here about a year, he got another place at a Draper's and Sale-shop in <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-19">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17640307n10-1 OA17640307-geo-19"/>Houndsditch</placeName>, and from thence he moved to a like place in <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-20">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307-geo-20" type="type" value="street"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17640307n10-1 OA17640307-geo-20"/>Drury-lane</placeName>, much in the same capacity. In these two latter places he learned so much of the business as to open a shop for himself on <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-21">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17640307n10-1 OA17640307-geo-21"/>Ludgate Hill</placeName>, which much surprized all who knew him from his beginning; and puzzled them to account, whence the capital should arise to enable him to venture on such a house. But this blaze, having served his turn, was soon extinguished, and the house shut up in darkness. This is said to have been about the year 1760. His next step was to remove to <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-22">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307-geo-22" type="type" value="county"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17640307n10-1 OA17640307-geo-22"/>
                  <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-23">
                     <interp inst="OA17640307-geo-23" type="type" value="urban_centre"/>
                     <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                           targets="OA17640307n10-1 OA17640307-geo-23"/>Godalming</placeName> in Surrey</placeName>, where, out of the spoils already picked up, he dealt in corn and flour to <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-24">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307-geo-24" type="type" value="urban_centre"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17640307n10-1 OA17640307-geo-24"/>London</placeName>, having purchased a mill for that purpose, and was getting money apace; this held on for about eighteen months, and he told me he might have done well here, and continued so, had not some of his former companions, ever restless, and seeking whom they may devour, found him out, and came down to extort a sum of money from him, or threatened to blow him. He not answering their large demands, they exposed him as one who had been a bankrupt and in gaol, &amp;c. He was soon pointed at by his neighbours and others (with whom he had hitherto kept up his credit) as one who had been so and so in <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-25">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307-geo-25" type="type" value="urban_centre"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17640307n10-1 OA17640307-geo-25"/>London</placeName>, and was now come down to cheat the country. This obliged him to sell his mill and decamp; and he added, that 90l. of the price was still due to him, which he hoped they would pay his wife. Of her he always spoke with tender concern, and, to aggravate his sorrows, said they had three children; the last of which died of the gaol distemper, caught by being with his mother to visit him in the prison. It is known, and generally believed, that this convict had been too frequently and deeply concerned with several persons (some of them before named in the paper found in his pocket when taken) in sundry frauds and forgeries to procure goods, to get possession of effects and estates on counterfeit securities, and then raise money upon them. One of their most successful methods was to put on the guise of considerable dealers and persons of property, to strike a bargain, pay down some cash in hand, and give bills for the rest, which, on enquiry, proved much like the bill for which he was convicted. This he seemed conscious of, when he endeavoured to account for his conviction on other principles than those of justice and law; for he insisted on being innocent of any forgery in this case; but, said he, I was unfortunately connected with a set of bad people, and had but a light character, and it was determined that some one must die, and I am singled out to fall a sacrifice. By whom and what number of men this was determined, he did not explain; but often hinted, that a person concerned in his prosecution was no better than he should be. Several exploits in their way are reported of this sett of confederates. Prince had agreed with a principal for an Oyster-meter's place at <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-26">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307-geo-26" type="type" value="parish"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17640307n10-1 OA17640307-geo-26"/>Billingsgate</placeName>. He would have paid down 100l. cash, and 400l. more in bills: But this latter part not being approved, broke off the bargain. When he dealt as a <rs id="OA17640307-occupation-8" type="occupation">Draper</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17640307n10-1 OA17640307-occupation-8"/>, he took a journey into the <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-27">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17640307n10-1 OA17640307-geo-27"/>West Country</placeName> with his ingenious accomplice F - r, under the stile and title of F - sh - r, Esq; of F - s - r hall in <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-28">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307-geo-28" type="type" value="county"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17640307n10-1 OA17640307-geo-28"/>Lancashire</placeName>, where, by offering a good price, they dealt with a clothier for the value of 1500l. in pieces of cloth, then lying in a</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA176403070008"/>
            <p>great warehouse in <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-29">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307-geo-29" type="type" value="urban_centre"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17640307n10-1 OA17640307-geo-29"/>London</placeName>, for which they paid down 600l. in cash, and gave bills on supposed Merchants for 900l. They had the pieces delivered to them by order; but when the bills became due, the persons by whom they were payable were not to be found. The two accomplices were secured, on an affidavit or oath made by the creditor, or prosecutor, and sent to prison; their attorney found, or pretended to find, a flaw in the affidavit, trumped up a prosecution for perjury against him, which, it is said, terrified him so, as to induce him to give the defendants a general release, and 400l. more by way of composition.</p>
            <p>It is well known, that Prince and his companion aforesaid were fellow-prisoners in <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-30">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307-geo-30" type="type" value="site"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17640307n10-1 OA17640307-geo-30"/>Newgate</placeName> for a fraud in March 1761, in obtaining several pieces of superfine cloth by false pretences. A little before they were to be tried for this fact, the prosecutor was prevailed on to make a debt of it, by their paying down some little money, and giving him some large promises to pay the rest. They were detained as debtors in <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-31">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307-geo-31" type="type" value="site"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17640307n10-1 OA17640307-geo-31"/>Newgate</placeName> five or six weeks, till F - r first, and Prince in a week after, moved themselves by Habeas Corpus to the <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-32">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307-geo-32" type="type" value="site"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17640307n10-1 OA17640307-geo-32"/>King's Bench prison</placeName>, from whence, in less than a year, they were both cleared by the compelling clause in the Act of Insolvency. They were well known in each of these prisons on other occasions.</p>
            <p>On the day that Prince was convicted, some young gentleman was seen to give him a quarter guinea, for his present relief; and said, at the same time, that his father had lost 1000l. by him. For that and the like purposes, he and his accomplices had taken a house in <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-33">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307-geo-33" type="type" value="street"/>Bread-street</placeName>, facing the <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-34">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307-geo-34" type="type" value="site"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17640307n10-1 OA17640307-geo-34"/>Three Cups Inn</placeName>, the better to give a colour to their transactions.</p>
            <p>When men have long turned their whole thoughts, and laid out their talents on such deep schemes of fraud and villainy, they may truly be said to have sold themselves to work iniquity; their heart is perverted, and become callous to every good impression, which they have long resisted and stifled. There is a root of bitterness in them, which it were impossible for human strength or means to change or extirpate; and if ever they are changed so as to be saved, it can only be by the mighty power, the extraordinary grace, the exceeding great love and mercy of that God, to whom nothing is impossible. But let sinners take heed how they presume upon these perfections, and dally with divine patience and goodness. It is for this very reason, because there is mercy with him, therefore he is to be feared.</p>
            <p>These thoughts are occasioned by a sudden change in this prisoner, which flattered us with hopeful appearances of a good work begun in him, on January 25, the festival of the Conversion of St. Paul, when the Psalms, the proper lessons, and other offices of the day were explained and applied to the prisoners, teaching them that the same heavenly light and grace which had converted Saul from being a persecutor, a blasphemer, and injurious, to be a most zealous Apostle and Preacher of the Gospel, was most surely recorded, and still shone bright in the hearts of all who were open to receive it, and that for this very cause he obtained mercy, to be a pattern to others, who should hereafter be convinced. After service he came, of his own accord, and spoke to this effect; first, that he was sorry for some refractory misbehavour he had been guilty of yesterday in the chapel, and also that he was now glad he did not die of the goal distemper before his trial,</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA176403070009"/>
            <p>(for he said he was, indeed, very wicked when first put in gaol, but hoped he was now spared to repent,) tho' he should die a shameful death; that he had not an opportunity of attending chapel above two Sundays during his confinement, before trial, having been ill the best part of three months; that he had been drawn in and connected with bad men, but now saw his folly, for they were his ruin; he added, that a friend who supported him, promised to use his endeavours to save his life, but he would make the best use of his time, and not depend on it. He was in the same cell with another convict, who could read well, and had several proper books lent them, which they promised to make good use of.</p>
            <p>One of these bad connections is little known or spoken of, viz. that which he had with <persName id="OA17640307n37-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n37-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n37-1" type="surname" value="PERROTT"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n37-1" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Perrott</persName>, his neighbour on <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-35">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17640307n10-1 n37-1 OA17640307-geo-35"/>Ludgate Hill</placeName>, who was executed at <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-36">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307-geo-36" type="type" value="site"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17640307n37-1 OA17640307-geo-36"/>Smithfield</placeName>, November 11, 1761, for concealing his effects as a bankrupt; not long before which was the failure of Prince, with some similar causes and circumstances. This connection was carried so far, that it is said F - r, at least his associate, if not Prince himself, was concerned in a scheme to rescue Perrott out of gaol a few days before his execution; which was indeed then apprehended, and guarded against. (See page 12, 13, of the Account of <persName id="OA17640307n37-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n37-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n37-2" type="surname" value="PERROTT"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n37-2" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Perrott</persName> and <persName id="OA17640307n37-3">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n37-3" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n37-3" type="surname" value="LEE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n37-3" type="given" value="SAMUEL"/>Samuel Lee</persName>.)</p>
            <p>The respite of Prince, the night before his fellow convicts were executed, has been mentioned in the preceding Account; as also that the reasons and means of that respite seemed unknown even to himself; but this was owing to his dissimulation with me, and perhaps shame also to avow the real means and motives by which that respite was obtained. To conceal which, when asked, a few days after, how this respite came about, he amused me with the following blind stories; that he was visited Feb. the 14th, the evening before execution, by a gentleman of fortune from <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-37">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307-geo-37" type="type" value="parish"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17640307n10-1 OA17640307-geo-37"/>Spitalfields</placeName> (his name being forgot;) he asked him a few questions, and going away left two shillings for him at the lodge; when he heard this, he revolved in his mind, why should two shillings be left for a man who is to die to-morrow? He conjectured, therefore, this respite was obtained by his means, thro' the interest of a noble Lord and some gentlemen, for whom he once procured a sum of money, as a broker, on some goods and an estate, for which he gave a bond. And as the estate is now vested in him, it must be forfeited if he dies: To prevent this, he would seem to suppose he was respited. He added, that he had suffered much by law and imprisonment on account of that affair, as the parties believed he had defrauded them of a large sum, but at last cleared himself, and believes they are satisfied of his innocence. The real story he alluded to, is thus reported; that he advised a certain N - b - n, who applied to him in necessity for ready cash, to take up goods from a manufacturer in <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-38">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307-geo-38" type="type" value="parish"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17640307n10-1 OA17640307-geo-38"/>Spitalfields</placeName>, to the value of 2000l. which being put into the hands of Prince, when he had raised a proper sum on them, he returned three or four hundred pounds to his employer, and sunk the rest. This was an expedient he was well practised in, the raising of money on goods, however obtained, of which there are numberless instances. This is one of those abuses of trade and credit, which perverts this practice into one of the worst species of robbery; and is common among that obdurate set of enormous criminals, who live luxuriously</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA176403070010"/>
            <p>upon the spoil in our prisons under the name of debtors. For it must be allowed, that in proportion as the right use of fair trade and well-grounded credit is beneficial to society, and is, in fact, the support of millions in these nations and dominions; so the abuse and perversion of either, or both, is detrimental and destructive to numbers.</p>
            <p>But so long habituated was this criminal to the use of false pretences, that he could scarce divest himself of them to his dying day. Whatever pretences he had made use of to conceal the real occasion of his respite from me, the true state of it was first hinted by another, and in due time fully cleared up; and it was thus. He sent his wife to a compassionate Gentleman, in the Commission of the Peace for Middlesex, to inform him, that <persName id="OA17640307n40-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n40-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n40-1" type="surname" value="PRINCE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n40-1" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Prince</persName>, her husband, was able to make some material discoveries for the publick utility, she herself making an affidavit to that purpose, and that he was ready to give his information to proper persons. This was on the 14th of February, the day before he was to suffer. Proper application being made above, by the Gentleman aforesaid, in a few hours a respite, for three weeks, was sent down. And the next day, Prince being examined in an apartment of the prison, gave the following Information.</p>
            <p>MIDDLESEX. The Examination of <persName id="OA17640307n41-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n41-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n41-1" type="surname" value="PRINCE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n41-1" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Prince</persName>, now under sentence of death in <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-39">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307-geo-39" type="type" value="site"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17640307n41-1 OA17640307-geo-39"/>Newgate</placeName>, taken this 15th day of February, 1764.</p>
            <p>THIS Examinant says, that he knows Ed - d H - t, late of the Seven-dials, Cheesemonger; T - s G - ff - h, a Cabinet-maker; J - n W - ms, late a Change-broker, and who now lives near Grosvenor, or Hanover-Square; <persName id="OA17640307n42-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n42-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n42-1" type="surname" value="WHITE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n42-1" type="given" value="GEORGE"/>George White</persName>; who lately died in <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-40">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307-geo-40" type="type" value="site"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17640307n42-1 OA17640307-geo-40"/>Newgate</placeName>; Ch - s Wh - e, brother to the said G - e, who is now at large; J - h H - mm - d, and S - l F - r: Says, that about last Spring he frequented H - ll's, at the <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-41">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307-geo-41" type="type" value="street"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17640307n41-1 OA17640307-geo-41"/>
                  <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-42">
                     <interp inst="OA17640307-geo-42" type="type" value="site"/>
                     <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                           targets="OA17640307n41-1 OA17640307-geo-42"/>Wheatsheaf</placeName>, in Purpoollane</placeName>; that he there saw the aforesaid Ch - s and G - e W - te, who told him, that they lived by picking of pockets; that he also then and there saw, in company with the said two Wh - s, two lusty country-looking fellows, who the said Wh - es informed him, lived by robbing on the highway, and by committing other robberies, but does not know the said last mentioned two persons names, but that they use L - l - y's, in <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-43">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307-geo-43" type="type" value="street"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17640307n41-1 OA17640307-geo-43"/>Golden-lane</placeName>; says that about nine months ago he was sent for to the <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-44">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307-geo-44" type="type" value="site"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17640307n41-1 OA17640307-geo-44"/>Royal Oak</placeName>, as he believes at <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-45">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307-geo-45" type="type" value="parish"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17640307n41-1 OA17640307-geo-45"/>Mile-end</placeName>, by G - e Wh - e and Ed - d H - t, who informed him they had a good job for him to do; says they did not then inform him what the job was, but appointed him to meet them at <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-46">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307-geo-46" type="type" value="parish"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17640307n41-1 OA17640307-geo-46"/>
                  <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-47">
                     <interp inst="OA17640307-geo-47" type="type" value="site"/>
                     <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                           targets="OA17640307n41-1 OA17640307-geo-47"/>the Angel</placeName> at Islington</placeName>, at five o' clock the same evening; says he met them there accordingly; says he stayed some time there, when and where they told him, that money must be had, and that if he would go along with them, they had a scheme to get it that night; says they set out from <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-48">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307-geo-48" type="type" value="parish"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17640307n41-1 OA17640307-geo-48"/>Islington</placeName>, and proceeded together on horseback to the <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-49">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307-geo-49" type="type" value="site"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17640307n41-1 OA17640307-geo-49"/>
                  <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-50">
                     <interp inst="OA17640307-geo-50" type="type" value="site"/>
                     <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                           targets="OA17640307n41-1 OA17640307-geo-50"/>Halfway-house</placeName> in the bottom of Finchley Common</placeName>, where they had some brandy; from thence went to <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-51">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17640307n41-1 OA17640307-geo-51"/>Whetstone, and put up their horses at the <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-52">
                     <interp inst="OA17640307-geo-52" type="type" value="site"/>
                     <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                           targets="OA17640307n41-1 OA17640307-geo-52"/>Green Man</placeName>
               </placeName> there; from thence went to <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-53">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307-geo-53" type="type" value="urban_centre"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17640307n41-1 OA17640307-geo-53"/>Barnet to the <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-54">
                     <interp inst="OA17640307-geo-54" type="type" value="site"/>
                     <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                           targets="OA17640307n41-1 OA17640307-geo-54"/>Green Man</placeName>
               </placeName> there, where they drank; from thence went to the <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-55">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307-geo-55" type="type" value="site"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17640307n41-1 OA17640307-geo-55"/>
                  <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-56">
                     <interp inst="OA17640307-geo-56" type="type" value="site"/>
                     <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                           targets="OA17640307n41-1 OA17640307-geo-56"/>White Lion</placeName> at Kitt's Inn</placeName>, put up their horses there, and after staying some time returned towards London, till they got on to <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-57">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307-geo-57" type="type" value="site"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17640307n41-1 OA17640307-geo-57"/>Finchley Common</placeName>: says they then took across the Common towards South</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA176403070011"/>
            <p>gate, when they told him they had come out on purpose to rob the Mail: says they staid together on horseback till they saw the Mail cart come along from <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-58">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307-geo-58" type="type" value="urban_centre"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17640307n41-1 OA17640307-geo-58"/>London</placeName>; when they desired this informant to go and rob it, and at the same time told him, it was a very rich Mail on account of Chester fair: says he refused robbing it, clapt spurs to his horse, and rode away to his lodgings, opposite the <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-59">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307-geo-59" type="type" value="parish"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17640307n41-1 OA17640307-geo-59"/>
                  <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-60">
                     <interp inst="OA17640307-geo-60" type="type" value="site"/>
                     <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                           targets="OA17640307n41-1 OA17640307-geo-60"/>Royal Oak</placeName> at Mile End </placeName>aforesaid: says that about twelve days afterwards the said W - te and H - t again called upon him at his lodging, and that they drank together at the Royal Oak; that they then took him into the fields, and told him they had robbed the Mail at the time they wanted him to rob it as aforesaid; and that W - te then gave this examinant a black pocket-book, now in the possession of T - s M - r, Esq; in which was sixteen or eighteen Bank notes of different sums, all which, they told him, they had got out of the aforesaid Mail: says they desired this informant to put the notes by, but not to put them off without their knowledge: says he kept them about a month, and returned them to them again at the Royal Oak aforesaid: says that a few days afterwards they gave him a thirty pound bank bill, which he, in his way from <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-61">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17640307n41-1 OA17640307-geo-61"/>Ascot-Heath</placeName> races, put off to a Butcher in the morning, who lives opposite the <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-62">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307-geo-62" type="type" value="urban_centre"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17640307n41-1 OA17640307-geo-62"/>
                  <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-63">
                     <interp inst="OA17640307-geo-63" type="type" value="site"/>
                     <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                           targets="OA17640307n41-1 OA17640307-geo-63"/>White Hart</placeName> at Slough</placeName>, who is a lusty man; that H - t and White told him the said note was taken out of the aforesaid Mail: says he afterwards put off a bank bill, at <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-64">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307-geo-64" type="type" value="urban_centre"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17640307n41-1 OA17640307-geo-64"/>Bury St. Edmund's</placeName>, to G - e M - n, an Attorney, of 20l. which he also had from W - te and H - t, and which they told him they got out of the Mail in manner aforesaid: says H - t told him he buried his share of the bank notes and other papers, which were taken out of the said Mail, in his cellar, near <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-65">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17640307n41-1 OA17640307-geo-65"/>Lombard Court</placeName>, Seven-dials: says the widow of G - e Wh - e now lives at Matthew Fr - h's, at Coney, and verily believes that she now has concealed, either in a trunk or in two boxes, papers taken out of the aforesaid Mail. Says, that at the time the said Mail was going to be robbed, as aforesaid, he rode a bay mare, fourteen hands high, which he hired in <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-66">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307-geo-66" type="type" value="parish"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17640307n41-1 OA17640307-geo-66"/>
                  <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-67">
                     <interp inst="OA17640307-geo-67" type="type" value="site"/>
                     <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                           targets="OA17640307n41-1 OA17640307-geo-67"/>Red Lion</placeName> yard, Clerkenwell</placeName>; that G - e Wh - e rode a brown horse of his own, which at that time stood at the first inn on the left hand going down <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-68">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307-geo-68" type="type" value="street"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17640307n41-1 OA17640307-geo-68"/>Old-street</placeName>; that H - t rode a little black horse, which was hired of C - kst - e at <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-69">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307-geo-69" type="type" value="parish"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17640307n41-1 OA17640307-geo-69"/>Mile-end</placeName>, where he this examinant then lodged; that Wh - e was dressed in a brown suit of cloaths, all of the same; but at that time had in his saddle-baggs, a dark grey coat, a black shag waistcoat, and leather breeches; that H - t was dressed in a brown coat and waistcoat, and leather breeches; that he had an old brown great coat tied before him, but that Wh - e had no great coat: Says J - ks - n was a sailor, but now dealt in horses; is a short thick man, and used to pick pockets.</p>
            <p>
               <persName id="OA17640307n44-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n44-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n44-1" type="surname" value="PRINCE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n44-1" type="given" value="JOHN"/>JOHN PRINCE</persName>.</p>
            <p>It was observed by one well versed in these matters, that after this information was known to be on foot, it was designedly or incautiously kept by the prisoner for twenty-four hours; in which time notice for escape and secreting the effects might be given to the parties, and so the design be defeated. That in consequence of it search warrants were issued, and several parties taken up, but nothing was to be found, or proved.</p>
            <p>It was also humanely observed, with due concern, by a Magistrate, that the matter of this examination did not come</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA176403070012"/>
            <p>before the Magistrates in a due and regular channel, by confession made, in a serious hour and frame of preparation, to the proper Minister of the prison, by whom it might have been laid before them, that they might judge whether it deserved the extraordinary favour of a reprieve sine die, and not merely serve the turn of a short, because ill-founded, respite, by which the unhappy convict underwent the dreadful vicissitudes of hopes and fears, and was at length disappointed, to the great disturbance of his mind, and interruption of the regular progress of his preparation. But whom had he to blame for thus undertaking what he could not perform? But there have been like cases of others, who, when sinking, will catch at these twigs.</p>
            <p>The matter of this information being referred from authority to three Magistrates, to consider and report whether the case merited a farther respite, it was agreed and concluded to send a written message to Prince, to acquaint him, that his discoveries hitherto were of no service to the publick, and for the most part known before; therefore not to flatter himself with farther favours, unless he could better fulfil his promise; this being signed by the aforesaid three Gentlemen, was sent to him by the hand of his wife, at least nine or ten days before he suffered. Yet he thought proper to keep this whole transaction a secret from me, nor did it come to my knowledge till communicated thro' an authentic hand after his execution: Insomuch that it now seems unaccountable, how he could amuse himself and me with the appearance of hope, without truth or reason, to the last day; sometimes affecting to expect to know more in a few days; again, insinuating that he was sold by those who better deserved the same fate; then to suspect the intercepting or suppressing some paper of intelligence, which he obscurely hinted at by the application of some bank bills; and dropping other half sentences then unintelligible to me; but which, I now conceive, he must know to be impossible to be true, unless he suspected his wife, or could doubt his own eyes in the answer she brought him. And yet it is well known, she was unwearied and importunate in her applications, and strained some points, at her own peril, to save his life.</p>
            <p>As he was frequently warned by me not to build too much on the renewal of this respite, he assured me he would not; for which he gave an instance; that while he was <rs id="OA17640307-occupation-9" type="occupation">shopman to a draper</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17640307n44-1 OA17640307-occupation-9"/> in <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-70">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307-geo-70" type="type" value="street"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17640307n44-1 OA17640307-geo-70"/>Drury-lane</placeName>, he was picked out as an expeditious rider, to ride post with a respite for a convict in a distant county for six weeks, which was renewed from time to time for six months; and yet at last he suffered.</p>
            <p>In the interval of this respite, Prince was far from being composed, but seemed rather fretful and captious. Some ignorant visitor having told him that his life and character was published, much to his disadvantage, being no other, I presume, than the Grub street half-penny speech, he or his friends absurdly took it in their head to suspect, and at last to accuse me, of doing him this ill office. It greatly shocked me, that in the midst of all the best offices I could do him, he should imagine me capable of so much inconsistency. However, considering his ignorance, and the torturing suspence he was in, I patiently gave him all the satisfaction I could, that I never had seen that paper, nor knew what he meant. Still he, in his resentment, seemed unsatisfied, and brought and returned me all the pious and proper tracts I had lent him for his better</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA176403070013"/>
            <p>instruction and preparation. Being calmly asked, how he could do without them? he answered, he had other good books of his own. He still attended the chapel, except an odd day, when in a sullen fit. The last Sunday he had to live, two persons, having desired leave, happened to come with me to go to the chapel; he outrageously attacked one of them, a working Printer, with hand and tongue, seizing him by the collar, was ready to choke him, and using the bitterest imprecations against him, for having published his life; and swore, if he went up to chapel, he would tumble him down stairs. The man assured him (as, I believe, he well could) that he was quite innocent, and an utter stranger to the affair: Prince answered, It was you, or that parson there! Luckily, I had gone first up to chapel, and was not disturbed with this outrageous fray, till after service being ended, and returning to the press-yard, I reproved the man, with some warmth, for neglecting to come up to the service. He then explained the matter, and pleaded his fears of Prince, as a very reasonable excuse. This matter was quickly made known to Mr. A - k - n, who with temper and prudence undertook to set Prince right. By his means he was convinced of his rash judgment and gross misbehaviour, and when visited next day, relented, asked pardon, and expressed sorrow for his fault, of abusing a person who had spoke favourably of him in the account that was then published. And in truth, none of those papers, so offensive to this unhappy man, ever fell under my eye, tho' enquiry was since made to procure one of them. And considering that those ill-timed and ill-natured invectives, against a man in his critical situation of doubt and fear, might lessen his hope of farther mercy, his resentment, tho' foolishly misplaced, admits of some sort of excuse. The two last days he employed chiefly in writing notes and sending messages to some officers of the Mint and the Post-office; one from each of which came, and had private conferences with him, by which he seemed to expect a renewal of his respite: But, in fine, he was told, they could do him no service. On these occasions, he only told me in general, that his mind and conscience was not easy, till he had opened what he had to say to those gentlemen before he suffered, which, he told me, was a discovery concerning the robbery of the Chester Mail: But said nothing of his conversation with the Gentleman from the Tower. And as to his discovery concerning that robbery of the Mail, it is strongly surmised, for good reasons, that it was all hearsay evidence, which he had learned in conversation from his fellowprisoner, G. White aforesaid, who died in Newgate, and is believed to be the person, or one of them, who committed that fact; for neither Prince nor his wife, when closely examined, could ascertain the time when it was committed. He told me it was above a year ago, while his examination makes it only three quarters of a year; and she, from the circumstances of her husband's returning home in a morning, would have proved it to be in June last: whereas it appears, from the Advertisement, to be on the 7th of September last, between three and four in the morning, by two footpads, the one rather a tall man, pitted with the small-pox; the other rather a short man, in a sailor's jacket and a check shirt, &amp;c.</p>
            <p>He seemed to become very serious and attentive the two last days, in the chapel, when I explained to him, from the chosen Lessons of Isaiah the fifth and St. Luke the sixteenth, and other places, the necessary distinctions between moral good</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA176403070014"/>
            <p>and evil, virtue and vice, obedience and disobedience, and their inevitable consequences; and also the certainty and eternal duration of two opposite states, from the Parable of Dives and Lazarus. When visited the evening before he suffered, several proper and affecting prayers were offered up, in which he humbly and heartily joined. He was very thankful, and expressed his gratitude in the tenderest manner, seizing my hand and kissing it, and shewing great sorrow that he had ever distrusted my care and fidelity, and wished he had placed that confidence in his minister which he put in others.</p>
            <p>The Morning of EXECUTION.</p>
            <p>HAving saluted him with a blessing of Peace, and asked him how are you? he said, As well as can be expected. He had two books in his hand, which I lent him a second time the preceding evening. He was asked, have you made good use of those books? He answered, he had, as long as light was allowed him, which was but an hour after I left him at six. Had you any sleep? Yes, he said, he lost himself for about two hours, and then returned to his thoughts and exercises proper for his approaching change.</p>
            <p>At Prayers and the Administration he behaved with humble and attentive devotion, only seemed too little acquainted with his part of the office, unless directed. After which, he was reminded, to keep in his heart this surest and highest pledge of the love of God, and in his passage to meditate on the articles of the Christian Faith, and these two petitions - Thy kingdom come; thy will be done in earth as it is in heaven: And to comfort himself with the hope that this chastisement is a mark and proof of God's love to his soul, intended by a right use of it to save him from worse, infinitely worse, hereafter. He seemed very thankful, and promised he would comply with these directions. He went down directly, and passed thro' the operation of having his irons knocked off, and his hands and arms bound, with great resignation. He said, indeed, one thing which had better been spared, " That he might " have saved his own life had he put " others in his place; but this he did not " chuse to do." This speech, compared with what has been before related, seems to prove he was not yet purged from the dross of all dissimulation and false pretences. This was his weak side.</p>
            <p>When put in the cart, he appeared intent on his book, and regardless of any thing that passed around him. There were few spectators here in comparison, and fewer at the place of execution; this execution being scarce known, or expected by the public.</p>
            <p>When brought to the tree, he seemed calm and chearful; and being asked, said he was very easy. Also, Whether he now acknowledged the justice of his sentence? he answered, there was no fraud intended, nor forgery committed; but as his King and country had found him guilty, he submitted. He added, that nothing lay heavy on his conscience, nor had he any concern, but that dear, worthy, good creature he left behind him; to whom, he assured me, he was married, whatever malicious report may say to the contrary. The usual proper devotions being performed, in which he joined and also the surrounding people, he looked round with a calm countenance, but seemed to want words; he then said, "The peace of God be with you all; I wish you more grace than I have had, and not to come to this sad end which I have brought myself to." Then having received the last benediction, he quietly resigned his life and suffered his sentence.</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA176403070015"/>
            <p>An ACCOUNT of the BEHAVIOUR Of ANNE BAKER, <persName id="OA17640307n59-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n59-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n59-1" type="surname" value="ROBINS"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n59-1" type="given" value="PETER"/>PETER ROBINS</persName>, <persName id="OA17640307n59-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n59-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n59-2" type="surname" value="ROCKET"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n59-2" type="given" value="JAMES"/>JAMES ROCKET</persName>, and <persName id="OA17640307n59-3">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n59-3" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n59-3" type="surname" value="STEWARD"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n59-3" type="given" value="TIMOTHY"/>TIMOTHY STEWARD</persName>.</p>
            <p>BY virtue of the King's commission of the peace, oyer and terminer, and gaol-delivery of Newgate, holden for the city of London and county of Middlesex, at <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-71">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307-geo-71" type="type" value="site"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17640307n60-1 OA17640307-geo-71"/>
                  <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-72">
                     <interp inst="OA17640307-geo-72" type="type" value="site"/>
                     <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                           targets="OA17640307n60-1 OA17640307-geo-72"/>Justice-hall</placeName> in the Old-Bailey</placeName>, before the <persName id="OA17640307n60-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n60-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n60-1" type="surname" value="BRIDGEN"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n60-1" type="given" value="WILLIAM"/>Right Honourable William Bridgen</persName>, Esq; <rs id="OA17640307-occupation-10" type="occupation">Lord-Mayor of the city of London</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17640307n60-1 OA17640307-occupation-10"/>; <persName id="OA17640307n60-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n60-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n60-2" type="surname" value="GOULD"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n60-2" type="given" value="HENRY"/>Sir Henry Gould</persName>, Knt. one of the <rs id="OA17640307-occupation-11" type="occupation">Judges of his Majesty's Court of Common Pleas</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17640307n60-2 OA17640307-occupation-11"/>; the Honourable Mr. Baron Perrott; <persName id="OA17640307n60-3">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n60-3" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n60-3" type="surname" value="EYRE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n60-3" type="given" value="JAMES"/>James Eyre</persName>, Esq; <rs id="OA17640307-occupation-12" type="occupation">Recorder</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17640307n60-3 OA17640307-occupation-12"/>, and others of his Majesty's Justices of oyer and terminer of the city of London, and Justices of gaol-delivery of Newgate, holden for the said city and county of Middlesex, on Wednesday the 22d, Thursday the 23d, Friday the 24th, Saturday the 25th, Monday the 27th, and Tuesday the 28th of February, in the fourth year of his Majesty's reign, five persons were capitally convicted and received sentence of death, for the several crimes in their indictments set forth, namely,</p>
            <p>
               <persName id="OA17640307n61-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n61-1" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n61-1" type="surname" value="BAKER"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n61-1" type="given" value="ANNE"/>Anne Baker</persName>, <persName id="OA17640307n61-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n61-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n61-2" type="surname" value="ROBINS"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n61-2" type="given" value="PETER"/>Peter Robins</persName>, <persName id="OA17640307n61-3">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n61-3" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n61-3" type="surname" value="WHARTON"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n61-3" type="given" value="JAMES"/>James Wharton</persName>, <persName id="OA17640307n61-4">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n61-4" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n61-4" type="surname" value="ROCKET"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n61-4" type="given" value="JAMES"/>James Rocket</persName>, and <persName id="OA17640307n61-5">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n61-5" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n61-5" type="surname" value="STEWARD"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n61-5" type="given" value="TIMOTHY"/>Timothy Steward</persName>.</p>
            <p>1. And on Friday the 23d of March, the report of the said malefactors was made to his Majesty, by Mr. Recorder, when <persName id="OA17640307n62-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n62-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n62-1" type="surname" value="WHARTON"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n62-1" type="given" value="JAMES"/>James Wharton</persName>, for the robbery of <persName id="OA17640307n62-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n62-2" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n62-2" type="surname" value="CURTISE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n62-2" type="given" value="ANNE"/>Anne Curtise</persName> of 2s. on the <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-73">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17640307n62-1 n62-2 OA17640307-geo-73"/>King's highway</placeName>, was respited, and the other four abovenamed ordered for execution, on Wednesday March 28th, and were executed accordingly.</p>
            <p>2. <persName id="OA17640307n63-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n63-1" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n63-1" type="surname" value="BAKER"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n63-1" type="given" value="ANNE"/>Anne Baker</persName>, <rs id="OA17640307-occupation-13" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17640307n63-1 OA17640307-occupation-13"/>, was indicted, for that she, (together with <persName id="OA17640307n63-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n63-2" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n63-2" type="surname" value="HILL"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n63-2" type="given" value="ANNE"/>Anne Hill</persName>, <persName id="OA17640307n63-3">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n63-3" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n63-3" type="surname" value="DOLEMAN"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n63-3" type="given" value="JAMES"/>James Doleman</persName> and <persName id="OA17640307n63-4">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n63-4" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n63-4" type="surname" value="WRIGHT"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n63-4" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Wright</persName>, not taken,) in a certain alley, near the <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-74">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17640307n63-1 n62-2 n63-3 n63-4 OA17640307-geo-74"/>King's highway</placeName>, on <persName id="OA17640307n63-5">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n63-5" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n63-5" type="surname" value="PORTER"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n63-5" type="given" value="THOMAS"/>Thomas Porter</persName> did make an assault, putting him in corporal fear and danger of his life, and violently taking from his person one guinea and twelve and six-pence in money, numbered, his property, January the 8th.</p>
            <p>The prosecutor, <persName id="OA17640307n64-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n64-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n64-1" type="surname" value="PORTER"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n64-1" type="given" value="THOMAS"/>Thomas Porter</persName>, a <rs id="OA17640307-occupation-14" type="occupation">seafaring and lighter-man</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17640307n64-1 OA17640307-occupation-14"/>, who then lodged on <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-75">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17640307n64-1 OA17640307-geo-75"/>Snow-Hill</placeName>, drinking a pint of beer at the <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-76">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307-geo-76" type="type" value="site"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17640307n64-1 OA17640307-geo-76"/>
                  <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-77">
                     <interp inst="OA17640307-geo-77" type="type" value="site"/>
                     <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                           targets="OA17640307n64-1 OA17640307-geo-77"/>Bell</placeName> in the Old-Bailey</placeName>, fell into this ill company, and had a quarrel raised against him, for speaking a word to save the prisoner from the stripes of a rattan; he went out to avoid them; and the two women, mentioned in the indictment, followed him close, under pretence of getting some persons to see him righted. They got the two men abovementioned. They decoyed him from one alehouse to another, between <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-78">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307-geo-78" type="type" value="site"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17640307n64-1 n63-1 n62-2 n63-3 n63-4 OA17640307-geo-78"/>Fleet-Market</placeName> and the <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-79">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307-geo-79" type="type" value="site"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17640307n64-1 n63-1 n62-2 n63-3 n63-4 OA17640307-geo-79"/>Old-Bailey</placeName>, from seven till twelve at night, and then the women persuading him to see them home to <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-80">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307-geo-80" type="type" value="street"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17640307n64-1 n63-1 n62-2 n63-3 n63-4 OA17640307-geo-80"/>White-Cross Street</placeName>, they led him round through <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-81">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307-geo-81" type="type" value="street"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17640307n64-1 n63-1 n62-2 n63-3 n63-4 OA17640307-geo-81"/>Chick-Lane</placeName>, to <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-82">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307-geo-82" type="type" value="street"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17640307n64-1 n63-1 n62-2 n63-3 n63-4 OA17640307-geo-82"/>Black-Boy Alley</placeName>, where the prisoner, by a frightful whistle which she blew, had him surrounded by five, in a moment. The four now mentioned, struck and wounded him terribly, saying, they would have his money, life, and clothes; and then dragging him by the legs along the</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA176403070016"/>
            <p>street, they held him down, rifled his pockets, cutting one of them out with a knife; this made him cry out, Murder, help, mercy. The prisoner said, Blast him, murder him, &amp;c. Some door opening at that instant, they fled. He caught Wright and hauled him up Chick-Lane; a watchman said, he dared not to assist the prosecutor, among such a number of thieves as are in that lane, for fear of being murdered; and he was advised to let go the robber, which he did. The prisoner was taken the second night after, by a warrant from <persName id="OA17640307n65-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n65-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n65-1" type="surname" value="FIELDING"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n65-1" type="given" value="JOHN"/>Sir John Fielding</persName>, and by help of some of his men, at the said <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-83">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307-geo-83" type="type" value="site"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17640307n63-1 OA17640307-geo-83"/>Bell ale-house</placeName>. Having denied the charge as long as she could, with great impudence and imprecations, she at last confessed it, and impeached her accomplices, saying, she and <persName id="OA17640307n65-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n65-2" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n65-2" type="surname" value="HILL"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n65-2" type="given" value="ANNE"/>Anne Hill</persName> had 6s. each, and the two men 12s. each; that they lay together that night; and she was an unhappy woman. All which is confirmed by several other witnesses.</p>
            <p>Being convicted, she, with the other two Protestant convicts, attended the chapel, February the 26th, and before prayers heard an exhortation suited to their sad case, with which they seemed deeply affected. On Tuesday afternoon, the 28th, they received sentence of death. After this they were daily instructed in a manner suited to their gross ignorance, and evil habits, and taught to join in the service, with which they seemed little acquainted. Baker could not read, and required the more labour to be laid out in teaching her. She said she was only nineteen years of age, the daughter of a Printer, of the name of Craddock, born in <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-84">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307-geo-84" type="type" value="parish"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17640307n63-1 OA17640307-geo-84"/>
                  <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-85">
                     <interp inst="OA17640307-geo-85" type="type" value="site"/>
                     <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                           targets="OA17640307n63-1 OA17640307-geo-85"/>St. John's Square</placeName>, Clerkenwell</placeName>; the name of Baker being that of her husband, a sailor, now abroad; that while her father lived, she got a little instruction, and could read; but he dying, left her poor mother a widow, with five children, about four or five years ago; in her tenth year she had a fever, which hurt her eyes, so that she was blind nearly for a year, and so lost her reading. When recovered, and at a proper age, she was put out by the <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-86">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307-geo-86" type="type" value="parish"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17640307n63-1 OA17640307-geo-86"/>parish of St. Bride's</placeName>, to a man in <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-87">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307-geo-87" type="type" value="street"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17640307n63-1 OA17640307-geo-87"/>Rosemary-Lane</placeName>, to learn the business of <rs id="OA17640307-occupation-15" type="occupation">closeing shoes, and dealing in old cloaths</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17640307n63-1 OA17640307-occupation-15"/>; here, she described her treatment to be so very bad, that she ran away, and made her complaint to the parish officers. They passed her back to <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-88">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307-geo-88" type="type" value="parish"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17640307n63-1 OA17640307-geo-88"/>Whitechapel parish</placeName>, in which her master lived, to whom she was compelled to return, and was then treated worse than ever; for she said, he was the first that corrupted her, and used to lock her up, and force her to yield to his wicked purposes. She then fled from him entirely, and went and hired herself at the <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-89">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307-geo-89" type="type" value="parish"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17640307n63-1 OA17640307-geo-89"/>
                  <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-90">
                     <interp inst="OA17640307-geo-90" type="type" value="site"/>
                     <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                           targets="OA17640307n63-1 OA17640307-geo-90"/>Blue Ball and Crown</placeName> in Black-Friars</placeName>, a publick house, where she lived for two years. But being seduced by some unhappy young girls like herself, she then went to a house of ill-fame near <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-91">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17640307n63-1 OA17640307-geo-91"/>Fleet-ditch</placeName>, begun to walk the street, and has been in these wretched and detestable courses for some years, so that she now seemed languid, distempered, and decayed, at an age when youth and virtue would have ripened her into blooming health and strength. She was free to confess she had lived in several bad houses, partly as a <rs id="OA17640307-occupation-16" type="occupation">servant</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17640307n63-1 OA17640307-occupation-16"/>, and partly as a guest. She owned she was in company with the prosecutor, and the other men, who frequent those houses, and go a thieving; but denied the most odious and cruel parts of the charge against her, pretending she knew not the men had robbed and abused the prosecutor, till she heard him cry out murder, and then she ran away. They were duly warned</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA176403070017"/>
            <p>not to dissemble and hide their sins, but to repent of them all without reserve. After the Death warrant she seemed so far convinced of this duty, that she humbly and heartily opened several acts of theft she had been guilty of; such as going off with a guinea now and then, of a guest, which was entrusted with her to change; and once she stole three guineas of a sick man, whom her mother was a nursing. She was also concerned in the robbery of a man at the <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-92">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307-geo-92" type="type" value="street"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17640307n63-1 OA17640307-geo-92"/>
                  <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-93">
                     <interp inst="OA17640307-geo-93" type="type" value="street"/>
                     <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                           targets="OA17640307n63-1 OA17640307-geo-93"/>
                     <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-94">
                        <interp inst="OA17640307-geo-94" type="type" value="site"/>
                        <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                              targets="OA17640307n63-1 OA17640307-geo-94"/>Turk's Head Bagnio</placeName>, in Catharine-street</placeName>, near the Strand</placeName>.</p>
            <p>While the Death-warrant was delayed, she and her-fellow convicts seemed to forget their condition and to relapse into bad habits and filthy conversation; but when she found she must die, she wept and lamented much; was filled with sorrow and shame for her past sinful life, and became more thoughtful and serious than ever.</p>
            <p>By help of the plain instructions which were daily given them, she endeavoured to prepare herself with all the requisites for receiving the holy communion; and after careful examination and repeated instruction, was admitted to it the day before she suffered, not without hope and comfort.</p>
            <p>3. <persName id="OA17640307n70-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n70-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n70-1" type="surname" value="ROBINS"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n70-1" type="given" value="PETER"/>Peter Robins</persName>, <persName id="OA17640307n70-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n70-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n70-2" type="surname" value="GALLIHER"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n70-2" type="given" value="CHARLES"/>Charles Galliher</persName>, and <persName id="OA17640307n70-3">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n70-3" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n70-3" type="surname" value="GODFREY"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n70-3" type="given" value="JANE"/>Jane Godfrey</persName>, otherwise <persName id="OA17640307n70-5">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n70-5" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n70-5" type="surname" value="SIMONDS"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n70-5" type="given" value="JANE"/>Simonds</persName>, <rs id="OA17640307-occupation-17" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17640307n70-3 n70-5 OA17640307-occupation-17"/>, were indicted, for that they, on the 16th of January, about the hour of one in the night, the dwelling house of <persName id="OA17640307n70-4">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n70-4" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n70-4" type="surname" value="WATTS"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n70-4" type="given" value="CHRISTIAN"/>Christian Watts</persName> did break and enter, and steal one large silver salver value 5 l. one silver apple scoop value 2 s. two silver tea spoons value 2 s. one silver table spoon value 6 s. two silver dessert forks value 3 s. one pair of cotton stockings value 2 s. one pair of worsted stockings value 2 s. one canvas bag value 1 d. and 20 s. in money numbered, the property of the said Christian, in her dwelling house.</p>
            <p>This burglary and robbery is the more aggravated, as it was perpetrated against a lonely gentlewoman in years, at <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-95">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307-geo-95" type="type" value="county"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17640307n70-1 n70-2 n70-3 n70-4 n70-5 OA17640307-geo-95"/>
                  <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-96">
                     <interp inst="OA17640307-geo-96" type="type" value="urban_centre"/>
                     <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                           targets="OA17640307n70-1 n70-2 n70-3 n70-4 n70-5 OA17640307-geo-96"/>Staines</placeName>, Middlesex</placeName>, afflicted with deafness, and unguarded by any company in her house, which stands alone in the <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-97">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307-geo-97" type="type" value="street"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17640307n70-1 n70-2 n70-3 n70-4 n70-5 OA17640307-geo-97"/>Hampton Road</placeName>. In the morning of the 16th or 17th of January, she found the glass of her window had been broke, the sash of the staircase unscrewed, her chamber door broke to pieces, which had been fastened with a lock and bar, her pocket taken from under her head, emptied, and thrown in the passage; five locks broke; the several things mentioned in the indictment missing, besides a feather-bed thrown out of a window into the garden. Three of her neighbours, being called in, were eyewitnesses of the damages, to which they gave testimony. Mr. Bolt, by applying to <persName id="OA17640307n71-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n71-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n71-1" type="surname" value="FIELDING"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n71-1" type="given" value="JOHN"/>Sir John Fielding</persName>, and advertising the particulars, traced the affair to the prisoner Robins, who was stopt with the salver, on Sunday the 22d of January, by Mr. Hebbleswaite, a Watch-maker, in New-Street, St. Martin's in the Fields, and given in charge to Mr. Sheffield the Constable. He said first, it was a family piece of plate, that belonged to his mother. Then, before the Magistrate, that it was thrown at him, by a man galloping by his door, with several other improbable falsehoods, till at last the prosecutrix coming to town, and swearing to the property, he declared the truth in all its circumstances, discovered his two accomplices, and that he had sold the rest of the plate at Mr. Master's, a Silver-smith, in Coventry-Street, where they found it.</p>
            <p>
               <persName id="OA17640307n72-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n72-1" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n72-1" type="surname" value="GODFREY"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n72-1" type="given" value="JANE"/>Jane Godfrey</persName> was taken in the street, and Galliher in his bed at <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-98">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307-geo-98" type="type" value="urban_centre"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17640307n70-2 OA17640307-geo-98"/>Egham</placeName>: She swore against a fourth person, who being taken up, and examined, was set at liberty, being thought innocent. She would</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA176403070018"/>
            <p>have turned evidence, but was not judged, by Mr. Bolt, sit to be credited.</p>
            <p>The prisoner in his defence denied no part of the evidence given against him, but rather confirmed it, by admitting he first named the person to be robbed, in very abusive and opprobrious terms; which terms expressed more vengeance against the injured prosecutrix, than a sense of his own guilt, or the least remorse for it at this time. Bad symptoms, indeed! which glared so strong against him, that they probably contributed to countervail all the powerful interest since used to save his life.</p>
            <p>There being nothing found on the other two accomplices, nor no evidence against them, but that of the prisoner; they are acquitted and let loose. But let them be warned, by his fate, how they intangle themselves again.</p>
            <p>For some time after conviction Robins said he could not read, but stood silent in the chapel, and took no proper books to assist him in the cell: For this reason, perhaps, Wharton, his fellow convict, was put in the same cell to read to him, till they disagreed in about a week, and were parted; when it came out that Robins could read a little tolerably, and having books put into his hands, began to apply himself to it, both in chapel and in private. His case and condition having been strongly and frequently represented to him, he seemed really affected; he began to look serious, dejected, and terrified, and to give more earnest heed to instruction. He was naturally of a good spritely countenance, about twenty-four years of age, well-made, of a middle size, seemed strong and active, and capable of doing much good, or evil. It should have been mentioned before, that when first questioned, what he was convicted for? he put on a piteous face, and said it was for robbing a house, but he was never in it, nor near it. This was gross prevarication, after all that he had confessed, and was proved against him. He was reminded, that he was now in a situation, where the hiding of his guilt could be of no service to him, in the presence of him to whom his heart, life, and actions were open and visible; to whom if he denied his guilt, it was not only vain, but must seal his destruction. On this he was silent for the future about his innocence; and only insisted that this was his first fact; and from this he never departed. His meaning in the former assertion he explained to be, that he was not one of those who broke into the house, but only stood at the window and received the goods, and, to his cost, sold them too.</p>
            <p>On his insisting that this was his first and only fact, he was told it was otherwise believed and reported by those who knew him at <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-99">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307-geo-99" type="type" value="urban_centre"/>Staines</placeName>. He seemed surprized, and appealed to his character there; and pleaded the common excuse, that he was in liquor when he did this.</p>
            <p>He told me he was born in <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-100">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307-geo-100" type="type" value="urban_centre"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17640307n70-1 OA17640307-geo-100"/>Northampton</placeName>, that his father was a plumber and glazier; which business he had not thoroughly learned, but used to work at <rs id="OA17640307-occupation-18" type="occupation">house-painting</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17640307n70-1 OA17640307-occupation-18"/> at <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-101">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307-geo-101" type="type" value="urban_centre"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17640307n70-1 OA17640307-geo-101"/>Staines</placeName>, and sometimes at <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-102">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307-geo-102" type="type" value="urban_centre"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17640307n70-1 OA17640307-geo-102"/>London</placeName>; that he used also to break and ride young horses. He did not mention, what I heard from others, that he was some time in the <rs id="OA17640307-occupation-19" type="occupation">light horse</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17640307n70-1 OA17640307-occupation-19"/>, and of Lord Albemarle's troop; which being reduced, he was discharged. Also that he could earn 20s. a week as a <rs id="OA17640307-occupation-20" type="occupation">plumber</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17640307n70-1 OA17640307-occupation-20"/>.</p>
            <p>He was married to a young woman of a decent family at <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-103">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307-geo-103" type="type" value="urban_centre"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17640307n70-1 OA17640307-geo-103"/>Staines</placeName>, by whom he has left issue. His wife and brother are said to have been very active in applying to get his sentence mitigated, and some</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA176403070019"/>
            <p>great personages spoke for the same favour, but could not prevail.</p>
            <p>He, with the other convicts, had relapsed into a scene of very indecent conversation about the 18th of March, while the sword of justice seemed suspended; but being reproved, and the danger of so hardened and desperate a temper set before them, they seemed to relent, and behave better the few remaining days.</p>
            <p>After the Death-warrant he was remarkably composed, and said he expected no other, and hoped he was on a good foundation. On expressing his preparation and desire, he was admitted to communicate. Wharton also, who is respited, humbly and devoutly joined with them in this duty, the day before and the morning they suffered.</p>
            <p>On the 25th, being the last Sunday they had to live, the nature, end, and institution of the holy communion was summed up to them a-new, before prayers. The prisoners in general were serious and attentive, and the convicts behaved with deep humility and sorrow. Then followed the morning-service. From the first proper lesson, Genesis chap. xxxix. the two very contrary characters of faithful Joseph, and his lewd, perfidious, and vindictive mistress, were contrasted and set in opposite points of view. The blessing and prosperity of Joseph sprung hence, that the Lord was with him, and preserved him in purity of heart and integrity of life; while they who forsake God are left to themselves, to work their own ruin. The epistle for the day, Ephes. ch. v. proved exactly suitable to warn and reprove these backsliding convicts, and other prisoners, for their bad habits and conversation, which was therefore opened and applied to them. For this ye know, that no whoremonger, nor unclean person, nor covetous man who is an idolater, hath any inheritance in the kingdom of Christ and of God: The conscience and experience of sinners joining to convince them, that (without repentance) the punishments are and will be inflicted, as sure as denounced. Let no man deceive you with vain words: for because of these things cometh the wrath of God on the children of disobedience. In the afternoon they were farther instructed from the ixth chapter of Jeremiah, and the xiith chapter to the Hebrews, and from other proper portions of Scripture on different occasions.</p>
            <p>4. <persName id="OA17640307n84-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n84-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n84-1" type="surname" value="ROCKET"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n84-1" type="given" value="JAMES"/>James Rocket</persName>, otherwise <persName id="OA17640307n84-5">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n84-5" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n84-5" type="surname" value="PRICE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n84-5" type="given" value="JAMES"/>Price</persName>, and <persName id="OA17640307n84-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n84-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n84-2" type="surname" value="STEWARD"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n84-2" type="given" value="TIMOTHY"/>Timothy Steward</persName>, were indicted, for that they (in company with <persName id="OA17640307n84-3">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n84-3" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n84-3" type="surname" value="REDMOND"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n84-3" type="given" value="JOSEPH"/>Joseph Redmond</persName>, sick in gaol) in a certain footway, near the <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-104">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17640307n84-1 n84-5 n84-3 n84-2 n84-4 OA17640307-geo-104"/>King's highway</placeName>, on <persName id="OA17640307n84-4">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n84-4" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n84-4" type="surname" value="PENNINGTON"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n84-4" type="given" value="JOHN"/>John Pennington</persName> did make an assault, putting him in corporal fear and danger of his life, and violently taking from his person a metal watch, value 3l. three metal seals, value 12d. a brass watch-key, value 1d. three guineas and five shillings in money numbered, his property, November 20.</p>
            <p>This fact was brought home to the two prisoners, on the evidence of one of their accomplices, <persName id="OA17640307n85-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n85-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n85-1" type="surname" value="LOWTHER"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n85-1" type="given" value="JOSEPH"/>Joseph Lowther</persName>, (there being five of them concerned) supported by the prosecutor's swearing to both Rockett and Steward; and also by <persName id="OA17640307n85-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n85-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n85-2" type="surname" value="JACOBS"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n85-2" type="given" value="HENRY"/>Henry Jacobs</persName>, son of a Jew Silversmith in <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-105">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307-geo-105" type="type" value="parish"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17640307n85-2 OA17640307-geo-105"/>Wapping</placeName>, to whom the said two prisoners sold the watch and seals for a guinea, and the property of which was also sworn to by the prosecutor. He was first cruelly knocked down with a poker by one of this inhuman gang, who is now a respite in Newgate. Pennington being somewhat in liquor, and a stranger about those parts of <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-106">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307-geo-106" type="type" value="street"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17640307n84-4 OA17640307-geo-106"/>Nightingale-lane</placeName> and <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-107">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17640307n84-4 OA17640307-geo-107"/>East Smithfield</placeName>, had enquired his way of them, and was making home through <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-108">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307-geo-108" type="type" value="parish"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17640307n84-4 OA17640307-geo-108"/>Chelsea</placeName> to <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-109">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307-geo-109" type="type" value="parish"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17640307n84-4 OA17640307-geo-109"/>Battersea</placeName>
            </p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA176403070020"/>
            <p>, where he lives, and is a <rs id="OA17640307-occupation-21" type="occupation">Slater</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17640307n84-4 OA17640307-occupation-21"/>, <rs id="OA17640307-occupation-22" type="occupation">Plaisterer</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17640307n84-4 OA17640307-occupation-22"/>, and <rs id="OA17640307-occupation-23" type="occupation">Painter</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17640307n84-4 OA17640307-occupation-23"/>. These five seafaring men were prowling about, and had formed a scheme to rob a Chandler's shop of the till, while one of them was buying some bread and cheese: This being prevented by the people being on their guard, they were looking out for some other prey when they met with this unlucky man, whom they marked out, followed, and beset, till they treated him in the manner described. 'Tis well the knot is broke!</p>
            <p>
               <persName id="OA17640307n87-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n87-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n87-1" type="surname" value="ROCKETT"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n87-1" type="given" value="JAMES"/>James Rockett</persName> told me his true name is <persName id="OA17640307n87-2">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n87-2" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n87-2" type="surname" value="LOCKART"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n87-2" type="given" value="JAMES"/>Lockart</persName>, that his father was a Scotchman and belonged to the army, and his mother an Irish woman; that he was born in the English camp, then in some part of <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-110">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307-geo-110" type="type" value="region"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17640307n87-1 n87-2 OA17640307-geo-110"/>Germany</placeName>; he pretended he was but sixteen years of age, but it proved afterwards he could not be less than twenty-two or twenty-three years old, for he was said to be an old offender, and companion to Steward, who owned himself to be about that age. They were often invited to attend our service, but refusing to come, they were warned not to trust in any other means of salvation without true repentance, and an entire change of mind and manners. They had enlisted themselves under a different persuasion, and would give little account of their past life. They were both illiterate, and very ignorant.</p>
            <p>
               <persName id="OA17640307n88-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n88-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n88-1" type="surname" value="STEWARD"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n88-1" type="given" value="TIMOTHY"/>Timothy Steward</persName> was born at <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-111">
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17640307n88-1 OA17640307-geo-111"/>Knightsbridge</placeName>, where his father lived some time, and, as he said, was one of the Gardeners of Kensington gardens, which employment, I was told, he quitted for that of a Coal-heaver in the river, and about <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-112">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307-geo-112" type="type" value="parish"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17640307n88-1 OA17640307-geo-112"/>Wapping</placeName>, in which neighbourhood his mother now lives. This lad served his <rs id="OA17640307-occupation-24" type="occupation">apprenticeship to the sea</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17640307n88-1 OA17640307-occupation-24"/> in a vessel out of <placeName id="OA17640307-geo-113">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307-geo-113" type="type" value="urban_centre"/>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y"
                        targets="OA17640307n88-1 OA17640307-geo-113"/>Scarborough</placeName>, in the <rs id="OA17640307-occupation-25" type="occupation">coal trade</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17640307n88-1 OA17640307-occupation-25"/>, and was afterwards in his <rs id="OA17640307-occupation-26" type="occupation">Majesty's service</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17640307n88-1 OA17640307-occupation-26"/> for two years. When asked what religion his parents professed? he answered, he knew not, for they taught him none, nor ever made him go to any place of worship, to which he and his companion were strangers. No wonder, will the serious reader be apt to say, they were brought to this untimely and shameful death! Their religion being to chuse, and they incapable of making any distinction, it was said in the prison they chose the church of Rome, on account of some emoluments allowed them. These two behaved careless and insolent till they found themselves included in the Death-warrant, when they appeared more thoughtful and humble.</p>
            <p>On the Morning of EXECUTION.</p>
            <p>
               <persName id="OA17640307n90-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n90-1" type="gender" value="female"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n90-1" type="surname" value="BAKER"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n90-1" type="given" value="ANN"/>ANN Baker</persName> and Robins, when visited, were found in a composed and hopeful temper, as they were left the day before. Baker said, she had asked pardon of her mother for all her disobedience and rude behaviour to her, and had taken leave of her mother and sister in peace. Robins confessed nothing farther. The usual good offices in the chapel were performed for them, and they seemed well supported and resigned. About nine these two were put in one cart, and Rockett and Steward in a second; one of the latter, viz. Rockett, behaved with levity, dancing in the cart, and calling out to some sailors in the crowd, What ship, brother? He was in a different temper at the place of execution, where he confessed, "he was in the company that committed this robbery; but had deserved this death for other facts more than this; that he would not take warning, though he had been transported from Hicks's-hall, but returned from the Havanna in a King's ship, and fell again into bad company at Saltpetre-bank." Steward denied "he</p>
            <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="OA176403070021"/>
            <p>had been long in these courses, but was foolishly drawn into this fact."</p>
            <p>Robins was very easy and calm; both he and Baker behaved with great devotion, and were prayed for by the surrounding multitude, at their own request. They warned others to beware of bad company and bad courses; to which purpose Baker repeated this couplet:</p>
            <p>Take heed ill company and vice to shun,</p>
            <p>Lest soon like mine your glass may run.</p>
            <p>When prayers were ended, and I had parted from them, she fainted, and was only supported by the cord; after which they quickly suffered their dreadful sentence.</p>
            <p>This is all the account given by me,</p>
            <p>
               <persName id="OA17640307n97-1">
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n97-1" type="gender" value="male"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n97-1" type="surname" value="ROE"/>
                  <interp inst="OA17640307n97-1" type="given" value="STEPHEN"/>STEPHEN ROE</persName>,</p>
            <p>
               <rs id="OA17640307-occupation-27" type="occupation">ORDINARY of Newgate.</rs>
               <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y"
                     targets="OA17640307n97-1 OA17640307-occupation-27"/>
            </p>
         </div0>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>