<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div0 type="sessionsPaper" id="16830524A">
            <interp inst="16830524A" type="collection" value="BAILEY"/>
            <interp inst="16830524A" type="year" value="1683"/>
            <interp inst="16830524A" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/16830524A"/>
            <interp inst="16830524A" type="date" value="16830524"/>
            <xptr type="transcription" doc="16830524A"/>
   
            <div1 type="frontMatter" id="f16830524a-1">
               <interp inst="f16830524a-1" type="collection" value="BAILEY"/>
               <interp inst="f16830524a-1" type="year" value="1683"/>
               <interp inst="f16830524a-1" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/16830524A"/>
               <interp inst="f16830524a-1" type="date" value="16830524"/>
         
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="16830524a001"/>The TRUE PROCEEDINGS OF THE SESSIONS, Begun at the OLD-BAYLY, On Thursday the 24th. of May, 1683.</p>
               <p>Giving an Account of the several Tryals, viz. for Murders, Felonies, &amp;c with Condemnation of those Convicted.</p>
               <p>Printed by Authority.</p>
            </div1>
   
   
      
         
            <p>
            
               <persName id="u16830524-6-defend1" type="defendantName">
                  Mary 
                  Philips
               <interp inst="u16830524-6-defend1" type="surname" value="Philips"/>
                  <interp inst="u16830524-6-defend1" type="given" value="Mary"/>
                  <interp inst="u16830524-6-defend1" type="gender" value="female"/>
               </persName>
             (being one that Buys and Sells Old Cloaths in Thamesstreet) was Indicted for being accessory with 
               <persName id="u16830524-6-person2">
                  Anne 
                  Parkinson
               <interp inst="u16830524-6-person2" type="surname" value="Parkinson"/>
                  <interp inst="u16830524-6-person2" type="given" value="Anne"/>
                  <interp inst="u16830524-6-person2" type="gender" value="female"/>
               </persName>
             to the stealing a black Suit, a Campagne Coat, and Several other Goods from one 
               <persName id="u16830524-6-victim3" type="victimName">Mr. Wood
               <interp inst="u16830524-6-victim3" type="surname" value="Wood"/>
                  <interp inst="u16830524-6-victim3" type="gender" value="male"/>
               </persName>
            , which said Parkinson being fled, is Outlawed for the same. The principal thing which aggravated the matter against Philips was, that she did not keep them in her Shop where she pretended to Buy them, but had hidden them up two pair of Stairs, under a very great parcel of Old Rags. But many Witnesses speaking to her good Reputation, and to the Buying them in her Shop, she was therefore Acquitted.</p>
      
   
   
      
         
            <p>
            
               <persName id="u16830524-7-defend4" type="defendantName">
                  Isabel 
                  Barker
               <interp inst="u16830524-7-defend4" type="surname" value="Barker"/>
                  <interp inst="u16830524-7-defend4" type="given" value="Isabel"/>
                  <interp inst="u16830524-7-defend4" type="gender" value="female"/>
               </persName>
            , Indicted for Keeping a Common Bawdy-house in Moor-Lane, not far from Moor-fields; but there being no proof thereof, more than that a Married Man lay for some time at her House with a Strumpet as Lodgers, and affirming they were Man and Wife, she was therefore brought in not Guilty.</p>
      
   
   
      
         
            <p>
               <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="16830524a002"/>
            
               <persName id="u16830524-4-defend5" type="defendantName">
                  John 
                  Butler
               <interp inst="u16830524-4-defend5" type="surname" value="Butler"/>
                  <interp inst="u16830524-4-defend5" type="given" value="John"/>
                  <interp inst="u16830524-4-defend5" type="gender" value="male"/>
               </persName>
            , Indicted for Stealing a white Caster, a Sword and Belt, &amp;c the Witnesses proved that he coming into a Publick House with other Company to Drink, and being shewed into an upper Room, he left his Company, and went into a back Chamber, from whence he took the said Goods. He in his defence said, the Closet or Back-chamber door being open, and he full of Drink, did go in and take out the Sword, which one of his Consorts afterwards got from him, but denied the rest, this Confession of his making it so evident, he was found Guilty of Felony.</p>
      
   
   
      
         
            <p>
            
               <persName id="u16830524-3-defend6" type="defendantName">
                  Christopher 
                  Gage
               <interp inst="u16830524-3-defend6" type="surname" value="Gage"/>
                  <interp inst="u16830524-3-defend6" type="given" value="Christopher"/>
                  <interp inst="u16830524-3-defend6" type="gender" value="male"/>
               </persName>
            , a kind of Beggar-man, under pretence of Begging, went into a Shop, and put up some Half-hundred weights (or one at least) into a Bag, which being noted by a Milk-woman he fled, but when taken confessed he had at times Sold four such Weights to a Pewterer, all which were lost from the same place, and the Pewterer since restored Three of them to the Owner, he was therefore found Guilty.</p>
      
   
   
      
         
            <p>
            
               <persName id="u16830524-13-defend7" type="defendantName">
                  Sarah 
                  Stephens
               <interp inst="u16830524-13-defend7" type="surname" value="Stephens"/>
                  <interp inst="u16830524-13-defend7" type="given" value="Sarah"/>
                  <interp inst="u16830524-13-defend7" type="gender" value="female"/>
               </persName>
            , Indicted for Picking the Pocket of 
               <persName id="u16830524-13-victim8" type="victimName">
                  Nathaniel 
                  Berry
               <interp inst="u16830524-13-victim8" type="surname" value="Berry"/>
                  <interp inst="u16830524-13-victim8" type="given" value="Nathaniel"/>
                  <interp inst="u16830524-13-victim8" type="gender" value="male"/>
               </persName>
             of Eighteeen pence, upon the Trial it appeared Berry had Pick'd her up somewhere in Fleetstreet, and carrying her to Drink, she Pick'd his Pocket of the said Money (being all he had) But the said Sarah Stephens in her defence, so confidently denied any knowledge she had of him, or ever to have seen or drank with him; that at length Berry would not swear positively she was the Woman, wherefore she was acquitted.</p>
      
   
   
      
         
            <p>The Middlesex Jury being then Sworn, these Prisoners following were by them Tried, viz. 
               <persName id="u16830524-5-defend9" type="defendantName">
                  Henry 
                  Castleford
               <interp inst="u16830524-5-defend9" type="surname" value="Castleford"/>
                  <interp inst="u16830524-5-defend9" type="given" value="Henry"/>
                  <interp inst="u16830524-5-defend9" type="gender" value="male"/>
               </persName>
            , and 
               <persName id="u16830524-5-defend10" type="defendantName">
                  Thomas 
                  Williamson
               <interp inst="u16830524-5-defend10" type="surname" value="Williamson"/>
                  <interp inst="u16830524-5-defend10" type="given" value="Thomas"/>
                  <interp inst="u16830524-5-defend10" type="gender" value="male"/>
               </persName>
            , Indicted for stealing the Coat of a Person unknown, to the value of 5s. The Prosecutor lived some where in St. Giles in the Fields, to whose Shop Castleford came to Sell the said Coat, Williamson in Company with him. This Shopkeeper suspecting them to be men of an ill Life, caused them to be Seized, and at length Committed; a Bunch of about 12 or more Pick-ock Keys being found in Castlefords Pocket, in excuse of which he then declared he made and sold them. But upon his Tryal he denied it, and said he found them, also that he bought the Coat of a Woman in the street, who Cried Gold and Silver Lace, that he did wear it upon his Back, and had it on when he came to the Shop, which he would not have done if stoln: In conclusion they were both acquitted.</p>
      
   
   
      
         
            <p>
            
               <persName id="u16830524-10-defend11" type="defendantName">
                  Susan 
                  Morgan
               <interp inst="u16830524-10-defend11" type="surname" value="Morgan"/>
                  <interp inst="u16830524-10-defend11" type="given" value="Susan"/>
                  <interp inst="u16830524-10-defend11" type="gender" value="female"/>
               </persName>
            , Indicted for Stealing an Alamode Hood, a Gold Ring, three Holland Aprons, three Cambrick Handkerchiefs, some Laced Sleeves and other Linnen, it appeared she was a Servant Maid to 
               <persName id="u16830524-10-victim12" type="victimName">
                  Charles 
                  Butler
               <interp inst="u16830524-10-victim12" type="surname" value="Butler"/>
                  <interp inst="u16830524-10-victim12" type="given" value="Charles"/>
                  <interp inst="u16830524-10-victim12" type="gender" value="male"/>
               </persName>
            , whose Wife dying when he lay sick, at that opportunity she conveyed away such goods; she was found Guilty to the value of 10d.</p>
      
   
   
      
         
            <p>
            
               <persName id="u16830524-2-defend13" type="defendantName">
                  John 
                  Edgerly
               <interp inst="u16830524-2-defend13" type="surname" value="Edgerly"/>
                  <interp inst="u16830524-2-defend13" type="given" value="John"/>
                  <interp inst="u16830524-2-defend13" type="gender" value="male"/>
               </persName>
            , Indicted for the Murder of 
               <persName id="u16830524-2-victim14" type="victimName">
                  William 
                  Stephenson
               <interp inst="u16830524-2-victim14" type="surname" value="Stephenson"/>
                  <interp inst="u16830524-2-victim14" type="given" value="William"/>
                  <interp inst="u16830524-2-victim14" type="gender" value="male"/>
               </persName>
             at Shadwell, by Shooting off a Pistol at him Charged with Powder, and one Leaden Bullet, which piercing the right part of his Head, he thereof languished, and the next Morning died. But upon the Trial it appeared that the Deceased Stephenson had taken the Pistol from Edgerly to look upon it; that he attempted to Shoot it off, but it not Firing, as he was returning it again to Edgerly, without the Musle end to himself, it accidentally went off and Kill'd him, without the Trricker being pull'd by Edgerly, but as the Cock had been left by Stephenson; therefore it was found Per Infortuniam.</p>
      
   
   
      
         
            <p>
               <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="16830524a003"/>
            
               <persName id="u16830524-11-defend15" type="defendantName">
                  James 
                  Wilson
               <interp inst="u16830524-11-defend15" type="surname" value="Wilson"/>
                  <interp inst="u16830524-11-defend15" type="given" value="James"/>
                  <interp inst="u16830524-11-defend15" type="gender" value="male"/>
               </persName>
            , Indicted for stealing a Livery-Cloak from the Coach Box of a Gentleman that has a Country-house in Hampstead, which he he confest: But the Evidence against him, valuing the Cloak but at 10d. the Jury accordingly found him Guilty to the value of 10d.</p>
      
   
   
      
         
            <p>
            
               <persName id="u16830524-1-defend16" type="defendantName">
                  Peter 
                  Anderson
               <interp inst="u16830524-1-defend16" type="surname" value="Anderson"/>
                  <interp inst="u16830524-1-defend16" type="given" value="Peter"/>
                  <interp inst="u16830524-1-defend16" type="gender" value="male"/>
               </persName>
            , Indicted for a Robbery upon the High-way, committed upon 
               <persName id="u16830524-1-victim17" type="victimName">
                  Samuel 
                  Newton
               <interp inst="u16830524-1-victim17" type="surname" value="Newton"/>
                  <interp inst="u16830524-1-victim17" type="given" value="Samuel"/>
                  <interp inst="u16830524-1-victim17" type="gender" value="male"/>
               </persName>
            , and 
               <persName id="u16830524-1-victim18" type="victimName">
                  Samuel 
                  Blackbourne
               <interp inst="u16830524-1-victim18" type="surname" value="Blackbourne"/>
                  <interp inst="u16830524-1-victim18" type="given" value="Samuel"/>
                  <interp inst="u16830524-1-victim18" type="gender" value="male"/>
               </persName>
            , from whom were taken their Campaigne Coats, Swords, Gold Rings and Moneys, numbred in all to a considerable value. Newton and Blackbourne gave evidence, that they being coming from Colchester were on this side Bow, near where the Man Hangs in Chains set upon by Four Foot-Padds, who pulling them off their Horses, drew them over a Gate to a Dunghil out of the Road, where they Rifled them. Newton Swore he believed Anderson to be one of the Four, but that two only were upon him, and Two upon Blackbourne, of which Two Blackbourne Swore positively that Anderson was one; that he threatned to Shoot him if he spoke a word, and that whereas Blackbourne spoke thick, Anderson Swore he had gotten a Diamond Ring in his Mouth, for which he felt with his Fingers, and threatened to kill Blackbourn if he Bit him: The Evidence therefore being plain against Anderson, he was thereof found Guilty.</p>
      
   
   
      
         
            <p>Mr. 
               <persName id="u16830524-9-defend19" type="defendantName">
                  William 
                  Tyndal
               <interp inst="u16830524-9-defend19" type="surname" value="Tyndal"/>
                  <interp inst="u16830524-9-defend19" type="given" value="William"/>
                  <interp inst="u16830524-9-defend19" type="gender" value="male"/>
               </persName>
            , Indicted for the Murder of 
               <persName id="u16830524-9-victim20" type="victimName">
                  Thomas 
                  Milward
               <interp inst="u16830524-9-victim20" type="surname" value="Milward"/>
                  <interp inst="u16830524-9-victim20" type="given" value="Thomas"/>
                  <interp inst="u16830524-9-victim20" type="gender" value="male"/>
               </persName>
             Gent. Upon the Trial it appeared to be thus, viz. Milward Being a Life-Guard-man, upon some controversy in Law against one Taunt, whose cause Tyndal seemed to Espouse, had conceived a Grudge against him, and to revenge the same, Way-laid him several days, (Mr. Tyndal Living at or near the Mews-Yard.) The most material Witness for the King was a Drawer, who said he saw Mr. Milward waiting in the Gate-way going to the Mews, and that Tyndal coming by, Milward struck him several Blows with a Cudgel, then throwing it away, drew upon him, Swearing Dam you Dog draw (or such like words.) That Tyndal stooping, got up the Stick Milward threw away, and with that defended himself until Milward Cut him in several places, and beat the Stick out of his hand, when forced for defence of himself, he stept Two or Three Paces back and drew, that Milward pursued him with great violence, and thereupon Tyndal gave him the Wound of which he died. And whereas at that time Tyndal was in Black Cloaths, and Milward in light Gray. Two other Witnesses did Swear that assoon as the Black Man came up by the Mews Gate, the White Man took up a Cudgel which stood by him, and violently struck the Black Man several Blows, then threw the Stick away, and drew upon him in manner according to the Drawers Evidence, and that when at last the Black Man drew, the White Man run upon the very Sword, and that by his violent forcing upon the Black Man, his Death was rather occasioned, than by any intent in the other to kill him.</p>
            <p>Other Witnesses were that saw Milward set that Cudgel behind the Gate, and walk about to wait for Tyndals coming by.</p>
            <p>Witnesses For Tyndal were many, amongst which Mr. Howel a very material one, saying that Milward came the Saturday before to Tyndals House, and knocking at the Door, Tyndal came down, and they walked <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="16830524a004"/> together awhile, but at parting Milward dispitefully took hold of Tyndal, saying God Dam you Rascal, you know this is not a place, come out into the Mews, and I'le be revenged on you.</p>
            <p>To which Tyndal replied, what you have to say to me I'le answer at the Law, but if you come hither to Assassinate me, I'le  complain to your Officers. Much other Evidence came in, which made it apparent Tyndal had used all means possible to avoid Fighting, and when set upon, was forced thereto for safeguard of his own Life.</p>
      
   
   
      
         
            <p>
            
               <persName id="u16830524-12-defend21" type="defendantName">
                  James 
                  Dockray
               <interp inst="u16830524-12-defend21" type="surname" value="Dockray"/>
                  <interp inst="u16830524-12-defend21" type="given" value="James"/>
                  <interp inst="u16830524-12-defend21" type="gender" value="male"/>
               </persName>
            , and 
               <persName id="u16830524-12-defend22" type="defendantName">
                  Sarah 
                  Carter
               <interp inst="u16830524-12-defend22" type="surname" value="Carter"/>
                  <interp inst="u16830524-12-defend22" type="given" value="Sarah"/>
                  <interp inst="u16830524-12-defend22" type="gender" value="female"/>
               </persName>
            , were Indicted for Stealing a Sheet to the value of 5s. from 
               <persName id="u16830524-12-victim23" type="victimName">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Shipton
               <interp inst="u16830524-12-victim23" type="surname" value="Shipton"/>
                  <interp inst="u16830524-12-victim23" type="given" value="Elizabeth"/>
                  <interp inst="u16830524-12-victim23" type="gender" value="female"/>
               </persName>
             Widdow, into whose House they came to Drink; the Widdow and her Daughter did Swear the Sheet to be upon their Bed before the said two Persons came, and that they miss'd it assoon as they were gone, none else being in the Room: Dockray produced several Witnesses for his good Reputation, and the Prosecutor was of the belief he was innocent, but that Sarah Carter had privately Stole the Sheet, however they were both Acquitted.</p>
      
   
   
            <div1 type="punishmentSummary" id="s16830524a-1">
               <interp inst="s16830524a-1" type="collection" value="BAILEY"/>
               <interp inst="s16830524a-1" type="year" value="1683"/>
               <interp inst="s16830524a-1" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/16830524A"/>
               <interp inst="s16830524a-1" type="date" value="16830524"/>
         
               <p>There was only one Person, viz. Peter Anderson received Sentence of Death this Sessions. </p>
               <p>Christopher Gage Burnt in the Hand.</p>
               <p>John Butler craved benefit of his Clergy, but when he came to the Book could not read, so upon his further Importunity, was set aside for Transportation.</p>
               <p>James Wilson, and Susan Morgan, being each found Guilty to the value of 10d. only; have Judgment to be Whipt.</p>
               <p>Samuel Lambourne, who was the last Sessions Sentenced to dye for Stealing a Gelding of a great Price, but had the favour to be Reprieved, being one amongst others that since attempted to break the Goal, is now appointed to be Hanged.</p>
            </div1>
   
         </div0>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>